<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="100014">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vQJmw_h8nai6q1l5RmgO1w__thumb/img/_wiBvUH5hUD3Ktq2iF8yimnRCfc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1027989.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vQJmw_h8nai6q1l5RmgO1w__original/img/7njJGaNa--6Dibkd7MxjTvtRGMc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1027989.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Whirred PLAY" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; - &amp;lsquo;The Holy Grail of Family Board Games&amp;rsquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;What is Whirred PLAY&amp;trade;?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is a unique word game designed so that anyone can win regardless of their vocabulary and designed so that everyone can play together no matter the composition or size of the family or social group.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Reason Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; was Developed&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; was developed because existing board games did not satisfy a need to be able to play a game with the whole family where everyone was challenged and mentally stimulated, but where everyone had an equal chance of winning. Games of chance such as &amp;lsquo;snakes and ladders&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;ludo&amp;rsquo; can be won by anyone, but they do not offer a lot in the way of mental stimulation for those taking part and soon the thrill of being able to play a board game together as a family diminishes.&amp;#10;More intricate family board games such as &amp;lsquo;Scrabble&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Monopoly&amp;rsquo; do provide the level of mental stimulation required. However, one is much more likely to win these games if one has more life experience (to be able to play strategically) and more education (knowledgeable about a subject). As a consequence younger family members, or those with self perceived lower life skills, shy away from playing these games because they always expect to get beaten.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In order to encourage these groups of people to join in, adults will often have to play below their best to give them a chance to win and to maintain their interest in playing the game. Whilst this is fun for a while, it soon becomes difficult for the adult to gain enough satisfaction from playing the game from the levels of satisfaction achieved by seeing their offspring&amp;rsquo;s delight at winning.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How is Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; Unique?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;So Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; enables everyone to play a game at their own level of skill and strategy, but whatever their level this does not determine whether or not they are more or less likely to win. Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is open for any number of players to join in at the same time, so unlike when playing &amp;lsquo;Scrabble&amp;rsquo; (maximum four players) or &amp;lsquo;Monopoly&amp;rsquo; (maximum six players), no member of the family or social group need sit on the sidelines. Everyone can join in the fun.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Additionally, Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is designed so that at all times in the game everyone always has a chance of winning, no matter their position on the board, until the eventual winner crosses the finishing line. In games such as &amp;lsquo;Scrabble&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Monopoly&amp;rsquo; there will come a point where it is obvious certain players are not going to win.  Some participants may decide that they will leave the game at this point and that can have a detrimental effect on the pleasure of all parties involved in playing the game. This also may become a hindrance for future participation from those who have departed early. A special feature of Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is an element of the game called &amp;lsquo;Pare Up&amp;rsquo;, especially designed to provide ample opportunity for players to bring the leader back to the chasing pack.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Another element of Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; that ensures maximum interest from all parties is that any particular game should last no more than 30 minutes. &amp;lsquo;Scrabble&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Monopoly, in particular, can run on for long periods of time and this can be a barrier for those with shorter attention spans, usually children, to want to take part. And with over 440 cards in Whirred PLAY&amp;trade;, there is very little repetitiveness, as a typical game usually only utilises 30 to 40 cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Additionally, the game play of Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is designed so that everyone is participating all at the same time. No-one has to wait for any one particular player to finish their turn, which in some other family board games can often be quite a long time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is Educational&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; is based on the simple premise of spelling everyday words that just happen to be homophones, a key stage two literacy curriculum topic, it has high appeal amongst both parents and teachers as an excellent fun method of teaching children this difficult subject. Children will want to play Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; because of all of the elements of inclusivity and equality listed above, and parents will be delighted that a game they want to play offers more than just a fun half hour.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Schools can utilise Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; in formal teaching classes due to its all inclusive nature and the ability for the whole class to participate in it, with an equal chance of winning it, at the same time regardless of its size or composition. The competitive nature of Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; especially appeals to boys, traditionally a more difficult group of students to enthuse about learning how to spell.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; - &amp;lsquo;The Holy Grail of Family Board Games&amp;rsquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;So Whirred PLAY&amp;trade; really is a board game like no other. Everyone can take part, everyone has an equal chance of winning, everyone can apply their own level of strategy and utilise their own level of life experience, everyone is involved at all times, everyone can win at all times during the game, no-one gets bored, everyone gets educated and everyone has fun.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1025" value="Word Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="24573" value="Annets Entertainment Ltd." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>