<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="100471">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/LWySxQRxET4BuKG0q5SEow__thumb/img/Am92CTB90W4xK5ow8TdXBmEqgG0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1028708.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/LWySxQRxET4BuKG0q5SEow__original/img/QRrcAM1ZxdMRCo599JAPkzBOif4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1028708.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="TROLLBURGER" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The players are gnomes in the employ of a troll on a burger restaurant. The troll told them: &amp;quot;One of you will be fired at the end of the day; the one with worst cash!&amp;quot;. The troll will take the customer&amp;rsquo;s orders and he hope the gnomes make their work fast, very fast; because if they delay an order, the customer (another troll, usually!) will get angry and leave the restaurant without paying.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAME COMPONENTS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;15 order cards&amp;#10;95 product cards&amp;#10;12 counters: 3 green, 3 blue, 3 yellow and 3 red&amp;#10;Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAME PLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Trollburger&amp;quot; is a 2-player card game. At the start of the turn, the starting player turn over the top deck card and show the number on it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If that number is equal or higher thant the number of order cards on table, another order card is drawn and placed on the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then the starting player choose to perform one of 4 actions on his turn. He can make that action as many times as the number shown at the start of the turn:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Take cards from the product deck&amp;#10;   -Search a card from the product deck&amp;#10;   -Discard cards from the hand&amp;#10;   -Place products on the table to build a burger&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then, he can choose to deliver a burger to the customers. The player can deliver an incomplete burger, in the hope that the customer does not realize.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Next, the other player takes his turn, using the same number; &amp;#10;and at last he becomes the starting player for the next turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If at any time, a 5th order has to be added on tha table, the older order on table is discarded (and any player who was working on it, loses his product cards).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GOAL&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a player devilers an order he takes that order card. &amp;#10;The game ends if 4 orders are discarded or the last order card is drawn.&amp;#10;At the end of the game, each player add the victory points of his order cards. The player with more victory points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(Here you can find all the files to print &amp;amp; play your own Trollburger).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Los jugadores son gnomos que trabajan para un troll en una hamburgueseria. El troll les ha comunicado que uno de ellos sera despedido al final del dia; aquel que aporte menos al negocio. El troll es el encargado de coger los pedidos de los clientes y espera que los gnomos hagan su trabajo rapido, muy rapido; pues si se retrasan en entregar un pedido, el cliente (normalmente otro troll!!) se va a enfadar y se ira del restaurante si haber consumido.COMPONENTES DEL JUEGO&amp;#10;&amp;#10;15 cartas de pedidos&amp;#10;95 cartas de productos&amp;#10;12 contadores: 3 verdes, 3 azules, 3 amarillos y 3 rojos&amp;#10;Reglas&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EL JUEGO&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Trollburger&amp;quot; es un juego de cartas para 2 jugadores. Al principio del turno, el jugador inicial gira la carta superior de la baraja y muestra el n&amp;uacute;mero que aparece en ella.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Si ese numero es igual o mayor que el numero de cartas de pedidos en la mesa, aparece una nueva carta de pedido y se a&amp;ntilde;ade al centro de la mesa.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Despu&amp;eacute;s el jugador inicial elige cual de 4 posibles acciones quiere realizar en su turno. Podra hacer esa accion tantas veces como el numero que se ha mostrado al principio del turno:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Coger cartas de la baraja de productos&amp;#10;   -Buscar una carta en la baraja de productos&amp;#10;   -Descartar cartas de la mano&amp;#10;   -Colocar productos en la mesa para elaborar una hamburguesa&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Despues, puede elegir entregar una hamburguesa a los clientes. El jugador puede entregar una hamburguesa que no este acabada, con la esperanza de que el cliente no se de cuenta.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Acto seguido, el otro jugador realiza su turno, usando el mismo numero; y al final se convierte en el jugador inicial para el siguiente turno.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Si en algun momento, se debe anadir un 5&amp;ordm; pedido a la mesa, el pedido mas antiguo que hubiera en la mesa se descarta (y cualquier jugador que estuviera elaborando ese bocata, pierde los productos que tuviera en la mesa).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OBJETIVO&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cuando un jugador entrega un pedido se queda esa carta de pedido.&amp;#10;El juego finaliza si 4 pedidos se han descartado o si se muestra el ultimo pedido del mazo.&amp;#10;Al final de la partida, cada jugador suma los puntos de victoria de sus cartas de pedidos. El jugador con mas puntos de victoria es el ganador.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(Aqui puedes encontrar todos los archivos necesarios para imprimir y jugar a tu propio Trollburger)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2048" value="Pattern Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5841" value="Theme: Food / Cooking" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="40733" value="Toni Serradesanferm" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>