<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="101743">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Multiverse Jumpers" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Remember Quantum Leap and Sliders? Maybe reading the Exiles series from Marvel Comics? Well this were it's at The game is a 3-5 players co-op where players work together to get back to their home dimension (Earth Prime). To do so they must split their forces between completing missions for/against historical figures encountered in alternate worlds and repairing the Navigator, a device that may lead them home... at least before it's out of power.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Introduction:&amp;#10;&amp;hellip;You just woke up... the last thing you remember is being on that late night bus, slipping in and out of consciousness, rocked by the vibrations of the almost retired vehicle. Then you&amp;rsquo;re here, wherever that may be, everything looks strange but familiar, like looking through a cracked mirror. The other passengers are here too, and they found a device they say can take you all home. How do they know? Who knows indeed? It&amp;rsquo;s worth a shot, anyway you&amp;rsquo;re not liking the sounds of whatever is approaching.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You and the others have fallen through the dimensions that make the multiverse, an infinity of alternate realities where the best utopias and the worst nightmares can be found. The strange device you found, this &amp;quot;Navigator&amp;quot;, seems to be the key to get home. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem in good shape. Was it damaged before, is it the cause of your being here, is it some sort of test? All you know is that the batteries are fading fast and you and your fellow multiverse castaways better fix it and find your home dimension before you stay stranded forever...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aim of the game:&amp;#10;Players must work together to complete the missions set by the Navigator on each world they land and repair the Navigator along the way to ensure that they make it back to their home dimension: Earth Prime. Each turn, the players will encounter a historical figure in a new dimension where things are different and must somehow be righted: a ruthless Benjamin Franklin has sided with the machines to destroy mankind and must be stopped, a benevolent Genghis Khan needs help surviving in a dying world... those are but a few of the thousands of possible missions the players will have to complete before going home.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay:&amp;#10;Each player receives a character card, indicating their strengths and weaknesses along five stats (Status, Fight, Intellect, Stealth and Tech). Each turn, by revealing one of each Alternate World, Target and Mission cards, the players get to face one of over 25000 challenges. As a group, they decide who will attempt the mission and pool their relevant stats to form the mission dice pool. Scoring more successes than the target in the contest set by the Mission card will allow the other players to repair the Navigator device. It's up to the players to assess their chances against various challenges and decide when to use the precious power left in the Navigator until they reveal the Earth Prime card hidden among 29 Alternate World cards to win the game. However the players can lose the game if the Navigator runs out of power or if they run out of World cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="51925" value="Pierre Rebstock" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>