<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="108079">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/s6vLAzKF2qPNW2oG0zGmkw__thumb/img/Y5XjPZQ_dCWLxFWZ_ejhWVwRaIM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1090482.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/s6vLAzKF2qPNW2oG0zGmkw__original/img/ZsHGg-XYLPkJkEKcVDi9o9ASr4E=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1090482.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bibliogamo" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Bibliogamo is a solitaire game of book production and libraries. In this game you will play the role of a publisher in the city of Bibliogamo. Using cards to hire artisans, you will put them to work in six city tower workshops, each devoted to a different kind of book. The Chief Librarian of the City will, in turn, tour the city buying books at what he considers their proper value. Prestige Collection cards generate victory points depending on how well you can fulfill the requirements of the Chief Librarian&amp;rsquo;s collection.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Needed to play: the game board showing the city of Bibliogamo, the 47 Artisan cards, the 7 Prestige Collection cards, 26 black eurocubes representing your Artisans, and 16 red eurocubes to act as track markers in the game. Additionally you&amp;rsquo;ll need one pawn to represent the Librarian.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Win: The game is over when the Time Track eurocube reaches [40] and you complete your turn. For each book you produce, you gain 1VP. For each 5 Florins you have, you gain 1 VP. Prestige VP is awarded as indicated on the Prestige Collection card chosen at the start of the game. Your total VP is your score for the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Five Turn Phases:&amp;#10;1. Move the time track eurocube forward one day closer to [40].&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. Move the Librarian Pawn clockwise 3 spaces, then turn over the top Artisan card from the draw pile on to the discard pile and move the Librarian accordingly as indicated by the Librarian icon on the left-hand side of the card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3. Look at the small Artisan icon below the Librarian icon on this same card. You may not play any card with that Artisan symbol on it this turn unless you discard a card from your hand with a matching small Artisan icon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4. You may now do any of the following, but in order:&amp;#10;a. Pay 1 Florin to move the Librarian forward or backward one space. You may pay 1 Florin for each space you wish to move the Librarian.&amp;#10;b. Sell a book, if completed, in the Tower the Librarian is currently standing on. Turn over the next 2 Artisan cards from the draw deck. Place the second card to the right of the first and look at the florin value on the second card as indicated by the Florin icon at on the first card. This is the amount the Librarian is willing to pay for this book. You may pay extra 1 day of time to turn over another card replacing the current Florin amount. You may continue to do this, paying 1 day of time per card turned over, until you are satisfied with the price.     &amp;#10;Mark this amount on your Florin Track and return all Artisan eurocubes from the completed book to your pool. Then mark the production of a book on your Book track, moving the red eurocube forward one space, and if the book is one of those needed for a Prestige Collection, mark that book on the Prestige Collection card as well with a red eurocube. Note: you may pay extra days of time only if they remain on the Time Track. Lastly, place all drawn cards used to calculate the Florin value on the discard pile.&amp;#10;c. Discard one Artisan card from your hand to the discard pile and place that number of black eurocubes on the Artisans indicated by the card, on any one Tower. Then discard one more card from your hand to pay for those Artisans. You may do this action twice if you wish. You do not receive any surplus Artisans from the discarded card. Nor do you receive any surplus Artisans if your tower already has the number required for that Artisan type. The second time you do this action you may add Artisans to the same tower or a different one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5. Draw back to a hand of 5 cards. If the draw deck is exhausted, shuffle the discard cards for a new draw deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1070" value="Renaissance" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="19564" value="Contests: Solitaire Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="56419" value="Theme: Art" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="60939" value="Theme: Books / Libraries" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="51" />
			<average value="6.38529" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.51881" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="16260" bayesaverage="5.51881" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.2598" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="121" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="5" />
			<wishing value="80" />
			<numcomments value="57" />
			<numweights value="3" />
			<averageweight value="1.3333" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>