<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="111491">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-onUvEfAnYY6FWn7Gw9QJg__thumb/img/Xr36hKaRasAVYMqd5tcm2nr_hHg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1873752.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-onUvEfAnYY6FWn7Gw9QJg__original/img/V3g9Dpa75AF-awV6tbBRnwyB7jM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1873752.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Cock Robin" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Game of Cock Robin" />
			    				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="5" value="The New Game of Cock Robin" />
			
						               													<description>From a description of the game at ALL ABOUT GAMES&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Following most of the words of the Cock Robin nursery rhyme the card game has the players answer the questions found within the rhyme. The first one being, &amp;ldquo;Who killed Cock Robin?&amp;rdquo; And the last one being, &amp;ldquo;Who will sing the psalm?&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;The old card game offers a twist at the ending and differs from the nursery rhyme. The players of the game are told Cock Robin is alive and well and they have all been telling a story! This is the part of the game which truly has the players interacting with each other and reveals the fun age of the times.&amp;#10;The directions for the game of Cock Robin begin with choosing a person to be the dealer. After having all the cards dealt out to theplayers, the dealer is then the person who asks the questions.  For example, the dealer reads the first question of &amp;ldquo;Who killed Cock Robin?&amp;rdquo; The correct animal card to specifically answer is the Sparrow card. It reads, &amp;ldquo;I, said the Sparrow, with my bow and arrow. I killed Cock Robin.&amp;rdquo; If the player has the &amp;lsquo;Sparrow&amp;rsquo; card, he lays his card down on the table in front of him and the dealer asks the next question to the next player (Who saw him die?).&amp;#10;If the player does not have the sparrow card in his hand, he picks a card from the player to his left and reads a generic answer card (often humorous) before laying that card on the table in a separate pile. The dealer proceeds to ask the next player the same question until the correct answer card is found and played. The player who answers the question will take any of the generic cards played to the question and place them (if there are any) in his hand&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once all the questions have been read and answered the exciting part of the game begins! The dealer reads the following script,&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;Oh, Mr. Bullfinch, Oh, Mr. Popinjay &amp;#10;Never believe what these little birds say-&amp;#10;Bad little birds&amp;mdash;telling us a story-&amp;#10;Cock Robin is alive in all his glory!&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;The dealer continues to read the next line of,&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;Cock Robin is all alive&amp;mdash;Mr. Sparrow, pay a fine for that story now, about your bow and arrow.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player who has the Cock Robin Sparrow Card in front of him must then &amp;lsquo;pay the fine&amp;rsquo;. The fine is anything the dealer wants it to be. In the directions, suggestions for the fine are, &amp;ldquo;to kiss the one loved best (which is often the looking glass), or to flatter some of the other company&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;Additional scripts are read for each of the animals and the players with these cards in front of them must do what it says. Other examples are as follows:&amp;#10;  Cock Robin is all alive&amp;mdash;Miss Lark, Shut your eyes and sing us a song in the dark. &amp;#10;  To pay for the story you told&amp;mdash;Mr. Linnet, tell us where your night cap is, and how you get in it. &amp;#10;  Your manners are very bad, Mr. Rook, in all your reading what was your dullest book?&amp;#10; The last script read reveals the winner of the game of Cock Robin. It reads, &amp;ldquo;And now Mr. Thrush, Come out of your bush, and sing us a song. Or give us a riddle; and we&amp;rsquo;ll grant you the fame of winning the game.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1860" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2073" value="Acting" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="2551" value="McLoughlin Brothers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="28" value="Parker Brothers" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>