<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="112136">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4Wu8I1tBQ3FJvZ5g67UiQg__thumb/img/fFcn449WTa58ONn6s1KqTOM9GuQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1145133.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4Wu8I1tBQ3FJvZ5g67UiQg__original/img/hhHUyQcDVXeIExifmoUUr906kUc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1145133.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Cadaver City" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>An Offal Game for 1 or 2 players&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pity the poor people of Cadaver City. Long ago they filled up all their cemeteries with their loved (and not so loved) ones. Now they&amp;rsquo;ve run out of room so they have taken to dumping the bodies down the sewer (out of sight out of mind). You, enterprising 3rd Class Sewer Engineers (Plungers), see a chance to make some fast money and solve the corpse clog threatening to overwhelm the existing system. At a quiet back door behind the Treatment Plant a line of customers queue up for the bits and pieces you have on offer. Deliver them the right parts, aged to the right amount of time and you&amp;rsquo;ll receive your reward.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Needed to play: The deck of 27 cards&amp;#10;10 eurocubes in each of 4 colors for the body parts (white for Bones, brown for Organs, gray for Brains and red for Hearts) and 9 black eurocubes for the rats&amp;#10;1 eurocube marker in each of 2 other colors to keep track of player scores on the Gore Track&amp;#10;1 large bag [or an old sock] (the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts) to hold all the body parts, 10 small ziplock bags to act as body bags in the game and 1 four-sided die&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup: Place the 4 Sewer Pipe cards,  Gore Track, and the score markers between the Plungers (players).&amp;#10;Shuffle the customer deck and deal 2 customers to each Plunger, placing the rest in a face down draw pile known as &amp;ldquo;The Queue&amp;rdquo;, next to the Sewer Pipe. Each plunger should place their customers face up in front of them.&amp;#10;Shuffle the tool deck and deal 3 tools to each Plunger that they will use as their initial hand of cards. The remaining tool cards will be placed in a tool card draw deck next to The Queue.&amp;#10;Place the body bags within reach of both Plungers. Each Plunger should take 1 body bag for each customer they have during the game. Lastly place all the body parts and rats in the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase 1: Adding new body parts&amp;#10;Roll 1d4 and add that value to the number of waiting customers in front of them. The Plunger will then blind draw that number of body parts from the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts. Shift all existing body parts towards The Clog to make room for the incoming body parts. Rats will never move. Set aside any body parts that are shifted off of the Day 3 card into a reserve pile. Place the new body parts in the order they are drawn on the Sewer Pipe cards beginning from the rightmost space on the Day 1 card. If any rats are drawn they will be placed on the Rat spaces beginning from the far left of the Day 3 card. Any body part occupying a Rat space where a Rat will be placed, during this phase, will be removed and tossed back into the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roll 1d4 and place that many reserved Day 3 parts on The Clog card spaces, tossing the rest back in the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase 2: Filling orders&amp;#10;Each customer card lists the number of parts required to fill the order.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To fill an order a Plunger must choose all of any of 1 type of body parts on any one Sewer card (meeting the desired aging requirement) placing those parts in the customer&amp;rsquo;s body bag. Any extra body parts not needed for the orders go back in the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts. Plungers may use the body parts to attempt to fill 1, 2 or more customer orders as long as the body parts are of the desired type and aging. If a customer&amp;rsquo;s complete order is filled the Plunger scores the money value, indicated in the lower right corner of the customer card, on the Gore Track. All body parts from this order are then tossed back in the Bag O&amp;rsquo; Parts. A new customer is then drawn from The Queue.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tool Cards: Each Plunger may use one of their tool cards at any point during their turn. Once played, the card will be placed on a discard pile next to the tool card draw pile and a new card is drawn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game End: The game ends in one of two ways:&amp;#10;a. The Clog card has become full of body parts. In this case, the current Plunger finishes their turn and any final scoring is marked.&amp;#10;b. All 10 customers have had their orders filled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Plunger who has earned the most money is declared the winner and receives a promotion to 2nd Class Sewer Engineer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game can be played solo as well. See the rules for modifications to the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2013" value="Commodity Speculation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="8" />
			<average value="6.3125" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.826797" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="24" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="12" />
			<numcomments value="11" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>