<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="112275">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/eW8p9VZPi63qt-MLNsmV3Q__thumb/img/W7ifOy1hRmfOk7kuPyRaxJUEIGc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1215136.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/eW8p9VZPi63qt-MLNsmV3Q__original/img/o6Pj-JHSAQVOt0DPda-6gy9aUCY=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic1215136.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Wizard&#039;s Tournament" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Wizard's Tournament&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every year, wizards from all over the realm come together to fight over the title of Archmage to become the most powerful wizard in the world.  Wizard's Tournament is a fantasy deck building game of magic combat where two players attempt to defeat each other using spells, monsters, and relics.  The game comes with thirty-five different sets of cards but only twelve of these card sets are picked at random to be used during a game.  These cards are added to a player's deck during a game so every time you play, it will feel like a new and exciting game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Spell Cards&amp;#10;Spell cards allow a player to perform special actions including dealing damage, drawing cards, healing, and causing an opponent to discard cards.  When cast, the ability of a Spell card occurs once and then it is discarded.  Fast spells can be played at any time but regular spells can only be cast on the owner's turn.  Spell cards can also be discarded to add Spirit to your Spirit Pool.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monster Cards&amp;#10;Monsters are permanent creatures used to attack your opponent and defend you from enemy monsters.  Every monster has a special ability that makes them more dangerous and difficult to defeat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Relic Cards&amp;#10;These permanent artifacts give a player special abilities that allow them to perform an action every turn until they are destroyed or stolen.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play&amp;#10;Each player starts with thirty Life.  If a player reduced his opponent's Life to zero, he wins the game.  A player can also win by having thirty or more Spirit in his Spirit Pool or by having one hundred or more Life.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player starts the game with ten Spirit cards.  Twelve cards are drawn from the Selection deck and these twelve card sets are placed on the table.  The starting player is determined randomly.   Before play begins, the player that is going first draws one card and the player going second draws three cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are three possible icons on the each card: Green, Blue, and Red.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Green Icons: This is the Cast cost to activate a Spell, Monster, or Relic card.  This is also the purchase price in Spirit to add this card to a player's discard pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Blue Icons: This is the amount of Spirit added to a player's Spirit Pool when a card with a blue icon is discarded without activating it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Red Icons: Monster cards have red icons equal to its Power.  A monster's Power is equal to a monster's Life and the amount of damage it can deal to a player or another monster.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Turn Sequence - 5 Phases&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Draw Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A player draws five cards from her deck.  A player may never have more than ten cards in her hand at any time.  If a player cannot draw a card because her deck has run out of cards, the player must shuffle her discard pile into a new deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Purchase Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During any phase, Spirit cards or Spell cards can be discarded to add Spirit to a player's Spirit Pool equal to the number in the blue icon on the card.  This Spirit can be spent to purchase any of the twelve cards in the center of the table.  To add a card to your discard pile, you must pay the value in the card's green icon in Spirit.  Only one copy of each card can be purchased each turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Magic Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players can spend Spirit to cast Spell, Monster, and Relic cards.  When Spell cards are cast, their ability is performed once and then they are discarded.  When Monster and Relic cards are cast, they are placed in play with an Activation token. Relics and monsters can use their abilities during the Magic and Combat phases.  An Activation token is placed on a relic when it is activated.  Relics and monsters with an Activation token cannot be activated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combat Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A Monster card can be used to attack another player or defend you from an attacking monster.  Monsters with an Activation token on them cannot attack, defend, or use their ability.  To attack, select all the monsters under your control that you want to attack.  Your opponent then decides which of his monsters will defend against each of the attacking monsters.  More than one monster can be used to block a single attacking monster.  After the attack, place an Activation token on each of the attacking monsters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a monster attacks and is not blocked, the defending player&amp;rsquo;s Life is reduced by the Power of that monster.  If a monster is blocked by a defending monster, both monsters deal damage equal to their Power to his opponent.  If a monster's damage is ever equal to or greater than its Power, it is destroyed and placed in its owner&amp;rsquo;s discard pile.  If a defending monster cannot absorb all this damage, the excess damage is applied to the defending player.  Excess damage applied to an attacking monster is ignored.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If more than one monster is used to block a single attacking monster, the attacking player may apply damage equal to the Power of the attacking monster divided amongst any the defending monsters in any way.  Any of these defending monsters that receive enough damage to be destroyed are placed in his owner&amp;rsquo;s discard pile.  If a group of blocking monsters cannot absorb all the damage, the player that controls them has his Life reduced by the excess damage.  All the Power of the blocking monsters are combined and applied to the attacking monster.  If the damage dealt is equal to or greater than the Power of the attacking monster&amp;rsquo;s Power, the attacking monster is destroyed and placed in its owner&amp;rsquo;s discard pile and the excess damage is ignored.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;End Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All Activation tokens are removed from play, all monster damage is discarded, and all Spirit Pools are emptied.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3 or 4 Player Optional Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game can also be played with optional rules for three or four players when you use the extra Spirit cards included in the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players: 2&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Time: 30 Minutes&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ages: 12+&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Contents: 292 Cards, Tokens, and a Rule Book&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="51046" value="James T. Kato" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="17982" value="JEN Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>