<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="113307">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Ancient Americas: Cities of Promise" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From South America to Central America to North America there are remnants of large civilizations that have disappeared leaving behind only the ruins of temples, city structures and fragmented settlements. The Ancient Americas are shrouded in mystery and intrigue. The people were religious with a fashionable culture. Their cities were the central hub to life and these civilizations enjoyed much abundance and prosperity all while in the midst of conflicts that were trying to destroy them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;General Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game is for 2 to 4 players ages eight to adult. Players build a 'city of promise' by building their civilization with important structures and with valuable characters that then defend the city from corruption's power.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Building Cards - Throughout the deck are Building Cards. To build structures for the 'cities of promise' and to use important historical figures within the cities, a player  must try to collect specific cards and in the right amounts. Some cards cost more than others and the value of the cards vary in power. Players who gain the right building cards pay the cost of the card and a new part of the city is then added.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Timer - Corruption Cards play as timing cards and determine when the game ends. When the 18th Corruption Card is placed down the game ends for all players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player add up their cities power points. If the total is greater than the total points of Corruption Power Points  then they have WON! Yes, that's right, there can be more than one winner in this game making it more rewarding for the whole family. And if the friendly competition is that HIGH you can find out who's city had the most strength and they can be the Grand Winner!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Types of Cards&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Corruption Cards - New cards are drawn at the beginning of every turn. Any time a Corruption Card is drawn it must be played during the player's turn and added to the Corruption Card area (typically the middle between all players).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Building a City - Players that purchase City Cards with the Build Cards will be able to piece the city together in any combination left to right or right to left. As players strive to get the better City Cards it may be necessary to discard unwanted or undesirable City Cards in the hopes of gaining a better one on the next draw.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Specialty Characters - Character Cards can be added to your city by purchasing them with the Build Cards and then placing them under the correct City Card they belong to. These cards also have a power point value so players can seek to add the best characters to their city to give it the best advantage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bonus Power Points - Saints Cards, Resources Cards, and Faith &amp;amp; Works Cards can be stored under Character Cards for later purchases of City Cards and Character Cards. Unused Build Cards can add additional power points at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1015" value="Civilization" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="54111" value="David F. Coleman" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="54111" value="David F. Coleman" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="19246" value="Family Game Designer LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>