<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="114116">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Jf0JR2PS1q3tXeOsK5hWBQ__thumb/img/wFlw7F4jlC2_J9T9-UVBiQQ0lI0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1738044.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Jf0JR2PS1q3tXeOsK5hWBQ__original/img/dn3oOizaoTh-INuJdPIhnURu9oE=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic1738044.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fluke" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Fluke - The Wealth Building Game of Accidental Inventions&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fluke simulates Corporate America - the wild, wild world of intellectual property that is grounded in inventions and entrepreneurship. Players will experience thrilling scientific research, wacky inventions, stock explosions, gigantic wealth and legal duels. Many world changing, highly profitable inventions were created by accident while in the midst of scientific research to discover something else. These inventions would have never been created if someone was not creatively seeking to solve a problem.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Everyone is memorializing Steve Jobs as he dominated Corporate America setting an even faster pace for the wild, wild world of Intellectual Property.  Here&amp;rsquo;s your chance to see if you can dominate Corporate America   like he did.  Show your corporate executive skills by building the largest portfolio of cash, patents and research corporations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will maneuver through the Risk and Rewards of the wild, wild world of intellectual property acquiring patents, research corporations and of course, cash. The game ends when the first person loses all of their cash. Each game participant will tally their portfolio.  The game participant with the largest portfolio wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAME PLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning of the Fluke game, a player is selected to be the manager of the Venture Fund. The Venture Fund holds 2.4 billion dollars, the patents, and research corporations.  Each player receives 200 million dollars from the Venture Fund. They will roll the die and land on a game space. They have the option of:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1.    Paying a licensing fee  to the owner of the  patent / research corporation&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.    Purchasing the patent/ research corporation indicated on the game space from the Venture Fund if no player owns it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3.    &amp;ldquo;Wheel and deal&amp;rdquo; with another player for purchase of their patent/ research corporation. Resale prices are indicated on the back of cards. If it reads &amp;ldquo;negotiable&amp;rdquo;, Name your best price and wait to see if another player accepts your price.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a player lands on the stock explosion space, they can explode any patent or research corporation they own. They will receive the stock explosion marker and the cash from the Venture Fund.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAME ENDS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First person to run out of cash the game ends. Each player will count their cash, tally up the resale prices of their patents and research corporations. The person with the largest portfolio values win. Players can continue to play after portfolio tally is complete.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2005" value="Stock Holding" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="54072" value="SG Creative" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="19223" value="Upheaval Media, LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>