<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="114392">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qNVAMKN4-yMesSbTtQFQjQ__thumb/img/5Rs5O_itp0r3lZuWksOl660mVMU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1332017.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qNVAMKN4-yMesSbTtQFQjQ__original/img/ynVmIX9WKgF2b-3POQ7iQvIER7U=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1332017.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Piastowie Narodziny Orła" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Try your hand as a Prince of the Slavic tribes. Prudent management of network resources to build economic power. Show your strength and courage and obedience among the warriors gain and advantage on the battlefield. Prove that you deserve to be called the first Polish ruler!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is a breakthrough ninth and tenth centuries. The three ambitious princes at the head of the three great tribes are preparing to fight for the lands of Wielkopolska and Kujawy. Polanie, led by Siemowit extend their rule, the submission of its subsequent settlement and erected at strategic locations mighty castles. Goplanie tribe inhabiting Kujawy, led by cruel Popiel, are preparing to invade the lands lying to the left Note&amp;#196;&amp;#135; river. Lords of the Glapian tribe in Kaliska region  push to the north, trying to grab the fertile lands of central Wielkopolska. The eyes of all the princes look at Gniezno, where is Lech Hill most important center of Slav worship. The prince, who will conquer Gniezno, will gain great authority among the Slav population, which may force the rulers of other tribes to submit to his authority. However, the princes plans can be thwarted. There are rumors that at the mouth of Warta strengthen the invaders from the far north, the Vikings ...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Board game &amp;quot;The Birth Piast Eagle&amp;quot; is designed for 2-4 people. Playing time is approximately 2-4 hours, depending on the number of players. Their task is to get as much the prince's authority as possible. They can expand it by winning the general, a reasonable policy, Stewardship of goods and skillful manipulation of the priestly caste. Players may also lose the authority as a result of shameful defeats or show weakness in intertribal political arena.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;The Birth Piast Eagle&amp;quot; is a history-strategic game. Players moving tokens, indicating different types of early medieval armies. Players giving orders have to decide what action it will take in the next stage of their subjects. Depending on the order of the generated power player, these activities take on momentum or slow down. Events included in the pages of random events can absolutely interfere with the planned course of play, forcing players to complete the reform of the established strategy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Design is the winner of a competition organized by the historiographer Polish History Museum and funded by the Ministry of Culture and National Heritage in the financing of educational and cultural activities by the &amp;quot;education +&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Characteristics of the tribes in the board game &amp;quot;Piast Eagle Rise&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Glapianie:&amp;#10;This is the Slavic tribe has its headquarters on the southern edge of the board of the central stronghold - Kalisz. Their unmistakable tramp over the years built a network of trade and diplomatic relations and strong economic fundamentals. Due to the high economic potential of their treasury fills up quickly. Some minor deficiencies in the disposal of the military are offset by the money, according to the rule: &amp;quot;War is not so much a question of weapons, what the money&amp;quot; - Thucydides.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Glade:&amp;#10;This starts the game Slavic people in the central part of the board - in Giecz. This site brings with it a blessing and a curse. Is extremely advantageous location close to major towns in the game, including Gniezno. While the downside is undisputed that the Glade are surrounded by &amp;quot;benevolent&amp;quot; neighbors from four sides. Polan's strengths is military power, whose core is the cavalry, as well as the ability to quickly build great castles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Goplana:&amp;#10;This is the Slavic tribes settled in the vicinity of Lake Gop&amp;#197;&amp;#130;o headquartered in Kruszwica. Begin the game in the eastern part of the board. Their military potential - economic development is balanced, thus, are very formidable opponent. Have the ability to quickly mobilize resources, and a lot of defensive capabilities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Vikings:&amp;#10;The tribe is led by visitors from far northern lands. They begin the game board in the north west - the Santoku. Have the greatest military potential, the most important role is played by an elite infantry Scandinavian. Neither the army nor the stockade could not stop them in the march of Gniezno. The problem may be difficulties in the supply and finance - &amp;quot;Money is the nerve of war,&amp;quot; Cicero.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1082" value="Mythology" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="56159" value="Krzysztof Ignaszak" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="56160" value="Grzegorz Małecki" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="21097" value="Fundacja Rodem z Polski" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="4.875" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.74553" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="10" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>