<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="116823">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/osdKNwYRRt2Lt4hFruDWFA__thumb/img/T5EMCJrUyz4Wcxna6U694mTpC3E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1735569.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/osdKNwYRRt2Lt4hFruDWFA__original/img/aM-0A89tuJ5TIY3wUD74MzHnzoI=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1735569.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dark Legacy" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Welcome to world of Dark Legacy. A world ruled by the ruthless battle mage by the name of the Kaiser. The planet of Titan is at war. The Kaiser is bringing the world to its knees. This is a war where anything is possible and anyone can become a legend. It is here where your journey begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Will you join the Kaiser and his allies in the total domination of the planet or will you be part of the opposition? You get to decide how this story will tell itself. Make sure to choose wisely, for the fate of the planet lies within your hands.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Make your choice!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dark Legacy is a unique strategy game that mixes the best elements of Magic the Gathering, Dungeons and Dragons and Chess and wraps them all up into a in-depth sci-fi/fantasy story. In Dark Legacy, players are no longer bystanders of the battle,  they get to be part of it as a war general within one of six different factions. With the unique and various weapons, armor and relics, that a player can equip themselves with, players can become whomever they imagine themselves to be.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Dark Legacy, it is the players objective to destroy their opponents and their armies, by building a deck of magic spells that no one can withstand, rolling the d20 in their favor and strategically summoning their army to be the strongest. Just like in real battle you will have to anticipate the probability of the unexpected. Don't make choices too hastily for they may be the demise of your army and yourself.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dark Legacy is a game that can be played one-on-one or in team battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Here are the type of cards that can be played in Dark Legacy:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Enhancement cards are for summoned creatures, weapons and the Hero. These cards can either strengthen or weaken that which it is place upon.&amp;#10;     Creature cards are just that. They are the faction specific cards that each one of the six different factions use to strengthen their army to win the battle.&amp;#10;     Magic cards are the spell cards used to tip the balance in battle. There are faction specific magic cards and general magic cards.&amp;#10;     Armor cards are only for the Heroes in battle. This gives each Hero extra defense points on top of their life points.&amp;#10;     Weapon cards are only for the Heroes in battle. There is a wide variety of weapon cards and as the Hero levels up there are stronger and more magical weapons that become available to them.&amp;#10;     Relic cards are ancient cards with abilities that are available to every player if you find them. There are relics that will fit every players style of fighting.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Evolution System for Battle&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Before the battle begins, players must decide who is going first.&amp;#10;     At the beginning of every battle each player draws five cards.&amp;#10;     Each player is now allowed to place one card on the equip side of the mat. This card has to cost 0 and the player has to have the correct skill level to put that card down.&amp;#10;     There is no damage permitted for the first round in battle, meaning that no one can attack or cast spells that deal damage until it is the first person&amp;rsquo;s turn again.&amp;#10;     The player that is going first must begin the battle by drawing a card. (At the beginning of every turn players will draw a card.)&amp;#10;     In order to cast any of the player&amp;rsquo;s cards they must roll the d20. There is only one roll per turn, unless there is a card in play that allows for another roll. The number that you roll will be the&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;number of casting points you have to cast cards from your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     In order to cast spells you have to have a high enough SKILL LEVEL (SL) and have enough CASTING POINTS (CP).&amp;#10;     The player can then cast any number of cards as long as they have the proper SL and CP.&amp;#10;     If the opponent has the ability to counter the spell they can do so after the card is cast.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now the second round begins.  At the beginning of the player&amp;rsquo;s turn they must draw a card and then decide weather to attack or cast and use the cards abilities to help you win the battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Charging Field&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Players may put any card, within their faction or subsection, on this field face down. This card is now charging. This field is to be used for cards that are above of your skill level. &amp;#10;     You may place cards that are in your skill range, but that would defeat the purpose of charging the card. In order to cast the card that you put on the charging field, it must charge for the difference of your skill level and the skill level required to cast&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1044" value="Collectible Components" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2027" value="Storytelling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="240142" value="Dark Legacy: The Rising" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="56885" value="Bryan &quot;Kaiser&quot; Tillman" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="56885" value="Bryan &quot;Kaiser&quot; Tillman" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="21426" value="Kaiser Studio Productions" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.55903" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="12" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="5" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>