<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="118047">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Bum1Wjoh8FtB3B9ZMdKs-A__thumb/img/rMDAZaEHumjGSVagTWTcHbdgVqI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1207297.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Bum1Wjoh8FtB3B9ZMdKs-A__original/img/8ZfSssekUV1OfU9QFuNXPDtO-gk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1207297.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Revolt and Revolution" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Revolt and Revolution is the newest offering from our strategic partnership with Victory Point Games, and the first game we are producing from their immensely popular States of Siege series.  The idea for this and future volumes is to thematically take two existing titles from VPG's States of Siege line and add a third as-yet-unpublished game to the pack to create a GMT boxed set using larger counters, full sized cards, and mounted maps, all utilizing the talents of GMT's art and production team.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The States of Siege game system from Victory Point Games features solitaire play in which the player is thrust into the role of defending a central position from attackers advancing on a number of fronts using area movement.  Event cards provide the challenges and opportunities players use to fend off defeat while they battle for victory.  Each game in the series introduces new elements to the robust game engine and expands the possibilities of what can be simulated.  With each event card, players have a variety of actions possible but are limited by the number of action points on a given turn...in a States of Siege game there are just never enough points to get all the things done they would like.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Revolt and Revolution puts the player at the center of the epic clashes of ideology and culture in Europe through the 17th, 18th, 19th and 20th centuries.  You, the player, get to participate in the conflicts of Divine Right vs Parliamentarianism, Absolutism vs Republicanism, and Despotism vs Bolshevism. You'll rub (simulated) elbows around your game table with King Charles I and Cromwell, King Louis XVI and Robespierre, Czar Nicholas II and Lenin, and participate in historic conflicts as Cavaliers battle Roundheads, Monarchists battle Jacobins, and 'Whites' battle 'Reds' across the fields, towns and cities of England, France and Russia.  The outcome of these wars changed the face of Europe and the World forever.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The titles in Revolt and Revolution are dynamic -- your decisions affect the course of events in both the short and long term.  Unlike most historical games which enforce a linear outcome and constrain you to the path of history, in the States of Siege game system your decisions and strategies can alter the existing timeline.  Now you have a chance to take command and make history or change it!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first game in the pack is by series creator Darin Leviloff.  Soviet Dawn: The Russian Civil War, 1918-1921: The Russian Civil War 1918 - 1921 puts you in the position of defending the Bolshevik Revolution from the array of 'White' forces bent on its destruction.  Can you deal with the great crises of that time and defend the revolution? Will you withdraw from the Great War (WWI) or exercise the Bukharin Option and fight on? Can you execute the Czar in time, or will the 'Whites' rescue him? Will you fortify Petrograd or press your offensives home? How will you deal with internal and external dissent?  These are just some of the challenges to meet as you decide the fate of Communism in the 20th century.  Revolt and Revolution will include both the base game Soviet Dawn and its expansion pack.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The second game in the tri-pack is from series developer John Welch.  Levee En Masse: The Wars of the French Revolution 1789 - 1802 puts you in the position of defending the Republican Revolution from forces both within and outside of France, during the tumultuous years of the French.  Can you suppress the forces of Monarchy and Despotism to maintain the Republican spirit in France? Can you export the revolution by liberating neighboring states and creating sister Republics? Will you be able to keep order in Paris as it suffers from riot after riot? Can you rally your armies to defeat those of rival European states like Britain, Prussia and Austria?  These are just a few of the obstacles you must overcome to end Monarchy and bring forth the era of Republican government that will transform Europe in the 19th century.  Revolt and Revolution will include both the base game Lev&amp;eacute;e en Masse and its expansion pack.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The third game in Volume I is a never-before-published game in the States of Siege series!  John Welch's Cruel Necessity: The English Civil Wars 1640-1653:  The English Civil Wars 1640 - 1653 puts you in charge of Puritanism and Parliament and their attempts to usher in the Reformation and Age of Reason.  Can you create a fighting force capable of defeating the Royalist Armies of Charles I?  Can you foster Puritan religious reforms while suppressing those of your rival Protestants  and hated Catholics?  Can you forge an alliance with the Covenanters of Scotland and prevent them for going over to the King?  Can you manage the rebellions in Ireland without draining too many men and resources to do so?  These are just some of the dilemmas you must balance in order to bring an end to Divine Right Monarchy and usher in the Age of Revolution.  The GMT edition will include a grand tactical combat mini-game in addition to the base game of Cruel Necessity - after all, what fun would an English Civil War game be without the charge of cavalry and the push-of-pikes?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#226;&amp;#151;&amp;#143; Three 17&amp;quot; x 22&amp;quot; mounted maps&amp;#10;&amp;#226;&amp;#151;&amp;#143; 88 Large Square counters&amp;#10;&amp;#226;&amp;#151;&amp;#143; 56 Round counters&amp;#10;&amp;#226;&amp;#151;&amp;#143; 180 Event cards (60 for each game)&amp;#10;&amp;#226;&amp;#151;&amp;#143; Three 10-page Rules booklets (one for each game)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="40" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22185" value="Admin: Cancelled Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8164" value="Players: Wargames with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="3245" value="Series: States of Siege" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="10535" value="Darin A. Leviloff" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="36053" value="John Welch" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8007" value="Victory Point Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="12" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>