<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="119445">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JwhIJOvCpyKkQRzCISzEDg__thumb/img/VNuM7bTfCN5Kr5jDHkrj7GmQLqU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2612871.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JwhIJOvCpyKkQRzCISzEDg__original/img/XjnFZ4Fs77711U7l7S4UdM9wmXo=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2612871.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Acquaint" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>At last, there's a fun new way to avoid the dreaded &amp;quot;awkward silence&amp;quot; when dating someone new! Introducing ACQUAINT&amp;trade; - the revolutionary &amp;quot;real deal&amp;quot; card game that helps first-, second-, or even third-time daters get better acquainted. It was designed not only to create conversation and calm nerves, but to also help daters better determine each other's &amp;quot;keeper&amp;quot; potentials; needless to say, finding out early on whether or not they are truly compatible may prove to be a time-saving, preventative measure of future heartache.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This highly interactive card game includes questions, tasks, lessons and more! It encourages 'authentic' conversation through the sharing of thoughts, experiences, feelings and values. Questions range from light-hearted topics to semi-personal and serious, and fun &amp;quot;off-the-wall&amp;quot; topics are included throughout.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OBJECT: Collect as many Rose Cards in your hand as you can by discarding as many other cards as possible. Players perform any task(s) listed on the discarded card on each turn. There are a total of 9 Rose Cards, and the player with the most in their hand at the end wins. The main point of the game, however, is for the players to get to know one another better.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CARDS: Includes 52 cards total &amp;#10;&amp;#10;     9 ROSE CARDS&amp;#10;     20 'REAL DEAL' QUESTION CARDS &amp;#10;     4 FILL-IN-THE-BLANK CARDS&amp;#10;     6 DISCUSSION CARDS&amp;#10;     5 SCALE (&amp;quot;What # Are You?&amp;quot;) CARDS&amp;#10;     6 MISCELLANEOUS CARDS ('Listening Check' Card, 'Deception Destroyer' Card 'Share' Card, 'Flirt' Card, 'Deal Breaker' Card, &amp;amp; 'Compromise' Card) &amp;#10;     2 PROTECTION CARDS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;START: SHUFFLE CARDS WELL before starting (keeping all the cards facing the same direction). Choose which player will go first. Players must also choose in advance the level of play preferred for the 'REAL DEAL' Questions from the three levels listed below.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;REAL DEAL QUESTION CARD LEVELS: &amp;#10;&amp;#10;     LEVEL 1 ('a' questions) - Simple, light-hearted questions to learn a little about your date - questions that are generally easy to answer and don't take that much thought&amp;#10;     LEVEL 2 ('b' questions) - Moderate get-to-know-your-date questions - questions that get a little more serious, where people can reveal a bit more about themselves&amp;#10;     LEVEL 3 ('c' questions) - Deep questions designed to create a bonding emotional connection, or, to better spot potential 'RED FLAGS' in advance--ideal for 'bold' daters. Keep in mind DISHONESTY CAN DESTROY EVEN THE BEST OF RELATIONSHIPS! PLAY AT YOUR OWN RISK! Warning: Some questions may be considered to some as personally inappropriate for a new date, even though the questions are in good taste. (The reason someone may pass on a question need not be explained -- besides, a little mystery can often prove to be an effective strategy as well.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PLAY: Each person is dealt 7 cards (one at a time) face down. The remaining cards are placed face down in a pile in the center of the table, forming the draw pile (or the Selection Pile). The first player (aka THE DISCARDER) takes a turn by drawing the top card from the Selection Pile followed by choosing a card to discard from his/her hand, reading it out loud first. Players then respond to any directions from the card accordingly. When finished, the DISCARDER places the card face up right alongside the Selection Pile, into what will be the Discard Pile (unless otherwise directed). Similarly, the other player then takes their turn, and so on.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SCORING: The game ends as soon as soon as the last card is picked up/discarded. The players then count the number of Rose Cards in their hands, and the player with the most roses wins. (If both players end up without any roses, it's considered a tie game.).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1037" value="Real-time" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2027" value="Storytelling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="65322" value="Mechanism: Story Creation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61207" value="Theme: Love / Romance" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>