<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="121605">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Astromino" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Astromino -- Dominoes of the Universe&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is a new twist on the age old theme of Domino games from times past. Astromino uses the universe, space travel as an overall game theme. The tiles have the form of the Kite and the Dart, original shapes developed by Sir Roger Penrose as a part of his tiling research projects in the 1970&amp;lsquo;s. When &amp;ldquo;Dominized&amp;rdquo; these unique shapes open a new set of possibilities for Domino game design and play. Astromino Basic, Full and Advanced Sets are recommended for ages 8 through 101 years. We have play tested Astromino and to date it has done well with all age groups. This Kickstarter Project will be a mega play testing opportunity. The tiles can also be used as blocks or a puzzle just to form shapes and make patterns, it is one way of playing solitaire Astromino.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Astromino Game Sets&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     The Basic Astromino Game includes 60 tiles (30 Kites and 30 Darts) with sharp gray scale graphics. Basic game instructions are included.&amp;#10;     The Full Astromino Game includes 100 tiles (50 Kites and 50 Darts) with four color graphics. Full game instructions are included with this set of tiles.  Two playing surfaces for the more complex games, approximately 22&amp;rdquo; x 34&amp;rdquo; with game instructions make the Full set into an Advanced Game of Astromino.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Astromino Game Play Basics&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     To start the game &amp;ldquo;Big Bang&amp;rdquo; the tiles, i.e. shuffle or mix them face down on a large table top to form the &amp;ldquo;Galaxy&amp;rdquo;. Now choose a tile to determine who starts the game. The player with the highest double tile will be the starter. Once the starter is determined the other players return the tile to the Galaxy as the starter places his double to start the game.&amp;#10;     Now each player will choose their own hand from the Galaxy, 5 Kites and 5 Darts. Each contestant plays one tile per turn from their hand of ten tiles, matching like numbers on the tiles, long edges to long edges and short to short. The basic game continues as a string of connected shapes the Moon and the Star take shape. These shapes Moon and Star must be formed using 5 Kites or 5 Darts, respectively. The shapes are assembled and connected, one to another as the game proceeds. The string of shapes undulates and forms the line of play, always a unique field of play. Like Domino games a typical hand in an Astromino game will last between 15 and 25 minutes.&amp;#10;     Tiles may fit here or there and need to be turned and matched in your head as you choose your next move. Careful don&amp;rsquo;t make an &amp;ldquo;Anti-matter&amp;rdquo; move or if caught you will lose your turn! Strategy comes into play as you make plans for your next move to defeat your favorite opponent(s).  Hide your tiles using the Player Tray.&amp;#10;     If you are lucky maybe you can &amp;ldquo;Shoot the Moon&amp;rdquo;, it is a play where you complete any shape and clear your hand by playing two (2) or more tiles all at once. Astromino rules include many options so you can choose from them and play the game as you like it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Options&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     There are six diferent games each one can incorporate these options to some degree.  Play options include Rule of Seven, Blank is a wild to play, Add a Shape,  Shoot the Moon, and scoring sevens or just scoring tile values with extra points for completing a shape.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning the Game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Although optional scoring rules are included, the main goal of the game is to use all the Astromino tiles in your hand. When you are down to your last Astromino tile yell &amp;ldquo;ASTEROID!&amp;rdquo; Fair warning to the opponents you are about to defeat. You win the hand when all your tiles are played. You win the game when you win two hands.  Maybe you will be lucky enough to &amp;ldquo;Shoot the Moon&amp;rdquo; for the win.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Six Unique Games in one!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Basic Line of Play Game&amp;#10;     Moons and Stars Game&amp;#10;     Sun, Earth and Moon Game&amp;#10;     Sumerian Sevens and Twelves Game&amp;#10;     Freeform Penrose Tiling Game&amp;#10;     Four-Stage-Star Game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="97" value="Traditional Games: Dominoes" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="58982" value="Roger Saunders" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>