<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="121916">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Greek Guardians" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>[GreekGuardians.com]&amp;#10;Theme:&amp;#10;Greece of yesterday was a different place than it is today. The age of Ancient Greece was frought with peril, sacrifice and prayer. To get anything done, people would pray to the gods for favor. To complicate matters, the right prayer had to reach the right deity in order to have any chance at success. It was very confusing and complicated life. To simplify this vast set of choices a Greek everyman or everywoman would face, I have chosen two paths that you and your opponents must set your sights towards. Order and Chaos, both are neutral, they are not bad or good in the classical sense, but rather a point of view. By the end of the first players turn, each player must align with Order or Chaos and build their strategies and play their cards towards that means.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Goal:&amp;#10;Each player draws cards that move players towards your final goal of 21 culture points. Each action, each king, queen, god, monster, philosopher, literally each card can either add or subtract culture points, cause mayhem, deny abilities, outright kill foes, or otherwise meddle towards your cause or to take an opponent away from their cause, for your chosen faction (Order or Chaos). There is one initial turn to set up and identify which faction, Chaos or Order, you will be gaining points towards and then there are 4 turns, one per season: Spring, Summer, Fall, Winter. If a player does not reach 21 culture points, at the final play of Winter, the player with the highest amount of culture points WINS!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game-Play:&amp;#10;Players will determine who goes first and will draw (and play) cards in the correct slots (Gods, Titans, Stars, etc.) and each card will have passive and active effects that resolve at the end of each player's turn. There is a (normal sheet of paper size) game board that shows where different cards &amp;quot;live&amp;quot; Passive effects will usually be &amp;quot;Add one culture point towards either Order or Chaos&amp;quot; (depending on the Card's Alignment). Active effects (or action cards) will require using action points (each player gets 5 action points per turn; the game has 4 turns total, so each play and card management is very important) that can alter the landscape of the game and change fates FAST.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unique Feature (Stacking):&amp;#10;Say a certain God card is played (let's say Zeus) and he is Chaos aligned. And say there is a chaos aligned star already in its slot and another chaos aligned Titan in her slot. There is a bonus, or stacking, effect of having a bunch of &amp;quot;like-minded&amp;quot; cards, so this combination of three cards (each say producing one chaos token for this turn, 1+1+1=3) there would be a +2 chaos bonus. So if the player can navigate the correct stacking of &amp;quot;like-minded&amp;quot; or similarly aligned cards, there are bonus effects that can speed up your plan (OR slow down opponents).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="10" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="10" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1082" value="Mythology" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2048" value="Pattern Building" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>