<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="126550">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/P60EzObk9XmhW66Cp-1QRA__thumb/img/OE-aucXqYFzUXu8xgYvk71hycjQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1364276.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/P60EzObk9XmhW66Cp-1QRA__original/img/K8kokpFC36Y9RZ1-UCXslgPJ8f8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1364276.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Władca Areny" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The world became a hostile place after the gods had abandoned men, embittered by their weakness. The elements appeared to conspire against the mortals and their heritage, bringing pain, hunger and destruction. And when the end of the human race seemed close at hand, an idea emerged amidst the deserted lands, and breathed hope into the surviving few. An idea of great power shimmering in a man about to fight for his own life. Thus began the era of the warrior; a warrior who, defiant to all, challenged heavens themselves. It was then that the wastelands saw the first Arenas, places endowed with mystic character, where the daring fought to death trying to single out the mightiest of them all. Some claimed that he was to win back gods&amp;rsquo; favor; others that he was to become their equal and finally challenge even them. New habitats started to emerge around the Arenas, suddenly all vibrant with life and ruled, singlehandedly, by a Warlord, the best of the warriors. A Warlord sovereign, drawing passionate gaze of women and envious glances of men. A Warlord supreme, who thanks to his triumphs seemed to put humanity on a pedestal. A Warlord absolute, whose place could be taken by anybody willing to issue a challenge. The Warlord of the Arena.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Warlord of the Arena (W&amp;#197;&amp;#130;adca Areny) is a tactical board game that simulates a duel of barbarian heroes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will create a unique warrior by distributing a number of points between six skills. Those skills will determine a warrior's agility, toughness, speed, sword mastery, etc. Warriors created this way will gain access to a vast armory. Various medieval weapons raging from daggers to heavy two handed axes await their test in battle. Throwing knives and crossbows, poisoned blades and big hunting dogs - all of this deadly weaponry varies in dealt damage, weight and special abilities, changing players' strategies for the fight. The strongest of warriors will be able to clad themselves in heavy plate armors, while the weaker ones will have to survive wearing only leather. Once warriors spent all of their gold, the players will build the arena. Even though the Arena is divided in several dangerous spaces, delivering special effects and fighting modification, players will be allowed to bring some extra mayhem to this place. Snakes, deadly spikes and a powerful chained beast wandering all over the arena are waiting to be bought for special points by the players to influence their tactics even further. Once the warriors and the arena are ready the duel begins. Each player can choose from arange of fighting moves (both defensive and offensive) to defeat his opponent. Chance of successful move attempt will be determined by your position on the arena, chosen weapon and position of your opponent. Lure your opponent out to the slippery floor and then jump him from behind to gain advantage ! Players will quickly exchange moves dancing in a sophisticated sword fight, using elements of the environment in order to win. There are 3 ways to win the duel. You can defeat your opponent by dealing one powerful blow which will kill him instantly or several minor ones that will cause him to bleed to his death! You may also poison him, which will cause them to lose consciousness and grant you victory. You can also try to deal a injury so painful that the opponent warrior will surrender, fearing for his life. All this brutal mayhem awaits you in Warlords of the Arena.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="4">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="4" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="4">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="3" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="61931" value="Sebastian Grabski" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61933" value="Przemysław Baraniak" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61936" value="Jarosław Marcinek" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61934" value="Michał Migacz" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61938" value="Mateusz Rasiński" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61937" value="Grzegorz Rutkowski" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61935" value="Mariusz Szulc" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="61932" value="Magdalena Thanais" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="90" />
			<average value="6.65333" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.5398" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="12455" bayesaverage="5.5398" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.75811" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="114" />
			<trading value="4" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="14" />
			<numcomments value="17" />
			<numweights value="11" />
			<averageweight value="3.4545" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>