<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="128082">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Qe4UHYIxFOUDOjGVzu4iMA__thumb/img/aj0Kg01gy1YqDPZ5B8o_B42ZohM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1371984.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Qe4UHYIxFOUDOjGVzu4iMA__original/img/Pj7WVs4WdQq_uGOa0mS7SdWcK-w=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1371984.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Tutatis" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Tutatis is a fantasy gaelic football game produced by Greebo Miniatures, an italian editor already known for its high quality fantasy miniatures. The game is set in the fantasy world of Triskearth, a brand new world utterly created by the designers of the game. Its history and geography, as well as the background for every race, are described in the first 150 pages of the rulebook. The remaining twenty pages describe the gaming rules, bringing to life a fast &amp;amp; furios game of tactic and bashing!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played on a 11 x 16 squares field, each team can field on the pitch seven payers. Every team (are planned to be released nearly thirty teams) has its own rooster of players, each one with its stats (movement, strength, agility, constitution, ball play), skills and costs, including three different captains. The game time is divided in two halves each one made up of six turns for each player. Turns are played alternatively by each player, completing the action of a single player before passing to the next one. The aim of the game is to score more points (goals or kicks over the crossbar) than the opponent, and you can achieve this with a passing/dodging style or with a more brutal one. Someone could recognize a gameplay similar to other games concerning sports, but this is not a great flaw since Tutatis has it's peculiar flavor thanks to the rules of gaelic football (ie. not forward passage, soloing rule exc.) and to the characterization of each team.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Greebo miniatures has produced a prerelease box of the game (with rules still in beta) at the 2011 Lucca Comics &amp;amp; Games convention, and it was a sold out. That box contained a cardboard field, Italian rulebook, two Greebo's d6, a ball and two teams in 15mm (orcs and dwarves). Since then on Greebo's website have been published in English and in Italian the definitive set of rules and the roosters for the new teams, all available as free downloads. At the moment have been released three kinds of fields (irond peak, thornwell and standard), the miniatures of some mercenaries and nine teams: orcs, dwarves, evil puppets, necros, poffy and five different teams of thornwell (frogs, lizards, turtles, snakes and a mixed team). Greebo's team is working on the championship rules expected to be released as open beta in mid autumn 2012, as well as on a new edition of the game box. It's also on the desk the translation of the rules in french and spanish.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="4">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="4">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6925" value="Theme: Fantasy Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23085" value="Greebo  Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.91548" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="20" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="10" />
			<numcomments value="5" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>