<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="12935">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/sn8D0HNiS8FoRSKWtMdT0g__thumb/img/SvxLsUqv8erbqge2TCbfC4wWZk0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic77841.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/sn8D0HNiS8FoRSKWtMdT0g__original/img/B8AB89emg2ha3zTd6oYYWuuLnZU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic77841.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="World War II in the East" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>World War II in the East is a division-corps scale wargame depicting the Second World War in Asia and the Pacific.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;World War II in the East gives you control of all of the major participating nations that fought World War II, and allows you to play a simple yet accurate portrayal of the war. World War II in the East can be played with Axis and Allies figures and rules, but is meant to be played as a stand-alone game with over 900 counters. However, the rules and the hex sizes still allow Axis and Allies fans to get the most accurate World War II wargame they can find while still using the popular rules and pieces, if they wish.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In fact, World War II in the East can be used effectively to bring Axis and Allies fans into the wargaming hobby as the game combines some of the features of Axis and Allies and conventional counter wargames to produce a new style of game that is simple yet complex, fun yet challenging.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With World War II in the East, you fight major carrier engagements, have air battles over Guadalcanal, conduct landing operations on the many island chains of the Pacific, outflank and surround forces in Burma, as Japan transport resources from Southeast Asia and the East Indies, and manage the industrial output of your nation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;World War II in the East includes over 900 counters depicting the armed forces of the major belligerents as well as informational counters needed to play the game. Along with the major nations, you can find in the counter mix Australian, New Zealander, Indian, and East African units, as well as the well-known American fighter squadron that fought with China against the Japanese.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The beautifully hand-drawn map is made up of 12-pieces, totalling a size of 47 by 36 inches. The map has all of the charts and boxes needed for game play and has a scale of approximately 300km per hex. The hexes are large enough to hold Axis and Allies pieces, but it is ideally played with the counters that are sized to decrease mess and accidents during play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is best played with the grand campaign which runs from December 1941 until the end of 1945, in monthly and bi-weekly turns. Scenarios allowing you to play shorter scenarios will be posted on the publisher's website as they become available.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;World War II in the East&amp;rsquo;s complexity is what sets it apart. It sets it apart from the other Axis and Allies games as the complexity is far greater and the history more accurate. It also sets it apart from the conventional counter wargames as it&amp;rsquo;s complexity is slightly more simple, yet still depicts the war accurately while being fun and challenging. This is not a simple game, but its complexity allows both experienced and beginner wargamers to understand the rules and enjoy the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;World War II in the East can be combined with World War II in the West to play the entire global war, both games combining to use over 2,500 counters and 25 square feet of maps!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2004" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="360" />
						               				<minplaytime value="360" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="360" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2389" value="Eric Grenier" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3393" value="Grenier Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="6.75" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.94746" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>