<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="130289">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/PROoLLF2oSpPIOPFOGDwSQ__thumb/img/HqyB4jV7OwtgtE3HASjMnbOnico=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1412487.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/PROoLLF2oSpPIOPFOGDwSQ__original/img/jN6rYEl8GCzC509ykbt80fjtYCs=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1412487.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="123 Dice" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>123 Dice Game by Collective Wisdom&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This small-box game has eight 1&amp;quot; dice with large numbers ranging from 1-72.  Rules for 14 games and a few variations are included.  All are math games designed for preschool through fourth grade.  They are:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;________________________________________&amp;#10;Preschool - 1st Grade:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Number Identification Game - Roll the dice and name the numbers, earning a point for each number correctly identified.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Order of Numbers Game - Roll all dice, re-rolling duplicates.  Put the dice in numerical order.  Earn one point per roll and play to five.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Counting Game - Roll all dice except the &amp;quot;81&amp;quot; die.  Select any two dice and say aloud all the numbers between them.  Earn one point per roll.&amp;#10;________________________________________&amp;#10;Games and Activities for 1st and 2nd Grades:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Another More Challenging Counting Game - Plays as &amp;quot;Counting Game&amp;quot; above except that a point is earned for each number named, encouraging players to select dice that are further apart.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Blind Toss Number Value Game - A moderator rolls all the dice and gives one to each player whose eyes are shut.  Each player then goes around the circle, saying whether their number is greater than or less than each other player's die.  If his is less than any player, he is eliminated.  Eventually, one player will remain in the round and earn one point.  This is repeated except that the lowest number will win the second round.  Continue until a single player scores six.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Odd Even Game - Roll all dice and divide them into even and odd piles.  Earn one point for each roll.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Addition Game (Adding 2 numbers) - Roll all dice.  Select two, add them and announce the sum.  One point is given for each correct answer.  Play to ten points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Addition and Subtraction -  As above for Addition Game, but continue, subtracting the lesser die from the greater die and announcing the difference.  One point is given for each correct answer.  Play to ten points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Addition Game (Adding 3 Numbers) - Roll all dice and choose three.  Add them together and announce the sum.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Challenging Variation of Additiona &amp;amp; Subtraction Games - Instead of granting one point per correct answer, players earn the answer as the number of points, thus encouraging players to select harder dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Place Value Game - Roll dice until all show single-digit numbers.  Select any three and name the three-digit number they form.  Earn one point for each roll and play to 28.  Optionally, offer an extra point for each number that is written out long-hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;________________________________________&amp;#10;Games and Activities for 3rd and 4th Grades:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Multiplication Game I: Each player writes down a set of five numbers.  Before rolling, each player will announce which of those numbers they will be using.  After rolling all the dice, select three and multiply each by the number chosen before the roll, scoring one point per correct answer.  On his next turn, the player must choose a new multiplicand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Multiplication Game II: Roll six dice.  Divide the rolled dice into three pairs and multiply each pair, announcing the product.  Earn one point per correct answer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Challenging Variation to Multiplication Games I and II: Play as above except that players add the products to their scores instead of one point, thus challenging them to select higher-yielding combinations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Division Game: Roll all dice, removing any duplicate numbers.  Identify any pairs of dice where one can be evenly divided into the other.  Die may be used more than once.  Earn one point per pair identified.  Before the next player rolls the dice, they may review the pairs and earn two points for any missed pairs they identify.  Play to 30 points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Equation Game: Roll all dice.  Identify any valid equations - addition, subtraction, multiplication or division.  Each equation will require at least three dice, but may use more.   Earn one point for each die used.  Continue making equations, re-using dice as needed.  Play to 25 points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;________________________________________&amp;#10;The dice are of good quality and have the following faces:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A:  1 -  2 -  3 -  4 -  5 -  6&amp;#10;B:  2 -  3 -  4 -  5 -  8 -  9&amp;#10;C:  2 -  9 - 10 - 10 - 11 - 12&amp;#10;D:  3 -  4 -  5 -  6 -  7 -  8&amp;#10;E:  3 -  5 -  6 -  7 -  9 - 10&amp;#10;F:  8 -  8 - 16 - 24 - 32 - 40&amp;#10;G:  9 - 18 - 36 - 54 - 72 - 81 &amp;#10;H: 10 - 15 - 20 - 25 - 30 - 40&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2004" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="10186" value="Collective Wisdom" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>