<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="13319">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4pLjNJ61DDfAUz9HLtFxmg__thumb/img/7H0cwZTXY-BDGnJ9nj6McyOHYFM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic224660.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4pLjNJ61DDfAUz9HLtFxmg__original/img/ouKfoFIQLpv-R69VQRf2ASWHnJw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic224660.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Par Fore The Course" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This game is an indoor game designed and developed by golf professionals to simulate the thrills and excitement of actual outdoor competition.  The object of the game is to run up your opponent&amp;rsquo;s score, while completing your own round in as few strokes as possible.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Par Fore the Course is an indoor game designed and developed by golf professionals to simulate the thrills and excitement of actual outdoor competition. As much as possible, Par Fore the Course is played the way real golf is played. But there&amp;rsquo;s added excitement, because Par Fore the Course goes beyond the gentlemanly rules of the Royal and Ancient Game. In this competition, if you play a shot that lands you in trouble, your opponent does not stand back politely while you escape from your predicament. No! He gleefully drops you into a lot deeper trouble! And you do the same to him!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To start, cut the cards and the low card becomes the dealer and also plays first, play then follows clockwise. Once all first shots have been played, the player furthest from the hole plays. When two players are the same distance, the player arriving first plays. Once on the green, continue to putt until in the hole. Winner of each hole plays first on the next hole. In case of a tie, the player who played first on previous hole plays first for the next tee.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Begin each hole by drawing up to 5 cards to your hand. To begin par 3&amp;rsquo;s roll 2 dice and to begin par 4&amp;rsquo;s and 5&amp;rsquo;s roll 3 dice. The roll of the dice determines your ball's landing point and do the following based on the par of the hole and where it landed:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     If on the fairway - play a card trying to match the suit of the position you landed. Whether it matches or not will determine what happens next (water, sand trap, out of control, make it to the green, etc)&amp;#10;     If in a sand trap &amp;mdash; roll 2 dice (and/or play a card). The number rolled is the distance you are from the hole, unless doubles are rolled. In that case, the result will depend on whether you have a matching numbered card in your hand.&amp;#10;     If in the water &amp;mdash; count one penalty stroke. Then, move your ball to a drop area on the board represented by a circled D. Any numbered card can be played to the green. The number on the card represents the distance from the hole.&amp;#10;     If off the fairway &amp;mdash; You are out of bounds and count a 2 stroke penalty and roll dice again.&amp;#10;     If on the green &amp;mdash; you can putt. The number of the card played to make it to the green determines the distance to the hole. Roll dice to see if you putt into the hole.&amp;#10;     If the number cannot be found - You have a lost ball. Count 2 penalty strokes and roll dice again. (Note: A number is missing on each hole. The missing numbers are: Hole #1&amp;mdash;9, #2&amp;mdash;12, #3&amp;mdash;5, #4&amp;mdash;10, #5&amp;mdash;12, #6&amp;mdash;12, #7&amp;mdash;15, #8&amp;mdash;13, #9&amp;mdash;9)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OUT OF CONTROL: &amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Your ball is considered OUT OF CONTROL if you don't have a matching suit card for your numbered location OR number is off the fairway, but not in the water, a sand trap, or out of bounds. In this case, the player to your left plays a card and it determines what happens to your ball.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HOLE IN ONE:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     When a player rolls two 1&amp;rsquo;s and holds the Ace of the suit shown in the middle of the green, they score a HOLE IN ONE!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SCORING: Each time a player rolls the dice from the tee or on the green, count 1 point. Each time a card is played either by the player or his opponent, count 1. At the end of each hole add penalty shots incurred to your score. Lowest total after 9 holes wins. (Use far right of score pads to count each stroke.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="11" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="98" value="Components: Traditional Playing Cards" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5652" value="Sports: Golf" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3817" value="Par Fore Games Inc." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="5.6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.49666" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="19" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>