<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="133137">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/C7toWRdUzMZw1Qev3Lgn7A__thumb/img/fh2EJPrH4uBTf1QbsffrJ3OzNSM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1693254.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/C7toWRdUzMZw1Qev3Lgn7A__original/img/1wK9192BGgatu30SCf0KHw6of2U=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1693254.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Diggin Deep Football" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>There are a lot of quality tabletop football games out there. Some play quickly, where you can get a final score with relative ease.  Some are more complex, giving the gamer a more 'head coach' feel.  I'd like to think that Diggin Deep Football falls somewhere in between, and is the perfect game for the Fantasy Football fan.  You can very easily take your fantasy football roster, plug it into Diggin Deep Football, and play a full game of football with full stats in about 60-90 minutes.  It adds an extra dimension to the Fantasy Football craze.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay is smooth and should be easy to pick up.  Plays should normally take only one roll of the dice to resolve a play.  Before the play, the offense calls the play and the players involved.  The defense attempts to 'call' the play as well.  If they are correct, penalties go against whoever handles the ball.  If they are wrong, the play proceeds as normal with no penalty to the ball handler.  Think Tecmo Bowl from the old Nintendo days, when you called the right play on defense, you got to blitz the QB.  The better your defense 'calls' the play, the better the end result will be for the defense in Diggin Deep Football.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;My vision for Diggin Deep Football would be as a great fit for the casual football fan who loves fantasy football.  Anyone can play a game right out of the box and play with stock teams.  Since the game is played with cards instead of team sheets, you can mix and match players across different teams (like Fantasy Football.  The game also can cater to the more hardcore football fan.  When do you put 'Nine in the Box' against a team who relies heavily on the run, or maybe try to fool the defense by setting up a screen with your backup Tight End.  Diggin Deep Football should have something for everyone.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Diggin Deep Football also has some of the aspects that have become the flagship of any Diggin Deep Sports product.  The more talented players can 'Dig Deep' in certain game situations to tilt the scales in their favor.  Imagine TRYING to play defense against a Jim Brown who is Diggin Deep.  How about trying to convert a 3rd and 12 against a Bears Line backing Core that is Diggin Deep?  The Diggin Deep methodology is not only limited to 'skilled' positions.  Anyone on the offense and defense (including offensive lineman), can dig deep in certain game situations.  The Check the Deck is back as well.  The deck will determine penalties, check players for injury, making adjustments to player's Diggin Deep chances, or any other unforeseen event that could happen during the course of a game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="111" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="112" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="113" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="114" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="115" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5640" value="Sports: American Football / Gridiron" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="62502" value="Rob Lennon" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="32992" value="Diggin Deep Sports" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.75" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.25" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="4" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>