<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="134798">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6f4OpwkOIfrIdo_wvh2cKg__thumb/img/7uCp8GtUh-K91Sbs5U6mfOWYM68=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1501440.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6f4OpwkOIfrIdo_wvh2cKg__original/img/OxSdeLOn3tcNPxGcu25YZa3TlC4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1501440.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Malifaux: The Depleted" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Depleted are a group of minions for the Neverborn. They are mean to complement the Dark Debts crew.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the Malifaux Tactica wiki page:&amp;#10;The Depleted are basically cheap targets for the Hungering Darknesses.....hunger for Brilliance. He heals more with them, but they take more damage, and they are drawn to models with the Brilliance trait. They're insignificant, unless within LOS of the hungering darkness.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Depleted are the empty living shells of people who have been using Brilliance for too long, as such they are not combat monsters. They have a below average Cb value with a lower-end damage spread. These low stats can be slightly deceiving however, because the Depleted get a positive flip to damage against models with Brilliance and any model they wound receives one burning token, upping their damage potential a decent amount. This has some possible synergies with Iggy, the only other Neverborn minion who currently uses burning tokens and a Ht 1 Woe who can be taken in a Ten Thunders crew with Lynch.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Reduced to Cinders is a defense trigger with great offensive potential. When killed in melee with this trigger up, the Depleted explodes like a mini-Papa Loco, giving all models within 2&amp;quot; 2 Dg and Brilliance. One important thing to note about this is that the depleted are Hard to Kill - This means you know when they're on one wound, and when they will be killed, so you will know exactly when to cheat in a crow (Preferably a low one), to trigger this.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Depleted form the throw away tarpits and objective grabbers of Lynch's crew.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;They can be startlingly fast once buffed up, capable of pushing 5&amp;quot; towards a model with brilliance, then double walking another 10&amp;quot; (or 12&amp;quot; with The Source up), for a grand total of 15&amp;quot;-17&amp;quot; of movement in a turn, which ignores severe terrain. Although they are Insignificant on their own, this goes away when they have LoS to the Hungering Darkness. When given Reactivate by the Hungering Darkness, these guys can (1) interact with objectives up to 20&amp;quot;-22&amp;quot; away in a single turn, and the loss of such a cheap minion can be an acceptable trade for those final victory points. The push action also allows them to easily escape combat, making them very hard to lock in place.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Reduced to Cinders is an extremely useful way to get the Hungering Darkness into position. The Depleted gets thrown up into the enemy lines and dies, exploding for damage and handing out Brilliance. At the same time the Hungering Darkness comes into play and can activate and attack with all of the Brilliance buffs already in effect. This can only be triggered by enemy attacks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="101" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="102" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="103" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="104" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="105" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="52328" value="Malifaux" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="10053" value="Wyrd Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>