<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="134843">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/A6zLZ-0qfKmUes0GHkm8kg__thumb/img/2ClZciqs1tuA2VlcTvS825FKWSM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1502800.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/A6zLZ-0qfKmUes0GHkm8kg__original/img/ik6hsCb26g8Xo1vmeCkSp8ZBFR8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1502800.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Minosse" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>After winning the war against Athens, Minosse ordered that each year, 9 young men and 9 young women were to be sent as sacrifice to the Minotaur. Teseo departed to end this foul doing. In Creta met Arianna, Minosse' daughter, that fell in love with him and reveled him the greatest labyrinth secret: the strength of the Minotaur came from 4 magic Talismans created by Minosse, infusing the creature's soul in them. The only way to kill the Minotaur was to divide the Talisman. Teseo did it, after avoiding the maze traps, than fought the man-bull, killing it after a fierce battle. &amp;#10;Hundreds of years later, a greedy hand was going to get the last of the four mighty artifacts, not caring about the warning Teseo carved on the maze wall &amp;ldquo;Never gather what has been divided&amp;rdquo;. A tremor shook the walls and with a loud roar the central labyrinth section collapsed, filling the air with a cloud of hundreds years old dust. A scary and inhuman scream echoed through the stone corridors and while the dust fell down, a huge shape with pointed horns and a large, sharp axe in hand slowly appeared.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Minosse is a labyrinth game in which four player compete to collect talismans and to get out before the Minotaur catches them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The board is created by randomly placing tiles in a 8&amp;times;8 square, with the four goal squares in the center, and with adventurers' starting tiles in the four corners.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is divided into 3 phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     In the first phases the adventurers run toward the center of the labyrinth to get the first talisman. First one to arrive chooses first. To do this, each player gets 3 action points that can be used to rotate tiles, creating a free path to the center, to move from one tile to the next one (as long as you have a connected hallway. Note: these AP (action points) can rotate any tile, so you can use them to slow opponents, disrupting their path. With he first talisman, you also earn a God favor. Talisman power recharges with time, after you use it; God favor is a one shoot power to help you win.&amp;#10;     The second phase starts after everyone gets one talisman. Adventurers must collect the other 3 talismans to complete the ancient artifact. The rules are the same as the first phase, 3 AP for rotating tiles, moving, and activating Talismans where needed.&amp;#10;     When the first adventurer collects the fourth talisman phase 3 begins. The labyrinth center crumbles, and the exit appears. The exit is guarded by the Minotaur, who'll try to catch everyone that got all the four talismans. After each adventurer's turn, the Minotaur moves. Each player secretly lays down a card with a direction and they reveal them all together. The Minotaur moves according to cards. If the Minotaur hits an adventurer with 4 talismans, he badly slows him down. The winner is first adventurer to reach the exit carrying four talismans.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1059" value="Maze" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1082" value="Mythology" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="7.875" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.216506" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>