<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="134801">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/kt3HIYEfXEcnlpdOx7fdOw__thumb/img/VXKpV97ic5a8ZLheW3rCtrKElqo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1501434.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/kt3HIYEfXEcnlpdOx7fdOw__original/img/ehKmtYfCklpLSRcVV24ORQ5OB78=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1501434.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Malifaux: Mr Graves" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Mr. Graves is an expansion unit for Malifaux. He belongs to the Neverborn faction.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the Malifaux Tactica Wiki page:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Overview&amp;#10;Mr. Graves is the Honeypot's bouncer and secret Nephilim skinwalker.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mobility&amp;#10;Mr. Graves respectable walk and charge ranges and has Shove Aside, allowing him to move through HT 1 or 2 models. He has a (1) action called &amp;quot;Show ya the door&amp;quot; that initiates a CB-&amp;gt;DF Duel with Graves and an enemy model within 1&amp;quot;. If Graves wins he can Push the model up to 5&amp;quot; and graves can then push himself into Base contact with that model. He has a (0) spell called &amp;quot;Bar's Closed&amp;quot; that's a 6&amp;quot; pulse. He picks a spot within LOS and 6&amp;quot; and any model that fails to resist the spell (using willpower) is pushed 4&amp;quot; directly away from the chosen spot. Although this ability does not move Mr. Graves himself, it can be useful for adding to the speed of his crew.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Offense&amp;#10;His fencepost packs a nasty punch with a minimum of 3 Dg and receives a positive flip to damage against Height 1 and height 2 models. He can flurry with that Fence post, and he gets a Rams to his combat when swinging on models with the Brilliance characteristic. This allows him to easily trigger &amp;quot;Broke Something&amp;quot; which causes a model damaged by the Fence Post to be unable to spend more than 2 AP during its next activation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;He has the Wicked and Ruthless characteristics as well to let his disengaging strikes hurt and ignore those harmless/pitiful models.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;He also has a ranged damaging spell - Settel Tab, one that he can discard cards for in order to gain positive flips on its damage. This can be used in melee and has a respectable severe damage of 5. Bear this in mind if you are facing spirits.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Resilience&amp;#10;He has Black Blood to punish people hitting him in Melee along with Armor 1 and Slow to Die. He has a (0) spell called &amp;quot;Keeping the Peace&amp;quot; that's a 6&amp;quot; Aura that makes charging enemy models win a CB-&amp;gt;12 duel before their attack flip or they receive a negative flip to their charge damage. He is Ht3, so keep this in mind when it comes to hiding models behind him and when trying to get him into cover.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tips and Tricks&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bar's Closed&amp;#10;Although at first glance Mr. Graves seems to be not a lot more than a beatstick, this surprisingly versatile spell gives him much more scope in a crew. Unlike similar spells, such as Zoraida's repulsive, the push effect does not emanate from the model generating the pulse, but from a point he picks when he casts the spell. It must be noted that it isn't models within 6&amp;quot; of the point that are affected, its all models within 6&amp;quot; of Mr. Graves.&amp;#10;Some tricks that can be played with this ability include, but are not limited to:&amp;#10;push your models further up the table&amp;#10;push enemy models off objectives&amp;#10;push models into Mr. Graves' melee range so that he can flurry them.&amp;#10;push models off heights to cause damage&amp;#10;separate models that are engaged in melee&amp;#10;push brilliant models towards the Hungering Darkness so it can feed from them&amp;#10;bring a model closer to Mr. Graves so that he can use Show Ya The Door&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="52328" value="Malifaux" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="10053" value="Wyrd Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="9.66667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.471405" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="14" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>