<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="135442">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/2wbZbVXouZo5POeDi_tyVg__thumb/img/l3wEMCoz-XOoYKz8tcWnrdW6h10=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1514525.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/2wbZbVXouZo5POeDi_tyVg__original/img/w25eMdnpmOsnH3c1tyUj-AskWCg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1514525.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ascendance: Call of Thuria" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ascendance is a sci-fi game set in a grim future, where mankind has discovered a new resource: the Divine Power. Using this newfound power, they gained the ability to control and reshape everything around them. On earth lies the only way to reach Thuria, the place where this power lies. Several alien, or former human, races have come to earth to reach this place and claim the Divine Power for themselves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Ascendance - Call of Thuria board game is designed for 2-4 players of ages 12 and above. It is played with decks of cards which the players customize for themselves through the extra cards available on the game box, or future expansions. Players deploy Units, Structures and play cards from their hands, reserving Divine Abilities for when things get tough. The Game Board is used to play Events which harass or assist the players and also to help players choose Advantages, special situations that may turn the tide of battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is won via one of two ways. You can either destroy your opponent's Fortress by reducing its Hit Points to 0, or gather enough Divine Power to use your Ultimatum and completely annihilate your opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAMEPLAY&amp;#10;Once players have chosen the cards to use in their Decks, they must choose 5 Divine Abilities for the current match and then the game can begin. The game is separated into Phases, with each player completing their own Phase separately, unless another player intervenes. Players use Production Credits (usually called just Credits) to deploy Armies, play Commands from their hand and any other costs necessary. These Credits can be acquired by the Fortress, or other Structures. Players may also purchase Enhancements on their Structures or Units to make them better or change their use. Divine Power Points are also acquired every turn and the players use them to perform their Divine Abilities, powerful cards that may, if played at the right moment, judge the outcome of a battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn, the chaotic landscape of Thuria or the monstrous Zordath pose a threat to the players. Events are drawn every turn and usually harass the players by forcing them to attack the Zordath or face a natural hazard. However, sometimes one can take advantage of these Events and gain the upper hand. Once in a while, an Artifact or a Power Source may surface on the world of Thuria. Claiming these may also grant a bonus.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Finally, each player at every turn chooses an Advantage on the Game Board. Choosing one locks it from the other players, so sometimes it may be preferrable that your opponent does not have a certain Advantage than you having one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phases are summarized below:&amp;#10;Event Phase - An Event is drawn and resolves.&amp;#10;Advantage Phase - Players choose their Advantage on the Game Board.&amp;#10;Draw Phase - Players draw Cards, gain Divine Power and pay any costs.&amp;#10;Support Phase - Armies are deployed and any purchases are made.&amp;#10;Assault Phase - Units are sent to deal damage to the opponent's Fortress.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="40" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="65863" value="George Katsoulis" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="65864" value="Vaggelis Manousakas" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23711" value="Random Crew Productions" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="8.125" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.216506" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>