<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="137800">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TaehGqdpDFa5eDRDyVZvSA__thumb/img/Fdac0kXY79N51LZ6k1Pvh4kiqoc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1694369.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TaehGqdpDFa5eDRDyVZvSA__original/img/aPLBLMFpTajqyC2fIt7LLvc22sw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1694369.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Famous Divisions: Guards Armoured Division" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Guards Armoured Division" />
			
						               													<description>Guards Armoured Division: Part of The Famous Divisions series by Decision Games, started with Gross Deutschland Panzer (World at War magazine #20) and continuing with British Guards Armour, uses a system that represents a new evolution in design that brings tactical elements to an otherwise operational simulation. Recreating four battles of the British Guards Armour Division in 1944 and 1945, this game includes four battles: Operation Goodwood, Operation Veritable, Bonninghardt Ridge, and Joe&amp;rsquo;s Bridge. It was designed by John Schettler and developed by Eric Harvey and Ty Bomba.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Famous Divisions Series offers a new concept: game play is governed by the drawing of &amp;quot;Event Chits&amp;quot; during combat. Combat is not simply resolved by comparing the attack strengths and defense strengths of units, but is modified by a random chit-draw of over 140 possible &amp;quot;events&amp;quot; that introduce the elements of chaos and unpredictability to combat resolution. Event Chits can be nullified by other Event Chits; so players never know how an attack may be resolved based solely on odds ratios.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each hex represents approximately 500 meters from side to opposite side. Each game turn represents approximately six hours; however, the game turns aren't divided into separate friendly and enemy turns. Rather, each is comprised of numerous individual HQ activations. All of the HQ activation chits are placed into a cup, and each is drawn one at a time to initiate the activation (movement and combat) of a particular headquarters and its associated companies. When that HQ&amp;rsquo;s activation is finished, a new HQ is drawn from the cup, and then its activation begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Famous Divisions: Guards Armour is a special edition game that includes two counter sheets (560 counters) and four maps (on two 22 x 34 inch sheets) of the various battlefields where the division fought. Combat units are individual companies featuring distinct vehicles and weapons, shown as icons along with the unique capabilities of the vehicle or weapon portrayed. At company level the game play is tactical in many respects: units have individual range values, different movement capabilities depending on type (wheeled, tracked and leg), and the rules cover such things as demolishing bridges, pontoon bridges, weather, overrun, supply, infantry riding tanks, direct ranged fire, artillery barrages, opportunity fire, night, fortifications (bunkers, trenches, mines, dragon&amp;rsquo;s teeth), engineers, armor recovery vehicles, airpower and anti-aircraft.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;While not a purpose-designed solitaire system, the Event Chit mechanism makes the series easily adapted to such play, since the player won't know what chits may be drawn that could alter combat, or what order the HQ activations will take place. Some examples of the 140 Event Chits are: Sniper, Good Commander, Ambush, Experienced NCO, Caught in Crossfire, Fanatic, Radio Out, Critical Hit, Frontal Assault, Elite Troops, Outflanked, Hand-to-Hand Combat, and Friendly Fire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game includes two maps (22x34&amp;rdquo;) and two counter sheets containing 560 counters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Scale:&amp;#10;Game Turn: 6 hours&amp;#10;Hex: 601 yards / 550 meters&amp;#10;Units: Company&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Inventory:&amp;#10;Two 22 x 34&amp;quot; full color mapsheets&amp;#10;Two dual-side printed countersheets (560 1/2&amp;quot; counters)&amp;#10;One 32-page rulebook&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Solitaire Playability: Medium&amp;#10;Complexity Level: Medium&amp;#10;Players: 2 or more&amp;#10;Playing Time: 4-15&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="3244" value="Magazine: World at War" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3878" value="Eric R. Harvey" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1380" value="John Schettler" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="102" value="Decision Games (I)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="21" />
			<average value="6.89048" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.67244" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="147" />
			<trading value="3" />
			<wanting value="5" />
			<wishing value="9" />
			<numcomments value="27" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>