<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="138492">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/1Yv5qoRMk4kW5a83wNYjiw__thumb/img/wd6JkzFSEf22_kq_fsPyxLMczjI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1590803.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/1Yv5qoRMk4kW5a83wNYjiw__original/img/TMKVIinDVCNxeJ9a3J2tzAYCBa4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1590803.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="REVOLVIQA Red" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>REVOLVIQA&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RevolvIQa, the revolving game series debuted in N&amp;uuml;rnberg Toy Fair 2013. It&amp;rsquo;s basis is an innovation: playing piece supported revolving mechanism. The supporter is a playing piece onto which a constituted bottom surface in the middle of the revolving device is laid upon. A playing piece supported revolving device can make 6 playing pieces step at once.&amp;#10;RevolvIQa Red and RevolvIQa Blue are two independent games, packed into independent boxes, however these ones are intending to be an overture of revolving game series.&amp;#10;In a RevolvIQa box there are 3 individual games: 2 pcs. revolving puzzle games in varied difficulty levels (1 player) and 1 pc. revolving board game (2 players). Playing adventure and rules are varied, however a.m. structure is the same in both RevolvIQa boxes.&amp;#10;Play with revolving puzzles first:&amp;#10;the basic idea here is to have different coloured balls as a &amp;bdquo;pixel&amp;rdquo; of a pic on a playing field. The playing field plate is removable and exchangable. It has a hexagonal shape and it is hole-punched at 37 places in bee-cells pattern. It is to be put onto a basic board having 37 spheric recesses in the same pattern area. After pouring the required balls onto field, revolve until all the coloured balls match with the colours of the graphic. Starting with any ball arrangement results solution! A &amp;bdquo;Fox&amp;rdquo; and a &amp;bdquo;Galaxy&amp;rdquo; in RevolvIQa Red, a &amp;bdquo;Parachute&amp;rdquo; and a &amp;bdquo;Birthday&amp;rdquo; in RevolvIQa Blue is available as main theme on graphics of the playing fields.&amp;#10;Play with board games next:&amp;#10;There are equal starting chance arrangements for both players and one after the other order playable games by immediate revolving in both RevolvIQa board games. &amp;#10;Player wins, who revolves 5 in one row of its chosen coloured balls at first: that&amp;rsquo;s the board game about in RevolvIQa Red. Defeat arrives as magic touch in most of the cases. It&amp;rsquo;s name: &amp;bdquo;COLORICA-5&amp;rdquo;.&amp;#10;Player wins in board game of RevolvIQa Blue, whose all chosen 4 ferries are able to cross the sea first, or the one, whose opponent can&amp;rsquo;t revolve rule-wise anymore. It&amp;rsquo;s wintertime and some areas in the sea is frozen (white balls on the board). Revolving rules: revolve on water only (support on dark blue balls only), at least one of revolving player&amp;rsquo;s ferries shall change place during revolving action, the opponent&amp;rsquo;s can be revolved at the same time, but only if opponent&amp;rsquo;s previous revolving action took place elsewhere. Captivating and exciting. It&amp;rsquo;s name: &amp;bdquo;FERRY&amp;rdquo;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;REVOLVIQA Red&amp;#10;3 games in the box: Fox, Galaxy, COLORICA-5&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Revolving puzzle and board games that are developing creativity and logical and strategic skills for 1 or 2 players, children or adults.&amp;#10;Description&amp;#10;Fox&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Revolving puzzle games that are developing creativity and logical skills for 1 player, children or adults. Revolve so that the colored balls could get into their position!&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;Galaxy&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Revolving puzzle games that are developing creativity and logical skills for 1 player, children or adults. Revolve so that the colored balls could get into their position!&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;COLORICA-5&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Games developing logical and strategic skills for two players. The purpose of the game is that one of the players should be able to revolve five balls next to each other, in one line.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="24599" value="Colorica Kft." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="6" />
			<average value="6.91667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.731247" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>