<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="138447">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZcXQ_6rbwA1psU0buLM9GA__thumb/img/Yb8zimmTDkk7Vx4Vg4vUI7G91s0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1571718.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZcXQ_6rbwA1psU0buLM9GA__original/img/qIZsJC8vyplkQnklzUV6QVQ4CRI=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1571718.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Malifaux: Lilith Avatar of Nature&#039;s Malevolence" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the Malifaux Tactica Wiki:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lilith's Avatar is unique in that she interacts very heavily with terrain, and can make significant changes to woods terrain and the board as a whole. She creates and spreads woods terrain, and then makes that woods terrain very scary for her enemies. She retains most of the abilities of her pre-Avatar form, though many become more woods-dependent. Lilith also gains some very useful long-range attacks and damage effects, which can assist in pushing opponents around and controlling board position.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Avatar Form, Lilith suddenly needs to worry about two things that didn't matter as much before, woods terrain and Blood Tokens.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Woods Terrain: An overwhelming portion of Lilith's Actions, Spells, and Attacks work only in woods terrain, or work much better in woods terrain. Lilith wants to stay near the woods, and to keep her enemies near the woods too. Place your initial woods terrain carefully, keeping near any objective locations and any likely spots for enemies to congregate. Be sure your Illusionary Forest is in a good place, too, before you Manifest Lilith's Avatar. You can spread woods further from these existing locations, using Lilith's Sanguine Proliferation spell. This requires a 9 card or better, and suits don't matter, so you should plan to have a card in hand for it in case your flip isn't enough. This growth can seem very slow, however, since you can only expand by 3&amp;quot; for every action, so it's usually best to do this only if you're setting up an immediate attack on an opponent who's not quite in reach of the forest on Lilith's turn. Note also that Sanguine Proliferation costs a Blood Token, which can be in short supply.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gaining Blood Tokens: If you're fighting against living or Undead opponents, Lilith can usually gain a Blood Token every time something dies: anyone killed by her Nature's Revenge spell, or killed within 8&amp;quot; of her and in base contact with a woods terrain, generates a Blood Token. Note that you also generate Blood Tokens when your own models are killed within 8&amp;quot; of Lilith if they're in base contact with a woods terrain. Lilith's most likely crews (Nephilim and Waldgeists) are all considered living, so this may provide some benefit or at least consolation. She can also gain a Blood Token when she kills a living or Undead unit by using Drain Blood, but this is a (0) Action so she can only use it once per round. Note, though, that if your enemy has a lot of Constructs, Nightmares, Objects, Spirits, or Soulless models, these won't give you any Blood Tokens so it may not be worth Manifesting.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Spending Blood Tokens: While pre-Manifest Lilith only really keeps her Blood Tokens to feed her young or try to meet a scheme for VP, in Avatar form she has tremendous need of Blood Tokens. Avatar Lilith uses Blood Tokens to use her Erupting Underbrush mass melee attack, to expand the woods with her Sanguine Proliferation spell (though she can use Blood Tokens from nearby minions within 6&amp;quot; instead for this), and to attack units with her Nature's Revenge spell (though this may also give her Blood Tokens back, possibly generating a profit if she kills a lot of wounded minions). On top of this, she can also use Blood Tokens to grow and mature her Nephilim. The demand and uses of Blood Tokens are quite high for Lilith, so take some care in choosing the right way to spend a Token. A good general rule is: if it's going to kill at least one enemy model, it's worth spending a Blood Token, especially if that model is living or Undead. Otherwise, the Blood Token is probably better spent growing a Terror Tot.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Card Flow Control: Avatar Lilith retains her Rush of Magic Ability and Bloody Fate trigger, so you will often pull a card and discard it during play. This doesn't give you more control cards, but it can be a helpful way of raising the average value of your cards and helping you find the Mask (or occasionally Crows) cards you need. Remember to use these card flow effects, since they will help refine your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="52328" value="Malifaux" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="10053" value="Wyrd Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="3" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>