<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="139561">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/c1Inv6fpqR0EgcMVveR1Tg__thumb/img/OUOFh_NavbCrKnRbSgeuNsQ1T6o=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1637785.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/c1Inv6fpqR0EgcMVveR1Tg__original/img/T0IQjlSqEEH-ya4HZdrs710boDI=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1637785.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Álmok e Cartas Assombradas Edição de Colecionador" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This is a collection of Card Games by Vince Vader published by Ceilikan jogos. It was avaliable only during pre-order for both games and limited to 200 units.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;Aacute;lmok is a game about deep buried memories in the mind. It is a journey between dreams and nightmares. It is an experience based on the unconscious perceptions of the oniric mind.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In &amp;Aacute;lmok, the players are in deep sleep, trying to collect parts of their dreams to scape an eternal nightmare. Use your memory, find your way to the wakening, tap in sleeping powers of the unconscious mind, be the first to get free from your dreams.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;Aacute;lmok&amp;#10;&amp;Aacute;lmok uses the classic Memory Game mechanic with some twists to make the game more dynamic and enjoyable. In your turn, you turn cards face up and check if they are a group, like the classic game, but here, the groups must have 3 cards, but you can combine then using their color or their number, much like a rummy game. Each group you form, give you points and also a special dream ability that you can use later to gain even more points or save for bonus points in the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player who reaches a certain amount of points first (based on the number of players), is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cartas Assombradas&amp;#10;Cartas Assombradas (Haunted Cards in English) is a game where the players are supernatural investigators in a journey inside an old haunted manor. In each round, the players try to explore more and more of the house to prove their courage and gain points. The bravest (or luckiest) player that was not catch by the house's ghosts and explored more of the house, win more points. When dawn came, the player with more points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Using a Push Your Luck mechanic, in your turn, each player take a card from the stack. If it is a house hallway, it means that the player explored that hallway and receives its points. If it is a ghost, he can lose some points, or even get out of the round. There are also equipments to help players in this adventure. Before he plays, a player can choose to leave the house in that round and gain the points he collect so far. If a ghost catches him, he loses all points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when dawn came, being dawn a card that is shuffled in the deck before the third round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="139558" value="Álmok" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="139559" value="Cartas Assombradas" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="52964" value="Vicente (Vince) Martin" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="52964" value="Vicente (Vince) Martin" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7335" value="Ceilikan Jogos" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="8" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>