<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="139645">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/CwbLY9pyIg6OGwJ6E_VEMA__thumb/img/gkrltVx8sI4Takbfif5S7iUX56w=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1597792.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/CwbLY9pyIg6OGwJ6E_VEMA__original/img/6-VSPCBxQBAo1jDttzP5hXEOxEo=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1597792.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="VICTUS Gladitorial Combat" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Victus recreates the the ancient world&amp;rsquo;s most deadly sport, Gladitorial Combat! This is a complete stand alone game that puts two or more players in control of history&amp;rsquo;s greatest fighting machines using Dynamic Movement, Abilities Pooling and pure Cunning! The rules allow for play of one off games to settle old scores, bracketed tournaments or full immersion in the Ancient world using the Victus Campaign system. In the campaign, Gladiators battle to win their freedom or to gather glory as they advance in both wealth and skill. The Fortuna tables are used to expand a Gladiator's fate beyond the arena.  The rulebook comes with it&amp;rsquo;s own board and paper models to allow for quick start to play; however, since gameplay takes place on a hex board, scale is not limited.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players use a system to record their actions each turn and perform them in the order of a contested Initiative, which is determined by a roll off with modifiers for gear based on weight. Although Actions are recorded, maneuvering takes place in each turn as players perform counter strikes and have chances to maneuver in response to their opponent. Guard and Facing play a role in this.  Gladiators use their Fortitudo (used for striking), Agilito (used for defense and movement), and Virtus (used for stamina and as a resource pool) to perform their Actions each turn through the phases. As wounds are dealt, Gladiators become weaker.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Weapons have different effects against different armor and carry their own advantages and disadvantages in relation to the fighting styles. For example the Thracian's Sica is able to reach behind a Myrmillo's shield more effectively.  Striking takes place with models either targeting specific areas of the body or attacking untargeted areas with both players rolling in Attack/Defense. Armor for specific areas hit are taken into account and then if the attack passes through the armor the player rolls on a Wounding Table which can lead to anything from a Stun to a Fatal Wound. Fatal Wounds are worked up to, Stuns count as Modifiers to Abilities and subsequent rolls on the Wound Table. Gameplay invloves combatants striking, counter striking and working each other over in the process.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As this action is taking place, a Gladiator can attempt to ask for Missus, i.e. Mercy (if the match allows!) and depending on his performance and roll on the Missus table he could prolong his fighting career before being seriously wounded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1050" value="Ancient" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2689" value="Action Queue" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5606" value="Ancient: Rome" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6993" value="Theme: Gladiators" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="9171" value="Jayson Gardner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4361" value="Iron Ivan Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.866025" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="11" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>