<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="140113">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/dFiDpa6Mcyty1CIufLTe4Q__thumb/img/M67h7aKxTxPkmWGh9pNTbhhfBjo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1608322.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/dFiDpa6Mcyty1CIufLTe4Q__original/img/YWtStNG82FHSfRSRuAsBpsU9LW4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1608322.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Vietnam" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>English:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Vietnam is a collector NAC based wargame, set in this bloody conflict. It recreates the battles and challenges that came under american detachments. The huge amount of tokens shows the different units and weaponry used: Viet Cong, Green Beret, heliborne troops, infantry, mortars, anti-aircraft, missile launchers, Chinook, Cobra, Huey and Cayuse helicopters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two, three or four players take command of American and South Vietnamese troops, and the army of North Vietnam.&amp;#10;Once initial troops placed on the board, each player takes turns moving the mobility factor of each unit, applying modifiers depending on the passing zone (rivers, streams, jungle paths, roads and rice fields).&amp;#10;Infantry units can engage in combat with adjacent opponents, existing differences between combat values &amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;&amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;depending on their experience and equipment (guerrillas, viet cong, infantry and Green Berets are an example).&amp;#10;Artillery units can launch ranged attacks against other tabs or objectives.&amp;#10;The weather factor also plays a big role.&amp;#10;The firepower and mobility offered by different types of helicopters are the great strength of the American contingent, as opposed to the number of North Vietnamese infantry and difficult terrain mobility, may be grouped, giving the oportunity to cheating with empty groups that must be discovered approaching them.&amp;#10;Several Fire Support Base, which at siege are recreated in an extended area on the board, providing another level, much more exciting, including mines and barbed wire to open a gap.&amp;#10;At the end of the round 14, players earn points for every target that their units still maintain (bases, hills and villages). The winner is the most points of victory has joined.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Similar: Vietnam&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Spanish:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Vietnam es un wargame de coleccionista, basado en el juego de la desaparecida NAC, y ambientado en el conflicto que le da nombre. En &amp;eacute;l se recrean los combates y dificultades a las que se vieron sometidos los destacamentos estadounidenses. La enorme cantidad de fichas reflejan las diferente unidades y maquinaria usada: viet cong, boinas verdes, tropa helitransportada, infanter&amp;iacute;a, morteros, antia&amp;eacute;reos, lanzamisiles, helicopteros Chinook, Cobra, Cayuse y Huey.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dos, tres o cuatro jugadores toman el mando de las tropas americanas y survietnamitas, o el ejercito de Vietnam del norte.&amp;#10;Una vez colocadas las tropas iniciales sobre el tablero, cada jugador se turna moviendo el factor de movimiento de cada ficha, aplicando modificadores dependiendo del tipo de zona por el que pase (r&amp;iacute;os, riachuelos, jungla, caminos, rutas y arrozales).&amp;#10;Las unidades de infanter&amp;iacute;a pueden entablar combate con los adversarios adyacentes, existiendo diferencias entre los valores de combate dependiendo de su experiencia y equipo (guerrilleros, viet cong, infanter&amp;iacute;a y boinas verdes son un ejemplo).&amp;#10;Las unidades de artiller&amp;iacute;a pueden lanzar ataques a distancia contra otras fichas u objetivos.&amp;#10;El factor climatol&amp;oacute;gico tambi&amp;eacute;n juega un gran papel.&amp;#10;La capacidad de fuego y movilidad que ofrecen los distintos tipos de helic&amp;oacute;pteros son la gran baza del contingente americano, en oposici&amp;oacute;n a la cantidad de infanter&amp;iacute;a norvietnamita y su movilidad por terreno dificultoso,pudiendo agruparse, enga&amp;ntilde;ando al contrario con grupos vac&amp;iacute;os que avanzan y deben ser descubiertos acerc&amp;aacute;ndose a ellos.&amp;#10;Existen varias Base de Apoyo al Fuego, que al asaltarse se recrean en una zona ampliada en el tablero, ofreciendo otra escala, mucho m&amp;aacute;s emocionante, incluyendo minas y alambradas por las que debe abrirse una brecha.&amp;#10;Al finalizar el turno 14, los jugadores suman puntos por cada objetivo en el que a&amp;uacute;n mantengan sus unidades (bases, colinas y poblados). El ganador es el que mayor cantidad de puntos de victoria haya sumado.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1109" value="Vietnam War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="10618" value="Country: Vietnam" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="67721" value="Jose Luis Mellado Valle" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="67721" value="Jose Luis Mellado Valle" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="24836" value="Ronin7 Juegos" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>