<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="140458">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Hit fast! Hit hard!" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>As the eastern bloc crumbles in 1989 Gorbatjov is ousted in a reactionary coup led by the Soviet military. In desperate attempt to turn back time and unite the eastern bloc the long prepared offensive into western Europe is launched.  A critical element for success is to be able to interdict the American reinforcements over the Atlantic to its NATO allies. That job belongs to the submarines of the arctic fleet in Murmansk. But they need air support and support from surface vessels as well and Murmansk is too far away from the North Atlantic seas to provide that support. In order to seize air fields and naval bases on the Norwegian west coast as fast as possible an invasion of Finland and Sweden is launched at the same time  as the Norwegian border is crossed on the Nordkapp to outflank the Norwegian easily defensible terrain along the northern coast.  Neutrality will not protect Sweden this time. But maybe an army of 600 000 trained men and 600 tanks will?&amp;#10;This game deals with the southern part  of the Soviet operation against Sweden, the invasion of Sk&amp;aring;ne. The well trained paratroopers of the VDV and the equally well trained Baltic marines land to face the bulk of the Swedish armoured brigades supported by infantry and artillery in terrain ideally suited for armoured units.  Will the Swedish built  turret less tank Strv 103 meet the expectations, though twenty years in service now, or will it be up to the British built Centurions, with more than thirty years in service,  to destroy the invaders? &amp;#10;With X pages of rules, XXX counters X maps and  13 scenarios the game is designed to help understanding of the challenges of the Swedes as well as those of the Warpac. While gameplay is designed to be fast and easy with command and control issues being in the centre of the design the optional rules allow for deeper study into logistics and recovery. Units are platoons and each game turn equals one hour . Hexes are 500 meters across.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Hit fast! Hit hard! centres on the 7th armoured brigade, PB7 Malm&amp;ouml;brigaden, and its hypothetical but well planned and trained actions around Ystad on the Scanian south coast.  Equipped with Strv 103C, the upgraded version of the famous &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; tank was the cutting edge of the XI. Division responsible for repelling or at least fixing an invasion  aimed at Ystad or Trelleborg. While PB7 might be superior in fire power to the air assault and naval infantry units it initially will encounter these are the elite units of the Soviet union. If the soviets seize a working harbour mechanised units with T-72M1 tanks are sure to pour in fast.  You will also see  parts of two different Swedish types of infantry brigades as well as territorial defence units  and the 12th independent mechanised battalion with Strv 102R, partly upgraded Centurions, and motorised rifle companies in trucks rather than Pbv 302 infantry fighting vehicles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2057" value="Chit-Pull System" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="55907" value="Ola Palmquist" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="24451" value="Battle Staff Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>