<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="141052">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TLcPgjY2c7OLcQGQ4-ggMQ__thumb/img/ES1dsWG0E85iXRwUnZZ915i1lNk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1753760.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TLcPgjY2c7OLcQGQ4-ggMQ__original/img/pXu5gjblakZPYCYJr9GrRnf66ls=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1753760.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ultrium Sphere: Tëra-nëva Sphere" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In a distant future, man has conquered space and the ultimate entertainment is an extremely violent sport called ULTRIUM SPHERE.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In these matches, anything goes. At least two teams oppose each other, competing to score the 3 decisive goals that lead to victory. The teams usually belong to powerful corporations or mere independents, and the players come from the entire Galaxy (human beings, androids, genetic experiments or aliens). ULTRIUM SPHERE has become the most popular game throughout the universe and is watched by hundreds of billions of entities. The players who manage to survive the game and perform outstandingly well are virtually elevated to the rank of Divinities and are named the ULTRAs. &amp;#10; In ULTRIUM SPHERE, each player is the leader of an Ultrium Sphere team, which he/she tries to lead to victory.&amp;#10;Each team consists of two decks:  25 Ultra Cards and 25 Interaction Cards. The Ultra Cards represent the team members and describe their race and various characteristics, offensive (tackling, attack, shot) and defensive (resistance, save, pass). The Interaction cards are the different strategies that the team can apply. &amp;#10;At the beginning of the game, each player draws 4 Interaction Cards and 6 Ultra Cards. The 6 Ultras are to be laid out in two lines, the attack line and the defense line (3 Ultras in each line). The Interaction cards stay in hand. &amp;#10;The Ultras can be used either for their special ability or to carry out various actions according to their place on the field. The strikers can undermine the opponent&amp;rsquo;s defense (tackling, attack) or try to shoot a goal. The defenders can make passes to strikers (a pass must take place prior to every shot at goal) or stop the opponent&amp;rsquo;s shots. The player must activate the Ultras (i.e. turn them at a 90-degree angle) when he/she uses them. Once activated, the Ultras can no longer be used. Therefore, the player must not activate all his/her Ultras during his/her turn, since the activated Ultras will not be able to defend during the opponent&amp;rsquo;s turn. When the player chooses to play an action, he/she must cast a 12-sided die and add the Ultra&amp;rsquo;s personal bonus for the action chosen. To know whether the action succeeds or not, the player compares the total to a success threshold, which must be exceeded or not depending on the type of action.&amp;#10;The Interaction card may be used at any time to strengthen one&amp;rsquo;s own Ultras or weaken the opponent&amp;rsquo;s Ultras. &amp;#10;When the turn begins, the player draws 1 Interaction card and set all his/her Ultras upright. First, he/she can replace Ultras and have 2 Ultras swap place. He/she can then use the Ultras and Interaction cards.&amp;#10;When the player can no longer or does no longer want to carry out any action, or when he/she scores a goal, his/her turn ends and the opponent can begin his/her turn.&amp;#10;The game goes on until one of the players scores 3 goals.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2012" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6924" value="Theme: Sci-Fi Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="67971" value="Nicolas Smeers" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="24942" value="AzaoGames" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.408248" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="22" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>