<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="143625">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/bHxrTXxgz_yvTbOJWN8yiQ__thumb/img/9t-aI08cJ6D1czgWSUuMDU1BdBk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1682733.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/bHxrTXxgz_yvTbOJWN8yiQ__original/img/ESrDgAUI4GV5mNgyBM9Npmwa8GU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1682733.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="ATS TT: Orders for the Major" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the publisher's website:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAVRUS, 29 June 1944: Company of the Argylls bore the brunt of the first assault made by 10th SS &amp;ldquo;Hohenstaufen&amp;rdquo; in Normandy. As waves of Panzer Grenadiers broke against the Argylls&amp;rsquo; position, B company PIATs drove off the accompanying tanks. By evening, the enemy had infiltrated the sunken road behind B Company, driving a wedge between it and the rest of the battalion. The position of B Company&amp;rsquo;s forward 11 Platoon became difficult, as it was engaged front and rear. Difficult, but not impossible, so long as ammunition held out. Captain Mackenzie, 2 i/c B Company, was leading 11 Platoon. Earlier in the afternoon, he used the platoon PIAT to drive off three enemy tanks that were manoeuvring along the hedges north of the Bougy road. By evening, he and his Platoon had been given up for lost. But just before sunset, he led the fourteen survivors of 11 Platoon back into the Battalion perimeter. He had only withdrawn from the fight when his 2 inch mortar had taken a direct hit and the platoon had no rifle ammunition left. He brought out all but his most seriously wounded. Mackenzie&amp;rsquo;s gallant stand won him a Military Cross.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Many years ago military historian par excellence Ian Daglish joined CH to launch the first in a string of historical modules created by onsite research. What followed was a successful career as a military history book author, penning titles including Operation Bluecoat and others for Pen &amp;amp; Sword. Before his research went into books focused on the British experience during the Battle of Normandy, Ian's work was brought to the fore in the form of what became ATS's SCOTTISH CORRIDOR. This release has long been slated for new editions and the time is finally here, NOW, in the form of ORDERS FOR THE MAJOR and SHOUT FOR PIATS. Times have changed, art has changed, and we continue to strive to create the most eye-pleasing tactical-level game cartography and color counters to provide you with an interesting and evocative experience. Both of those elements make the ORDERS FOR THE MAJOR equal to a brand new approach, with color die-cut counters, maps that simply DEFEAT the earlier versions on every level, and more. More as in scenarios using the new and popular layout plus optional scenario OOB tweaks that pop the action in tournament-sized actions ... to meatier versions. The product stays true to design Daglish, and the new OOB changes are provided as additional content for those that want to boost the octane and push the redline ... and up the Panzer count ... in their gaming.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The new counters include more Tommy Atkins (i.e., British nationality), an all new set of Waffen SS in yet another one of their camo patterns (never before published), PLUS AFVs and guns in Normandy camo.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="240" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="56" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="57" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="58" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="59" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="60" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="112" value="Series: Advanced Tobruk System (Critical Hit)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="7090" value="Scottish Corridor: Lion Rampant" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2960" value="Ian Daglish" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="928" value="Critical Hit, Inc." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="8.2" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.979796" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="29" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>