<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="145011">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="DexQuest" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>DexQuest is a family fantasy dexterity game in which you roll a specially weighted ball down a ramp, down a series of 3D steps made from the large box and a series of smaller boxes inside. The ball is weighted to stop when it slows and even very young gamers (5+) will soon get the hang of stopping it exactly where they want as it&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit easier than flicking.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your rolls down the steps relate to movement and actions on the map. For example, if you want to move to a river location on the map, you will need to roll the ball to stop anywhere on the middle &amp;lsquo;river&amp;rsquo; step. You might also catch a fish or find a gold coin in the water if the ball stops on one of many special icons spread across the steps. Be careful, though &amp;ndash; if your DexBall finishes out of bounds or on an ambush icon there will be consequences!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The map locations are seeded at random with purple event cubes which players can travel to and undertake quest challenges. In true fantasy tradition these quests might be instant treasure chests, challenges, or monsters. All challenges and combat are completed by aiming for different sections of the 3D steps, which include many different &amp;lsquo;zones&amp;rsquo; in which you must land to win gold. The game ships with 10 exciting and varied adventure cards, increasing in difficulty, each containing a short story and 20 quests. The game can be played PvP competitively (up to 4), co-operatively, and solo - the different adventures are tailored to these different game types.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the Standard game the launcher location changes between 5 positions each turn to make aiming the DexBall that little bit more challenging. In Easy mode the launcher stays in its central position meaning you can aim with real accuracy every turn. Beginners are also allowed more rolls.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game really comes to life when players have collected enough gold to buy an upgrade from a choice of 16 on their player mat. Upgrades include LEVITATION: being allowed to move the DexBall&amp;rsquo;s finishing position by one ball width; FISHING ROD: which allows you to collect fish when landed on, which can then be eaten for bonus re-rolls and travel rolls, and SECRET MAP: allows you to use the shortcuts on the map meaning you can move faster and track down more gold quicker. Other upgrades give you more control choosing quests, faster map movement and extra gold bonuses. Upgrades must be made left to right in sequence on the mat making for some painful decisions as you will want them all!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Early adventures are very easy and designed to help all players acclimatise to the idea of rolling on the steps then moving on the map to travel and collect goodies. Later adventures are more challenging, with tougher monsters to fight and traps enabled on the 3D steps. Your opponents will take on the role of monster each time, making rolls to add to the monster&amp;rsquo;s base strength, meaning you never quite know how tough the next growling beastie will be.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;DexQuest&amp;rsquo;s art and design and manufacture is by Isla Tetra and Isla Tetra 2&amp;rsquo;s Will Sargent and will be published by Solway Games in Jan 2019. Reserve your copy of the first collectible 300 now. A Kickstarter campaign will follow if anyone is remotely interested in the game ;)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1032" value="Action / Dexterity" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2027" value="Storytelling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5552" value="Mechanism: Finger Flicking Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="35640" value="Will Sargent" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="35640" value="Will Sargent" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="11675" value="Solway Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="1" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>