<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="146075">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="I am Providence" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>I am Providence&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1-4 players &amp;#10;Worker placement&amp;#10;Variable player powers (advanced version)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I am Providence, sets the players in Arkham. Mass and its surrounding areas.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will place their workers at different locations to gain types of resources that will help fight the terrors that will visit Arkham.  You'll collect lore, arcana,  and research resources, in addition to gaining the trust of cultists who will help usher in some of the more advanced terrors to Arkham. You must know your enemy and their plans if you wish to defeat them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game will have a built in time mechanic that will unleash unspeakable terrors on the town unless the players choose to confront it first.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The eldritch deck will contain 3 levels of terror which will visit the town.  Each time the game is played the deck will vary, as a certain number of cards is added to each of the three levels, changing with the number of players. &amp;#10;Example. There are 18 level 1 terrors, in a typical game there will be only 6 in the level 1 deck. When setting up the game players will randomly choose 6 terrors and shuffle them.  Ensuring that you'll always have a fresh, exciting game as you never know what horrors may come to town.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Battling an ancient evil one won't always be easy, but will undoubtably increase in difficulty as the game progresses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When battle commences, a player will flip the top of the eldritch deck and have to have the corresponding resources to defeat the terror. &amp;#10;Defeating the terrors that confront Arkham will earn you valuable Elder signs (victory points) as well as possibly gaining additional resources.  Encountering these ancient terrible entities won't be easy on your psyche though, defeating or even just encountering these awful creatures can affect your sanity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Collect too many insanity cubes and one of your workers will be eliminated from the game and have to check in to Arkham Asylum.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game progresses through all three levels of the Eldritch deck, culminating with a final battle with an Elder god.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a player defeats the final Elder God in the deck the game ends and Arkham is temporarily safe.  The player who has gained the most Elder Signs will claim victory.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the advanced game, players will become famous personalities from the Lovecraft Mythos, gaining benefits and even possibly penalties based on the chosen characters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I am Providence will be deeply rooted in the Lovecraft Mythos, never straying from the original source material. Many authors have continued the work of HP Lovecraft, expanding his Mythos and building a world of terror. We will focus solely on his writing and works for the base game.  (Though who knows of we'll see a return to Arkham in expansions).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Artistically, I am Providence will capture the theme and essence of the late 60's and early 70's American International Pictures movie one sheets.  The goal is to present I am Providence as a lost movie title in their series of films that were based on the works of Poe, though their films &amp;quot;The Dunwhich  Horror', 'The Haunted Palace'  and 'Die, Monster, Die' borrowed heavy from Lovecraft.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5141" value="Theme: Cthulhu Mythos" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>