<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="149067">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XHhzGvoQdQEGaakluRqw8w__thumb/img/aCbTfAJjYl6YHfApqpcarUAU-wk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1826695.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XHhzGvoQdQEGaakluRqw8w__original/img/pwZG_iRxvnloElWv4BCmfhvIpJg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1826695.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Centerpiece" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Centrepiece" />
			
						               													<description>Centerpiece is a roll-and-move game primarily for 2 players, or 4 players in teams. It's described by the designer as &amp;quot;super-charged Monopoly,&amp;quot; but it's most similar to Mario Party without the mini-games. The game board is printed on map paper, which allows it to fit inside the small box. After unfolding the board, the colorful box top becomes the &amp;quot;centerpiece&amp;quot; of the game board. Players take turns rolling two dice off of the box top; at least one die must end up on the game board itself, and neither can roll farther than the board's border, or the roll is invalid. They then move the sum of their roll. Every space has special effect that triggers either when landed on or when leaving the space. The goal of the game is to collect feathers, represented by paper money, in order to buy puzzle pieces. Puzzle pieces can be purchased when the player lands on two of the corner spaces, and passing the Start Together space generates an income of 25 feathers. Feathers can also be gained and lost in various ways.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aside from rolling off the box top, the main distinguishing feature of the game is that each player's pawn is represented by a pair of stacked poker chips. When landing on the Banana Split garden space, the poker chips are split up, and are subsequently treated as separate pawns. If they ever occupy the same space, other than the Banana Split space, they are recombined. Split pieces give more options when moving, and some spaces reward the player for having their chips either combined or separated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As in Monopoly, rolling doubles allows the player to move again, and rolling snake eyes sends the other player's chips to the Bird Cage (identical to Monopoly's Jail space).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Description from Kickstarter:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Super-charged Monopoly. Dice fall off box, the game travels in. White and black poker-chips get pulled apart and put together.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To play simply learn to drop the dice off the box, and keep them on the game-board.   The very first corner space states, Divide Your Game Parts.  What made that work, are five No/Rest circles added to select spaces.  They take away the choice, of which game-piece to move.  Before I adding those circles, catch-22's would happen.   A different space states, Exchange Your Bank of Feathers.  It allows a player to come from behind at anytime.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The inside of the box works great as a game-bank.   Each time around the board Eagle, Duck and Seagull feathers are rewarded.   The goal of CENTERPIECE, becomes a RACE to purchase nine-puzzle-spaces one at a time.  Have a bank of two-hundred feathers, have game-parts together.  Then land on the Start Sun space, or Bidgecage space to WIN.  Players keep score, with black and white pawns, under the box, at the games center.   Who's best at finding the best price for a numbered puzzle-space, while staying out of the Birdcage corner space.  For example to Rent A Horse, to get to the Half-Price space, or not.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All together there are twenty-eight game spaces.  One last example of a game-space states.  Roll Doubles While Here, and spend three-turns at the Birdcage corner. Your game pieces, if divided, would be joined again.  Rolling doubles while in the Birdcage, lets a player leave early.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Because the game-board paper was designed for new maps, it folds forever.  ( It was the most expensive part of the game.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CENTERPIECE = fast-paced FUN!!!  Tested on family and friends.   People will ask what's the fun all about?   Copy-righted in 1992, a ten-year renewal was also completed.  Old-school face-to-face battle with new IMPROVED format.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1991" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1032" value="Action / Dexterity" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="71049" value="Daniel S Muehlmeier" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="71688" value="Lee Mothes" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="26177" value="Warm Wax" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>