<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="149108">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pqmEDOrgC8xncyfRfaqOZQ__thumb/img/UbaYdRGz7HXX28Dwqd8OO9tBfl8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1972549.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pqmEDOrgC8xncyfRfaqOZQ__original/img/9fv1Z_IdrCwjUQ5cjm-Mqrs5Q74=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1972549.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Sulphur" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the company website:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played out between forces composed of several vehicles and infantry squads per side. Each vehicle has a number of design options regarding which weapons are selected, engine size and various offensive and defensive accoutrements such as extra armour, targeting devises, smoke dischargers etc. This means that players can create very different vehicles from the same chassis. &amp;#10;With the infantry we have divided them into a number of categories such as Light Infantry, Assault Infantry, Warriors and Heavy Weapons. Each category has a defined profile, a set of stats, weapons and armour that help it conform to their definition. This means that each type of squad has a particular function on the battlefield.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Light troops for instance move fast across the battlefield are good at scouting out the enemies dispositions and also getting out of trouble fast. Assault troops are designed to get in close with the enemy - they have the armour and firepower to take the fight to their opponents. The Warriors role is obviously to make contact with the enemy and destroy them in deadly hand-to-hand fighting. And Heavy Weapons teams are designed to hang back a bit and support forward units with heavy long-range fire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will therefore need to learn how to use their troops to their best advantage as well as how to combine them with other squads in their force for maximum efficiency and effect. For instance, using light troops to identify targets, using heavy weapons to weaken and suppress the target and then sending in the warriors to finish them off at close quarters. Sounds easy? Not so in practise! What this simply means that it is not just a case of the dude with the biggest gun winning the day (although the game does have plenty of big guns!). The right troops have to be used at the right time in the right way.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game also includes a number of leader types. These are heroes with certain special skills that will boost the performance of the force. Some of these figures might be just great individual fighters, others may have leadership skills that can enhance the power of the rest of the force.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;What is very apparent to players is the amount of choice that they have in creating their force, from vehicle design to infantry squad selection and leader choice. A different army can be assembled for every game. &amp;#10;Most battles will be fought over very challenging terrain. All manner of risks and rewards can be found - from hidden obstacles, explosive and flammable materials but also extra ammunition and weapons. The terrain always plays its part in games of Sulphur.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Another vital component to the game is the use of Asset Cards. These are played and collected during the game to further enhance the performance of a force. Each card is specific to a certain troop type (for example light squad, leader, vehicle etc). Each card will award the player a special skill or piece of equipment that will benefit that squad (and hopefully encourage the player to use the squad to its maximum advantage). These Asset Cards can have great significance in the game and add to the players burden of command and decision making - but they are a lot of fun too, especially when they thwart the plans of your opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;And from time to time there are the deadly and unpredictable incursions of Sulphur. The deadly field of  battle is made even more challenging by this unholy threat. Will the combatants form a temporary truce and turn their guns on this new and devastating threat or will they abandon their opponents, withdraw from the field and let them face the terror alone? The menace of Sulphur hangs over every battlefield like a cloud. Most times it does not appear - but the fear and unease that it generates is ever present&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="59609" value="Misc: Free Wargames" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="41799" value="Theme: Post-Apocalyptic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="305133" value="Running Hot!: A Sulphur Scenario" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="305134" value="Sulphur Campaign" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="8783" value="Stephen Danes" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44827" value="AB One Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="26023" value="Terragnosis" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>