<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="149417">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/GrRIv8xaY9-4l4ur7-wNCg__thumb/img/KngQQduUcTA3pzLSro4KdHEhAS4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1805816.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/GrRIv8xaY9-4l4ur7-wNCg__original/img/rUAcMua6oXbrr_5KVKn73rPRIjw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1805816.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="IPA: The Agents" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Important information/hints.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Having seen a clear difference in ratings between people who have had the game displayed to them and people who have not. We have put together a little information that might help giving players a better experience with the game. &amp;#10;Hopefully, this will help improving the enjoyment of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The most essential part of the game is the Space Shop. It must be used or the game will become boring and you are left with a feel of just chasing one another without any tactical considerations. The Space Shop adds strategic/tactical depth to the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is about making tough decisions figuring out when it will pay off to sell cards and thus earning credits for purchases. When and where you place field equipment is of the utmost importance. Failing at placing your field equipment the right place can cost you the game. Like in chess you must carefully consider your next moves and in accordance to your plan, buy and place field equipment. Credits are not easy to come by, so be sure not to buy field equipment without having carefully planned out a strategy on how to use the field equipment. &amp;#10;Do not expect to keep a favorite weapon throughout the whole game (although it is possible). At a certain point you may have to give it up&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Here are a few hints:&amp;#10;Gravitational Enforcers are among other things used for preventing a melee-heavy agents from catching up to you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Space Tunnels are used to travel vast distances and thus ensuring that enemy agents will not get too far away from you. Keeping them within your reach.&amp;#10; Sentries are very useful to the agents as they give you more fire power. Placed correctly you can cut off fleeing agents or blow down walls  that enemy agents may use as a defensive barrier trying to buy a little time. But placing sentries randomly is just a waste of credits/cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Melee weapons. If you are not a really experienced player, you should not only go for strength and melee weapons. As a beginner you should go for precision and intellect and later in the game , you could attempt using the melee weapons as a support weapon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game. &amp;#10;IPA - The Agents is a tactical strategy game that takes place in a near future. You take on the roll as one of the agents of &amp;quot;the agency&amp;quot;, who fight other agents in an attempt to find rare objects to his/her employer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Among many other things the game includes 200 playing cards of which 145 are distinctly different.  These cards are both used as items for in-game fights and they are also used as the currency of the game. The currency can be spend on buying equipment that is placed physically on the gameboard or for buying temporary boosts for your agent.  All cards are valuable in one way or another and you must wisely choose how to use them. This gives an economic aspect to the game as the number of cards at your disposal is limited. &amp;#10; There are small roleplaying elements in the game that make sure that you cannot use an especially powerful  card early in the game. This mechanic is made to reduce the agony of an unbalanced game.  &amp;#10;To strengthen the replay value of the game, the obstacles (walls) of the game are placed on the gameboard before the game starts. This is incorporated into the beginning of the game as a strategic element which ensures that the gameboard looks different every time you play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are alternative rules that among other things varies the luck factor of the game. Gamers have different needs when it comes to the luck factor. Now they have the opportunity to adjust the luck factor so it meets with their needs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;We have experimented with a new kind of artform. Every picture is a uniquely hand painted painting made by a Danish artist.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are many tutorials on our website and we try to make tutorials on request from our fans, if we find a need for it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game may look complex, but most players get into the mechanics/dynamics quickly. When we attended the boardgame fair at Essen 2013, we saw that most players had understood and gotten into the mechanics after only 5-6 turns into the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;We are in the Beta phase of a new game mode called &amp;quot;Vampiric Elite&amp;quot;, which &amp;quot;kills&amp;quot; the player-elimination&amp;quot; part of the game. All players stay in the game until it ends, thus dealing with &amp;quot;Player Elimination&amp;quot; that some people do not like. Instead the winner is found by a unique point system that awards being a good, but somewhat aggressive, tactician. You must be able to deal the most damage possible while staying aloof of enemy attacks. The whole point system is monitored by the agents' life.&amp;#10;In this game mode it is possible for up to 8 players to participate.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Don't miss out on a tactical treat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="71167" value="Allan Beyer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="26057" value="Mougil Entertainment" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="14" />
			<average value="6.17857" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.91307" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="34" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="6" />
			<numweights value="6" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>