<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="150318">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TtUiIvUXRTSlJK1FyHGk7Q__thumb/img/FVPzWsNdmZtMshhCjUXmC-bUOy8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1962663.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TtUiIvUXRTSlJK1FyHGk7Q__original/img/iE_qJ7EDMeQnI_OcFCY0GGhH71o=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic1962663.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="Los Señores del Mal" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Lords of Evil" />
			
						               													<description>Its not easy to be a Master of Evil. The working hours suck... Finding efficient minions is a pain... and keeping your well-earned treasure safe from the hands of the so called &amp;quot;Heroes&amp;quot; ends up being a full-time job. But... this is YOUR JOB and fame in the Inner Circle of Evil is everything to you so why not show the other Masters how a demonic job is really done! Masters of Evil is a game for 1 to 6 players where each player takes the role of an Evil Master that is repelling the attack of a variety of heroes trying to gain as much reputation as possible by imprisoning the heroes when defeated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning of the game 5 hero cards are dealt to each player so 3 can be chosen. Those heroes will be attacking your Den. Each turn a Monster is Summoned and you will have to place one of your minion tokens on one of your heroes that have that monster symbol. If you complete a card by filling all the monster, traps, and spells symbols you defeat that hero and can claim it as a reward by imprisoning him/her into your dungeon cell. Some heroes provide a special reward when defeated... from adding an extra monster to getting a special Overlord ability.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After placing minions a die is rolled to determine if a type of hero attacks. To repel an attack you can remove monsters from that hero card for a value equal, bigger or lower than the hero attack (defined by the roll of 1D6). If you repel the complete attack you are undamaged. If you repel a portion you can get the rest of the damage by reducing your life (which begins with 10). Also you can simply nullify the attack of a hero by distracting them with one of your treasures. Spells can be used to change the summoned monster type and Traps can nullify any attack (even if they are not in the card of an attacking hero).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When the 6th hero is collected by any player the game is over and the scoring phase begins. Players get the points in the hero cards but also get points for the most types of each monster and if they collect at least 3 cards of a Hero Type.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;No es facil ser un Se&amp;ntilde;or del Mal. Las horas a las que hay que levantarse apestan... Encontrar sirvientes eficientes es un dolor de medula... Y conservar tu &amp;quot;bien merecido&amp;quot; tesoro de las garras de los heroes termina siendo un trabajo full-time. Pero es tu OFICIO y la fama adquirida en el circulo Interno de la Maldad lo es todo para ti... asi que porque no mostrar a los demas Se&amp;ntilde;ores como se hace un buen trabajo demoniaco! En los Se&amp;ntilde;ores del Mal los jugadores toman el rol de Se&amp;ntilde;ores Oscuros que estan repeliendo el ataque de audaces heroes aprisionandolos cuando son derrotados para asi ganar la tan preciada fama.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Al comienzo del juego se entregaran 5 cartas de heroe a cada jugador de las que seran elegidas 3. Esos heroes atacaran tu Guarida. Cada turno sera Invocado un Monstruo y tendras que colocar un token de minion en uno de los heroes que tenga en su carta a dicho monstruo disponible. Si completas todos los slots de la carta derrotas al heroe y puedes reclamar la recompensa aprisionandolo en una celda. Algunos heroes proveen recompensas especiales cuando son derrotados... desde otorgar un monstruo extra a darle al Overlord una habilidad permanente.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Luego de colocar los minions se tira un dado para determinar el tipo de heroe que atacara. Para repeler un ataque se pueden remover monstruos de la carta de dicho heroe por un valor igual, superior o inferior que el ataque del heroe (definido por un D6). Si repeles completamente el ataque no eres da&amp;ntilde;ado. Si solo se repele una porcion recibes el resto del da&amp;ntilde;o reduciendo tu vida (que comienza en 10). Tambien puedes anular un ataque entregandole uno de tus tesoros. Los hechizos pueden ser usados para invocar un monstruo diferente del que se ha invocado y las Trampas anulan cualquier ataque (incluso si no estan en la carta del heroe atacante)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cuando un jugador aprisiona a su sexto heroe el juego termina y comienza la ronda de puntaje. Los jugadores obtienen puntos por cada heroe capturado, pero tambien por mayoria de determinado tipo de monstruo y variedad de heroes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="101" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="102" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="103" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="104" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="105" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2060" value="Pattern Recognition" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="12172" value="Guillermo H. Nuñez" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="71689" value="Julieta García" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>