<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="15198">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZNmszq-10vYhrLnP59rASw__thumb/img/dn3j6f3Sspwom8cl90f5LFYInS8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic63570.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZNmszq-10vYhrLnP59rASw__original/img/caABxqstgurHwNhg2uEIRzpxAvc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic63570.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Armatac II" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the inside cover page of the books:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;The ARMATAC II system is a component system which allows the player to purchase books and playing pieces as they are needed, to recreate the battles and campaigns of World War II. The players create armies of different sizes and nationalities and must use all of the skill and knowledge of strategy they possess to defeat their opponents. Rules are provided on how to play the games, but these can be looked upon as guidelines. It will constantly be stressed that this is your system and the rules can be altered to suit your particular style of play. The games can be played as simple or complicated as you prefer. Because of the endless variety of combat situations which can be constructed, we hope players will never tire of the system.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;We offer 5 books within the system, each one covering 300 weapons. There are 2 aircraft books, 2 naval books and 1 armor book. This means a total of 1,500 weapons are covered. A total of over 1,000,000 of these weapons were produced and we provide production figures for all of them. Our playing pieces are larger than those offered by other gaming companies and are presented in a variety of shapes which look like the weapons they have been chosen to represent. Our playing pieces are available in four different 4 color camouflage patterns. A national insignia sheet is also available in full color and contains over 500 insignias from over a dozen countries. When applied to the playing pieces, these insignias combined with the size, shape and camouflage patterns provide an air of realism and excitement never before attainable at the price they are offered.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Because of the larger size of our playing pieces, it stands to reason our hexes must be larger to accommodate them. In keeping with our policy of non-restriction, a stencil is available within our system which allows the player to trace this hex pattern across any playing surface they choose. A readily available and inexpensive playing surface is poster board (22&amp;quot; x 28&amp;quot;). Two of these boards butted together make a good beginner size and three boards make a good overall size for any type of gaming activity. These boards can be left plain, or full color scenarios can be drawn on them prior to tracing the hex pattern. Even those players with limited artistic ability can create personalized scenarios with a little time and patience. Maps can be purchased of oceans, continents and individual countries. These maps are relatively inexpensive, are good size for gaming and make for an extremely attractive playing surface. County survey maps can also be acquired, as well as city and county street indexes for those who wish to engage in street fighting. A hex pattern sheet is also provided with our stencil which can be inexpensively reprinted at your local quickie printer.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;A map or scenario can also be applied to a window shade and our design traced across it. The shade can be stretched across the playing area and retained at the ends while in use. For those with a permanent playing table, shade brackets can be attached to one edge of the table and the shade snapped in. The pull tab can be retained at the opposite edge with the aid of a nail. In this way the shade will rest squarely on the table top and remain taut. A variety of shades can be prepared and used as they are needed. This should be especially appealing for clubs. Games can also be played on non-hex surfaces by simply substituting inches for hex speed, which is contained in the WARGAME CHARTS. Remember, we will recommend how the games should be played, but the final decision is up to you.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1980" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3454" value="Armageddon Design Group" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>