<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="151971">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/P-zxzoajw0ytYkqacoHtYg__thumb/img/6pBkQTf1ftMPGLT01KZiQqZ7svI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2051265.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/P-zxzoajw0ytYkqacoHtYg__original/img/NJ2hwpuGU7bonWln-6ig85gt95g=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2051265.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Low Blow" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Object&amp;#10;To have the lowest score at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components&amp;#10;A 5x4 board whose four rows, are in four colors&amp;#10;20 - d6 dice, 5 dice each that match their color row&amp;#10;30 communal counters of any color, 25 if playing a 3 player game&amp;#10;A pot to hold the counters and some way of keeping score&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup&amp;#10;Place the empty board between the players.&amp;#10;Place the pot with the 25 to 30 counters nearby so all the players can reach them.&amp;#10;Players decide what color home row belongs to them.&amp;#10;Players get 5 dice each in their color home row.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play&amp;#10;Play, as many rounds as there are players.&amp;#10;A turn moves clockwise and the youngest player rolls first. In subsequent rounds rotate the start player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On your turn, you will do one of these things;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(A) Pass if you have no dice.&amp;#10;(B) Roll one of your dice of any color you choose, the number and color of dice in your possession may change during the course of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then you must choose ONE of the following actions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(1) Place the die on any open square on the board. If there are any counters in the Pot, take up to the value of the die you just placed. If the Pot's contents are insufficient, you take all the counters available and your turn ends. If the Pot is empty, you choose either the player to your left OR right, and take counters from her/him UP TO the value of the die just placed but ONLY IF THAT PLAYER HAS 1 OR MORE DICE. If the chosen player has fewer counters than the die's value, take all their counters and your turn ends. Do not take counters from a 'dice-less' player or&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(2) If the Pot is empty (if not, you must do action 1 above), you may force a trade with either the player to the left or right of you. Give this player the die you just rolled even if he had no dice before receiving yours, you then take counters from this player UP TO the value of the die just rolled MINUS 1. A die showing 4 pips gets you 3 counters, a die showing 5 would get you 4 counters. If you give him a 1, you receive no counters. If the player has insufficient counters to meet the value required, you take all of his counters. You may also give/force the die to the player if he has no counters. Your turn now ends.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Remember you are not out of the game if you are out of dice or counters. Dice may be traded or given to you and counters may be taken from you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when all rounds have been played and scored.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring&amp;#10;At the end of each round add up each player's dice in their home row individually ignoring dice color. Then subtract 1 point for each die residing and matching a player's home row.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Track each players scores after each round and then tally the rounds at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Only after the end of the last round do you subtract the counters in your possession from each player's round totals; these are now the final scores for each player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a draw occurs, play another round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the lowest score is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="25" />
						               				<minplaytime value="25" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="25" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="78590" value="Components: 4 x 5 Grids" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="62677" value="Rey Alicea" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="62677" value="Rey Alicea" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.25" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.75" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>