<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="152028">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/5pRY7IiSGUE3L-AdFh2eIA__thumb/img/pnOWJJSdEaCCO3l8f299XAYeZuw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2244357.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/5pRY7IiSGUE3L-AdFh2eIA__original/img/HXDLtyZyvcxQeCFo8lR3bxYuQkY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2244357.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="War Fighters" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>War Fighters is a unique, 2 player (3 player if you want to), traditional card game that incorporates aspects from 4 different card games, in a lightning-fast paced game. Players have 5 different game play styles to choose from and can play with different amounts of cards, in a half deck, full deck, or custom deck format. This is an &amp;ldquo;E-Rated&amp;rdquo; card game, sure to get your family involved, and easy enough for anyone to enjoy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 10 decks to choose from: Ninja, Pirates, Aliens, Robots, Monsters, Undead, Ghosts, Vampires, Werewolves, and Zombies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is designed to bridge the gap between games for really young children such as: &amp;quot;Uno,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Crazy 8's,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Old Maid,&amp;quot;  and games for older children such as:  &amp;quot;Magic the Gathering,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pokemon,&amp;quot; etc.  It is designed to be an easy to pick up and play card game for children ages 6+, families, and casual players.  There are multiple ways to play the game, multiple decks to build, and players can even make up rules once they get comfortable with the gameplay. The trading card and custom deck options are just that...options, and are not required to play the game, unless you want to, and that is always welcomed!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;War Fighters can be played by anyone, of any age, at any time, in multiple ways, without having to spend hours on rules getting confusing.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Basic Game Play (#1):&amp;#10;-Divide one deck in half evenly and give each half to a player.&amp;#10;-Each player will receive:  5 square fighters (Paper), 5 circle fighters (Rock), 5 ex fighters (Scissors), 4 attacks, 2 blocks, 2 truces, and 2 star leader fighter cards for a total of 25 cards in the basic version of the game.&amp;#10;-Each player shuffles their half decks&amp;#10;-Each player puts their decks to the left as their &amp;quot;draw pile.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;-Each player draws 5 cards.&amp;#10;-At the same time, each player plays a fighter card in the play area between them.  A fighter card will have a symbol of a circle, square, ex, or star on it.&amp;#10;-To determine who wins, Square beats Circle, Circle beats Ex, Ex beats Square, Star beats all.&amp;#10;-If both players play the same cards (ex:  circle vs. circle) then &amp;quot;war&amp;quot; is initiated and each player draws 3 cards from the draw pile and places it face down into the play area, and then plays another fighter card for the win. War continues until someone wins.  Each time the same cards are played, war is initiated again.&amp;#10;-The winner of each round gets all the cards in the play area and puts them into their &amp;quot;discard pile&amp;quot; to their right.&amp;#10;-When the cards in the play area are the same, players must draw the 3 cards and lay them face down followed by another fighter card.  However, when the cards are different (ex:  circle vs. square) a player can then decide if they want to use an &amp;quot;attack&amp;quot; card, &amp;quot;block&amp;quot; card, or a &amp;quot;truce&amp;quot; card.&amp;#10;-An &amp;quot;attack&amp;quot; card is basically a &amp;quot;+1&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;one up&amp;quot; to the other player for the win.&amp;#10;-A &amp;quot;truce&amp;quot; card means you do not want to fight anymore and want your card back, so both players get their cards back.&amp;#10;-A player can choose to &amp;quot;block&amp;quot; an &amp;quot;attack&amp;quot; card as a defense to try and win the round.  A &amp;quot;truce&amp;quot; card cannot be blocked in the basic version of the game.&amp;#10;-After each round, each player draws back up to 5 cards for the next round.&amp;#10;-Each player can use their full hand in each round as needed, but can only use one fighter card during a round, unless  &amp;quot;war&amp;quot; has been initiated and the three face down cards need to be drawn.&amp;#10;-It takes one attack and one circle to beat a square, one attack and one square to beat an ex, and one attack and an ex to beat a  circle card.&amp;#10;-If a star card is thrown, it takes two unblocked attacks plus any fighter card (square, circle, ex) to beat the star card&amp;#10;-The objective of the game, or how to win, is to collect all the leader cards from the other player.&amp;#10;-On a 5 card hand, if a player does not have any fighter cards, they must show the other player their hand to prove they are not cheating, hand over one of their cards, shuffle all their cards, and draw a new 5 card hand.&amp;#10;-During war, if a player does not have a fighter card to finish the round, that player must count the number of cards in their hand, shuffle all their cards, and draw another hand with that number of cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play #2 - (War Strategies):&amp;#10;-During this game style, players can choose to use attack, defense, and truce cards in order raise the stakes before going to war and/or to cancel out the war.  So, when players use the same cards (Ex:  circle vs. circle), the attack, block, and truce cards can now be played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play #3 - (Aggressive Vs. Defensive):&amp;#10;-In this style of play, one person gets all the attack cards to start with, while the other gets all the blocks and truce cards.&amp;#10;-As an additional rule, one of the players can get the &amp;quot;power&amp;quot; card as well.&amp;#10;-The &amp;quot;power&amp;quot; card acts as 2 attack cards.  When used as an attack card, if a player wins the round, the other player's fighter card is taken out of the game until it is over, making the game go even faster.  Star Leader cards cannot be taken out of the game since they are needed in order to win the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play #4 - (Power Cards):&amp;#10;-In this mode, the loser of the previous round gets to use the power card to help &amp;quot;even the odds.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;-One power card comes in each box.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play #5 - (Custom Deck Options):&amp;#10;-In this option, players can play half decks, full decks, or customs decks, and build their own decks to battle with.&amp;#10;-Players can choose if the cards are deck specific as well.  For example, if one person uses ninjas and the other uses pirates, the you can assume that pirates do not know how to throw ninja attack darts or stricken, and therefore the cards are no good to pirates and only the ninja cards the player acquires can use those attacks.  This option is a bit advanced so most players who play this tend to put the other players fighter cards to the side and use the attacks, blocks, truce, and power cards in a non-deck specific mode.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Extra Game Information:&amp;#10;-This game is very open so players who are comfortable with the rules tend to master it and then make up their own rules for added fun.&amp;#10;-All decks play the same, but have different artwork to cater to everyones passions.&amp;#10;-This game can also be used to play &amp;quot;matching games,&amp;quot; where you lay cards face down and try to pair them up.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="3" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="5" />
						               				<minplaytime value="5" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="5" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1044" value="Collectible Components" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1090" value="Pirates" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2481" value="Zombies" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2003" value="Rock-Paper-Scissors" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="72329" value="Doug Oberndorf" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="26374" value="Tropic Mods Development" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>