<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="152552">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/C7FNhYwGjrYYyzNElUrgqA__thumb/img/X7HQ5AZyeF1GsK1GL9KcIO4dQOw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1900693.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/C7FNhYwGjrYYyzNElUrgqA__original/img/qDImvoqGuolufBQ7C4fLiQWlqK0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1900693.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The New Electronic Perfect Match Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>FROM THE BOX:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Haven't you always wondered who your perfect match is? The New Perfect Match Game is the fun way to find out. The game is played by couples who are asked a series of questions with four alternative answers supplied. These questions cover topics ranging from sex to politics and the arts. Each partner decides on their favourite response and uses the electronic Perfect Match device to check their compatibility and advance along the board. the first couple to reach the Perfect Match Heart Light are the winners. Who will be your Perfect Match?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Contents:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2 Electronic Perfect Match Devices.&amp;#10;288 Question Cards.&amp;#10;1 Die.&amp;#10;4 Position Markers.&amp;#10;Perfect Match Game Board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The players are divided into couples. Each couple takes a position marker and places it in the start square. Remove the perfect match cards from their perforations and place them in their marked positions on the game board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Perfect Match Cards:&amp;#10;These cards are divided into two categories: pink 'Girls' cards and blue 'Guys' cards. As the game proceeds, question cards are taken from the 'Girls' pile if the playing couple lands on a pink square or From the 'Guys' pile if they land on a blue square. Each card contains one questions with four alternative&amp;#10;answers marked A,B,C or D.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Choosing the right answer:&amp;#10;If the couple lands on a blue square, one of the other players picks up a 'Guys' card and directs one question on it to the male partner. He must choose the alternative which he feels is most appropriate to him. His partner must try to anticipate his feelings or attitudes on that question and choose the same alternative. Couples should be open and honest in their choice of answer. Similarly, if the couple lands on a pink square, a 'Girls' card would be taken and its question directed towards the female partner. She will choose and answer and her partner should try to anticipate this response.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Questions marked 'BOTH' are  designed to test compatibility, with each partner choosing their own favourite answer in response to the question asked.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Using the Electronic Perfect Match device:&amp;#10;These devices are in the shape of four hearts joined together. Each heart is labeled A,B,C or D, representing the four alternatives on the Perfect Match question cards. When a question is asked and each partner has silently decided on which alternative to choose, they each hold up their device with the chosen representative letter uppermost. They must not allow each other to see their choices. The two devices are then pressed together. If the electronic tone sounds, a perfect match has been achieved for that question.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dare Cards:&amp;#10;Scattered throughout both packs of cards are Dare Cards. If one these cards appears, the couple must perform whatever is required of them according to the instructions on the card. Their performance is adequate (as indicated by a show of hands) then the couple may roll the die again and continue their turn. Be warned - if you are too easy on others then there is no challenge to perform well. If you are too tough, then your opponent will be equally tough on you. So be fair!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing the game: Each couple rolls the die once and those with the highest score start, moving their marker the corresponding number of squares. One of the other players then reads the first question to the starting couple. If the couple achieves a Perfect Match, they roll the die again and advance the corresponding number of squares along the board. Remember, a couple can only roll the die and advance after  they have successfully answered a Perfect Match question or performed a Dare task. The couple continues in this way until they are unsuccessful in either a Perfect Match question or a Dare performance, in which case the control of the game is handed over to the next couple (moving clockwise).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning the Game:&amp;#10;The first couple to reach the Perfect Match Heart Light and then successfully achieve a Perfect Match from their Choice of either a Girls or Guys question will be declared the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    Special Note&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Should the electronic tone stop working use a nail file or a similar tool to lever apart the two case sections of the blue device. Carefully removed the battery, replacing it with one of identical type. Be sure to position it positive side up. When pressing the case sections back together, locate the letter &amp;quot;A&amp;quot; on the plastic cover over the battery position.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Based on the formerly popular 1980s Network Ten (and much later Seven Network in 2002) Australian TV dating game show of the same name.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1986" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="18" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="36" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="37" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="38" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="39" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="40" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1072" value="Electronic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="6862" value="Jnh Toys" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>