<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="153788">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/K19brauP19Rx_InsXVVaGA__thumb/img/dFW4Mob8ZRWYE7uRickqYkFK1xY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1905128.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/K19brauP19Rx_InsXVVaGA__original/img/8OURUPxyM3eyffOcghcYDeIO4J4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1905128.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Стань супер-злодеем" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Have you ever dreamt of becoming the Supervillain? Well, it's easier than it seems. All you need is a personal planet, several billions of faithful yet simple-minded minions (preferably small-sized and green-skinned) and a dozen of cunning plans. Or two dozens for your own piece of mind. Who are your archrivals? No superheroes I assure you as they are just mythic figures from graphic novels. So, you should beware your competitors, other villains who are eager to add the prefix super to their proud title.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Today becoming the Supervillain is even simpler than ever! A new boardgame by Right Games and Anton Lozovskiy provides you with everything you need for this fascinating activity. But for opponents &amp;mdash; I assume every self-respecting villain must have some.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Become Supervillain is a boardgame for two&amp;mdash;five players aged 12+. While competing for the title of the principal anti-hero, players spend their minions to complete secret projects, spin vicious intrigues and shatter opponents' plans with meteorites. You must be first to collect secret projects valued 5,000 points to win the game. Besides, the game can end earlier if all plan cards have been drawn. Then a player with overall maximum points becomes the Supervillain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There're two types of cards: plans (they are also secret projects and meteorites) and intrigues (they are also minions). Before the game starts, cards are shuffled into two separate decks and each player draws two intrigues. At turn's start, the active player draws a card from each deck, puts the intrigue in his/her hand and decides what to do with the plan card either by playing it face-up as a plan or face-down as a meteorite. To complete plans you need minions: as soon as the total value of minions on one of your plans become equal or exceed its cost, it becomes the secret project and yields victory points. Often it also gives you special abilities. If you don't want to handle some plan, you may turn it into a meteorite and send at somebody as a valuable gift. Then the card is put face-down with the arrow pointing at your victim. The latter has time before your next turn to deal with the flying meteorite (some intrigues allow shooting them down or even redirecting them). If your meteorite has successfully hit the victim, you draw an extra card from the deck and &amp;mdash; the most important &amp;mdash; destroy a minion on any of his/her plans.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Intrigue cards can also be played in two ways. First &amp;mdash; as an intrigue itself, in accordance with its text. Their effects are versatile and cunning as true villain's thoughts: take cards from opponents, charge meteorites, protect yourself, accelerate plans, etc. Second &amp;mdash; as a minion, by placing it on your plan (its value is indicated in the upper part of the card). During your turn you may play only one intrigue and one minion or just keep them for some better time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Become Supervillain is a speedy and funny parody boardgame with simple rules and lively gameplay. It learns not only to be cunning and vicious but also to shatter other villains' plans. Finally, if our world has to face the Supervillain, let it be you and not some thorough scoundrel.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2013" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="223573" value="Supervillain: This Galaxy Is Mine!" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="50730" value="Anton Lozovskiy" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="17748" value="Rightgames RBG SIA" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="8" />
			<average value="6.375" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.695971" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>