<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="159240">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XIx5zFX8nLS7uapSf6sDFA__thumb/img/WN4OQlpF2uF48vfLDPq_bAPpUSI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2020701.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XIx5zFX8nLS7uapSf6sDFA__original/img/hqlGlqsrhFdVBB0G3mo4wGGtZoQ=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2020701.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Business Mogul" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In Business Mogul you play as the leader of a rising corporate empire, competing with your peers to amass the most power. Game play is centered around building an economic engine, and uses a bidding mechanic where players must balance bids to get the good stuff and to avoid the bad against the actions needed to build their empire, while saving high bids as much as possible to convert to cash at the end of each season.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game has a fixed number of turns - six seasons of five rounds each - and total play time tends to be about 2-2.5 hours for 4 people (the game is designed for 3-5, with a solid 2-player variant), on par with a feature movie. In every round there is one card per player up for grabs - every player gets a card every round. The cards on which players bid are businesses that are used to build up your economic engine, extra actions to be saved until needed most (and they let a player do some things outside the normal rules of play), special agenda cards that give score a bonus at the end of the game (how much depends on how well the conditions for the given card are fulfilled), and bad events (which are to be avoided if possible).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players are bidding pick order rather than on a particular item. Each players uses a set nine of bidding cards (getting them all back at the start of each season), which represent how the player is dividing their attention that round between trying to get the best of the available items and getting other stuff done. Each bid has a specific action that it allows (lower bids have more powerful actions), and bids saved for the end of the season are worth extra money - the higher the bid the more it&amp;rsquo;s worth. These additional aspects associated with each bid, the action and the end-of-season cash value, make for exciting, meaningful choices every round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Business Mogul supports multiple valid strategies, though the highest final score usually goes to the player that dabbles in additional strategies beyond their primary one. The key to winning is being tactically smart about balancing pick order vs action vs end-of-season-payout, paying attention to the state of other player&amp;rsquo;s empires and the bids they've already used in the current season, and executing a strategy that adapts to the flow of items up for bid.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are some fairly common game mechanics/attributes that Mogul specifically does not have:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- It has no player-to-player aggression - the bidding each round is the only point of direct competition. &amp;#10;- It does not have random action outcomes (that is whether or not a given action succeeds is not determined by dice, card draw, or anything like that). &amp;#10;- It does not have any kind of territory control. &amp;#10;- It has no resources / production beyond money and end-game score.&amp;#10;- It does not require memorization of what&amp;rsquo;s been played; aside from a single hidden card each player gets at the start and the particular bid a player is making in a given round, the state of the game is fully revealed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22185" value="Admin: Cancelled Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="75321" value="Chris Warren" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="27289" value="Purple Valley Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>