<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="159472">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/BdhrOsrbr0c-R8tOaUr_wQ__thumb/img/Y1NeB2kFcadRgqDINrGnCGNyNsc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2022055.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/BdhrOsrbr0c-R8tOaUr_wQ__original/img/RL6LqRLaRa2TxdV1L3ZmWFmFYEE=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2022055.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="RPG Merchant Tycoon!!" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In RPG Merchant Tycoon!!, players take the roles of optimistic start up entrepreneurs, looking to set up shops in the bustling villages, towns or cities spread throughout the world of your typical 8-bit RPG game. However, these said villages, towns and cities aren't big enough for the 2 (to 4) of yas'! So it's time to get busy and dirty, trading and searching for loot to fulfill the growing line of adventurers looking for some gear! Expand your shop, spend your Gold stock (or hoard it!) wisely, trade with other rival shops, keep secret Stock all to yourself, call in favors from your happy Clients.....do whatever it takes to clinch market Dominance and be the only show in town and start reeling in the BIG money! Who knows, maybe that Flaming Sword of Justice you just sold will be used by the Hero that will save the world?!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPGMT!! is a 30-60min 2-4 Player high strategy card game in which the player's goal is to finish the game with the best balance between: The amount of Client's orders they were able to fulfill; the amount of Gold they personally have by the end; and the total quality's worth of items in their Display.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn Players can take up to 2 &amp;quot;Actions&amp;quot; (unless they get extra Actions thanks to fulfilling certain Client orders) in their attempt to fulfill Client orders for certain weaponry or item...ry. These Actions let the Players manipulate their Stock items (or Hand cards) and/or their Display items (cards face up in front of a Player for everyone to see/trade) in specific ways to try and beat the rush to fulfill those orders! Ran out of Actions for your turn, but you're only ONE Action away from fulfilling that order?! No Worries!! There are &amp;quot;Gold Actions&amp;quot; that you can use in a pinch, which let you spend Gold to do certain Actions that DON'T count towards your Action limit for your turn....WOOHOO!! After all the Clients have been fulfilled, the game ends and Players then move on to calculating &amp;quot;Dominance&amp;quot;, which will determine who the TRUE Merchant Tycoon is!!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The strategic decisions and stiff competition in RPGMT!! really heat up quick due to the fact that Players start out with only a limited number of Actions per turn AND a limited number of cards they can have, so EVERY decision counts! Everything from in what order you'd like to take your Actions, which Client you should fulfill, and should you or shouldn't you use Gold are crucial to Dominance. You might spend all your Action efforts to build up enough items to fulfill an order for a specific Client, but then the Player before you fulfills them leaving you at a disadvantage with items that you might not need now!! Remember, it's not just playing the current Client market, it's also knowing and playing to the weaknesses of your fellow Players!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="56" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="57" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="58" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="59" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="60" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="75112" value="Ryan Cowler" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="2456" value="The Game Crafter, LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="7.6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.23288" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>