<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="161502">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JQcLBvhghaIiLddi0q1i2Q__thumb/img/HeyS8xdx_tl-lNvVO9SGemKEbwI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2062896.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JQcLBvhghaIiLddi0q1i2Q__original/img/msu2KNhzMsJynWxAbCpJ0NytqbE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2062896.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Let&#039;s Go to College" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Let's Go To College game employs a gambling technique, with chips, to allow players to complete courses as a freshman, a sophomore, a junior, and a senior. Prentice employed illustrators to produce bright graphics in his games and utilized high quality materials as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the rules:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SETTING UP THE GAME. The playing board with the colored chart is placed in the center of the table. The playing cards are lined up with the four packs of picture cards, face up, on one side of the playing board. They should be in this order: Freshman, Sophomore, Junior and Senior. On the other side of the board the four packs of Fun, Sports, Re-Exam and Flunk cards should be placed with these words up. The chips are divided among the players so that each has an equal amount of l's, 2's, 3's, 5's and 10's.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PLAYING THE GAME. The player on the left of the host plays first As a Freshman entering I. O. U., he stands up each time he plays. If he fails to remember this, he must draw a Flunk card as a penalty, altnougn he does not miss his turn. He pays 5 chips, registration fee, to the business office. He then rolls the dice on the playing board as he tries to pass his first course. Only the dice which remain on the board alter rolling , may be counted, using only the top numbers. He multiplies the dice total by ten to find his grade for the course. After rolling the dice, the player proceeds all follows: If, after multiplying, his grade comes to 120: he must pay 2 chips to petty expense, on the playing board, placing the chips so they do not interfere with the chart. If his grade is 110, he must pay 1 chip. This means he has tried too hard to pass. In either case he rolls the dice again, right away. If his grade is 100, 90, 80 or 70, he can draw the top Freshman Course card and keep it. He also must take or put chips into petty expense as indicated opposite his grade on the chart. If there are not enough chips to take, he is out of luck, and can take only what is there. This happens quite frequently throughout the game. If his grade is 60, 50 or 40, he must place on playing board the indicated number of &amp;quot;put&amp;quot; chips. He then has his choice of drawing a Fun, Sport or Re-Exam card. He must read his card aloud and after fulfilling the duties, he returns it to the bottom of the same pack. &amp;#10;If his grade is 30, 20 or 10, he must place on playing board the indicated number of &amp;quot;put&amp;quot; chips. He then has to take a Flunk card and follow its instructions before returning it to bottom of pack. If both dice roll off the playing board he receives a zero, and must place 15 chips on the board and draw a Flunk card. As soon as a player has completed his turn, the next player on his left rolls the dice to obtain his grade for his first Freshman course, and so on. To pass Freshman year and become a Sophomore, a player must hold two Freshman Course cards. The first to finish Freshman year receives all chips in Petty Expense. As soon as each player finishes his first year he must pay 5 chips, registration fee for Sophomore year, to the business office. Sophomore year is the same as Freshman year, only players may now be seated while playing. Sophomores must have two Soph Course cards before becoming Juniors. The first to finish receives all chips in petty expense. As soon as players finish Sophomore year they pay 5 chips, registration fee for Junior year, to the business office. Junior year proceeds the same as Sophomore year. The first to finish receives all chips in petty expense. As soon as a player gets two Junior Course cards he must pay 5 chips, registration fee for Senior year, to the business office. Seniors must obtain the usual two Senior Course cards before graduation. The first to finish Senior year receives all chips petty expense and IMMEDIATELY the game is ended.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1944" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="2866" value="Electric Game Co." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>