<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="164463">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7n_2KqKCLQHev5-5gH0nmQ__thumb/img/RZLV6yP5Id5sJULYd_euqMpexWc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2214182.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7n_2KqKCLQHev5-5gH0nmQ__original/img/y2429B8rx7xAjBLYs19IQ2SNbQA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2214182.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="True to Life Baseball" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>True to Life Baseball is a dice/board game that accurately simulates all the drama of a real baseball game. In extensive testing the average team runs and hits were within 3% of actual game stats. TTL Baseball comes with 6 teams from the 2011 season. Each team has 23 players printed on 3 separate 8 1/2&amp;quot; x 11&amp;quot; card stock ivory paper. The player sheets come in 3 hole punched sheet protectors that make the game easily transportable in a standard binder. (binder is not included)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game has 4 different player modes; intro, basic, advanced, and 'Ultra Simulation Mode' which consists of using the advanced version along with all optional rules. After familiarity with the rule set, average game times range from 20 minutes for intro games to 40 minutes for advanced games. USM games would take a bit longer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is for 1 to 2 players and is highly suitable for solitaire play. TTL Baseball has over 1800 hours in development. The advanced game was designed first, then to shorten average game times a simpler pitching system was designed for the basic game. Finally, the intro game is a simplified version to allow players to start playing games without knowing all the advanced rules.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Think you could have managed a team to a better season record than the actual manager did? Now you have the opportunity. Play a single series or an entire season with season player stat sheets available separately. In addition, extra player sheets are available for most seasons that add an additional 4 players to every team. This would bring each teams roster to 27 players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game features base stealing, squeeze plays, maximum pitch counts, pitch guessing, defensive depth adjustments for infield and outfield. The advanced games pitching system is perhaps the most accurate available. Optional rules limit use on how often each pitcher may be used within any 5 game period. Bullpen managements are included to keep track of pitcher use. There are also ballpark ratings that make parks either allow more or less home runs just as in reality. A rare play table accounts for almost every possible play possible in baseball. ie. triple plays, double steals, power outages, rain delays leading to arm stiffness for starting pitchers, outfielders colliding....etc.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TTLB uses a unique pitching check mechanic that uses a separate roll on 50% of key batting outcomes. This 'Pitcher Check Roll' (PCR) ensures that both hitter and pitcher attributes are taken into account. This makes both pitchers ERA's and hitters BA's as accurate as possible.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5586" value="Sports: Baseball" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="77547" value="James Formo" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="27940" value="Life is Sport Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>