<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="164469">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Y5Q4X4SVfkhh3rrWUCorLQ__thumb/img/UCDb7z5kzTp3dYo0QbUm7IeFKg4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2216444.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Y5Q4X4SVfkhh3rrWUCorLQ__original/img/fH6DipfsrD9zjrhF2NaBOZfgsC8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2216444.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Hogen No Ran" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Hogen No Ran: Hogen Gannen (1156)" />
			    				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="保元の乱：保元元年　(1156)" />
			
						               													<description>The game's full name is &amp;quot;Hogen No Ran: Hogen Gannen (1156) (&amp;#228;&amp;#191;&amp;#157;&amp;#229;&amp;#133;&amp;#131;&amp;#227;&amp;#129;&amp;#174;&amp;#228;&amp;#185;&amp;#177;&amp;#239;&amp;#188;&amp;#154;&amp;#228;&amp;#191;&amp;#157;&amp;#229;&amp;#133;&amp;#131;&amp;#229;&amp;#133;&amp;#131;&amp;#229;&amp;#185;&amp;#180;&amp;#227;&amp;#128;&amp;#128;(1156), Hogen Disturbance: First Year Of Hogen 1156)&amp;quot;. This doujinshi (self-published work) is a simulation of the 1156 battle in Heiankyo (modern day Kyoto), Japan, between feuding factions of the Fujiwara family of kuge (nobles) fighting over who would hold the position of Tenno (Emperor).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Without getting too deeply into the complex web of politics surrounding the battle, the sitting Tenno Go-Shirakawa was involved in an ongoing succession battle with his half-brother Sutoku (the retired Tenno). Sutoku had been forced out by his father Toba years earlier in favor of another son (Konoe), and when Konoe died, Sutoku saw this as his chance to install his own son as Tenno. However, Toba insisted on installing another of his sons, Go-Shirakawa. When Toba eventually died, Sutoku took advantage of his death to plot with supporters to force Go-Shirakawa from the throne. As if this doesn't sound messy enough already, Go-Shirakawa and Sutoku both had supporters among the three major families of the day-the Fujiwara, Taira, and Minamoto. Supporting Go-Shirakawa was Fujiwara no Tadamichi, Taira no Kiyomori, and Minamoto no Yoshitomo. Supporting Sutoku was Fujiwara no Yorinaga, Taira no Tadamasa, and Minamoto no Tameyoshi.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Historically the fighting took place mainly on July 28-29. Minamoto no Tametomo (a Sutoku supporter) suggested a night attack, but was unwisely overruled by Fujiwara no Yorinaga. Instead, the next evening, Minamoto no Yoshitomo and Taira no Kiyomori led a night attack of their own on Sutoku's palace. Despite being frustrated in their initial attacks on the west gate by the incredible archery prowess of Minamoto no Tametomo, Yoshitomo and Kiyomori simply broke off the attack, moved to other gates, and torched the palace, circumventing that whole messy combat thing. Sutoku was exiled and most of his allies were killed in battle or executed. On the winning side, rewards were handed out, but what was seen as an uneven distribution by the Minamoto resulted in another conflict (the Heiji no Ran) three years later.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Hogen No Ran shares its game system with its follow-up, Heiji No Ran. The game runs for 11 turns, taking the action from the tenth day of the seventh month in the first year of Hogen to the 13th day (July 28-31, 1156, two turns per day with a night turn). Forces of the various factions are individual leaders with associated clansmen, rated for both troop strength and leader ability. Chrome rules put an emphasis on the favored tactics of the day, mainly the use of fire to flush out the enemy. There are also special rules for night attacks, allowing players to see if Minamoto no Tametomo's strategy would have brought victory to Sutoku. Victory is determined by unit losses and possession of the Emperor/retired Emperor. Counter numbers are low, the game system is clean and well thought out, and it does an excellent job of simulating the battle as it was recorded in the Hogen Monogatari (a gunkimono-'war tale'-written around the year 1200).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58654" value="History: Conflicts of the Heian period – Japan" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>