<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="166396">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/SzL5RDnSdMqDdo--ENvWgQ__thumb/img/nmKKnX6moDSu_Yr5Xbgj-245P9g=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2249866.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/SzL5RDnSdMqDdo--ENvWgQ__original/img/DOJjAz_bWCRhlEI31nYj6kO9ENs=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2249866.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Road to Heaven Board Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Road to Heaven Board Game is a fun multi-sensory game created to bring families together &amp;amp; bring the Bible alive in the hearts of all ages and backgrounds thereby drawing them to God and on their own Road to Heaven. The Road to Heaven was developed to provide people of all ages and backgrounds the opportunity to experience and learn the Word of God as spoken through our Lord Jesus Christ and as written in the Bible while having fun through an interactive multi-sensory game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Travel 157 spaces from worldliness all the way through the cross and end at Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Gates. But beware. Do you have what you need to get into Heaven? Along the streets paved with gold, players will learn how to live a true Christian life. Players will need to think strategically as they meet up with temptations and worldliness, a simple roll of the dice can determine your fate. Will you roll one die or two? Which piece or card will you decide to take? Encounter the forgiveness of the Lord and rejoice will the blessings showered upon you. The Holy Spirit is your guide, helper and companion throughout the game. As you play you will: Experience excitement to draw your family and friends together; Progress along the books of the Bible; Draw cards to test your Bible knowledge; Be reminded of strategies for addressing temptations in your life; Learn the difference between the wisdom of God and the foolishness of the world&amp;#10;Realize the importance of having the Holy Spirit as your companion and helper.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Road to Heaven Board Game design and game pieces are biblically based and include 3 sets of playing cards (Bible Book Cards, Blessing Cards and Knowledge Cards) and the following CUSTOM plastic pieces: 13 Lambs Book of Life pieces, 6 Crosses, 7 Earths, 6 Earth Stands, 6 Tips and Reminder Cards and 12 playing tokens in the shape of the Ichthys symbol or &amp;quot;Jesus fish&amp;quot; which are typically used to proclaim an affiliation with or affinity for Christianity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Road to Heaven Board Game comes with a full size bible and has original art work. Both the cards and plastic pieces are made of higher quality than is required and standard.  A minimum price of $39.95 plus tax per game was suggested by the manufacturer (plus shipping).  It is priced to sell.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Road to Heaven Board Game is a fun, family-oriented, Bible focused board game designed to be as competitive and engaging as it is spiritually enriching.  It is a game that will bring families together while at the same time teach all ages the books of the Bible and the scripture inside. You learn about the Bible in the midst of the ups and downs of the action.There is nothing comparable on the market that can provide a platform to learn the Bible in such a fun and exciting way!  What an opportunity to outreach and introduce Jesus to unbelievers in a non-threatening way.  You never know what will happen next.  We pray and know that this game will have a positive impact on your life and that you have a great time playing it again and again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Road to Heaven is a wholesome Christian game that&amp;rsquo;s fun AND meaningful. Road to Heaven teaches you how to live your life for Christ. Learn how even good things come out of bad things that happen along the Road to Heaven. This teaches that challenges you go through become opportunities for you to help others grow.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1115" value="Religious" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="75404" value="Religious: Christianity" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="78123" value="Denise Migliaccio" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.55903" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>