<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="169576">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ritratto d&#039;Autore: capolavori al Maschile" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Experience the thrill of making a single framework, bizarre and imaginative, borrowing the mustachioed smile Gauguin or Van Gogh's restless gaze to achieve a Bacchus certainly more extravagant than that of Caravaggio. But the game does not last long because to win the game then you have to make a genuine portrait, paying tribute to the great masters such as Raphael and Picasso, and composing their own portraits. You have to search in different areas of the game puzzle missing to complete your portrait, and the 10-sided die will tell you if you can take them freely, or you have to challenge your opponent in a feud with the nuts, or you will have to answer a question right on portrait you want to dial or the Artist who painted it ... The questions on Art and its Masters are more than four hundred, and were divided between questions Difficulty standard and ... questions &amp;quot;for the little ones&amp;quot;, specially designed to accompany children to the discovery of Art. With &amp;quot;Portrait d'Autore, masterpieces to Male 'gaming experience encompasses a mix of different emotions. The good fortune of being able to identify and take the missing pieces joins skill in answering questions, and everything blends the fun and imagination. The different portraits that will consist in the match, one of the most curious of the other, will not fail to arouse continuous emotions and feelings in the players. The main objective of the Game and what to discover the art and his most famous portraits, while stimulating the observation and discovery, fantasy and imagination, through the magic of a Portrait of the Author that is gradually becoming ... a true portrayal! Portrait of author also proposes to transfer to the players some knowledge of art history, through a lot of questions about the artists, their works, and on Art in general, which sometimes require the observation and research of the details: even children will learn in a spontaneous and always fun, challenging each other with questions to measure ... baby!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2009" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22783" value="Admin: Better Description Needed!" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="28660" value="CreativaMente" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>