<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="170106">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/swU4Av6Znk9E7RUfW_QMQw__thumb/img/yLLHJjZPpII1pLec3bXD08ez8KE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2338944.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/swU4Av6Znk9E7RUfW_QMQw__original/img/qoieQDTvfq67k2PNtLGhEgse0mM=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2338944.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Goal: The Match" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Plan, Play and Goal!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Description&amp;#10;Goal: the Match is a thrilling Collectible Football Card Game that simulates a soccer match using an strategic view between two players, from now on  they&amp;rsquo;re gonna be called Managers to distinguish them from football players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You could play a complete game of modern football: Goals, fouls, yellow/red cards, set pieces, tackles, waste of time, etc. in a game of 40 minutes approximately.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Goal: the Match you could assemble a team, the cards that will lead your style and the action cards that your team will deploy. All those cards will be get through a basic box and random card packs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Football players allows you to play cards, style cards will mark the general path about how they will be played and the action deck will determine what and how the team plays the match.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A brief  summary&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning of the turn. The manager with initiative will choose to realize one of the following turns: Move Turn or Highlight Turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1) Move turn: Represents the major and boring part of the match and normally doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear in the highlights of the news. In this turn teams deploy their game. It&amp;rsquo;s divided in two phases: Initiative and Replica.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this type of turn, the manager will start the Initiative phase by playing cards from hand (cost of cards is paid by field players), activating player special abilities and/or interacting with strategy cards previously deployed and style cards(They are deployed from the beginning). What is more, the cost in minutes of every played card will be increase the total minutes of the match. The Initiative phase ends when he stops playing cards or abilities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After that the opponent Manager will play a replica phase, in which he could carry a similar phase up to the maximum of minutes played in the Initiative phase by the opponent. Taking into account that some of the cards can only be played in the initiative phase(marked with an icon in the cost). This phase means the opponent is playing and deploying its strategy, not just waiting looking at the match.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2) Highlight turn: It represents what is amazing in a match , those scenes we watch in the TV match summaries. Contains up to two phases, attack phase and a possible counterattack phase(or even more than one).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase attack begins with the manager with initiative increasing the time in one minute. Beginning from him the following possibilities are gonna be played. a) Fast action card from hand b) Abilities from strategy card previously deployed c) Player abilities. When no one wants to continue, Both will  throw 3 dices of 6 faces. Also the defending manager will throw two incidence dices (they signal possible fouls,yellow/red cards, injuries, set pieces, etc) the difference after bonuses will mark what has happened: Goal, Dangerous play, good defence and [b]CounterAttack[/b].&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of replica turn or Highlight turn both Managers untap players and cards in the field and draw two more cards 2 (with a hand limit of 8 cards).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;QR Code&amp;#10;Each one of the game cards has a qr code QR that redirect to our database directly to this card page where any manager could solve doubts and everything about that card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Manager ID&amp;#10;Manager ID (MID) cames along with each copy of Goal: The Match. It&amp;rsquo;s used to measure your level as a manager. After being registered you may annotate results of your matches with other Managers with MID in order to follow statistics. At the end of season you may win amazing prizes!!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="40" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1044" value="Collectible Components" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2079" value="Variable Phase Order" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6040" value="Collectible: Collectible Card Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="23287" value="Crowdfunding: Verkami" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5551" value="Sports: Football / Soccer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="79474" value="Lonagan" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="79482" value="Ramon Bosch" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="79481" value="Husita" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>