<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="170740">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qzT2AaD5mVersFH_cSqKEQ__thumb/img/XzlEdf7O1ij2HXGwGGdvok9w92A=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2348377.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qzT2AaD5mVersFH_cSqKEQ__original/img/oqVOEqE90t9eSwF9812nlQl7ZkQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2348377.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Kaiju Conquest" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Kaiju Conquest is a strategy wargame depicting the battle for Earth in 2116 AD, with the First Inter-Species War between the humans of the United Earth Reaction Force (UERF), and the reptilian Sazzarran Empire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to have the most Victory Points based on control of damaged or non-damaged city and land zones by the end of game round five.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The initial invasion began in the Pacific Ocean and its bordering coastlines, which is also portrayed on the game board. There are 15 major coastal city zones and 7 land zones, which were involved in the war of the Pacific Campaign. The cities are beautifully illustrated by the artist, Becca T-R.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game contains eight Mecha characters of eight different designs well as 8 kaiju characters of eight different species, including the Warlord, who is the Supreme Commander of the Sazarran invasion force. Fighting along with and supporting the mecha are Army, Air Force, Navy and Marine forces combined into a common Military Unit (MU). The Sazzarran have their own version of Army, Air, Sea and other special units, also combined as a Military Unit. The UERF also have access to nukes and the Sazzarran have bio-bombs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are five game rounds. In each game round the players will receive a fixed number of Resource Points to build their MUs and respective Mecha and Kaiju. Each game round the Resource Points are two points less than the previous game round, starting with 15 points and ending with seven points. At the beginning of each game round, the players may also have received extra Resource Points by destroying the opposing players forces.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are five phases during each game round.&amp;#10; 1. Maintenance Phase: One of the players will move the hexagonal game round token to the next game round hex space. Both sides will then collect the number of Resource Points (RPs) as shown below the current game round number.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. Draw Phase: Both sides randomly draw six cards from their respective Tactic Card decks. These cards can be used during the Draw, Resource, Movement and Battle Phases to give bonuses respectively to each of those phases. The Sazzarran player then draws four Target Zone Cards. These cards display a particular city, a land or a sea zone. The Sazzarran player chooses two of the cards and the other two are discarded under the Target Zone deck. The two chosen cards will be the zones where the Sazzarran MUs and Kaiju will deploy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3. Resource Phase: The UERF will purchase their MECHA and MUs as well as any Nukes for the current game round, based on the number of RPs available. The Sazzarran will also be purchasing their Kaiju and MUs. The Sazzarran will also be deciding which zones the Kaiju and MUs will deployed into during the Movement Phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4. Movement Phase: The Sazzarran deploys their forces first at the designated target zones. If there are any UERF units in the zones, the Sazzarran must leave one MU for each UERF MU in the zone. Mecha and Kaiju can freely move between zones within their movement allowance, unless there is an opposing Mecha or Kaiju in the zone. If the zone is unoccupied, the Sazzarran can split up their Kaiju and MUs to take more zones in an attempt to damage and potentially destroy the cities and land zones.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once the Sazzarran has moved any or all of their units, the UERF counter moves their forces to a zone occupied by Sazzarran forces. Both sides may also attempt to blockade each other using the city, land and especially seas zones, to block movement from one zone to another.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5. Battle Phase: The players will battle for control of city, land, and sea zones. Each battle in a contested zone results in total elimination of an opposing force, unless they choose to withdraw after each battle round in that zone. All contested zones must be resolved with a battle. Once the last battle is fought, the game round ends. At the end of each battle in a zone, the players will receive Resource Points based on the build cost of the opposing unit destroyed. These Resource Points are tracked on the players Resource Trackers on their side of the game board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of game round five, the players will calculate their Victory Points (VPs. The Sazzarran receive one VP for each damage point on a city or land zone. The UERF receive one VP for each city or land zone that still have any Zone Points (ZPs) remaining. Both sides receive a VP for each zone occupied by at least one of their units. Both sides also receive VPs equal to the number of RPs they have remaining on their respective Resource Point Tracker. The side with the most Victory Points wins the game and will most likely have control of the Pacific Ocean and its coastal cities and land zones.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="121" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="122" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="123" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="124" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="125" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2958" value="Moving Multiple Units" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="24569" value="Theme: Kaiju" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="77938" value="Warren Loewen" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="124078" value="Starcat Games" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>