<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="172558">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/bVmrni87bnGEZSxAZf1qBA__thumb/img/X3abigP-S6o80wdE2U20nN3iTgg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2394189.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/bVmrni87bnGEZSxAZf1qBA__original/img/GZF310n9BVHi7Q83g4A5vJv0C2o=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2394189.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Crashland" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You barely made it to the lunar surface with your spaceship. Out of fuel, you set down in a crater and view the airless landscape before you. Somewhere there are the fuel tanks you need. &amp;#10;Can you find them in time?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aim of the Game!&amp;#10;In this solitaire game, you must find three rocket fuel tanks and return to your spaceship before your spacesuit runs out of oxygen or battery power. If either of these levels drops below 1 during a systems check, you have lost the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Needed to Play!&amp;#10;The deck of Map Cards (30 cards)&amp;#10;The deck of Event and Equipment Cards (21 cards)&amp;#10;1 Suit Card showing your remaining oxygen and battery power + 2 Tracking Cards which also include the Quick Rules Guide&amp;#10;1 Astronaut, 1 Spaceship, and 3 Fuel Tank counters&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setting the Game Up!&amp;#10;Shuffle the Map deck and deal the cards out face down in a 6 x 5 grid, there will be 5 rows of cards, each row will have 6 cards in it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Find the card on the grid with the Spaceship icon on it and turn this card over to the other side, placing your Spaceship and Astronaut on it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing the Game!&amp;#10;Each turn of the game will consist of 3 phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase 1. Movement&amp;#10;At the beginning of your turn you must move your Astronaut, from the card it is currently on, any number of cards in an orthogonal direction (this means up or down, left or right). The first two cards in distance you move you may do so for free. For each additional card you move during the turn you must lose either 1 level of your Oxygen or 1 level of your Battery Power. Move the Tracking Cards down the Oxygen or Battery tracks as needed to record this. You may change directions as you move (i.e. 1 card to the left and then one card up). You may never move diagonally.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You are trying to find, using your spacesuit&amp;rsquo;s equipment, a series of numbered beacons (in pairs) which will locate where the 3 Fuel Tanks are stored. These beacons give you a set of coordinates (one beacon points up and down, the other points left and right). You will need to locate the pair of matching numbered beacons and then move to the card the beacons point to. In the example to the right, X marks the spot where one of the Fuel Tanks is located.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase 2. Events and Equipment&amp;#10;After you have finished moving you must now draw 3 cards from the Events and Equipment deck. This deck has two types of cards.&amp;#10;If this deck is empty when you go to draw a card, shuffle the discard pile to form a new deck to draw cards from.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A. Event Cards - these cause you to lose Oxygen or Battery Power due to your exploration.&amp;#10;B. Equipment Cards - these cause you to gain resources you need (Oxygen and Battery Power), as well as give you special actions to help in your exploration.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Keep the Equipment cards in your hand from one turn to the next. You will need a pair of the same cards to gain the listed bonus. You may have no more than three Equipment cards in your hand at the end of the Events and Equipment phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase 3. Systems Check&amp;#10;You must now check your Suit Systems. If either your Oxygen or Battery Power level is below 1 you have lost the game. Do not forget that you may spend a pair of matching cards at anytime during the System Check phase (Phase 3) to gain the listed bonus, by placing the cards on the discard pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23816" value="Air and Nothingness Press" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="32" />
			<average value="6.35313" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.51426" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="17301" bayesaverage="5.51426" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.22576" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="79" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="4" />
			<wishing value="57" />
			<numcomments value="42" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>