<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="172832">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8G-ZkgzSEOPtmY5KCID3hQ__thumb/img/vP6EEi-55J-gIWANisxW20YlgNw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2457469.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8G-ZkgzSEOPtmY5KCID3hQ__original/img/-K4HpnguUyl-3mj0nxtDT5GNQeQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2457469.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="BlitzBall" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A) The idea behind Blitzball is to recycle the game BloodBowl, an all other game similar to BloodBowl (Kaosball, Slaughterball, Elfball, etc&amp;hellip;).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With BlitzBall, you can use any figures you want, provided you can classify them into 4 classes :&amp;#10;a. Leader.   b. Receiver.   c. Marauder.  d. Blocker.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For example, a human thrower in BloodBowl may be recycled in Leader for the game BlitzBall.&amp;#10;A human catcher may be recycled in...Receiver.&amp;#10;An Orc lineman may be recycled in Marauder.&amp;#10;An Orc Blitzer may be recycled in Blocker. Etc..&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You don't have any figure ? Tokens, symbolizing players, are provided with the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;B) At the beginning of a match of BlitzBall, you choose a team of 12 players, and you field 9 of them in the pitch (so 3 are on the bench).&amp;#10;Instead of using the specific pitch of Blitzball, you can use the pitch of Bloodbowl : in this case, you choose a team of 14 players, and you field 11 of them in the pitch (so 3 are on the bench).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each position has its own profile :&amp;#10;Movement, Brutality, Resilience, Agility, Passing, Control, Initiative.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In order to have a fluid game, there are NO special skills in BlitzBall.&amp;#10;All aspects of this game is managed by the player's profiles.&amp;#10;Movement : used for ...movements.&amp;#10;Brutality: used for tackles.&amp;#10;Resilience: used for knocked down players, in order to avoid serious injuries.&amp;#10;Agility: used when a player throws, catches, or picks up the ball.&amp;#10;Passing : used when a player throws the ball. A good Passing allows a player to make longer passes.&amp;#10;Control : used when a player kicks the ball, or attempts a Field Goal.&amp;#10;Also the Control is used to give inspiration to teammates.&amp;#10;Initiative : used when a player wants to perform complex movements (feint, jump, sprint, blitz). Also used to pick up the ball in certain conditions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;C) What about the turn sequence ?&amp;#10;At the beginning of the game a team makes a kick-off.&amp;#10;Then it's the turn (called activation) of the receiving team, followed by the turn of the kicking team, etc...until a team scores (TouchDown or FieldGoal). At this stage, the scoring team makes a kick-off, and so on...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;D) What happens during a turn (activation) ?&amp;#10;Normally, a coach (you or your opponant) activates up to 3 players.&amp;#10;It is a standard activation : only 3 players are activated, and they can performs any actions allowed in the game.&amp;#10;Sometimes a coach may opt for another mode of activation : Pass mode, Kick mode, Defense Mode, Movement Mode, depending on the tactical situation on the pitch. For example, the Movement mode improves the movements of the players, allows to activate the entire team in some conditions, but the only action allowed is &amp;quot;Moving&amp;quot;. Same thing for the Pass mode. The Kick Mode activates only the ball carrier and allows to escape from adverse pressure.&amp;#10;The Defense mode is the best mode if you want to tackle the opposing ball carrier, but this mode is available only if you roll the appropriate number on the dice...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;E) End of game and scoring.&amp;#10;You and your opponent agree on a time limit (45, 60 or 90 minutes), or on a maximum scoring (30 points for example), etc...&amp;#10;A team scores with TouchDown (5 or 7 points), Field Goal (3 points), or eliminated opponents (2 points).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;F) Style of Play.&amp;#10;Special cards are provided with the game : they allow to customize the style of play for your team : Pass play, Run play, Aggressive Play, Tactical Play, Polyvalent play, Mixed play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;G) Edited february 18, 2016. You have 2 types of optional players : Goliath and Flanker.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6925" value="Theme: Fantasy Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.75" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.25" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>