<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="174494">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Ntpi62QrFKo7LY8hjwoe7g__thumb/img/UR1qNI2iPoyUD_Prca3Ig4SfSAk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5091048.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Ntpi62QrFKo7LY8hjwoe7g__original/img/A8QmmPpfSyQHCaR2Iy5ZIZkWT0w=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5091048.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Space Dandy: Galactic Deck-Building Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A new take on the deck-building genre, featuring the zany universe of the hit show Space Dandy as seen on ADULT SWIM.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;That's right, baby! Dandy has gone and used the Aloha Oe's broken warp drive and managed to converge every possible alternate universe into one, causing multiple copies of everyone in the known galaxies to run amok! What does this mean for our intrepid heroes? Will all semblance of civilization fall into disorder and chaos? Will the universe, under the weight of so many simultaneous timelines, implode on itself into a cosmic Big Bang?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Well. Maybe. But for now it means the Alien Registration Center has reset the database and is allowing new registration of all previously registered aliens! That's cold, hard Woolong just out there for the taking, baby!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Space Dandy: Galactic Deck-Building Game brings the bizarre space-faring antics of the hit anime series seen on ADULT SWIM TOONAMI to the game table. It's similar to other Deck-Builders like Dominion and Ascension&amp;mdash;with an extra helping of phantom space ramen goodness. Each player begins the game with the same rather low-powered starting cards, but through careful play, you can acquire more to expand your options. Which cards you choose to take directly influence the kind of game you play!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards can grant new abilities, make it easier to acquire new cards, allow you to take extra turns, or even destroy cards from the game altogether! But the most important cards are the aliens. Not only can they improve your hand just like any other card, they can be played Planetside and directly attack the other Player. Why fiddle around endlessly with your deck when you can stick it to them and mess up their carefully laid plans? That's the Dandy way to play!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Even more importantly, aliens are how you win! When you register aliens, they are removed from play, but you get to score precious, precious Woolong that you need to win the game. But be careful! It can be difficult to decide if an alien is more useful in your hand, on the Planet, or in the Alien Registration Center's bank.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say the other cards aren&amp;rsquo;t important, too! Effect Cards cannot be registered OR played Planetside, but they let you manipulate the game to your advantage. Sick of that really great card the opponent keeps playing? DESTROY IT! Changed your mind about the card you played Planetside? WARP IT BACK! Keep your opponent&amp;rsquo;s on their toes with your carefully constructed (or hazardously haphazard) deck!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You can also fill out your space crew with other humans (and the occasional robot) that can&amp;rsquo;t be registered as aliens (obviously). But never fear! They make up for the lack of Woolong delivery with unique abilities of their own!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;So register those aliens, earn all the Woolong you can, and may the Best Dandy Win!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1113" value="Space Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="22568" value="Clay Gardner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29346" value="Seven Seas Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="26" />
			<average value="5.52026" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.89508" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="121" />
			<trading value="4" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="16" />
			<numcomments value="10" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>