<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="175487">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/s9kj2NtGLnwkGuNh3ilVBg__thumb/img/TlF49PYd9_VDqDm3dp4jAbixj4g=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2465838.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/s9kj2NtGLnwkGuNh3ilVBg__original/img/Mtj52toM4dZwDwe4uivzJqneaaA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2465838.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Swipe it!: Take what&#039;s yours..." />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In this exciting, fast paced card game, players are competing against each other to acquire as many cards from their opponents as possible! Some cards are worth more than others though, so be strategic about which cards you decide to &amp;ldquo;Swipe&amp;rdquo; from your foes!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played in rounds, and in one single round only four &amp;quot;Master Points&amp;quot; are available for players to win, either splitting the points between the players, or one player winning them all. Rounds continue until a single player reaches five Master Points, in which they win the game. The four Master Points in any given round consist of the following: 1) Master Number Point 2) Master Color Point 3) Master Shape Point and 4) Master Total Point.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game starts out with the dealer revealing the &amp;quot;Master Card&amp;quot; for that round (which is a Power Card that gets placed in the center of the playing field). The Master Card will have a number (1-10), a color (red,blue,purple,green), and a shape (X,O). Whatever the elements might be are what dictate the four ways to earn the &amp;quot;Master Points&amp;quot; in that round. For example: If the dealer reveals the Master Card that has the number 7, the color red, and the shape X, then players must steal cards from each other that have any of those elements (7s, reds, X's) and always high numbered cards. At the end of a round, players will reveal to each other all of the cards they have acquired throughout the round. In this example, the player who acquired the most cards with the number 7 wins the Master Number Point, the player who acquired the most cards with the color red wins the Master Color Point, the player who acquired the most cards with the shape X wins the Master Shape Point, and the player who acquired the highest sum after adding up the numbers on all acquired cards wins the Master Total Point.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are only two main types of cards in Swipe it!&amp;trade; There are the Power Cards (cards with a number, a color, and a shape; one of these cards gets promoted to master card at the beginning of the round) and then there are the Swipe Cards which have an &amp;quot;S&amp;quot; and a swipe arrow . Players need to combine one of each type of cards in order to initiate an attack against another player. Players can only acquire Power Cards from each other in order to gain points, where Swipe Cards simply allow the player's Power Cards to make an attack. In Swipe it!&amp;trade; a combined pair (a Power Card combined with a Swipe Card) can always freely attack a lower numbered Power Card or enemy pair. Example: a 10 on a Black Swipe Card can freely attack an opponent's 9 on a Black Swipe Card). Now the intensity rises when you are using a combined pair to attack a higher numbered Power Card or enemy pair. This is where the dice and rock-paper-scissors comes into effect, where essentially the attacker is wagering their lower numbered Power Card in a series of battles against their opponent's higher numbered Power Card. If the attacker loses, their opponent acquires the attacker's Power Card in play. This is especially huge when the attacker is risking their Power Card that happens to match the &amp;quot;Master Number&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Master Color&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Master Shape&amp;quot;, or is a high numbered card like a 9 or 10. On the other hand, if the attacker is wagering a Power Card that is low like the number 1 and does not match any of the Master Point categories, then who cares if they lose to their enemy right? The attacker may as well take the risk with that type of card in order try and win a great one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are also three different types of Swipe Cards (Black, Silver, and Gold) each one offering unique abilities; such as the Gold Swipe Card raising your Power card by +2 when it is attacking and by +1 when on defense, or the Silver Swipe Card granting the ability to &amp;quot;Punish&amp;quot; another player's Swipe Card, or being able to &amp;quot;Reassign&amp;quot; a combined pair with a different Power card (if you had a 1 combined with Silver Swipe Card, you can switch it to lets say a 10 on the Silver Swipe Card allowing you to attack higher numbered enemy cards for free). There are also some special rules too, such as &amp;quot;merge&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;master merge&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;cash-in&amp;quot; which can help players out of some sticky situations. A &amp;quot;merge&amp;quot; allows you to combine two Power Cards that share the same number (such as combining a 9 with another 9), forcing the combined cards to act as if it were a Black Swipe card, giving you the ability to combine a third Power Card to it to make an attack. &amp;quot;Master merge&amp;quot; is the same as a &amp;quot;merge&amp;quot; with the exception that the combined cards match the &amp;quot;Master Number&amp;quot; in play, forcing them to act as if it were a Gold Swipe Card. Lastly, the &amp;quot;cash-in&amp;quot; action allows a player to discard two alike Swipe Cards (such as discarding two Black Swipe Cards) to receive one new card from the dealer. This action can only be done once per turn, so if you were hoping for a particular card, you will not be able to cash in another pair of Swipe Cards until the dealer makes its way around to you again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The round ends once the dealer has dealt the last card, and the player dealt the last card takes their final turn. All players discard any remaining face up cards. They then flip over all acquired face down cards and determine the winners of the 4 Master Points for the round in this order; Master Number, Master Color, Master Shape, Master Total.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2014" value="Betting and Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2003" value="Rock-Paper-Scissors" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="81493" value="Earl Johnson, III" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29478" value="EJ3Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="1" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>