<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="177714">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/dklXqALN_OKjTsp50xZ7Iw__thumb/img/xp2g43X3hk0_KTKpRgELOnc9efU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2521674.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/dklXqALN_OKjTsp50xZ7Iw__original/img/M0vfIS04zPPJxV98FK6F9Yhtb_s=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2521674.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Archimago" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Archmage is dying... a successor must be found from the 4 schools of magic, so a contest is afoot. The Principal of the school with the most Prestige will be the next Archmage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player controls 10 wizards of one of the 4 different schools (on the base game they would be fire, earth, water &amp;amp; air). In the beginning players start with 4 wizards and add more to their ranks as the game progresses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn players will have to choose different locations on the board that suits their strategies from gathering resources, to recuiting wizards &amp;amp; heroes, going into quests, creating potions and spells they can use later, and fighting in the terrible DARK TOWER.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Since this game is euro styled, all of this elements are somewhat abstract, so in order to go into a quest you place a wizard on one of the adventure cards and if you pay the resources needed and have all the requirements for the quest to be successful you win the card and any reward that is given.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Heroes are an important part of the wizard guild as they provide extra abilities to combat and enhance how the resources are gathered. They can go up levels (up to 4) and with each level they grant more to the school they work for. Up to 2 levels can be earn in the usual tavern brawls... but the other 2 must be gain in quests or challenging the DARK TOWER.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Archimago has several elements shared by traditional Eurostyle games that use worker placement but at the same time potions and spells provide and interaction with the other players that if mastered can be of a great assistance to the School, events change game conditions, Characters can appear and add a new location to go to, etc.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The base game comes also with 1 scenario that is made of a set of cards that are mixed with the adventure cards and that when are dealt change the conditions of the game or offer sudden opportunities for the players that have the resources to risk or the desire to count on fate for better possibilities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is modular so it is highly expandable in several directions that will add to the system new possibilities and the feeling of adventure, starting with new scenarios that will make each game feel different, characters that will appear in the different locations to assist the players, events that will happen when creating potions and more sudden apparitions that will contribute greatly with the atmosphere of the world.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends on 1 of 4 conditions:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    The adventure cards spots cannot be filled.&amp;#10;    2 or 3 lines of potions/spells are depleted.&amp;#10;    Sometimes a Scenario Card will end the game when certain conditions are given.&amp;#10;    When all the Dark Tower Cards are gone.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the end Archmage is more than an eurogame, an experience that is worth trying. Each adventure card has been carefully designed so the title leads to the story below. Beyond the abstract elements there is a story going on in the game that those players that are fan of the detail will certainly love.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Spanish description:&amp;#10;El Archimago esta muriendo... un sucesor debe ser encontrado de entre las 4 escuelas de magia, asi que un concurso se realizara. El Rector de la escuela con mayor Prestigio sera el siguiente Archimago.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="12172" value="Guillermo H. Nuñez" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="71689" value="Julieta García" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="12172" value="Guillermo H. Nuñez" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29797" value="El Dragón Azul" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="6.66667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.49444" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>