<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="178926">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/0ykPW381_DQtaIkknljBwA__thumb/img/ObAJxwjeYljl_ux3q5IrAqzQhFY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2743422.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/0ykPW381_DQtaIkknljBwA__original/img/DzpD5WlLQLyr3IOde5SdBbAwFQc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2743422.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Roll Saga Baseball" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Roll Saga Baseball is a tabletop fantasy role-playing game that brings the excitement of big league strategic action and the realism of the ballpark to the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You'll be acting as Owner, General Manager, and Manager (OGM) and playing your games on a large 28 x 28 inch premium game mat that is not only a replica with precise dimensions, but also convertible: it converts into any one of the 30 major league ballparks in two simple and quick steps. Your game mat rolls up after each use to be stored nicely in its own box and carrying case along with all other game components.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On the field, you'll be using real replica scoreboards and full teams consisting of 40-man rosters. You won't have to refer to a lot of charts, either, as we've printed most of what you need right there on the player tokens themselves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How Games Are Played - A General Overview:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Games in Roll Saga Baseball are played just like games in true-life baseball. Game players act as Owners, General Managers, and Managers (OGMs) of baseball teams that consist of a full team roster of 40 players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each OGM (Owner/General Manager/Manager) selects his team and places all of the individual player tokens (each player token represents one team player) onto the field's dugout - the large white box on each side of the field. Each OGM then performs the necessary pre-game preparations like selecting a batting line-up (batting order) and choosing what starting, relief, and closing pitchers that they want to have in the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As each player comes up to bat, his player token is placed into the batter's box at home plate. The next batter in line after that batter would be placed in the on-deck circle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With a batter in the batter's box, the opposing team's OGM would then control his pitcher on the mound by selecting certain types of pitches to throw, targeting the locations of those pitches (according to each individual pitches movement), and rolling 3 six sided dice to determine the success of failure of the pitching action. Each roll is augmented by that particular pitcher's pitching ability (PIT), like '+3' for example, that would be added to the roll to increase the overall sum of the total. Pitchers, just like all other players, can have special skill-sets (like Pitching Under Pressure, or Endurance, for example) that can further augment plays and increase the pitcher's overall game performance.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The batter (the OGM playing with the team at-bat) decides to swing, let it go (not swing) or bunt. If he decides to swing, 3 six sided dice are rolled to determine the hit success or failure and, if hit, what type of hit (grounder, hot grounder, line drive, hard line drive, or fly ball results). If a hit is made, another roll is enacted using 3 six sided dice to determine the direction and speed (power) of the hit. Just as pitchers have a PIT ability that is added to their pitch roll, batters use their batting ability (BAT) which is expressed as a 'plus' to augment their 'to hit' roll. Additionally, batters have power ratings (POW) that are used to determine how much extra a hit can travel in feet (like, +50', for example). And just as pitchers, and all other player positions, there are many different skill-sets that can be possessed by a batter (like Clutch Hitting or Place Hitting).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As each play is played out, all of the things that are performed in a true-life baseball game are enacted by the opposing OGMs (Owner/General Manager/Manager) like fielding the ball, throwing the ball, running the bases, stealing, playing off base, sliding into base, picking off, etc. Every single action, bar none, of baseball is accurately replicated in Roll Saga Baseball through a precise and fluid game mechanic true to the game of baseball as we know it to be.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As the game continues, the player tokens are moved around the game mat/field just as players in a real baseball game would move in the course of a game: coming to bat, running the bases, running in the outfield to catch hits, and throwing the ball to get the opposing team's runners out.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring and Winning - A General Overview:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each team scores points just as in baseball - by bringing a base runner into, and across, home plate.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To keep score, authentic replica scoreboards are used. The scoreboards are erasable (marker included) and have places to record runs, hits, errors, balls, strikes, and outs - among other things. The team with the most points at the end of the game is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Levels of Play:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roll Saga has been designed to be very flexible in levels of play in order to ensure that those who don't know a lot about baseball can play at a level that does not require much knowledge. And, conversely, those that are baseball enthusiasts can replicate true baseball strategy and action without error.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It has been designed for 1 (solitaire) or two players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Additionally, these levels of play can be mixed during any game so that any action or series of actions (like an inning) can be simulated and other actions can be played out. A full game can be played in as little as 30-40 minutes, or as long as it takes for a normal major league baseball game (2-3 hours) depending on what the OGMs decide during the course of game play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5586" value="Sports: Baseball" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="83142" value="Jody Pike" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="8" />
			<average value="6.84" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.33263" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="13" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="5" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>