<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="179000">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Wombat Combat" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Long ago at the beginning of time, there existed only the Wombatonians and the One Wombat. The One Wombat gained his power by draining it from the Wombatonians. Eventually the Wombatonians launched their attack on the One Wombat to save themselves. In the end, the Wombatonians created six weapons called the Wombat Stones. When they used the weapons, the One Wombat split into many pieces, although its consciousness survived. The Wombat Stones became lost in six different pieces of the One Wombat. Eventually, these pieces became the planets we now know as Jupiter, Mars, Venus, Saturn, Neptune, and Earth. As time went on life began to grow inside them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every One Hundred Wombatonian Years a tournament is held, Wombat Combat. The evil Combat Croc has won the tournament for the past nine centuries--except suffered failure in the last Wombat Combat Tournament to the warrior known as West Wombat. Combat Croc ordered the Crocodan horde to attack the Island known as Australia on Earth. The horde raided and injured most of West Wombat's fellow warriors, including his Wombat Masters. This enraged West enough to re-enlist in this centuries tournament. He was not alone. Marauder Maus, Kaolin, and Major Waylin Bear, who was in search of his missing subordinate, Elizabeth Emu, were also following right behind West Wombat seeking revenge, and to compete in the next Wombat Combat tournament at the same time. But unbeknownst to West Wombat and the warriors, the tournament was a ruse, a diversionary trap set by the Combat Croc in an attempt to break the rules set forth by the Wombatonians, and in rescuing Elizabeth, Combat Croc's scheme was thwarted and the Combatants prevailed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In retaliation Combat Croc has scheduled an unsanctioned tournament on Earth. He seeks revenge and to claim all Wombat Stones so that he may take the place that the One Wombat once held.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player is dealt one Wombatant and a Wombat Stone. Both of these cards will be laid face-up on the table in front of the player who holds them. Each Wombatant has a certain amount of hit points they can absorb before they are defeated. As attack cards are laid in front of Wombatants, the points will be deducted from the hit point total until they are expended. The object of the game is to use your Wombatant to take the Wombat stones from all the other Wombatants in the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player will be dealt five cards from the Combat deck. On their turn, a player has the option to play an Attack card against any opposing player, or to lay a Counter card against the Attacks already played against them. After playing an Attack or a Counter, the player draws another card from the Combat deck. When a player's hit points are consumed, their player is out, and the last Wombatant to Attack them takes their Wombat Stone. All of the Combat cards in a defeated player's hand or before them are placed in the bottom of the Combat deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Wombatant who earns all of the Wombat Stones wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58141" value="Animals: Wombats" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="76036" value="Rian Heist" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="76036" value="Rian Heist" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>