<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="180537">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_F1_BFws8omGnD6CaLvrCA__thumb/img/QSj6_Sf_yrVYjsl9STw6lxC6MUQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2584136.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_F1_BFws8omGnD6CaLvrCA__original/img/PQlcYglVoVUk8mZSnrcv3lXip38=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2584136.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Berlin Airlift" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In April of 1948 soviet forces halted the supply of Berlin in the British zone then went on to block land routes in the American zone. This was easy to do since Berlin itself lay deep in the Russian zone. Two million civilians dependent on allied supply watched delivery slow to a trickle. Requiring a daily minimum of 5000 tons of food, fuel, and other necessities, Berliners began dipping into their reserves. American officials estimated they would run out of fuel in 45 days but would run out of food long before that.&amp;#10;The Allies faced a difficult decision. Abandoning the city would be a huge loss of face that could lead to the eventual loss of all of Germany to the communist bloc. On the other hand, with all land routes into Berlin cut the city could only be supplied by air, and was such a thing even possible? The Soviets didn't think so. When the blockade commenced, Americans were only capable of delivering 300 tons of supply a day. Together with the British who could manage 400 daily tons. Officials admitted the tonnage still fell woefully short.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Supplying a major city by air for an indefinite amount of time? Nothing approaching it had ever been attempted. Despite the overwhelming odds, the Allies determined to give it a go. Veteran pilots and aircrews were recalled as disbanded cargo units were refitted and flown back to Europe. The effort was massive... no, it was beyond massive, nevertheless, Stalin was certain the operation would fail. His determined opponents proved him wrong. This Herculean effort is remembered as the West's most selfless accomplishment.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Over the course of 12 months the airlift provided 2,225,510 tons of cargo for the city's survival. At one point an airlift plane was lifting off every four minutes. In the end, more supply was provided to Berlin by air than could have been provided by rail. The Soviets did not stand passively by. There were 726 recorded instances of Soviet harassment involving everything from aerial buzzing, and ground fire to rockets, chemicals, smoke and balloons. In the course of the airlift 25 aircraft were lost, costing the lives of over 100 American, British and German personnel. And during the course of the airlift, many curious and heartwarming incidents enhanced the legend of their effort, including the candy bomber, the tour of Clarence the camel and the Easter Parade.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Berlin Airlift is a historical treasure begging to be gamed and here we attempt to fit the bill. But a game is only as enjoyable as the conflict it portrays. The game pits players against each other in a race against the clock. Can players overcome accidents, miscommunication and soviet interference to achieve their goals? Who can deliver the most tonnage, and will it be enough for Berliners to survive? Naturally, Berlin Airlift is only representative of the larger enterprise, but in it, players will enjoy tense competition as they face all of the elements these brave allied aircrews faced when the war ended and - the blockade began.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will command either a British or American air squadron. Each squadron consists of up to three flights depending upon the number of people playing. Each flight contains from 3 to 5 period aircraft depending upon the scenario and the faction being played. Individual planes have a rated capacity and in some cases are restricted to carrying fuel. The object for each player is to attempt to carry his squadron's tonnage goals in fuel, food, medicine and spare parts into the city and carry refugees and finished products out (cargo is represented by colored cubes). Each turn the ACTIVE player rolls two dice, consults either the Personality chart, the Help &amp;amp; Hindrance or the Soviet Harassment Chart to determine effects, then begins drawing flight chits to determine who moves when. Strategy enters into the Active player's assignment of problems, decision making as to what to carry and who to fix, what base to return to and how to block opponents from reaching their goals. Oh, but players must be careful, for there is a cooperative aspect to the game. Players have to keep up the Berliner Morale for if it remains in the negative range after the final flight has delivered its cargo Berlin loses and so do all players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2650" value="Aviation / Flight" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2057" value="Chit-Pull System" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="18214" value="Cities: Berlin (Germany)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="46190" value="History: Cold War" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="8266" value="John Poniske" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="84424" value="David Thompson (II)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="51906" value="Nils Johansson" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="9512" value="Legion Wargames LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
											<rank type="family" id="5496" name="thematic" friendlyname="Thematic Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="21" />
			<wishing value="77" />
			<numcomments value="17" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>