<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="181010">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/aOhLYHJX6vBSdHdvm1E9Jg__thumb/img/c2g45uFzZZDqDxnZWruopc3hIJc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3461013.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/aOhLYHJX6vBSdHdvm1E9Jg__original/img/2UboQEeqRxSBJKafS7z76amV_cA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3461013.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Discovery Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Discovery Game is designed to be played by a married couple. It creates an atmosphere of exhilaration, where a couple can experience something similar to those initial &amp;quot;falling in love&amp;quot; feelings. During this process, true intimacy is developed and deepened. That being said, the game is also competitive; the couple competes one against the other as they both enjoy the benefits of their new-found intimacy. It is simply a great date night in a box&amp;mdash; accessible anytime and anywhere&amp;mdash; no costs, no distractions, no preparations, no planning.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Discovery Game is effective for the newlywed, the empty-nester, for couples that are very close and those who are struggling. This is possible because the couple controls the content and the pace of intimacy. The discovery game simply provides the environment and the parameters necessary for a great date to take place. Consequently, the game provides the perfect environment for a connected couple seeking an exciting night of physical intimacy, while also providing the perfect environment for a couple hoping to re-establish friendly lines of communication.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is a Focus on the Family &amp;quot;Reviewed&amp;quot; product. It has also received endorsements from FamilyLife, The American Association of Christian Counselors and Shaunti Feldhahn (the best-selling author of &amp;quot;For Men Only and For Women Only&amp;quot;).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In that there are property spaces one may purchase, and because the Reality Check spaces often impart financial setbacks similar to those encountered in real life, The discovery Game is sometimes said to be similar to Monopoly and the Game of Life. The discover Game is different from those games in that it was designed to generate intimacy in a relationship. To that end, the discovery spaces are among the most important spaces on the board. For when a player lands on a discovery space he or she draws a discovery card. The cards prompt the player to several types of actions&amp;mdash; all of which promote intimacy. The discovery Game is also unlike many adult board games which are purposed on inducing sexual intercourse. Sexual intercourse is often the outcome for many couples as they play, and The discovery Game does encourage mild physical intimacy and hugs, it is never coercive. Sexual intimacy that is spawned by The discovery Game is always the free choice of the players&amp;mdash; as a couple&amp;mdash; and the natural result of emotional intimacy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Spaces unique to the game are:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     The &amp;quot;Wish Space&amp;quot; (when a player lands on this space, using the included sand-timer, he or she must perform the wishes of his or her partner for two minutes. These wishes might be sexual in nature, but they might also involve household chores&amp;mdash; It is always up to the players and the actions must be mutually consensual).&amp;#10;     The &amp;ldquo;Center Square&amp;rdquo; (is a jackpot where monies from the players are directed at various points in the game. If a player enters the Center Square and rolls doubles, he or she acquires all of the money in the jackpot. If a player cannot roll doubles he or she can use his or her &amp;ldquo;Get Out of Center&amp;rdquo; card. If he or she has already used that card, the player may exit the Center Square by removing an article of clothing (socks, shoes, shirt, it is the players choice). A player can enter and exit this space from any Reality Check or discovery space on the board, and the Reality Check and discovery spaces are located all around the board. This makes the Center Square an extremely helpful way of navigating the board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One of the greatest things about The Discovery Game is, no one feels like they are working on their marriage! It's just fun! This is a tool that has been used by thousands of strong and struggling marriages alike, to move them toward passion. It normally takes at least an hour to complete. However, because much of the game is dependent on the discussions which ensue from the discovery cards, the discussions themselves determine the time it takes to play the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2008" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="18" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="9550" value="Misc: Used for Real-World Therapy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3320" value="(Unknown)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="4.6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.24499" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="11" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>