<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="181683">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HM6U8vZrLnpOD7V5MLG5gA__thumb/img/RkflrKYgAwmrfSONdXMaujzXJHo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2849524.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HM6U8vZrLnpOD7V5MLG5gA__original/img/RDfwyxk2vSaGakAkUbMPgvlxSus=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2849524.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Sentinels of the Multiverse: Chokepoint Villain Character" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>When she was an infant, Evelyn Moore&amp;rsquo;s parents turned to the U.S. government for help. Their daughter couldn&amp;rsquo;t talk yet, but she &amp;ldquo;spoke&amp;rdquo; to machines. More alarmingly, when she did, they fell into their components, which created a metallic cocoon for the child. None of this was covered by the parenting classes the Moore family had attended. A representative of a group called the Ironclad Project offered to take care of Evelyn, but only if her parents were willing to sign her over to the care of the project. Seeing no other option, they agreed, and Evelyn became the ward of the Ironclad Project.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Years went by, and Evelyn grew, learning to control her powers. She was told that she was being trained to be a part of the army. A new army that fought with better power instead of hundreds of soldiers. However, her lack of control and her hot-headedness meant that the Ironclad Project had little use for her. She had learned to absorb tech to plate herself in steel and coat her skin in wires, talking to the tech as easily as she talked to herself, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Even though she desperately wanted to prove her worth, those monitoring her kept wanting more than she could give.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then, one day, she absorbed a tank.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There had been talk of military training going on in the adjacent facility, and Evelyn wanted to know more. Sneaking past her monitors, she found herself next to a massive M1 Abrams tank. It spoke to her of cold steel and internal combustion. It sounded beautiful to her. So she let it fall into its pieces, and she wore its skin.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All hell broke loose in the army base. A tank had just fallen apart, and a person-shaped pile of plate-steel walked out of the wreckage. Soldiers opened fire on the figure, who ran through a wall, disappearing into the nearby hills.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Since then, Choke has been a regular opponent of the Freedom Five and their allies. She is frequently at the heart of troubles concerning military installations or stockpiles of weapons. It was hardly surprising that she ended up allying with the Vengeful Five when Baron Blade called. But when she was fatally wounded by K.N.Y.F.E., many believed that would be the end of Choke.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;However, Choke had heard a peculiar voice - unlike any she had heard before. The Freedom Five had recently prevented Deadline from destroying the earth, and the alien&amp;rsquo;s odd device was still housed in their headquarters. And she could hear its voice. It could save her, and she could give it purpose once again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Evelyn drew the resonating crystal at the heart of the device into herself, sealing her wound, but also opening her mind to the powers of the alien tech. It could sense weak points. She was originally trained to save the world, and now she knew how. She would show those at Project Ironclad that she was worthwhile after all. Using her new knowledge, she would erase all the weak points from the world. All she needed was a bit more power&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With the necessary elements right at hand, Chokepoint was born. Taking power from the tech of the heroes around her, Evelyn is on a self-appointed quest to destroy the weak points of the world, and beyond.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Chokepoint&amp;rsquo;s scope is without limit. She already has growing concerns that the star at the center of this galaxy will eventually die or explode, and that getting rid of it sooner rather than later might be necessary&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Chokepoint is a mini-expansion given as a pre-order bonus for Sentinels of the Multiverse: Villains of the Multiverse.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="131" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="132" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="133" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="134" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="135" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1116" value="Comic Book / Strip" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="17936" value="Game: Sentinel" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="17935" value="Theme: Superheroes" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="102652" value="Sentinels of the Multiverse" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="50244" value="Christopher Badell" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="50245" value="Paul Bender" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="50243" value="Adam Rebottaro" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="50243" value="Adam Rebottaro" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="17543" value="Greater Than Games, LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="304" />
			<average value="7.74046" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.79118" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="5.79118" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.31504" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2077" />
			<trading value="42" />
			<wanting value="21" />
			<wishing value="60" />
			<numcomments value="85" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>