<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="182101">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/fKpv51qjWg-xtvlgf6JCqQ__thumb/img/AOYK1LWHS4agU6Vw8EsB5mZWN-4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2659660.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/fKpv51qjWg-xtvlgf6JCqQ__original/img/LVlGBZ5B9xzmstDbLg2LDXo0CQM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2659660.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dark Matter" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>More than three millennia have passed since the human race left its native land. The discovery of the Sophia triad made real some theories previously thought impossible, theories that were experimented to prove their viability and each of them were performed, no matter whether it was possible or not.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dark Matter is a game from 2 to 4 players. Each player starts with three unique cards to play all the game. Each card is divided in two zones in its obverse and reverse, and each zone has one or several skills. Players play these skills to get matters to terraform planets, to recruit soldiers, to attack enemy planets, to improve their own planets, to use heroes and politics to manipulate their cards and opponents cards, to get resources, and more.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But players won't play only with their own cards. They can also use the opponent cards. Each time a card is played it changes its position, so possibilities are infinite. When a player uses his cards, he spins his card (from front to back) and when he uses the opponent cards, they flip the card (from up to down). In this way, new matters and skills are available to play more actions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Get victory points controlling planets and use them to get more resource gems, soldiers or skills. Recruit a huge army gives also victory points and it helps to get enemy resource from their planets. All this with only three cards in hand. Impossible? Try it out!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Han pasado m&amp;aacute;s de tres milenios desde que la humanidad abandonase su Tierra natal.  El descubrimiento de la Tr&amp;iacute;ada Sophia ha logrado que teor&amp;iacute;as cient&amp;iacute;ficas imposibles de demostrar no s&amp;oacute;lo se pudieran experimentar para vislumbrar su veracidad, sino que cada una de ellas se pudieran llevar a cabo.  Tanto si eran posibles, como si no.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dark Matter es un juego para 2 a 4 jugadores.  Cada jugador recibe al principio de la partida 3 &amp;uacute;nicas cartas que ser&amp;aacute;n con las que juegue toda la partida. Cada carta est&amp;aacute; dividida en dos partes tanto por su anverso como por su reverso.  Cada una de esas partes tiene una o varias habilidades que los jugadores podr&amp;aacute;n activar para generar materias con las que terraformar planetas, reclutar soldados para atacar los planetas enemigos, mejorar sus propios planetas, utilizar h&amp;eacute;roes y pol&amp;iacute;ticos para manipular sus cartas y las de los contrarios, generar recursos, etc.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;En su turno, cada jugador puede utilizar la habilidad de la parte superior de sus cartas que &amp;eacute;l vea y las partes superiores de las cartas de los dem&amp;aacute;s jugadores que vea (los anversos).  Cuando un jugador utiliza una de sus cartas, le da la vuelta en la mano, quedando la habilidad que ha utilizado a la vista de los dem&amp;aacute;s jugadores, que podr&amp;aacute;n usarla en sus turnos.  A la vez, si un jugador utiliza una de las cartas de sus oponentes, girar&amp;aacute; la carta en la mano de su oponente quedando la parte superior en la inferior.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Adicionalmente cada jugador puede usar las habilidades que le otorgan sus planetas terraformados y las habilidades de los dem&amp;aacute;s planetas controlados por los oponentes, enviando a sus soldados.  Al final de la cuarta ronda de juego, el jugador con m&amp;aacute;s puntos de victoria ser&amp;aacute; el ganador y due&amp;ntilde;o de la galaxia.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="5">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="4" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="3">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1113" value="Space Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="41094" value="Óscar Arévalo" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="24841" value="Víctor Pérez Corbella" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8351" value="Gen-X Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="70" />
			<average value="6.31143" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.52393" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="15184" bayesaverage="5.52393" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.63721" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="176" />
			<trading value="23" />
			<wanting value="5" />
			<wishing value="24" />
			<numcomments value="29" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="2.75" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>