<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="182529">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/F2_rMfwRFKTat7IvC2YPTQ__thumb/img/uxPGekf724cdjheRkm11fPYY-go=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2656171.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/F2_rMfwRFKTat7IvC2YPTQ__original/img/l3ya-Cd5IdAScj2j6iOlVcvdg10=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2656171.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Strategic Decision: World War II" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Strategic Decision: World War II covers the entire Second World War, from Poland to Nagasaki, from the Panama Canal to Bombay to Archangelsk to New York. High Strategic level gaming at the Army/Army Group level, and with unit production. No dice, no cards, nothing random used - you've only got yourself to blame if you lose! Two joined vinyl water-resistant maps: the Pacific (~21&amp;quot; x 14&amp;quot;) and European/African/MidEast (~27&amp;quot; x 20&amp;quot;) theatres are included.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For 2-6 players, the belligerents include Germany, Britain, France, Italy, the Soviet Union, China, Japan, the USA and major neutrals such as Poland, Yugoslavia, Greece, Turkey, Sweden and Spain. In the two-player game, it's the Axis (Germans, Italians, Japanese) against the Allies (USA, Britain, Soviets, France, China). There are three counter sheets of 88 5/8&amp;quot; counters each representing the land, air, naval and logistical units, mostly at the Army/Army Group level (infantry, tank/panzer, mech, shock, guards, SS, etc), with specialty units such as marines and paratroops. Air units represent tactical attack aircraft and strategic aircraft, including heavy strategic aircraft (B-29) and even atomics. The naval forces are flotillas of fighting ships, carrier task forces, landing craft and convoys. Logistical units play a major role in the game - no supplies, no attacks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Turns are quarterly, and proceed over two maps, one of Europe/North Africa/Middle East and one of Asia and the Pacific, with the US East Coast on the former and the West Coast on the latter. Units appear historically, but their entry can be altered when the players change historical invasion dates. There are many political rules that reflect the limits that the historical leaders faced.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As units are eliminated, they enter replacement pools and it is then up to the players to decide what branch gets priority in production: will the German player seek panzers for the Eastern Front, supplies for North Africa, or Tactical aircraft vs Britain? The allies can share resources up to a point, and lend lease may be all that keeps the Soviets from folding early.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players are free to try alternate strategies. Should the Germans hit Turkey to open a back door to the Middle East, the Suez and Baku? Should the US hit Japan hard early, or put the emphasis on stopping Germany? Should Japan join Germany's crusade against bolshevism or put the emphasis on naval victories?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Weather is incredibly important, affecting every turn except Summer. Winter slows everything down - except the Soviets.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are no dice in this game! Hitler didn't roll the dice, and neither did Stalin, Roosevelt, Hirohito, Mussolini or Churchill. They made decisions and lived with them. You'll do the same. There are no randomization of effects at all. Each of your actions determines your fate, as does your opponent's. There is no dice to bail you out or ruin your plans - you have only yourself and your opponent to blame for that!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Yet each game takes a different path. It is possible for Italy to be the last Axis player standing. It's possible for the Allies to knock Japan out a year early or liberate Eastern Europe without the Soviets. The Soviets might just take all of Europe. All of these outcomes happened in actual games. Each turn requires you to plan ahead, to anticipate enemy moves and your counter to them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="600" />
						               				<minplaytime value="360" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="600" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="83022" value="R. Steven Brown" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="83022" value="R. Steven Brown" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29828" value="Two Generals Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.41421" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>