<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="182778">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZK71VjY7AhvIMeEE6oaNvw__thumb/img/NpFnQYEAoKi2ypGZaLhHmHbSw3A=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2648467.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZK71VjY7AhvIMeEE6oaNvw__original/img/IVyTBVCdFQGsFdPZxmTPoT-3dzA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2648467.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Trivia Party: Sports" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Trivia Party: Sports is a card game that combines a traditional deck of cards with sports trivia.  There are four different ways to play:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Trivia Party, one player draws a card and asks a question of another player.  The answering player may choose from questions ranked from 1 (easiest) to 5 (hardest) and gains points equal to the difficulty level on a correct answer.  Incorrect answers gain no points.  After one question, the next player takes a turn.  Players play until the deck is used up or to an agreed total.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Upward Mobility is played similarly, but each player starts off being asked question one and proceeds through the questions to number five, earning the point value for each question answered correctly until he or she answers wrong.  So, for example, if a player answers questions 1,2 and 3 correctly but misses #4, the score would be 6 points.  Like Trivia Party, play continues until the deck is used up or until one player reaches an agreed point total.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Auction Trivia, each player starts with 25 points.  One player chooses a card and reads the 5-point question.  Players then bid on the card.  The highest bidder then wins the card and tries to answer all five questions on the card, gaining points for each question answered equal to the point value of the questions (for a maximum of 15 points per card).  These points are added to his starting point balance.  The winninbg player then becomes the next auctioneer.  Players are eliminated if their balance drops to zero.  The player with the most points when all cards are used up wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Trivia Poker, score is kept in the same way as Trivia Party.  However, when a player answers a question correctly, he or she keeps the card.  Players try to gain cards to build the best poker hand possible.  When a player gains a sixth card, he or she must discard any chosen card, keeping five cards.  The game ends when all cards are used or when all players hold five-card poker hands.  There are two winners: the player with the most points and the player with the best poker hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="993" value="Arrco Playing Card Co." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>