<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="186243">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/kWp07m8FtKNNp4BZINwlQg__thumb/img/uJMbguT9CFsMF9CvNkllMIeDrgU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2714170.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/kWp07m8FtKNNp4BZINwlQg__original/img/7fE-y0J1WkFdE2sIjXuzz4LMY2U=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2714170.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bezzerwizzer Kompakt" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Not to be confused with bezzerwizzer kompakt. This version contains no board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;BEZZERWIZZER Kompakt is a new way to play BEZZERWIZZER that makes it easier to play on the go, at the beach or anywhere else for that sake.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game contains 150 cards with questions in the same 20 categories as the original game, which means that they can be used as new challenges in the original game as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To start with the players are divided into two to six teams. Each team can consist of one or more players. Each team then gets a bezzerwizzer token that can be used once per round (see below).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now the game starts: Each team picks a token at random out of the included bag. There are 20 tokens - one for each category in the game. The token must be kept secret from the other players. The first team to go then choose either to answer a question in the category on their token or to swap with one of the other teams, without knowing what they will get. If they answer the question that they end up with correctly, they will receive 3 points - a wrong answer does nothing. Scoring is kept on the included pad. This continues till all teams have answered a question. The last team will not have the opportunity to swap, as all other teams have used up their categories.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn, each of the teams have one opportunity to bezzerwizze one of the other teams question. This means that if the team does not answer the question correctly, the team that has bezzerwizze'd has a chance to answer it as well. If the first team answers correctly however, the other team will have wasted their chance to bezzerwizze this round. The number of points you get for bezzerwizzing and answering correct depends on when you choose to do it; if you choose to bezzerwizze after the category is revealed, but before the question is read aloud you will get 2 points for a correct answer. If you do it after the question has been read aloud, you will only get 1 point for a correct answer. If the teams that bezzerwizzet can not answer correctly either, the original team will receive the points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The turn order then switches one place and the process starts again. If there are fewer category tokens in the bag than the number of teams when a new turn is started, all of the tokens are returned to the bag.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when one of the teams has 20 points (continuing the round to completion to allow other teams to reach 20 as well). Alternately, teams can choose to only play until the bag is empty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2009" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="15" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="9318" value="Game: Bezzerwizzer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameintegration" id="32441" value="Bezzerwizzer" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameintegration" id="186569" value="Bezzerwizzer Musik" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="186569" value="Bezzerwizzer Musik" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="32441" value="Bezzerwizzer" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8134" value="Bezzerwizzer ApS" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="17" />
			<average value="6.76" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.98838" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="42" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>