<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="186359">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/NxEplgEZnGaCCzuUtUZ1yQ__thumb/img/7bS8NfZCV4Pj7-y7WEQ97AeQp9A=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2715524.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/NxEplgEZnGaCCzuUtUZ1yQ__original/img/duJt_81r0f8vEFhBWnkDotaxOXE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2715524.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Middle Creek: Folio Series No. 6" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In a fight that largely determined the fate of eastern Kentucky, two small armies clashed along the swollen tributary of Middle Creek. An officer of some promise, Humphrey Marshall, generaled the CSA. A relative unknown commanded the USA by the name of James A. Garfield.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of the day, Marshall had no choice but to withdrawal. His supplies were thin and he was fearful of his army deserting. The battle unmade his reputation and he was barely heard from again. The Federals, conversely, celebrated a victory. Colonel Garfield earned a brigadiers star, and took the first step along the road that eventually led to the White House.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Contents:&amp;#10;1 28-Page Rules Book&amp;#10;1 4-Page Exclusive Rules Book&amp;#10;1 12-page Examples of Play and Glossary/Index&amp;#10;140 half-inch full-color, die-cut counters&amp;#10;1 22x17 Map/Playing Surface&amp;#10;Charts and Tables&amp;#10;&amp;#10;About the Rebel Yell! system&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Rebel Yell! is a simulation of American Civil War small-unit tactics. The playing pieces in the game represent companies of infantry and cavalry or sections of artillery Each infantry and cavalry unit has one strength point and is equivalent to between 45 and 100 men, depending upon the scenario. Each artillery unit has two strength points and equals two guns. The players of Rebel Yell assume the roles of divisional commanders.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each game turn is broken down into segments. During an action segment, the units of a particular player may conduct a single action. In the beginning modules these actions are: Move, Fire, Assault, and Rally. During any Small Arms segment, the units of a particular player may only fire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are no movement phases, fire phases, etc., as there are in other Civil War games. This absence, in addition to the fact that player segments are structured reciprocally, produces a feel of simultaneity uncommon to other designs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One of the most difficult problems faced by the Civil War tactician was the &amp;quot;problem of approach,&amp;quot; in other words, how he should maneuver his unit to some objective while keeping his casualties and disorganization at a minimum. A commander who did not pay heed to the destructiveness of &amp;quot;modern&amp;quot; weaponry would find his formation damaged up to three hundred yards from the enemy. Rebel Yell addresses this problem. Within restrictions, defending units may fire at the enemy as he advances. Like a real-life commander, a player can no longer be certain that when he initiates an advance, his units will reach their objective. Players may find that even one or two companies Standing to Fire will be difficult to dislodge by frontal assault.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Although Rebel Yell is a complex design, it is not out of the reach of the novice gamer. The rules are programmed, allowing small portions to be digested first and getting players into the game quickly. Provisions are made for such factors as infantry line formations (Standing to Maneuver, Standing to Fire, Skirmishers, and Cover), volley effects, leader quality, morale, and regimental flags. The rules for cavalry and artillery are also extensive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Although an excellent multi-player game, Rebel Yell accommodates the solitaire player, Likewise it can be played in a physically limited area. Rebel Yell is &amp;quot;big&amp;quot; only in the sense that it is detailed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1048" value="American Civil War" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="28241" value="Series: Folio (One Small Step)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3134" value="Richard A. Dengel" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="2597" value="Jon Compton" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="79464" value="Jennifer Cone" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="992" value="One Small Step" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="43" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="4" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="5" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>