<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="186569">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/B-0JdxxkDwRnLAadB-n-Mg__thumb/img/Oa2_lVgbHO7LGN4w_RDjdHQuhXs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2715975.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/B-0JdxxkDwRnLAadB-n-Mg__original/img/sruXR3h1YVLycm0Dbtmp7TpWlgc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2715975.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bezzerwizzer Musik" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Bezzerwizzer Musik uses the same rules as Bezzerwizzer Kompakt but contains only questions regarding music.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game contains 100 cards with questions in 12 music categories and therefor only 1.200 questions - less than previous versions. Both question cards and category tokens are kept in an orange color to make them distinct from the original BEZZERWIZZER game and BEZZERWIZZER Kompakt. This means that you can mix tokens from all of the games together and create your own game with precisely the categories you like.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The rules below are an exact copy of the ones from Bezzerwizzer Kompakt:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To start with the players are divided into two to six teams. Each team can consist of one or more players. Each team then gets a bezzerwizzer token that can be used once per round (see below).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now the game starts: Each team picks a token at random out of the included bag. There are 20 tokens - one for each category in the game. The token must be kept secret for the other players. The first team to go then choose either to answer a question in the category on their token or to swap with one of the other teams without knowing what they will get. If they answer the question that they end up with correctly, they will receive 3 points - a wrong answer does nothing. Scoring is kept on the included pad. This continues till all teams have answered a question. The last team will not have the possibility to swap as all other teams have used up their categories.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn each of the teams have one opportunity to bezzerwizze one of the other teams question. This means that if the team does not answer the question correctly the team that has bezzerwizzet has a chance to answer as well. If the first team does answer correctly however the others team will have wasted their chance to bezzerwizze. The number of points you get for bezzerwizzing and answering correct is dependent on at what time you choose to do it. If you choose to bezzerwizze after the category is revealed but before the question is read aloud you will get 2 points for a correct answer. If you do it after the question has been read aloud you will only get 1 point. If the teams that bezzerwizzet can not answer correctly either the original team will receive the points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The turn order then switches one place and the process starts again. If there are fewer category tokens in the bag than the number of teams when a new turn is started all of the tokens are returned to the bag.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when one of the teams have 20 points (the round is finished to allow other teams to reach 20 as well). Alternately you can choose to only play until the bag is empty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2009" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="15" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="9318" value="Game: Bezzerwizzer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameintegration" id="32441" value="Bezzerwizzer" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameintegration" id="186243" value="Bezzerwizzer Kompakt" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="186243" value="Bezzerwizzer Kompakt" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8134" value="Bezzerwizzer ApS" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.632456" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="13" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>