<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="188124">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/dYEBKjd4n6QFnw7L2f5AYQ__thumb/img/BXytuQA59ot9VctVBhSjVKZc9tM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2760503.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/dYEBKjd4n6QFnw7L2f5AYQ__original/img/uc8OYsubVWOfxtq5xeimSBQhbmw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2760503.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ostroleka 26 maja 1831" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka 26 maja 1831 covers the battle of Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka, one of the largest engagements of Poland&amp;rsquo;s November Uprising. It was fought between Polish army commanded by general Jan Skrzynecki and Russian army commanded by field marshal Ivan Diebitsch. The battle was the final part of the operation of Polish army against Russian Imperial Guard. The meeting near Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka was a bit suprising for both sides, especially for Poles who didn&amp;rsquo;t expect such quick appearance of Russian forces near their positions. Polish army was divided into two parts. The first part was situated on the eastern bank of the river Narew. The second, larger part was put on the western bank of the river. In Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka there were two bridges connecting both banks of the river (one of them was pontoon bridge).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first part of the battle was fought on the eastern bank of Narew. Polish forces tried to slow down an assault of Russians and withdraw to the western bank. Unfortunately, in consequence of earlier orders, one of Polish infantry brigades commanded by general Bogus&amp;#197;&amp;#130;awski was stayed to defend town Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka (situated on the eastern bank of the river), and there attacked by overwhelming Russians and partially routed, partially destroyed. Russians took control over Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka at noon. Then some Russian grenadier battalions decided to cross the river through the bridges to create a bridgehead for further operations. So started the second part of the battle. Polish main army began attacks to destroy Russian bridgehead and both brigdes to prevent main body of Russian army to cross the river. There were few attacks. At first they were not properly coordinated. Russian small forces on the bridgehead was supported by powerful artillery situated on the eastern bank of the river which was higher than western bank and allowed crossing fire (Russians formed two great batteries, one to the north and one to the south of Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka, and were shooting over own units on the western bank).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the later afternoon Polish attacks became more coordinated. Russians tried to gain more terrain, but it moved them out of the range of their supporting artillery and encouraged Polish army to make last, most powerful attack, which was stopped near to the river. The battle ended a famous charge of Polish horse artillery battery commanded by lt. col. J. Bem, which caused great chaos in the Russian forces and discouraged Russians to make general cavalry attack on Polish army in the end of the battle as they were used to do in the Napoleonic Wars. When battle ended, both sides had similar casualties (about 6 000 killed, wounded etc.). The battle is considered Polish army defeat because it left the battlefield and during the night and the next day started retreat, not chased by Russians who first weren&amp;rsquo;t sure they had won. The main effect of the battle for Poles was the fall of morale of soldiers and the upper command, which allowed Russians to take initiative in the later part of Polish-Russian War.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka 26 maja 1831 contains three scenarios, with one made to introduce players to the system and two historical ones, showing both parts of the battlle. The game is quite complex, tending to show full spectrum of tactic of the Napoleonic and Post-Napoleonic period, but in reasonably easy way. Basic game mechanic is similar to Igo/Ugo movement, but with two phases of movement: for cavalry and infantry, and two combat phases: for cavalry and infantry. Horse artillery is generally attached to cavalry and foot artillery is attached to infantry. Additional rules offer another movement systems but rather designed for further battles based on this rules, not for that one. Rules offer many possible reaction activities for non-active player during opposite player phase. Another rules feature is an unique combat calculation system based on traditional odds ratio but originally modified. The rules focuse on simulating cooperation of three kinds of weapon (infantry, cavalry and artillery) on the battlefield and showing different formations (column, line, square, skirmish, buildings defense). The playing time varies depending on the scenario, from 2-3 hours to whole day. It also depends on the players &amp;ndash; the longest scenario can be finished very quickly by autowin.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components:&amp;#10;- One mapsheet 96 x 68 cm &amp;#10;- Nine sheets of die-cut counters (978 counters totally, most of them are markers)&amp;#10;- One sheet of additional counters&amp;#10;- One rulebook and scenariobook (both in one book)&amp;#10;- Three dices (D6)&amp;#10;- Six sheets with tables and player aids&amp;#10;- One sheet with units tables (alternative way of marking units loses)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="4">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="4" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="600" />
						               				<minplaytime value="180" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="600" />
						               				<minage value="16" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="3">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1051" value="Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2710" value="Post-Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2079" value="Variable Phase Order" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58151" value="History: Polish uprisings – Russo-Polish Wars (1792-1794-1831-1863)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="290115" value="Ostroleka 16 lutego 1807" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="267025" value="Ostroleka 26 maja 1831: Iganie 1831" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="84415" value="Ryszard Kita" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="90108" value="Anna Andrzejewska-Godecka" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="87448" value="Szczepan Atroszko" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="87447" value="Wojciech Dąbrowski" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="30961" value="Instytut Wydawniczy Erica" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="87" />
			<average value="8.95977" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.56105" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="10227" bayesaverage="5.56105" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="1538" bayesaverage="5.93548" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.90314" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="109" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="16" />
			<numcomments value="44" />
			<numweights value="11" />
			<averageweight value="4.1818" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>