<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="188692">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/OZs4IwOm5lxDW-cOQ3HdPw__thumb/img/UZVa4Dy2Ok4-BLOtxTI8LJDLpMI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5234613.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/OZs4IwOm5lxDW-cOQ3HdPw__original/img/_JDjp6i8wiuQBApeiLnjjWIrAK0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5234613.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Battles of the English Civil Wars 1642 - 1651 Volume I" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Battles of the English Civil Wars (1642-1651) Series was originally published by TCS Games as several Desktop Published games. In the LCD tradition, they are perfect for those wanting a game that is fast to learn and quick to play. These games will include all new graphics, corrected errata, and consolidated rules.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Volume I features four of the most famous and significant battles from the First English Civil War (1642-1646) which saw  Royalist ('Cavalier') supporters of King Charles I against the Parliamentarian ('Roundhead') supporters of the Long Parliament.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Edgehill (1642): Charles marched on London intending to force a decisive battle with the main Parliamentarian army under the Earl of Essex.. They met  at Edgehill in the  first pitched battle of the war. Both armies were inexperienced and ill  disciplined, and many fled or simply set about looting the enemy baggage train. As a result the battle was inconclusive and the war would continue for another four years.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First Newbury (1643): Almost exactly a year later and we see Charles again facing the Earl of Essex. The Royalists had enjoyed a series of successes which had left the Parliamentarians in disarray. As Charles besieged the town of Gloucester, the Parliamentarians mustered a force under Essex and through surprise succeeded in breaking the siege. They then fell back towards London. The Royalist rallied and, overtaking the Parliamentarians, blocked the path to London at Newbury. A surprise dawn attack saw the battle initially going in Essex's favour. Royalist counter-attacks were bloody and Essex was at risk of being encircled but fought back and pushed forward again - only to be slowed by Royalist cavalry. The Parliamentarian force was split in two but the Royalists attempt to drive through and encircle the wings was unsuccessful. With night falling and both sides exhausted the battle drew to a close. Next day, short of ammunition, the Royalists were obliged to allow Essex to continue his march to London.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Marston Moor (1644): This was to be the largest battle of the Civil Wars and saw the Royalists under Prince Rupert and the Marquis of Newcastle facing a combined English Parliamentarian /Scottish Covenantor force under the Lord Fairfax,  the Earl of Manchester and the Earl of Leven. Rupert marched to break the siege of the Earl of Newcaste at York. The armies met outside York on Marston Moor but Rupert, who had sought battle, hesitated from attacking due to being outnumbered. Towards evening the Parliamentarian and and Covenantors took the initiative and launched a surprise attack. After two hours of fighting Cromwell routed the Royalist cavalry following which the Royalist infantry were annihilated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Naseby (1645): Though the war would continue for another 18 months, Naseby was the decisive battle of the First English Civil War, seeing Charles' main army, led by the King and Prince Rupert, destroyed by the Parliamentarian New Model Army under Fairfax and Cromwell. The Royalists held a strong position on a ridge between two villages but left it when they saw Parliamentarian cavalry withdrawing. Having redeployed the Royalists attacked and the two centres were soon locked in melee. On the Parliamentarian left the two cavalry wings engaged. The Parliamentarian cavalry broke and the Royalists pursued. After an initial face off on the Parliamenraian right, the cavalry wings engaged and the Royalists were routed by Cromwell. Unlike the Royalists on the other wing, only part of Cromwell's horse went in pursuit, with the rest attacking the Royalist centre - at the same time as a smaller attack on the other flank. The King sought to assist his beleaguered centre by personally leading his lifeguard to the rescue but was restrained . Rupert eventually rallied the horse  attacking the Parliamentarian baggage and returned to the field - but too late.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1102" value="Civil War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2725" value="Pike and Shot" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="33896" value="History: English Civil War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="31988" value="1st Newbury" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="29913" value="Edgehill: Dawning of the Revolution" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="40897" value="Marston Moor" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="29809" value="Naseby: The End of a Reign" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="8869" value="Roberto Chiavini" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="3439" value="Rick Barber" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="36911" value="Randy Lein" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="9512" value="Legion Wargames LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="20" />
			<numcomments value="5" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>