<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="188691">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7GSl8rnof2cu1B8lyXQNAA__thumb/img/kOHSR8iTVM_rYNEYaGLinAErR10=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2842023.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7GSl8rnof2cu1B8lyXQNAA__original/img/j9wMk7hAfcJZF6xzE66kUJSL_m0=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2842023.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bridges to Albion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>553 years in the future, seven colonies have been established on seven different planets throughout the galaxy. United Earth is stretched thin and has lost significant diplomatic and economic control over the 89 years since the first colony was established. Thanks to recent technological advances, a new planet, Albion, has suddenly become accessible through the construction of a series of space bridges. With this new access, United Earth has issued the Albion Initiative, which rewards the first pioneer that can successfully reach Albion by purchasing, constructing, and traversing four space bridges from their home planet. Once a player reaches Albion, they win the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In order to earn sufficient in-game capital to purchase the necessary bridges, players control a spaceship that they will use to accumulate wealth and to strike fear into the hearts of their fellow gamers. Players can complete a series of missions, buy and sell commodities on the intergalactic commodities market, and engage other players in combat in order to pilfer their stores.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn taken consists of three parts: Tile Placement, Movement &amp;amp; Transactions, and Refueling.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tile Placement: At the beginning of each turn, players must draw one Navigation Tile and place it in a space that connects it to that player&amp;rsquo;s game piece via the lanes on existent pieces. Through the placement of the Navigation tiles, the game board takes shape as game play progresses. Also, this means that no two play-throughs will utilize the same game board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Movement: After the tile is placed, players can then move their ship onto spaces that are connected to their game piece. In Bridges to Albion, players can only move as many spaces as they have fuel to reach. Each fuel cell displayed on their Ship&amp;rsquo;s Console can be used to move one space. Each ship comes equipped with room for three fuel cells (an amount that can be upgraded eventually).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Missions:&amp;#10;Each player starts the game with three mission cards. These missions can be completed at the player&amp;rsquo;s discretion. Once a mission is completed and the corresponding reward is received, a player can choose to draw another mission card. A maximum of three mission cards per player is allowed. Mission rewards increase with each mission completed, so completing more missions is more lucrative. However, when a player is prepared to traverse their Bridges, any incomplete missions will incur a 500c fine for each Mission Card that the player retains. Mission Cards may not be sold, but players are allowed to conduct one-for-one trades between themselves throughout the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combat:&amp;#10;Any time during the game that two ships attempt to inhabit the same space on the board, a combat event is initiated. In a&amp;#10;combat event, each player rolls one die. The player with the highest die roll wins, and the loser then must pay the winner the amount indicated on the pricing list. Ties are awarded to the non-attacking player. Battle losses are based on the number of missions the losing player has competed, and the more missions a player completes, the more they stand to lose in a fight.&amp;#10;Each ship&amp;rsquo;s weapons systems can be upgraded, allowing the player to roll more than one die in a combat event. The first&amp;#10;weapons upgrade allows the player to roll two dice, and the second upgrade allows them to roll three. The sum of all&amp;#10;applicable dice rolled is compared to the foe&amp;rsquo;s total sum.&amp;#10;It is possible for players to negotiate prior to a combat event being initiated in order to avoid the potential damage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Transactions: Once a player arrives to a planet, they are free to conduct any business that they so choose. The Intergalactic&amp;#10;Commodities Market provides an opportunity to buy commodities on one planet and then sell those same commodities on&amp;#10;another planet for a profit. Each ship has a limit of 5 commodities, an amount that can also be upgraded. Ship upgrades can be purchased either on planets or in space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Refueling: When a player has conducted all of their business, and is finished with their turn, they can then replenish their&amp;#10;fuel supply. Players are not required to purchase any fuel cells if they choose not to, but once they do (or decline to), their turn is then concluded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bridges:&amp;#10;In order to reach Albion, players must construct and traverse four Space Bridges beginning at their home planet. Once&amp;#10;purchased, players may place them in the outlined tiles. If a Navigation Tile has not been placed in a space, the Bridge may not be constructed over that space. Once (and not before) a player has built all four of their Space Bridges, other players have the opportunity to attack and destroy them. Once the player reaches Albion, they have won the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1113" value="Space Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2689" value="Action Queue" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2013" value="Commodity Speculation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2081" value="Network and Route Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2005" value="Stock Holding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="8.6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.33238" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>