<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="192069">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-jM2HU05TYumvfeZo0cmSg__thumb/img/0MXresc0w7nyCVUT3Ncc2avOTGU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2855691.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-jM2HU05TYumvfeZo0cmSg__original/img/taVEa6mS0_8HmLbirPx5po3IFQQ=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic2855691.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ironsides Preston 1648 Worcester 1651" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ironsides is a moderate complexity game on the decisive battles of Oliver Cromwell and the &amp;ldquo;Ironsides&amp;rdquo; of the New Model Army at Preston in 1648 and Worcester in 1651 which won the Civil Wars and established the English Commonwealth. Philip Jelley uses the same area movement design as Lilliburlero: The Battle of the Boyne, July 1690 (ATO 40), with units representing the regiments and batteries that fought the battles. Each turn represents one or two hours of time, with weather and nightfall affecting command and control and unit activations. Scenarios are included for both battles with historical deployments, free-set-up, and for Preston a short introductory scenario and a three-day campaign game. There are optional rules for units that might have fought at the battles, and a random events table. Ironsides contains 216 counters, two maps (11&amp;rdquo; x 34&amp;rdquo; for Preston and 17&amp;rdquo; x 22&amp;rdquo; for Worcester) and a nine-page rulebook.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PRESTON 1648 King Charles I was defeated by Parliament in the First Civil War, but secretly made an Engagement with the Scottish Duke of Hamilton to restore him to the throne. John Lambert&amp;rsquo;s 4,000 Parliamentarians could only slow Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s 20,000 invading army as it joined 3,500 Royalists under Sir Marmaduke Langdale and marched through Lancashire. When Langdale encountered Lambert near Preston on 17 August 1648 it was dismissed as another delaying tactic, and Hamilton continued south across the River Ribble. What they did not know was that Oliver Cromwell had forced-marched 4,500 &amp;ldquo;Ironsides&amp;rdquo; of the New Model Army 300 miles to join Lambert. Langdale desperately tried to hold off the assault, but was overwhelmed, and Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s divided and disorganised army was destroyed in a three-day running battle. With the Royalists defeated the Army purged Parliament so they could bring &amp;ldquo;Charles Stuart, that man of blood, to an account for that blood he had shed&amp;rdquo;.  His trial was a forgone conclusion and the King and Hamilton were beheaded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WORCESTER 1651 In 1650 the Scots invited King Charles II to succeed his father, so Cromwell invaded Scotland, destroying their army at Dunbar and taking Edinburgh. Charles II raised a new army, but with little chance of victory in Scotland he slipped past Cromwell and marched south to Worcester, hoping to rally English Royalists to his cause. Cromwell followed, joining the county militias raised by Fleetwood and Harrison, marching on the 16,000 Royalists with 31,000 men, intent on a battle of annihilation that would end the Civil Wars for once and for all. On 3 September 1651 Cromwell crossed the River Severn with a bridge of boats, dividing his army in order to encircle the Royalist army. Charles seized his chance and attacked the militia east of the river, but was repulsed, and the Ironsides chased his army through the bloody streets of Worcester, killing 3,000 and taking 13,000 prisoners. Charles fled to France, famously hiding in an oak tree to escape capture, while Cromwell would overthrow Parliament and make himself Lord Protector.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;bull; Two Mapsheets (11&amp;Prime;x34&amp;Prime; and 17&amp;rdquo;x22&amp;rdquo;) &amp;#10;&amp;bull; One Countersheet (216 9/16&amp;Prime; counters) &amp;#10;&amp;bull; One Rules Booklet &amp;#10;&amp;bull; Two Players Aid Charts (one for each player)&amp;#10;&amp;bull; Two Generals Display Charts (one for each side) &amp;#10;Two six-sided dice are required to play the game, but are not included.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="360" />
						               				<minplaytime value="180" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="360" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1102" value="Civil War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2725" value="Pike and Shot" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2021" value="Area-Impulse" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="66855" value="Cities: Worcester (England)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="33896" value="History: English Civil War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="263700" value="Ironsides: First Newbury, Second Newbury, Preston and Worcester" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="33440" value="Philip Jelley" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3320" value="(Unknown)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>