<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="193201">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The oobulous Island Arena" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to struggle! Roll the dices, create strategic combinations and challenge your destiny. Luck and persistence will allow to fight for your survival. But cleverness and intelligence will be essential to defeat enemies and achieve the final victory in the Arena of oobulous Island.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;oobulous is a world without a space-time dimension inhabited by beings with amazing supernatural skills, huge powers and intelligence, called oobuliani. oobuliani have opened a dimensional portal that has put in communication worlds belonging to different age, far apart, causing quite a stir among their Heroes keepers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The opening of portal has triggered an endless battle to the death for conquering the final victory. Four factions of heroes will come down to fight in the oobulous Island Arena and compete in quick and breath-taking duels to get the title of Supreme Hero.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SETUP.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Players choose their Hero Card. &amp;#10;     Determine who goes first by rolling one of the twenty-sided dice. The player with the most high roll goes first and attacks trying to damage immediately his opponent player.&amp;#10;     Each Hero has 20 life points and 0 oobu.&amp;#10;     Try to create attack/defense dices combinations and pay attention to the red number in the upper position on the dice faces. It specifies how many damages you can inflict to the enemy or the quantity of life points you may recover during own turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ON YOUR TURN (Order of Attack Operations).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Unleash the power of your Hero! Roll all 4 oobulous dices and make a maximum of 3 launches. Try to create attack combinations and risk to evoke the Hero Power with strategy and fortune. &amp;#10;     Inflict damages to the life points of your enemy. If you&amp;rsquo;re unable to create attack combinations, pass the turn and your opponent may try to counter attack. If your enemy is not able to attack, you&amp;rsquo;re again in attack. &amp;#10;     Roll your dices and choose the most powerful attack combinations, hit your enemy and get the chance to roll a bonus dice, the power dice. &amp;#10;     Resolve the roll of power dice. If you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, you will cause additional damages and obtain the opportunity to gain from 0 to 4 oobu by rolling the oobu dice. &amp;#10;     oobu dice will earn you the chance to collect oobu and activate special actions of your Hero during the battle. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ON YOUR TURN (Order of Defense Operations).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Fight for life of your Hero! Roll all 4 oobulous dices and make a maximum of 3 launches. Try to put together defense combinations and risk to evoke the Hero Power to your defense. &amp;#10;     Protect the life points of your Hero from the enemy attacks. If you don&amp;rsquo;t succeed to defend yourself, the turn will pass automatically to the opposing player, who he may try to attack and hurt your Hero again.&amp;#10;     Roll your dices and join the most strategic defense combinations with intelligence, challenge your enemy and get the chance to roll a bonus dice, the power dice.&amp;#10;     Resolve the roll of power dice. If you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, you will recover additional life points and obtain the opportunity to gain from 0 to 4 oobu by rolling the oobu dice. &amp;#10;     oobu dice will earn you the chance to collect oobu and activate special actions of your Hero during the battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WHAT ARE OOBU?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;oobu are a form of currency which players can spend in &amp;ldquo;The oobulous Island Arena&amp;rdquo; dice game to activate special actions of their Hero during the battle. Each player can reach a maximum number of N.20 oobu. Once players used its own oobu, they will have to start the collection again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Depending on the number of oobu collected the players can:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     earn life points or inflict damages buying additional rolls of the power dice ** With 2 oobu: 1 additional roll ** With 4 oobu ? 2 additional rolls;&amp;#10;     trigger a special &amp;ldquo;oobu attack&amp;rdquo;. The player can evoke an &amp;ldquo;oobu attack&amp;rdquo; of equal value of oobu collected until that moment in the game;&amp;#10;     evoke a &amp;ldquo;deadly attack&amp;rdquo; of the Hero. Collected 20 oobu the player can evoke the deadly attack and kill the opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WINNING THE GAME.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In The oobulous Island Arena dice game there is only a way to win the game: fight, defeat the enemy Hero and reduce his life points to zero.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="88837" value="Mariachiara Guffanti" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="88836" value="Andrea Trento" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>