<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="194520">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xd3DrklxvBLLQ8xyx7clxA__thumb/img/sVu-TqFb90a8HQTKHgn5g9ft5fQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2911280.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xd3DrklxvBLLQ8xyx7clxA__original/img/_CfFZwPx64b0hHULH7glIyu_Uj0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2911280.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Monopolis" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Monopolis (eng. Monopoly) game was made in Lithuania when this country was part of the Soviet Union, like the other Baltic states.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Just before the end of Soviet Union, politics became softer and allowed more things from the western culture like this game for example (not actual Monopoly version). Such things became popular among people, but the rule that everything had to be written in Russian remained, that's why this game's Rules are written in Russian.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The yellow lid of the game box only show the &amp;quot;shareholder cards&amp;quot; as well as some of the little &amp;quot;Chance cards&amp;quot;. &amp;#10;Each side of the little game board has 3 company spaces, 1 railwaystation and a &amp;quot;destiny&amp;quot; space (showing a yellow circle with some image).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The 23 spaces on the board are from onwards: &amp;#10;Pepsi-Cola -10%-circle - Marlboro - Kn&amp;iuml;b (Kiev) - Las Vegas - a Jail corner - Philips - policeman in circle - Opel - Alma-Ata - Ford - cowboy on totem pole (Destiny corner) - Parker - sun and cube in circle - Toyota - New York - Asahi - judge corner - Atlantic - sun and cube in circle - Honda - London and Panam.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The instruction on the destiny spaces respectively reads:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     side 1: pay 10% of your funds and put it in the &amp;quot;destiny pool&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;     side 2 with the policeman: pay a fine of 500 and put it in the &amp;quot;pool&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;     side 3 and 4: test your luck by taking a Chance card.  It is remarkable to see that the &amp;quot;Destiny corner&amp;quot; is officially used as the &amp;quot;Free Parking corner&amp;quot; in the unofficial family rules in Parker Brother editions!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Besides, there is an inner circle in the center of the game board, called Klondike, being an essential part of the game. Klondike can be entered any moment, by paying the Bank 500. Starting point is the pointing hand as in the main part of the game. The Rules for this section are as follows:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Landing on each of the empty yellow spaces player receives 1000 from the Bank.&amp;#10;     Landing on the space with the gold coin player receives 5000 and the right to return to the main game.&amp;#10;     Landing on the space with the money bag player receives 10000 and the right to return to the main game.&amp;#10;     Landing on the space with the pistol player loses all his money received in Klondike and has no right to leave the Klondike.&amp;#10;     Landing on the space with the black cat player loses all his money received in Klondike and must return one of his most precious shareholder cards to the Bank as well as one of the cheapest he owns, but he still has the right to return to the main game.&amp;#10;     Landing on the space with the pointing hand player must return to the main game with the money he collected in Klondike.&amp;#10;     Philips shareholder card. Instead of property deeds players receive a shareholder card  from the banker the moment they buy shares of a property or station. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How does that work? Let us take the Philips property to explain:&amp;#10;The first share, together with the &amp;quot;shareholders card&amp;quot;  (like a &amp;quot;property deed&amp;quot; in Parker Bros. Monopoly) can be bought for 16 the moment you land on this free space. A next player landing on this space have to pay you 4.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you are short of cash you can pawn this card with the Bank for 8.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A second share can be bought from the Bank for 160 after which a visitor must pay you 40. The value of this share however is 140. In order to remember how many shares you own on this property you place the blue plastic paperclip on line 2.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this way one can collect up to 5 shares by finally paying 6400. That moment the value of your total shares is 3200 and any visitor has to pay you 1600 each time he lands on this property. Should you run out of cash you can pawn this card with the Bank for 3200. &amp;#10;There are 18 small (56x69 mm) yellow Chance cards, to be placed on the red dot in the centre of the board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Some of the instructions on these Chance cards read:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Konkurentu dovana gangsteriui 1000$ = Player receives 1000 from each other player and he gets the right to throw the dice 3 times. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In addition he is allowed to rob another player, f.e. the moment he lands on a space owned by another player the owner must hand over all profit to this player. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Nenumatytos pajamos 50% = Player receives 50% of his own properties (stocks and stations) from the Bank.&amp;#10;     Mafija 1000 $ = Player has to proceed to the Destiny corner and pay 1000 fine.&amp;#10;     Air Mail = Player does not move per space but per board side. On doing so he is allowed to land on a space he likes, except on the corner spaces. However, he does receive 200 passing the Start corner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Black cat = Player must return one of his shareholder cards to the Bank, without the right to redeem it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The procedure with the stations is somewhat different: When buying a station player has to pay 800 to the Bank and in the same time he receives a hexagonal, plastic chip. The more stations a player owns the bigger profit he gets. The moment another player lands on your station he owes you 200 per station. Should an owner runs out of cash he can, like with the other properties, pawn a station with the Bank for 400 with the opportunity to redeem the station when he has enough money again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The money consists of rather a number of plastic coins in various colors and diameters. The 11 denominations are: 1 - 2 - 5 - 10 - 20 - 50 - 100 - 500 - 1000 - 5000 and 15000.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1989" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="100" value="Series: Monopoly-Like" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3320" value="(Unknown)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>