<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="194659">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/CYKIh8xBdjW3ACNvoLhCgQ__thumb/img/NYxL3RPNcWdQOQxyk0P0ireuIfw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6766370.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/CYKIh8xBdjW3ACNvoLhCgQ__original/img/febE1sXlufY_3aRZvwo38isEvCs=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6766370.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dueling Samurai" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Dueling Samurai - recreate the end of the Age of War in feudal Japan.  68 historic samurai square off in a battle royal of epic dueling, heart pounding action.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Immerse yourself in a world of combat, diplomacy, spying, culture... only those who also wage peace will become Shogun.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Natural disasters sweep the lands as the blood from duels is spilled upon:  Typhoon, Earthquakes, Tsunami, Volcano explosions... disease and flooding all get in the way of your plans to conquer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A rapidly growing tournament game ~ Dueling Samurai will be hosting tournaments world-wide in 2017.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;            Comments made about the rules of this game were based on a draft of the rule book, and gamer were informed it was a draft.  The reviewers also played a pre-launch tabletopia version which due to the interface, was lacking in our opinion.  We have had minor issues with rules clarity - not unlike any other game.***&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Join the Dueling Samurai Meet-Up: https://www.meetup.com/Dueling-Samurai/&amp;#10;Follow BigForest Creativity Lab of FB: https://www.facebook.com/BigForestCreativitiyLab&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to Play:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;48 historical samurai warlords are dealt to all players.  These warlords are the clan leaders of specific territories.  Each have characteristics that are based on history.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players, in secret, choose a castle territory.  When all players choose their castle territory players place their castle into their castle territory.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Clan tokens are placed in territories owned.  Players who wish to make certain warlords strong will stack clan tokens into these warlords.  Clan tokens represent both 1000 samurai and 1 HP for that character.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players make 3 actions in turn.  This happens twice which represents 1 decade or 1 round of play.  Players draw cards and get Clan Token bonuses after each half decade.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Actions:  Bribe, attack, move, castle movement.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bribe:  Bribe an adjoining warlord by committing 1 clan token to the action.  11 or 12 must be rolled on the dice.  If successful the committed clan token goes on top of the enemy warlord and his character card is given to the attacking player.  The warlord has switched sides.  If the bribe is unsuccessful the committed clan token gets put into the clan token stack of the adjoining warlord.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Attack:&amp;#10;Attack an adjoining enemy.  Advance as many warlords and their samurai armies to the border of the enemy territory.  The enemy may play cards against you at this time, do defensive troop movements.  The attacker may also play cards against the enemy.  Once card play is completed the attacker must choose which warlord will go into the duel.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The warlords duel!  D12's are rolled.  The attacker always gets +1 and the difference of the dice determines the damage.  Damage is counted by removing Clan Tokens from the stack of the warlord.  In a duel, the Clan Tokens now represent the HP of the warlord for the duel.  When Clan Tokens are gone the warlord is slain and the victor can move as many or no warlords and/or clan tokens into the claimed territory.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Movement Action: During a player's turn they may move as many warlords and/or clan tokens from one territory to another territory that is connected through ownership of land.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Castle Movement Action: requiring an entire decade (4 actions) a player may move their castle from one territory to another territory that is connected through ownership of land.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Object of Game:&amp;#10;Destroy all enemy castles.  If your castle remains standing you win.  Or, Dueling Samurai has a points scoring system that lets players end the game at the end of any half decade.  This being a tested tournament game, the points scoring system is easy to follow and very well developed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Card Play:&amp;#10;Players may play cards at any time in the game, making this a highly engaging and interactive board game.  &amp;#10;Bonus Cards: (Archers, Dueling Samurai, Horses and Ambush)  These have individual use in the game, but can also be combined during your turn to get more clan tokens.  There is a very challenging balance between hording these cards and using them for combat making the strategy very deep.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tournament Cards: (Sumo and Dojo)&amp;#10;Host a tournament.  If you win there are big rewards.  If you lose it can be a devastating turning point.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Attack Cards:  Religious Conversion, Spy, Ninja, Small Pox Demons, Demons, Revenge, Sniper Cannons, Riflemen, Battering Rams, Cannons, Navy, Assassin, Ronin, Pirates, Bandits, Inciting Revolt.  These cards (other than Ninja) can be played at any time in the game.  Each utilize D12 or D6 to deal damage.  1's are always fails and so are 2's on D12's.  On fails players roll against themselves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Defense Cards: These are used to block attack cards, often reversing the attack to a more devastating effect.  Some of them can be played anytime you are under attack, providing a defensive attack option.  Chinese medicine, Knife Cart, Furious Defense, Scouts, Gold, Bushido, Seppuku.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Peace Cards:  These are used to create peace.  Each card causes a different type of peace based on geography and the location of the clans that go into a truce.  Diplomacy (by Marriage, Decree of the Emperor or by Hostage Exchange), Peace Pipe, Brothels, Festival, Ceremony, Gambling.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="70948" value="Digital Implementations: Tabletopia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="91554" value="Richard Janutka" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="91554" value="Richard Janutka" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="31870" value="BigForest Creativity Lab" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="18" />
			<average value="6.64444" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.31683" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="32" />
			<trading value="3" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="9" />
			<numcomments value="14" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="4.25" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>