<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="194755">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/iksPGm7OME9X_VY_uQmVAQ__thumb/img/3Ks5ZbZPQiN_PJrphSOtyM5_J3A=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6761586.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/iksPGm7OME9X_VY_uQmVAQ__original/img/_Qfy6tviQj3q5jP1OOa-3dMPWs8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6761586.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="PlataPorma" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="PlataPorma" />
			
						               													<description>Political Story Telling Game. Free Print-to-Play. Designed by Ronald Villaver. CC Attribution-NonCommercial (CC BY-NC) Are you sure about your bets this coming election? What makes your candidates better than the rest? Use showmanship, quick wits, and satirical selling skills to convince the voting public that your team has what it takes to solve our nation&amp;rsquo;s current issues.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;DISCLAIMER:&amp;#10;This is a work of fiction. Names, characters, businesses, places, events, locales, and incidents are either the products of the designer&amp;rsquo;s imagination or used in a fictitious manner. Any resemblance to actual persons, living or dead, or actual events is purely coincidental.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup:&amp;#10;Shuffle the Political Issues and Candidate Cards into their respective piles. Give each player a starting hand of three Candidate cards. First player goes to whoever recently tried to weasel their way out of a violation and got away with it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Basic Game: 3 &amp;ndash; 5 Players&amp;#10;Plataporma is played in a series of rounds where players try to get the vote of the Voter player to earn points. The first to 3 points wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Step 1 : Reveal the Issue&amp;#10;The Voter chooses a card in their hand that will be the Current Issue for the round. They then read it aloud and put it on the table for everyone to see.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Step 2 : Promote Candidates&amp;#10;Each other player (starting from the player to the Voter&amp;rsquo;s left) chooses 2 cards from their hand to play as their candidates (President and Vice-President pairing). They must explain to the Voter why their candidates are the best to address the Current Issue. Once per round, if a player doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the candidates in their cards, they may discard as many cards from their hand to draw that many new cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Step 3 : Vote for favorite Candidate&amp;#10;After each player has taken their turn to promote their candidates, the Voter chooses which pair they liked the most. The player whose pair was picked wins the round and gets a point! They put the Current Issue card face down in front of them to track their points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Step 4 : Prepare for the next round&amp;#10;Everyone discards all used cards and then draws back up to 4 cards. If there are no more cards in the draw deck, shuffle the discarded cards back into the draw deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Step 5 : Start the next round&amp;#10;Start a new round with the player that won the last round as the new Voter for the round. The first player to get 3 points wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Debate Variant: 6 &amp;ndash; 10 Players&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The round begins with the Leader also known as the Chairman, drawing a Political Issue and reads out loud.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The players to the Chairman&amp;rsquo;s right and left are now debate opponents and selects their respective electoral match up. The rest of the players are called voters. The opponents have 2 minutes to explain why their pair is better than the other in addressing the political issue.&amp;#10;The chairman counts to 3; voters simultaneously raises their right or left hand to indicate their preferred pair in reference to the chairman&amp;rsquo;s right or left. The Opponent with the most votes wins a point. Chairman breaks ties.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players shuffle back played candidate cards and draws up to their beginning hand. Player to the chairman&amp;rsquo;s left is the new leader for the next round. Play continues until a player reaches 3 points, that player is the winner.&amp;#10;Party Variant: 10+ Players&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It plays the same as the basic game except for a few things: The voter draws 3 political issue cards and chooses to play 2. Players must address both issues.` The rest of the players only chose one candidate card and must declare to the other players their selection. Next they must convince someone else to be their running mate. If they are unable to get a partner, they are forced to use just one candidate. Players must do this selection as quick as possible.&amp;#10;Play goes as normal, except they now have 2 minutes per team, and both are making their presentation in tandem. Speaking and acting in character is highly recommended.&amp;#10;The voter chooses the winning pair, both players get a point each by giving them their Political Issue card. If a player was forced to use one candidate, they only get 1 point, represented by the Political Issue Card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/. All characters appearing in this work are fictitious. Any resemblance to real persons, living or dead, is purely coincidental. Opinions expressed by players playing this game are solely of their own and do not express the views or opinions of anyone else.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you liked this game, please check out my other designs at http://www.scripturedyou.com&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For updates and print-to-play files, always check the repository at https://github.com/rvillaver/PlataPorma&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2027" value="Storytelling" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="19285" value="Snake Oil" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="80626" value="Ronald Villaver" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="80626" value="Ronald Villaver" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29234" value="Ludus Distributors" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>