<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="196519">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/yuA19fYs9wb9aakXih00Ww__thumb/img/svMzguhGpEu-GuXbXSd40h7smK8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic2952643.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/yuA19fYs9wb9aakXih00Ww__original/img/0vTX8UDjYAKC8qEhDCzn1Qz4PXk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic2952643.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Kashindan" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the designer:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A &amp;quot;Kashindan&amp;quot; (&amp;#229;&amp;#163;&amp;#171;&amp;#230;&amp;#165;&amp;#173;&amp;#230;&amp;#132;&amp;#155;) was a feudal Japanese Daimyo's band of retainers, something similar to a small elite company or a unit of faithful bodyguards. Consequently, Kashindan is not a game for mass battles, but was designed to play skirmish fights in an hour, in which the loyal vassals of a hero fight each other for fame, honour, prestige, personal feuds or because they favour opposite sides in a larger political/military confrontation. From the lowest peasants to the most prestigious Samurai lords -- the composition of an army depends only on the hero's capabilities to convince and inspire followers, i.e. it is entirely up to the player's tactical decisions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Kashindan takes place in feudal Japan before a Portuguese ship stranded off the Japanese coast in 1543 and introduced the people of Nippon to the Arquebus (gun). During those times, honour meant a lot to &amp;laquo;the ones who serve&amp;raquo; (Samurai) and warriors would often ride up to the enemy ranks before a battle, challenging a worthy opponent to a duel. Duels could also be fought by appointment or over the smallest of insults. It was a time when life could come to an end very suddenly, be it by disease, famine or war, and this uncertainty partially shaped the attitude towards death and an honourable way to face it. Nevertheless, it was also a period during which social barriers were not yet as fixed and impenetrable as Toyotomi Hideyoshi would make them by the end of the 16th century -- an ambitious, driven man with some loyal retainers could conquer a province or even forge an empire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game does not require a lot of miniature figures, dice, rule books and expansions. To get started, 10-50 Ashigaru, Ninja, Peasants, Samurai and Sohei to represent a hero's Kashindan, about 10 six-sided dice (D6) and the aforementioned rules and game accessories are enough to drench your Katanas (Japanese swords) in blood. The army creation process allows a wide variety of styles to be played and the opportunity to adapt the commander to a player's personal style, whether you prefer to shoot arrows from a distance or to wield a Naginata in close combat. Although the author had the Heian/Kamakura period from 1000-1300 AD in mind, figures from up to the Sengoku Jidai (warring states) era should work as well with some historic laxity, as long as no firearms or face masks with beards are used.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game was written by a gamer for gamers, and while the use of a turn deck may not be unheard of, a small random factor and not always being able to move all figures add a level of tactics that offers challenges similar to the unforeseen influences that affect the outcome of every battle in real life. The game mechanics are deliberately kept reasonably simple to allow both new and veteran players alike to get into the game quickly. Not having to read through half a dozen Warhammer tomes means that scenarios can be played in different ways to allow for the improvement of one's approach or a revanche after switching sides within a reasonable amount of time, usually around an hour.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2007" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1070" value="Renaissance" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="28732" value="Theme: Samurai" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="90038" value="Jez Fairclough" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="29106" value="Adrian Walters" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="32217" value="Lupus Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>