<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="197903">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Unholy Upheaval" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Unholy Upheaval is a game that takes place in the Kingdom of Axios. Four sages, drawn by a mysterious power, accidentally disrupt the harmony of the forces behind the manifest world. Unwittingly they freed a great and terrible power, Orono. The sages recognized their mistake, but were hastily locked away by the knights of the Kingdom. With no one left to stop Orono, the Ancient Forces who formed Axios, must now gain back the loyalty of their creation and return harmony to the kingdom.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Unholy Upheaval players take the role of one of the 4 Ancient Forces of Axios. Using what limited resources they have, players must gain back the loyalty of their creation and take the power back from Orono. Whoever can acquire the most of Orono&amp;rsquo;s fragments will take the place as the dominant force once harmony is returned to Axios.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The playstyle of Unholy Upheaval is deck-building with minor PvP elements. Each player starts with a starter set of 10 cards and 0 fragments. They utilize their starter cards to build a more powerful deck from a common pool of available cards, the Aether.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The playing take turns playing and purchasing cards. Each turn follows the followng structure:&amp;#10;1. Check for any relic effects in your battlefield and perform their actions.&amp;#10;2. Play cards from your hand. Each card will provide either resources (Loyalty, Rage, Fragments)or provide powerful effects. Play Minions to your battlefield face up, and Relics into your opponent&amp;rsquo;s battlefields face up. Resolve all text on each card before playing another card.&amp;#10;3. Use loyalty to acquire Minions and Relics from the Aether. Defeat Shards from the Aether with rage, and gather Fragments from the supply as indicated on each card.&amp;#10;4. Once you have finished acquiring and defeating cards, place all Minion cards played this turn (that are not haunted) face up in your Discard Pile and draw 5 new cards from your deck (if you need to draw a card and cannot, simply shuffle your discard pile to create a new deck.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unholy Upheaval ends when the last Fragment is taken from the pool and the round is complete. This way every player has the same number of turns. Players can still earn Fragments after the last one is taken.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player counts the Fragments in their pool then adds that to fragment value of the cards in their deck. This number is represented by the fragment symbol in the upper right hand corner of Minions. Relics and Shards do not count towards your score at the end of the game. The player with the most total Fragments is the winner. In case of ties the player with the most relics in their deck is the winner&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="75" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="75" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="90572" value="Steven Machnik" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="32521" value="Quantum Earth Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>