<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="198629">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/LxiTpWgWuNc7Nw0W6qahiQ__thumb/img/ZZszXOA6W-jvAClnMlCMp7L5m6s=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3146031.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/LxiTpWgWuNc7Nw0W6qahiQ__original/img/54mpiFPw2C4WqerUp5yGUp-GT5w=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3146031.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Revolution &amp; Empire" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the publisher:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Authored by three of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading rules designers and Napoleonic historians, Revolution &amp;amp; Empire marks an exciting new approach to grand-tactical miniatures gaming in the Age of the French Revolution and Napoleon (1792-1815). Refight the legendary battles of the period&amp;ndash;Castiglione, Rivoli, Marengo, Austerlitz, Friedland, Borodino, Salamanca, Ligny, Waterloo&amp;ndash;with this meticulously researched rules manual.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Revolution &amp;amp; Empire players take the role of the great commanders of the period such as Napoleon, Wellington, Blucher, Charles, Suvorov, Mass&amp;eacute;na, and Lannes. Draw up your preliminary battle-plans in hopes of achieving your own decisive victory and watch as subordinates carry it to fruition. Revolution &amp;amp; Empire reflects the intense friction of war during this era, as billowing smoke and thunderous cannonades obscured the battlefield and increased the intense confusion and pressures of battle, and even the best plans can go awry by the accidents of war. Skillful management of reserves plays a decisive role in determining the outcome, as fresh troops must be carefully preserved to respond to the inevitable crisis of the battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the tactical level, players performing as division and corps commanders are faced with mastering the interaction of combined arms. No other period of history presents such a balance, as each arm&amp;rsquo;s strengths and weaknesses are dramatically highlighted. Perhaps as no system before, Revolution &amp;amp; Empire demonstrates the evolution of tactics throughout the entire period, from the demise Frederick the Great&amp;rsquo;s linear style of warfare to the development of a new tactical system for a new age. With Revolution &amp;amp; Empire, players will also foster a new appreciation for the brilliant tactics of generals like Wellington and Davout, men who won astonishing victories against staggering odds.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Revolution &amp;amp; Empire is also a valuable historical reference, as hundreds of generals and units are rated on their performance during the period in order to reflect their historical capabilities. Comprehensive rules reflect the many salient aspects of Napoleonic and Revolutionary combat, including massed skirmishers, grand batteries, fatigue, savage town fighting, bridge assaults, weather, and ammunition supply. Whether re-fighting the famous battles, or recreating the scores of smaller actions from the period, Revolution &amp;amp; Empire elegantly reflects warfare in this fascinating and turbulent period of military history.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1051" value="Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="24336" value="Empire" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2957" value="Scotty Bowden" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2973" value="P. Matthew DeLaMater" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="25693" value="Todd Fischer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1555" value="The Emperor's Press" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="7" />
			<average value="8.28571" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.82946" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="12" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>