<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="201912">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/CNZocobaWuiK963E9Vuw6g__thumb/img/pNlodY8POlECahkF1GX6d_JF9lM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3055879.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/CNZocobaWuiK963E9Vuw6g__original/img/WWWVFa04-12GNt4zug2pLvgL4to=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3055879.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="King &amp; Parliament" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The conflict between King Charles I and Parliament had come to an irreparable breach by the time the King raised his royal standard at Nottingham. There was now war between the King and his Parliament and the country was divided in its loyalties. The Royalists, who favor the King&amp;rsquo;s cause, begin the war with many excellent troops and an advantage in cavalry troops, but have initial limited financial support from mostly towns and castles. Parliament starts with a somewhat reliable force in the London Trained Bands and a more solid financial backing from most of the kingdom&amp;rsquo;s cities, but initial cavalry and leaders do not inspire confidence. Of course, the fortunes of war can change these circumstances over time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Two Player game refighting what is often referred to as the First English Civil War. This Renaissance conflict is often identified in the &amp;ldquo;Pike and Shot&amp;rdquo; category, since musketeers fought around blocks of pike men for protection from cavalry. &amp;#10;     Troop Types are represented with abstract counters. Infantry counters denote up to 1500 men and cavalry units represent up to 1000 men. There are units of dragoons and artillery trains as well. Special and elite units are also represented, such as the Northern Horse, Cornish Infantry, Lifeguards, and Hasselrigg&amp;rsquo;s Lobsters. Both sides can also press Levies into service when necessary. &amp;#10;     Game Boards display a map of England and most of Scotland. It is hex based with terrain within each and many prominent towns, cities, manor houses and castles are portrayed. Some of these locations have high fortification ratings and some do not. Necessary playing tables are located on the board for ease of play and necessary reference charts are provided to assist the players.  &amp;#10;     Noteworthy Commanders are represented in the game, with holding boxes for leaders of larger armies. &amp;#10;     Multiple Scenarios to play depending on when players want to begin and how long they want to play.  &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Features&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Leader Driven - Play is divided into turns, but players move alternately, sometimes one going before the other a few times depending on circumstances. Leaders are the core to the game system with all actions being mostly conducted by them. Leaders have ability ratings for strategy and battle. Some also have special characteristics peculiar to them such as Impetuous, Financial Resources, Cavalry Commander, etc.  &amp;#10;     Multiple Events Combination - These continuously have an effect on the game. This is provided by a combination of the turn chart, a random events table, and event counters. Event counters are played immediately on locations, leaders, or units and at times are deployed by the choice of a player. &amp;#10;     Strategy Counters - These can be rolled for by leaders, and the larger their rating the better. This provides some uncertainty as well as advantages and disadvantages as appropriate to each case. Strategy counters can be played immediately or held for the duration of the turn for opportune moments.&amp;#10;     Variable Combat System - Each side has a respective Battle Deck to add more panache to the Combat Result Table (CRT). The CRT gauges results based upon the size of the battle, so it is not one size fits all. &amp;#10;     Scotland Shown - Many games on the English Civil War focus solely England and Wales. The necessary parts of Scotland are shown here to include the effects of Montrose&amp;rsquo;s campaign on the war.&amp;#10;     Attractive Coin Counters - Provided to help track paying for the cost of war.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="16" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2725" value="Pike and Shot" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3331" value="Philip Sharp" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>