<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="203239">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rat Rod Race" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Rat Rod Race is a unique and fun new board game for all the family. It was designed to provide a more tactile and interactive experience for the players with a retro vintage style to match the theme. The game is a crossover which incorporates elements of traditional board games, card games, racing games and component building.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are two playing boards in the game, featuring a Junkyard and a Dragstrip.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;THE JUNKYARD&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players begin by stocking the junkyard board with all the parts for the Rat Rods. There are 4 disassembled vehicles whose components each have their own area. You choose where to place them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once the Junkyard has been stocked, players roll a dice to see who goes first and begin moving their tokens around the board, collecting all the necessary parts to build their vehicles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are four male and four female mechanic character tokens, allowing any combination of players. Parts must be collected in order, however players can choose which path to take to reach their favourite ones first. Depending upon which direction a player chooses to take, it will lead them to different types and styles of car parts within each category.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The aim is to get the parts you want first, before the others collect them. Different body types, different engines, blower styles and different wheel designs means loads of possible combinations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player that finishes their car first, takes pole position on the Dragstrip Board. As each of the other players finish, they take up the remaining positions in order. Positions on the grid determine the order of turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;THE DRAGSTRIP&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is where the real race begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The highly detailed Dragstrip Board is one of the largest made, with interchangeable sections to make it as short or long as you want. It can be assembled to almost 3m in length.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The road ahead is filled with potential dangers, with an extra element where players get to place hazard cones at strategic locations to try and stop the other players from winning the race. Every time a player lands on a road hazard or cone, they draw an action card from the deck which could delay them, send them back or forward, or other unexpected outcomes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Potential hazards along the way include potholes, radar traps, toxic chemical spills, oil slicks, loose car parts, and even quake damage. Remember too, that this is the Extraterrestrial Highway...so you never know what you might encounter during the race.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every time a player lands on a Hazard space, they take a card from the Action deck. Sometimes it's good news, sometimes it's bad!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 30 different Action Cards included in the game, with a little humour thrown in, and all with a unique Retro look.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;We also wanted to bring back the old school fun of a game spinner, so we've designed a custom &amp;quot;Speed Dial&amp;quot; which has multiple 10, 20 and 30 MPH markings on it. Each of these correspond with the gear you are in, 1st, 2nd, or 3rd, and players move one to three spaces accordingly.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="92847" value="James Colmer" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="92847" value="James Colmer" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="33280" value="Gremlin Game Studio" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>