<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="20569">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Space Barons" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>(Description based on prototype.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Space Barons is a quick game of trading space commodities, with commodities and thematic elements found in Felithian Finance, another Tom Wham unpublished game.  The theme includes many funny elements, such as the green eggs which could hatch, resulting in a fight against the awful green things from outer space :-)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Inventory: map showing star systems and connections between them; rocket ship pawns, home base pawns, transporters (similar to monopoly houses), galactic credits (money chits), 4&amp;quot;&amp;times;6&amp;quot; spaceship card with subsidiary engine and cargo hold cards, deck of delivery cards, deck of insurance cards, two six-sided dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players begin by selecting a spaceship dealer and rolling two six-sided dice, then buying one of the available spaceships.  They then build their home base (which doubles as a permanent transporter), selecting a star system from the map.  Each star system has a cost to build, ranging from 10-50, which indicates the value and number of deliveries that can be made to that system.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On each turn, players are dealt two delivery cards, which specify a cargo and three destinations, varying in value.  The cargo is automatically available at the system where the player's rocket pawn is located.  The player may keep as many cards as their spaceship has cargo holds, freely selecting between new cards and previously retained cards.  On a player's turn, they may move their rocket pawn a number of systems equal to the number of engines on their spaceship.  Upon arrival at a system specified by their cards, they are paid for the cargo.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are no restrictions on arrival at a system.  However, to depart from a system a player must possess a matter transporter at that system, or pay another player to rent their transporter.  If no transporter is present, the player must build one on a later turn in order to move.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During the game, players choose from a limited number of special actions, such as upgrading ships, building new transporters, advertising (to receive two extra delivery cards) or simply taking money (the least appealing option).  Only one special action may be taken each turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Random events are included in the delivery deck.  Some of these can result in loss of spaceship or transporter, or devaluing of cargo.  A player may buy an insurance policy, partially covering the cost of losing a ship or transporter.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The delivery deck has a reshuffle card.  Upon reshuffling, an end-of-game card is added to the delivery deck.  The player with the most money when the end-of-game card is revealed wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2005" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="126" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="127" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="128" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="129" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="130" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1113" value="Space Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1011" value="Transportation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="46" value="Tom Wham" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="4" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>