<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="205689">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xjtwq_YWsiGDK8ydnbAKCg__thumb/img/QAVTLJtzvLWypUBenNkyuci3oLk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3126245.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xjtwq_YWsiGDK8ydnbAKCg__original/img/XGGsTNPKXQOUp2eo6yq3iEluaN0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3126245.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Merchants of the Sea" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Description from the designer:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Hello Captain! We've got some new worlds to explore!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play solo, with others (up to 4 players) in coop style or against each other. Goal? Collect and earn the most Golden Coins when the last Merchant Ship arrives at his destination! This could take between 60 to 180 minutes. Depends a lot on how you play it! Playing pirate style? Possible! More into trading? Possible too! Or perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re a sneaky bastard and let your opponent drift of the corner of the Earth. Haven&amp;rsquo;t you heard it? The Earth is flat and you could fall off..&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every player starts with his/her own player card and a big empty table ready to explore new Islands to buy and sell goods (Silk, Coffee, etc). With the profits you buy upgrades to sail faster, turn sharper, become more devastating with better canons, upgrade the amount of goods you could hold and much more! Conquer the game controlled Merchants ships (up to 4) en bring them back to a safe haven. Collect their goods and earn even more Golden Coins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every player needs to sail upwind or at max with crosswind and depending on their speed marker placing their little ship marker 1 or more tiles further away. They pick randomly new tiles and place them adjacent around their ship. You will find probably more sea tiles (160+!) or maybe a new Island (up to 5)? Who knows! A fact is: no game is the same!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Don&amp;rsquo;t like the wind direction? Well, pay for it (in a auction) and change it! It comes with a flaw though: you&amp;rsquo;re sitting duck the next part of this round&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Remember: The player with the most Golden Coins wins in the end! Be wise to spend not all of your Golden Coins with upgrades/goods. You&amp;rsquo;re not the first to win with just a few Golden Coins ;-)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Description from the designer (Dutch):&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Welkom aan boord Kapitein. Je gaat nieuwe werelden ontdekken, handel drijven en de piraat uithangen!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Neem als speler een eigen overzichtsbord en plaats de markers op de getallen binnen de blauwe balken. Zoals je ziet heeft jouw schip de mogelijkheid om Suiker, Specerijen, Koffie, Zijde en Slaven te vervoeren.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Maar hoe goed kan jij de wind bevaren? Tegen de wind in kom je geen steek verder! En alleen met zijwind of meewind kom je vooruit.  Want dat moet je, je moet winst maken om jouw schip te verbeteren om uiteindelijk zo veel mogelijk goudstukken over te houden aan het einde van het spel als alle koopvaardijschepen binnen zijn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Kies een plek op de tafel waar vandaan jouw schip zal vertrekken (de jongste speler begint en daarna met de klok mee). Deze thuishaven beschermt je tegen anderen en daar kun je goudstukken veilig opslaan. Echter kun je in jouw thuishaven niets kopen, verkopen of upgraden. Geef de windrichting een slinger en kies de windrichting naar het Noorden, Zuiden, Oosten of Westen die het meest in de buurt komt&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Door jouw onervarenheid als Kapitein mag je jouw schip in het begin maar steeds 1 veld verder zetten. Met upgrades zal je sneller en wendbaarder worden. Iedere keer nadat je jouw schip hebt verplaatst leg je direct daar omheen nieuwe zeetegels en ontdek je misschien wel nieuwe eilanden met een haven. Aangekomen bij een haven worden op de eilandenkaart bijgehouden welke goederen gekocht en verkocht kunnen worden en voor welke prijs. Met goudstukken koop je upgrades in de havens die je aandoet. Besteed dus niet meteen al je goudstukken aan vracht!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Maar je bent niet alleen op zee&amp;hellip; Er varen ook andere piraten rond en misschien zelfs schijterige koopvaardijvaarders met interessante waren&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Een spel om alleen of met anderen om samen (of tegen elkaar) te strijden!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1008" value="Nautical" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1090" value="Pirates" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>