<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="205623">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/psIsuRNCim7P5VZH_nExHQ__thumb/img/T3rL3EGCturjQIyLBoG9DJRE788=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3124543.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/psIsuRNCim7P5VZH_nExHQ__original/img/rLX89L4yfgc2ReaKP-WP3u_F19g=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3124543.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Wolven" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You know the drill.  &amp;#10;Werewolves terrorize the villagers by night.  Fear crazed villagers run around lynching each other during the day and exercising secret powers in the darkness.  Blah, blah, blah.  &amp;#10;It&amp;rsquo;s all so deliciously clich&amp;eacute; it makes you want to laugh out loud.&amp;#10;Except that you, the Slayer, have a secret.&amp;#10;After a particularly rowdy night at the local tavern last Friday, you woke up with stiff joints and a set of unexplained claw marks down your back.  Ever since, you&amp;rsquo;ve been plucking your   eyebrows twice a day and craving rare steak.  Once, you even caught yourself trying to scratch behind your ear.  &amp;#10;With your foot.&amp;#10;Last night, you heard howling in the distance and it made the fur&amp;hellip; er&amp;hellip; little hairs on the back of your neck... stand at attention&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Wolven is a solitaire hidden role deduction game in which you (as the Slayer) seek to identify and eliminate the werewolves before they overrun the village&amp;hellip; AND before you sprout fur and claws!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The tokens in Wolven each have a picture of a villager on their front.  Each unique villager has a special ability that aids the player in the process of deduction, earns silver, or helps protect other villagers against the werewolves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The back of most of the tokens show picture of a Peasant, who is a sort of generic villager with a special ability of his own.  A few of the tokens, however, have werewolves on their reverse sides instead.  The object of the game is to identify which villagers have werewolves on the back and eliminate those tokens from play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To spice up the deductive part of the game, one or more of the villagers might also have a Peasant on their front face.  So when you see a peasant on a token, you're not sure if you're looking at the back of a villager token, or the front of a peasant token.  If it's a peasant token,you're not sure if the reverse side is another peasant, or a werewolf!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played by pulling tokens from a bag and viewing only one side, which is placed face up on the table.  You may continue drawing tokens until you decide to stop, or until you place a token that show a werewolf.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You may then spend silver to use the abilities of any of the face up villagers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you stopped drawing tokens before you drew a werewolf, you may then select the token of your choice to remove from the game.  Once it's removed from the game you can look at both sides to determine whether you've eliminated a werewolf or a villager.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If, on the other hand, you didn't stop drawing until a werewolf turned up, the token to be eliminated from play is selected randomly.  Drawing a werewolf also advances a token on the infection track.  If this token ever reaches the end of its track, another werewolf is added to the bag.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In either case, the tokens (other than that which was eliminated) are placed back in the bag and another round begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If, at the end of any round, all of the werewolves have been eliminated, the player wins.  If, however, the werewolves ever outnumber the regular villagers remaining in the game, the player loses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1028" value="Puzzle" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2057" value="Chit-Pull System" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="19564" value="Contests: Solitaire Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="2989" value="Game: Werewolf / Mafia" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="93888" value="Bruce Nettleton" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="93888" value="Bruce Nettleton" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="7.48" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.10526" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="14" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="19" />
			<numcomments value="11" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>