<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="206329">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-ZwbBOddAJgnWu1ZlVKQag__thumb/img/9r7zpNPF67tlf4Qg1zezIdbaLMU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3142426.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-ZwbBOddAJgnWu1ZlVKQag__original/img/Lk4IiMGDs71meWRwZ-l1WfpCp2s=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3142426.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Jukem Basketball" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Setup: Choose a player to be the dealer. The dealer shuffles the deck then deals five cards face down to each player. The dealer places the remaining deck face down near the center of the play area to form a draw pile. The discard pile: During the game, a discard pile will form next to the draw pile as players place cards onto it. Player cannot draw cards from the discard pile. The non-dealer player takes the first turn. Player then alternate turns. Keep paper and a pencil handy to keep track of your scores from quarter to quarter&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On your turn: Make one offensive play (if you can). Place an offensive card (or combination of cards) from your hand face up in the center of the play area. If your opponent plays a defensive card, you do not score. Then take the top card from the draw pile to replace it. This ends your turn. If your opponent does not play a defensive card, he/she says &amp;quot;Take it&amp;quot; You score the points shown on your card(s). Place the card(s) aside, face up into your scoring pile. Then take the top card from the draw pile to replace it. This ends your turn.  If no card in your hand are playable, discard two cards of your choice. Then take the top card from the draw pile to replace it. This ends your turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Offensive plays: On your turn, play one of the following cards, or combination, to try to score points. 2-pointer, 3-pointer and dunk are the cards that can be played.  You may play anyone of these cards to try and score the number of points shown on the card. On the same turn an AND 1 card is played along side any of the three cards to add one point to your score.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Defensive Plays: On your opponent's turn, after your opponent has made an offensive play, you may play a defensive card to block his/her shot. NOTE: the DUNK card is protected against some defensive plays but the JUKEM card is unstoppable.  After blocking your opponent's play, discard both your card and your opponent's card. Your opponent take the top card from the draw pile to replenish his/her hand, then you do the same. This ends your opponent's turn. Defensive cards: BLOCK!, MISS!, 3- Second violation, Brick!, Air Ball! and Technical Foul.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ending the Quarter: When the draw pile runs out, keep taking turns to play as many of your cards as you can. The quarter ends when neither player can make a play or when a player makes a HALF COURT shot. Tally up your score for the quarter and record it on paper. Your opponent does the same. Shuffle all of the cards thoroughly, then play the next quarter the same way you played the previous quarter. The player who did not deal in the previous quarter deals in the new quarter.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to win: &amp;#10;When the fourth quarter ends, the game is over and player tally their total points. The player with the highest score wins. &amp;#10;Overtime: In case of a tie, play another quarter to determine the winner. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="44186" value="Series: Jukem Sports" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5574" value="Sports: Basketball" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5665" value="Haywire Group" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="6" />
			<average value="5.105" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.50514" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="17" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>