<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="206328">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mia_DQupx-OpvfHFI3P7DA__thumb/img/zyosR7eSzCRTrZW4pj2Gvb_6a7I=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3142419.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mia_DQupx-OpvfHFI3P7DA__original/img/BXhJV3AZH6FeKmbpZ8zqqzDzx_Q=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3142419.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Jukem Football (Second Edition)" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Setup: Choose a player to be the dealer. The dealer shuffles the deck, then deals four card face down to each player. The dealer places the remaining deck face down in the center of the play area to form the draw pile, then turns the top card face up beside the draw pile to start the discard pile. The other player takes the first turn and players then alternate turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On Your Turn: Replenish your hand to five cards. You can replenish from the draw pile and/or the discard pile, but you can only draw one card ( the top card) from the discard pile per turn.  Make one offensive play (if you can) each turn to build your scoring drive. Ann offensive play is either a RUN card or a PASS/CATCH card combination.  If no cards in your hand are playable, discard one card of your choice face up on the discard pile. This ends your turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Offensive Plays:  Build your drive by placing offensive cards face up in front of you in a line, from left to right.  The most common offensive plays are RUN plays, and PASS and CATCH combinations.  There are also some special offensive plays that will add yardage to your drive. You may play any RUN card face up in front of you on any turn to gain the number of yards shown on that card or play a PASS and CATCH combination cards. To make a PASS and CATCH play, first play a PASS card, then play a CATCH card showing any number of yards within that range.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring a touchdown: To score a touchdown, you must have exactly 100 yards on your drive - no more, no less. Each touchdown immediately ends your drive and scores seven points.  As soon as you score a touchdown, stake all of your drive cards in a pile and set it aside to record your score.  This ends your turn. On your next turn you can begin a new drive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Defensive Plays: On your opponent's turn, after your opponent made an offensive play, you may play a defensive card to slow down or even stop his/her drive.  These include Holding! Sack! these stop your opponents drive, while the Fumble and Picked off cards end your drive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Half Time: If you draw the last card from the draw pile, you make as many plays as you can from your hand on that turn. After you've run out of plays, have been stopped by a defensive card, or have scored a field goal or touchdown, the half is over. Shuffle all the cards and play the second half the same way you played the first half.  The player who did not deal in the first half deals in the second half.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to win: When the second half ends, the game is over. The player with the most points wins. In case of a tie play again until a player scores either a field goal or a touchdown. That play wins the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="176" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="177" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="178" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="179" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="180" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="44186" value="Series: Jukem Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="57775" value="Jukem Football" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="10732" value="Flying Pig Games LLC" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5665" value="Haywire Group" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="14" />
			<average value="5.55357" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.30992" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="25" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>