<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="207075">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7WoFtxpxpufY1Te_qzkZFA__thumb/img/rSrO_fmyJoCRoRNgWy1yzZpJ_kc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3160548.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7WoFtxpxpufY1Te_qzkZFA__original/img/x6Yk7B6_84WY0I4sV-gjBt-i0XM=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic3160548.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Beer! The Outrageously Fun Drinking Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The hilarious card game where you assign drinks, steal from others, have blackouts and even an occasional drunken hookup. Beer! also tests your knowledge with crazy categories like Types of Liquor, Cartoon Dogs, and Excuses for Not Making Love. If you win, you get to assign LOTS of drinks to the other players!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RULES&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Object: To end a game with the highest cumulative number of drinks on the drink cards in your hand&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup: Deal each player five cards. Place the rest of&amp;#10;the deck face down in the center of the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play: A player begins a turn by either &amp;quot;knocking&amp;quot; (see below) or by playing a card After a card is played, take the appropriate action, then the player draws a replacement card. The player to the left of the dealer takes the first turn and play continues clockwise around the table. Stack the played cards in a pile face up next to the draw pile&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Card Values: If you play a drink card (One, Two Three, Four, or Six Drinks), assign that number of drinks to a player. Play a Social card and everyone drinks. For Blackout, select a player to lose a turn. If you play Steal, take a card from the player of your choice. (Don't look at the other player's hand and she draws a replacement card, you do not.) For the Drunken Hookup card, you select two players who either kiss or drink three drinks each (they decide)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Category Cards: If you play a category card, select one of the categories on the card and announce it to the group. Players then take turns naming items that fit into that category. You name the first item, then continue around the table until a player either repeats an item or cannot think of anything else that fits in the category. Allow 10 seconds per turn. The person&amp;#10;making the mistake takes a drink&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Knocking: If a player knocks instead of playing a card, that is the signal that the player wants to end the round. Each player following the knocker gets one last turn, then everyone shows their hands. Add up your cumulative drinks by counting the number of drinks on each drink card in your hand. The player with the highest number wins the round. you knock but do not win, take five penalty drinks. (Note: the round also ends if you reach the end of the deck and no one has knocked.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Assigning Drinks: The winner hands out his drink cards to whomever he chooses. Drink the number of drinks on each card that is given to you. (lf players tie each winner assigns only three drink cards.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="800" value="Kheper Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="8" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>