<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="209518">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/M-MFhz9i-xgQylSjZ9YAGQ__thumb/img/762ebPjZevt_l5trNiMmcQxcLzQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3196358.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/M-MFhz9i-xgQylSjZ9YAGQ__original/img/gepaF9Fvk6k6f8dSIp_-unx3eUU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3196358.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="G.M.O.ooh!" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You&amp;rsquo;re a Scientist, Salesperson, CEO, Inventor, and Promoter trying to dominate the market and survive the dystopian world of G.M.O.ooh!  Real-life Genetically Modified Organisms are intermingled with bizarre, advanced innovations to create a card game filled with laughs, debate, and fantasy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;G.M.O.ooh!&amp;rsquo;s key game mechanic involves debating the merits of the futuristic Organisms across a many of dimensions.  These unique factors lead to one-of-a-kind, creative discussions.  Only one G.M.O.ooh! Card survives per round.  The player with the last remaining G.M.O.ooh! Card wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each G.M.O.ooh! Card is a futuristic genetically modified organism, including background information and data on 5 Categories.  Each Category has a Description and a Rating number.  The Categories are Profit, Cost, Environmental Impact, Demand, and Risk.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each Challenge Card allows a player to Challenge and overtake the Current Leader.  Red Challenge Cards involve adding or subtracting Rating points or changing the Category.  Blue Challenge Cards allow the player to debate the Current Leader across 11 Debate types: Category Challenge (5 different Categories), Survive, Mate, Sales Pitch, Danger, Act, Fight, Outsmart, Race, Outgrow, and Looks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This description primarily covers the Basic Game.  The full details of the Advanced Game version are included in the instruction booklet.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup: Deal all of the G.M.O.ooh! Cards face down to each player.  This is the players Stack.  Players do not look at the cards in their stack until the top card is played.  Deal 3 Challenge Cards to each player face down.  Players can hold and view their Challenge Cards and also replenish up to 3 after each round.  The Dealer starts with the Current Leader Dial and the Dealer Button.  The Current Leader Dial acts as a scorekeeper for the Category and Rating within the current round and also denotes who the Current Leader is.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each round within a game includes 2 phases: G.M.O.ooh! Card phase and Challenge Card phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;G.M.O.ooh! Card phase &amp;ndash; This phase establishes the Current Leader.  The dealer introduces the G.M.O.ooh! Card, choses a Category, and states the Rating.  All players then reveal their Rating in that Category.  The player with the highest rating in the Category chosen becomes the Current Leader and announces their Card if necessary.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Challenge Card Phase &amp;ndash; Starting clockwise, the Current Leader then Checks for Challenges.  Players can then play a Challenge Card to attempt to become the new Current Leader.  There is a limit of 1 Challenge per player per round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Red Challenge Cards may result in an immediate change of Current Leader.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Blue Challenge Cards require a debate.  The Challenger first states their case, the Current Leader then defends.  A final phase allows all players at the table to ask questions or lobby before all players vote.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Voters should consider creative use of data provided on each G.M.O.ooh! Card when casting their vote.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Challenger must have at least 1 extra vote (A tie goes to the Current Leader).  The Challenge Phase then continues clockwise until all players have had 1 chance to Challenge.  A feature in the Advanced Game version allows players to pass and still Challenge in the same round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Current Leader when all challenges have been exhausted or one full pass around the table has been completed wins the round and moves their G.M.O.ooh! Card to their Winners Pile.  All losers in the round discard their G.M.O.ooh! Card to the Losers Pile in the center of the table.  In the Advanced Game version, players can Steal or Re-incarnate lost G.M.O.ooh! Cards using Yellow Challenge Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pass the Dealer Button to the left and continue with a new round.  When a player&amp;rsquo;s Stack is depleted, their shuffled Winners Pile becomes their new Stack.  A player is out of the game when they lose their last G.M.O.ooh! Card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the last remaining G.M.O.ooh! Card wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2017" value="Voting" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="95207" value="Jon Pawelko" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="95350" value="John Ashton Golden" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="95351" value="Jimmy Hasse" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="95352" value="Joshua Wright (II)" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="34229" value="Lampoon The System" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="9.33333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.471405" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>