<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="210645">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jkt3SdY7vEeh4rg1f2krUg__thumb/img/CST2MFKmXzOwCuY6uLKMpvoaQVI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5244992.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jkt3SdY7vEeh4rg1f2krUg__original/img/yJP53nQB0ycmiSYeOQBaSaB5Eic=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5244992.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dungeon Hack: The Dice Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Synopsis:&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;You are a party of stalwart adventures looking for riches and glory albeit you&amp;rsquo;ve never actually explored a dungeon or fought monsters.  You&amp;rsquo;ve been traveling the roads for days, haggard and worn, you find yourself in a small quite town that seems almost abandoned.   You make your way to the local inn and settle down for a nice hot meal when suddenly the door to the inn bursts open and what looks to be the local blacksmith calls out, &amp;ldquo;Derek&amp;rsquo;s farm on the outskirts of town has been attacked and the entire family has been slaughtered!&amp;rdquo;  Never one to shy away from danger you walk over to the distraught blacksmith and ask about the family and what happened.  He tells you of a giant Red Dragon that has been terrorizing the town; sending out his minions to attack the town folk and raid for supplies.  These monsters seem to be coming from a dungeon just outside of town and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing the town folk can do about it. The blacksmith tells you that he has heard of riches beyond imagination within the dungeon but also monsters of unspeakable evil.   After getting the location of the dungeon entrance you return to your party and talk excitedly about the current situation of the town and the Red Dragon.  Again, never one to walk away from a good adventure, although this would be considered your first, your party agrees to find this dungeon, destroy the dragon and all its minions forever!  &amp;#10;   With everyone in agreement you procure a room for the night and settle in with visions of hundreds of screaming villagers chanting your name and praising your heroisms for killing the mighty red dragon and saving the town.   Yet it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long for a slight chill to run down your spine as your vision turns dark and terrifying with the sight of a massive red dragon and it&amp;rsquo;s all-consuming, breath of molten fire engulfing the entire party and turning everyone to ash!    You quickly shake off the nightmarish vision and tightly close your eyes because tomorrow the adventure of your life begins!&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dungeon Hack &amp;ndash; The Dice Game: is a Solo Dice chucking, Dungeon crawling, Dice Placement, character advancing, card game.  You&amp;rsquo;ll take [4] first-time adventurers&amp;rsquo; [Fighter, Cleric, Thief, and Wizard] through a randomly generated dungeon with Rooms, Junction Rooms, Corridor Rooms and Corridors.   You&amp;rsquo;ll have to organize your party with two characters in front and two in back just how you would normally travel in a 10&amp;rsquo; wide dungeon corridor.  The [4] &amp;ldquo;Multi-level&amp;rdquo; Character cards allow YOU to decide your party&amp;rsquo;s order. This creates Front Line attackers/defenders as well as second line defenders.  Your characters will advance to the next level once they&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated enough experience killing monsters. &amp;#10;You&amp;rsquo;ll explore dungeon corridors and rooms, fight monsters, try to avoid and disarm traps, discover gold and magical items, and complete quests.  Each turn you will roll the dice, evaluate your choices and perform your actions; destroying monsters, resolving traps and traveling deeper and deeper into the depths of the dungeon till you finally reach the ultimate goal &amp;ndash; The Giant Red Dragon.&amp;#10;If you can stay alive and escape the dungeon with at least three of your party members, you earn the right to live as heroes; enjoying the spoils of victory. &amp;#10;Lose two or more of your party and you lose the game; becoming the next tragic story told at the local inn of a group of intrepid heroes seeking adventure and glory who never returned from the Red Dragon dungeon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;NOTE:  I would like to thank Tony Go for creating his game Deep Space D6 which not only inspired me to create Dungeon Hack but has help in some of the game play mechanics.  I have been given the ok from Tony Go to use some of the game mechanics within Dungeon Hack: The Dice Game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="59218" value="Category: Dungeon Crawler" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="73039" value="Category: Print-on-Demand" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="57049" value="Joseph Propati" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="83938" value="Nicoleta Stavarache" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51380" value="Medieval Man Publishing" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="17" />
			<average value="8.17647" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.54293" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="41" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="7" />
			<wishing value="109" />
			<numcomments value="33" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>