<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="213314">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/x06h8ibRfkB0tAv0O5VfmQ__thumb/img/eOoq0j3TpJu3qHhoEORoXzRvuaM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3315240.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/x06h8ibRfkB0tAv0O5VfmQ__original/img/bD5It1lmxxcVlbbFf9Qb45SNqNQ=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic3315240.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Jungla" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>An exciting game in which you must face the dangers of the jungle, to be the richest explorer. Explorers will go through the jungle in search of &amp;quot;Eldorado&amp;quot;. They will enter villages, cross rivers and confront beasts and tribes that will try to ensure that their expedition does not end well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player starts the game with a character board, which indicates the initial abilities of this, as well as the life he has in each moment. He also receives a pawn of his color and a tent of his color.&amp;#10;During the game, each player can find cards that help them improve their skills or increase their lives.&amp;#10;The forest is represented by 73 tiles that are initially face down in the center of the table, we will turn them when we go exploring them, and a river that we must cross to go to the different zones of the forest.&amp;#10;During the turn of each player can choose between three actions:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Explore the jungle; He moves his pawn to an adjacent tile, and turns it face-up. Once you have seen the type of tile, you must steal a card from the corresponding deck and solve it with a dice roll, which depends on the skill you have.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Recover territory explored; You can move your pawn by adjacent tiles from one to three, as long as they are scanned.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Getting a camp; If your pawn has been placed in an abandoned camp tile, you can place your camp there by placing the tent of your color on this tile. You can change the location of your camp as many times as you want throughout the game. (This helps you when you contract a disease of the forest, since you must go to this camp to receive the treatment and to be able to continue playing)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to be the explorer with more gold in his power when the game ends. The end of the game, occurs immediately when some explorer finds the mythical city of Eldorado, the player who finds it will receive a bonus of 10 gold coins.&amp;#10;You will also receive a bonus of 4 gold coins, the most cursed explorer you have surpassed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But beware, if a player is cursed when the game is over, he can not be a winner even if he is the one who has made the most money !!! So try to overcome the curses that you fell as soon as possible.&amp;#10;                        &amp;#10;                          *   *   *&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Un trepidante juego en el que debes enfrentarte a los peligros de la selva, para ser el explorador m&amp;aacute;s rico. Los exploradores recorrer&amp;aacute;n la jungla en busca de &amp;quot;Eldorado&amp;quot;. Entraran en poblados, cruzaran r&amp;iacute;os y se enfrentaran a bestias y tribus que intentar&amp;aacute;n que su expedici&amp;oacute;n no termine bien.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cada jugador comienza la partida con un tablero de personaje,en el que indica las habilidades iniciales de este, as&amp;iacute; como la vida que tiene en cada momento. Tambi&amp;eacute;n recibe un pe&amp;oacute;n de su color y una tienda de campa&amp;ntilde;a de su color.&amp;#10;Durante la partida, cada jugador puede encontrar cartas, que le ayuden a mejorar sus habilidades o a incrementar sus vidas.&amp;#10;La selva est&amp;aacute; representada por 73 losetas que inicialmente est&amp;aacute;n bocabajo en el centro de la mesa, las iremos girando cuando las vayamos explorando, y un r&amp;iacute;o que debemos cruzar para ir a las diferentes zonas de la selva.&amp;#10;Durante el turno de cada jugador puede elegir entre tres acciones:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Explorar la jungla; Desplaza su pe&amp;oacute;n a una loseta adyacente, y la vuelve boca arriba. Una vez visto el tipo de loseta, debe robar una carta del mazo correspondiente y resolverla mediante una tirada de dados, que depende de la habilidad que posea.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Recorrer territorio explorado; Puedes desplazar tu pe&amp;oacute;n por losetas adyacentes de una a tres, siempre y cuando est&amp;eacute;n exploradas.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-Colocar un campamento; si tu pe&amp;oacute;n se haya situado en una loseta de campamento abandonado, puedes situar all&amp;iacute; tu campamento situando sobre esta loseta la tienda de campa&amp;ntilde;a de tu color. Puedes cambiar la ubicaci&amp;oacute;n de tu campamento tantas veces como quieras durante toda la partida. (Esto te ayuda cuando contraes una enfermedad de la selva, ya que deber&amp;aacute;s ir a este campamento a recibir el tratamiento y poder seguir jugando)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;El objetivo del juego es ser el explorador con m&amp;aacute;s oro en su poder cuando la partida termine. El final de la partida, se produce inmediatamente cuando alg&amp;uacute;n explorador encuentra la m&amp;iacute;tica ciudad del Eldorado, el jugador que la encuentre recibir&amp;aacute; una bonificaci&amp;oacute;n de 10 monedas de oro.&amp;#10;Tambi&amp;eacute;n recibir&amp;aacute; una bonificaci&amp;oacute;n de 4 monedas de oro, el explorador que m&amp;aacute;s maldiciones haya superado.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;iexcl;&amp;iexcl;&amp;iexcl;Pero cuidado, si un jugador est&amp;aacute; maldito cuando la partida acab&amp;eacute;, no podr&amp;aacute; ser ganador aunque sea el que m&amp;aacute;s dinero haya conseguido!!! As&amp;iacute; que intenta superar las maldiciones en que hayas ca&amp;iacute;do lo antes posible.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="96914" value="Santiago Díaz" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="97593" value="Asela Membrives" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="96914" value="Santiago Díaz" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="97593" value="Asela Membrives" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>