<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="21628">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/VnLTAxiG93tR1h5cEENdFA__thumb/img/pndzMW_WHjHsu_zSypcNZGAO1LQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic109189.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/VnLTAxiG93tR1h5cEENdFA__original/img/xgRYa9zFZm4voj-beHmXP6W58Kg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic109189.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="1 on 1 Adventure Gamebooks: Battle for the Ancient Robot" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A one-on-one book game with a sci-fi/adventure theme.  Each player is a champion of their star-faring race, trying to find pieces of the Ancient Robot, a powerful and dangerous artifact of a lost civilization.  The pieces of the Ancient Robot are scattered throughout the galaxy, and the players move from system to system to find them by choosing which page to turn to.  In their quest, they will encounter all sorts of harrowing adventures, battling or befriending strange monsters, collecting strange new items to improve their abilities, and may even run across each other....&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The premise, as described by the books:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A million years before mankind invented fire or the Cybrtrons first oiled their gears, the Ancient Ones ruled the universe. For reasons lost in the mysteries of time, the Ancient Ones channeled all of their galaxy-spanning efforts into the building of one huge robot. There were twenty star systems in the realm of the Ancient Ones, and each one of the twenty was given the task of building one part of the massive robot.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The project was soon completed, the twenty parts constructed. The Ancient Ones had to bring the twenty parts to one central location and assemble the robot. But something went wrong -- perhaps a war between the systems, perhaps attack by some alien race. The Ancient Ones vanished. All that remained were the scattered parts of their robot.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One million years later, two parts of the Ancient Robot were recovered in different areas of the Milky Way galaxy. A team of humans discovered one part of the Ancient Robot in the year 2289 A.D., while exploring the planet Pluto. The Robot provided mankind with the secret of interstellar travel and a star chart marked with the location of the other nineteen parts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the same time, a civilization of robots also discovered a part of the Ancient Robot. Called Cybrtrons, they had overthrown their soft-skinned creators centuries before. They are now determined to rule the galaxy! The Ancient Robot part also gave the Cybrtrons the secret of interstellar travel and a star chart revealing the location of the other nineteen parts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Both civilizations immediately decide to go in search of the Ancient Robot. Records of the Ancient Ones reveal that the Ancient Robot has the capability to design and build technological devices that will advance mankind a thousand years. The Ancient Robot is also capable of destroying anything in its path! With this device, the Cybrtrons know they can conquer the galaxy!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Both civilizations are sending their best pilots into space to search for the Ancient Robot. The Cybrtrons and the humans have become aware of each other. The search for the Ancient Robot has turned into a deadly race.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;YOU are the leader of one of the two groups assigned to find the Ancient Robot!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Part of the series of 1 on 1 Adventure Gamebooks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1985" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="80" />
						               				<minplaytime value="80" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="80" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="86" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="87" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="88" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="89" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="90" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1113" value="Space Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="37" value="Series: 1 on 1 Adventure Gamebooks" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22232" value="Theme: Robots" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1832" value="James M. Ward" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="16" value="Tactical Studies Rules (TSR)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="15" />
			<average value="5.93333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.43604" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="52" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="11" />
			<numcomments value="9" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>