<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="216350">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/0TP9DnIDP9AzwLjfPNWyRw__thumb/img/mox1XrTNq737RbaDIskD6vR3Svc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3531570.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/0TP9DnIDP9AzwLjfPNWyRw__original/img/k8RMEJYF9rFU16D_Ogj9Mg1XusQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3531570.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Glory Gears" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Glory Gears is a historically accurate strategy game where 2 to 8 players control a race team of four riders and compete to be the first team to finish in a single or a series of races.  The game is inspired by Oscar Winning Movie, 'Breaking Away's' Little 500 Bicycle Race at Indiana University and created by Cutters Little 500 Champion Alex Bishop.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Glory Gears is an action packed, fast paced cycling strategy game with dynamic movement mechanics offering the most realistic gaming experience possible.  Besides a game that is incredibly historically accurate and movements that are mathematically correct, Glory Gears offers an amazingly fun play dynamic that evolves as players secretly choose to help others at times while other times breaking their friendships, alliances, and trust as the race draws closer to the end.  Added rules let you battle through wrecks, mechanicals, and secret team strategies while you create friends and foes racing your team of 4 riders around the track. However, as the checker flag approaches, there can only be one Glory Gears Champion!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Glory Gears has a multitude of optional rules and ways to play to ensure your gaming experience can be tailored to your liking. Everything from, rider stamina reductions, wrecks, dropping exchanges, mechanicals, playing out secret historical team strategies based off how specific teams won in certain years, to even playing out the entire spring race series events like in real life before the Little 500 event.  Players can choose to play out a historically accurate Qualifications run(great for 1 to 8 players), an Individual Time Trial(great for 1 to 8 players), and a Team Pursuit which involves all 4 riders of a team on the track racing against another at the same time (great 2 person game), or a fan and tournament favorite of the race series Miss N' Out, which states the last rider of each lap is eliminated until there is only one left! (great big group game)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;More info can be found at www.mindmeltgames.com .  Glory Gears just became available April 21st 2017!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Here is a link to the full rules/ game play suggestions and how to video.  http://www.mindmeltgames.com/how-torules.html&amp;#10;Here is the page page info found on the how to section of www.mindmeltgames.com&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GLORY GEARS RULES AND GAME PLAY SUGGESTIONS - (FROM THE HOW TO SECTION OF WWW.MINDMELTGAMES.COM)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ROOKIES&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TO MAXIMIZE YOUR GLORY GEARS ENJOYMENT AND PROPER SKILL BUILDING AS YOU RACE YOUR WAY TO VICTORY, WE RECOMMEND THE FOLLOWING RACE FORMATS AND RULES TO CERTAIN LEVELS OF PLAYERS.......THIS IS A GREAT PLACE TO START FOR BEGINNERS OR THOSE LOOKING FOR MAXIMUM FUN WITH THE BIGGEST GROUP OR THE SMALLEST GROUP OF PEOPLE IN THE SHORTEST AMOUNT OF TIME......&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RACES SUITABLE&amp;#10;1. MISS N OUT -location in manual 9.7/complexity level 3/learn time 1 min/play time 10-60mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this is the best race to learn the fundamentals and strategies of movement, pack dynamics, and stamina usage.&amp;#10;    this race is also the best for tournaments, and larger groups who want a strategic, intense, fun game in under an hour&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. INDIVIDUAL TIME TRIAL- location in manual 9.9/complexity level 1/learn time 1 min/play time 10 mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this is a great race to learn the fundamentals of the importance of pedal card order usage&amp;#10;    this race also represents the most basic 2 person game in glory gears, however more can play just not at the same time&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3. QUALIFICATIONS - location in manual 9.6/complexity 2/learn time 1 min/play time 5 mins per player&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this is a great race to learn the fundamentals of fast efficient pitting and exchanging of team riders&amp;#10;    this is a 1 rider on the track at a time game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4. TEAM PURSUIT- location in manual 9.8/complexity 3/learn time 1 min/play time 15mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this is a great race to learn the fundamentals of strategic, efficient usage of pace movement cards, stamina usage, and strategic order of rider movement&amp;#10;    this race represents the most strategic 2 person race in glory gears &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5. GLORY GEARS RACE- location in manual 1.0-6.0/complexity 6/learn time 5 mins/play time 20-120mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this is the traditional format for glory gears.  This race is the culmination of all 4 skill sets learned in the 4 previous racing formats.&amp;#10;    this race also includes a new 5th skill set of team strategy cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SEASONED RACERS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These races and rules are geared toward the more race hardened experienced players.  players can start here if they wish, but will find themselves learning a lot each race from all the intricacies and fundamentals of racing and play not gained from the other easier formats.  However, some champions are just born, and may do fine here.....&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6. GLORY GEARS RACE +DROPPED EXCHANGES- location in manual 6.0/complexity 7/learn time 5 mins/play time 20-120mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this race is everything of the previous glory gears race with the added ability to drop or botched the exchange of riders in the pit&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;7. GLORY GEARS RACE W/DROPPED EXCHANGES +MECHANICALS-  location in manual 9.5/complexity 8/learn time 5 mins/play time 30-150mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this race is everything of the previous glory gears race with the added ability to suffer a bike mechanical each lap of the 10 lap race.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;8. GLORY GEARS RACE W/DROPPED EXCHANGES, MECHANICALS &amp;amp; WRECKS- location in manual 7.0/complexity 9/learn time 5 mins/play time 30-180mins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this introduces wrecks, the most game changing and time expending rule&amp;#10;    this race represents the most realistic and complex of the glory gears race formats&amp;#10;    this race is great for those die hard racing and gaming fans, who don't mind a longer game with more steps per turn&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ALL STAR RIDERS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This race format is designed for the true die hard racers and those players looking for the most ultimate epic racing experience!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;9. THE COMPLETE GLORY GEARS RACE SERIES-location in manual 10.0/complexity 10/learn time 10 mins/play time 3hrs-6hrs&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    this race format is the complete game in one big race series&amp;#10;    players race qualifications, individual time trials, miss n out, team pursuit and finally the glory gears race with all rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5663" value="Sports: Bicycling / Cycling" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="98009" value="Alex Bishop" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="36388" value="Mind Melt Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="24" />
			<average value="4.91667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.0265" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="22" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="11" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="2.25" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>