<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="222401">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cCi2AhRqZp3X1w0klsMZWA__thumb/img/xzgEmudHvRUq50kIT4dx0VPmsKo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3708743.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cCi2AhRqZp3X1w0klsMZWA__original/img/22KSK-zl9jiCCk4LDlkyywaIt10=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3708743.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Campus Café" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Life is really busy on a college campus and the only place to really relax is the Cafeteria. This applies to everyone, except for you, since you are working students who served as waiters in the Cafeteria.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player control a waiter with its own asymmetric power, to use to overcome others. At the start of the game the objectives of the Month are revealed (for example, serve the largrest number of Hot Chocolates or the largest number of Professors).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During his turn the player rolls 2 coloured dice, and places them on spaces of the same colour. Special training skills allow you to re-roll the dice or turn a color in to another. Each space, based on the color, allows you to prepare specific drinks (there are 5 drinks on the menu). Once prepared, the player adds the drink to his or her tray: but beware the tray is heavy, so space is limited (some training skills allow you to unlock more space).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of turn, the player can choose to process one (or more, if you have the specific training ability) of the orders backlog on the Game Board: you must have and discard all the drinks shown on the card, get paid the bill ($ are Victory Points) and then pick up the Order Card, and place it in front of you. Specific training skills allow you to get extra tips from particular clients and/or drinks served. Once collected the Order card, the player will be allowed to use the special training ability shown on the card: the experience is always a teacher of life.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At a certain point, the cafeteria closes (there are a fixed number of Orders card to be processed, according to the number of players) and the round is ended, in a way that all players has performed the same number of game turns. A this stage the 'Employee of the Month' prizes are awarded and, who has the most Victory Points ($) is declared the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tipologiy: entry-level Splendor-like (Dice Placement)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;La vita &amp;egrave; veramente intensa in un campus universitario e l'unico posto per rilassarsi &amp;egrave; la Caffetteria. Questo vale per tutti, tranne che per voi, visto che siete studenti lavoratori che servite come camerieri nella Caffetteria.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ogni giocatore dispone di un Cameriere con un proprio potere asimmetrico, da sfruttare al meglio per prevalere sugli altri. Ad inizio partita vengono estratti gli Obiettivi del Mese, fra cui, ad esempio, servire il maggior numero di Cioccolate Calde oppure servire il maggior numero di Professori.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Durante il proprio turno il giocatore tira 2 Dadi colorati, e li colloca su spazi dello stesso colore. Particolari abilit&amp;agrave; formazione consentono di ritirare i dadi o di trasformare un colore in un altro. Ogni spazio, in base al colore, permette di preparare specifiche bibite (vi sono 5 bibite nel men&amp;ugrave;). Una volta preparata, il giocatore aggiunge la bibita al proprio vassoio: ma attenzione il vassoio &amp;egrave; pesante, quindi gli spazi sono limitati (alcune abilit&amp;agrave; formazione permettono di sbloccare pi&amp;ugrave; spazi).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A fine turno il giocatore pu&amp;ograve; scegliere di evadere uno (o pi&amp;ugrave; di uno se ha l'apposita abilit&amp;agrave; formazione) degli ordini inevasi presenti sul Tabellone: deve consumare tutte le bibite indicate, farsi pagare il conto (i $ sono Punti Vittoria) quindi raccogliere la carta Ordine, e piazzarla davanti a se'. Specifiche abilit&amp;agrave; formazione consentono di ottenere mance extra da particolari clienti e/o bibite servite. Da quel momento il giocatore beneficia dell'abilit&amp;agrave; formazione indicata sulla carta: infatti l'esperienza &amp;egrave; sempre maestra di vita.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ad un certo punto la caffetteria chiude (ci sono un numero prefissato di ordini da evadere, in base al numero di giocatori) e si completa il round, in modo che tutti abbiano eseguito lo stesso numero di turni. Quindi sono assegnati i premi Impiegato del Mese. A questo punto, chi ha pi&amp;ugrave; Punti Vittoria ($) &amp;egrave; dichiarato vincitore.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tipologia: per tutti (Piazzamento Dadi)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="94505" value="Pasquale Facchini" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="74905" value="Marina Fischetti" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="53716" value="Bartłomiej Kordowski" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="33007" value="Doppio Gioco" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="64" />
			<average value="6.60313" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.5333" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="13437" bayesaverage="5.5333" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.62066" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="95" />
			<trading value="5" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="33" />
			<numcomments value="15" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>