<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="222813">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/g5JHeE_M5z0riYVTMIG1Pg__thumb/img/1DHSWXT2UZnmSdFby9Z0sPsm2QM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3506110.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/g5JHeE_M5z0riYVTMIG1Pg__original/img/ULjUYQeMJfasmafjmbx1GyiGiGk=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic3506110.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Vigilante" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Your town &amp;mdash; your life &amp;mdash; hasn't been the same since HE came to power. He rules with fear and violence, and no one dares stand up to him. No one but you. Starting with nothing more than righteous indignation, you acquire the training, resources, equipment, and experience needed to take down the Nemesis and get back your life. You move in the shadows. You let nothing and no one stand in your way. You are a vigilante!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Objective:&amp;#10;In Vigilante, the goal is to become the first player to reach 40 Experience Points, then defeat the Nemesis.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player Ability Slots&amp;#10;Your playmat lets you keep track of your progress as you complete your costume. You can have 1 Head Equipment, 1 Body Equipment, 2 Arm Equipment, and 2 Signature Moves/Weapons. If you acquire Equipment, but there is no room for it, you gain the E.P. from it, but then must decide which card will stay on your playmat. The other card is removed from the game. It also states your character bonus. This bonus can be used once every turn and represents your area of expertise.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Turn Overview:&amp;#10;Each turn you will be using your skills (dice) to increase your experience and bring you closer to facing the Nemesis. Each turn consists of three phases:&amp;#10;1) Upkeep Phase.&amp;#10;2) Roll Skill Dice.&amp;#10;3) Use Skill Dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Using Skill Dice:&amp;#10;Once you have finished rolling your dice, you may engage them to further your plans. Dice can be used to Obtain Equipment, Steal Equipment, Discard an Equipment Card, Train, Gain Resources, trade one color of cubes for the other (Focus Intent) Obtain New Skills, or Patrol the City. You can do as many of these actions each turn as your dice will allow, in any order you want. If you cannot or do not want to perform any of these actions, you may just pass your turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game End&amp;#10;The game ends as soon as one player can defeat the Nemesis. To challenge the Nemesis, you must first reach (or pass) the 40 spot on the Experience Point Track. Once this is done, you can challenge the Nemesis. You must declare that you are challenging the Nemesis at the beginning of your turn after the upkeep phase, but before rolling any dice. Move your maker off the board and place it next to the area marked &amp;ldquo;Level One&amp;rdquo; on the Nemesis card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To defeat the Nemesis, you must be able to overcome all three levels on their card. You do not have to overcome all three levels in the same turn. If you overcome a level, you may move your marker to the next level and end your turn. You may also press your luck and attempt to overcome another level. If you do so, you gain the reward from completing the level. You can then re-roll your dice up to three more times, but none of the equipment you&amp;rsquo;ve used so far is refreshed. If you ever fail to complete a level, you lose all of the progress you made this turn and must move your marker back to the level it was on at the beginning of your turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You do not have to challenge the Nemesis each turn after acquiring 40 Experience. You can still use your turns to gain more equipment, experience, or training before attempting to challenge the Nemesis.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1116" value="Comic Book / Strip" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="99961" value="Mike Holyoak" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="597" value="Eagle-Gryphon Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>