<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="22310">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xLq-05phC9sVtOA5kKeS4g__thumb/img/4cpZVoJojFdBYLw7B1Cn7knv3_A=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1517687.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xLq-05phC9sVtOA5kKeS4g__original/img/1kIWtzeYwRGl7noK3x8x_zYy9dA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1517687.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Crescendo Chess" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the box:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;An introduction to an ageless game with a 20th century pace. The game of chess is simple. It is difficult only if you make it so. And Crescendo Chess is as simple as regular chess. It is played by the same rules. The chess men move the same. A full set of rules and instructions that completely cover Crescendo Chess are included. After several moves, you then enter into the exciting world of mobility, power, and cunning. Compounding the power and mobility of the chess pieces accelerates the game and sharpens one's perception of the effects of combining different pieces. Thus one gains a broader insight and a better appreciation of this game. Because of this, Crescendo Chess enhances regular chess.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Crescendo Chess is a new experience for any chess player. By following the rather simple rules, one can soon learn to think in terms of stacking, capturing and position playing. One important feature in Crescendo Chess is that the chess men have a hole on top and one on the bottom that permits pegging one piece atop another. When this is done, it is called &amp;quot;stacking.&amp;quot; A stack of chess men can then move across the board together. One soon learns not to exhaust the stack ineffectively. Experience teaches how to take advantage of the best stacking arrangements for certain types of attack and defense.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In one turn the stack moves first as the bottom piece normally would move as in regular chess, then continues as the next piece up would move, etc. It costs one turn to place a piece on a stack. On the next turn, the stack can make its move (see rule8). To give an example, a Knight can be placed atop a Bishop in one turn. Then, on a later turn, the two together would move the permissible diagonal move of the Bishop and the two together could continue, one - one, two, as the Knight would move.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;It is important that in stacking, the pieces are moved into the stack using their regular move, - that is, a Bishop diagonally, a Rook forward or sideways, etc. Each piece must be free to make its move as in regular chess rules.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Crescendo Chess is so called because it starts as regular chess and then increases in intensity. As stated, the first two moves by each player are made on a regular basis. After that, the next four moves by each player may be made where one piece is stacked on top of another to a two level height.Max. (L2). NOTE: See Glossary &amp;amp; Game Notations at end of rules. It is not necessary to stack the pieces if the player does not wish to do so.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Upon completion of a total of six moves by each player, the pieces may be stacked to a three level height. Max. (L3). This is the stacking limit for the rest of the game. The three can move first as the bottom piece, which then remains, then as the other two would move as a two piece stack.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1973" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="240" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="111" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="112" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="113" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="114" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="115" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="4024" value="Traditional Games: Chess" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="72463" value="Walter J. Dykoski" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5181" value="Strato-Various Products" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4666" name="abstracts" friendlyname="Abstract Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>