<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="224108">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_IJXgegV0l1InLqr5k9I2g__thumb/img/lhrMHHVzSAitd-v0DpOu1jWTonk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3486647.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_IJXgegV0l1InLqr5k9I2g__original/img/M_IpCauEw7-XaHWEMj8E2pUZwa0=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic3486647.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Magus: Aura Mortis" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Magus: Aura Mortis is a re-implementation of Magus: Fortuna et nostis. In Magus, the players embody powerful sorcerers who send heroes under their control to plunder the castle of Ardeth, their mentor, as they crave the treasures and secrets that are hidden there.&amp;#10;In a game the players must fulfill missions and different objectives until obtaining 10 dominion points and thus to proclaim the new lord of the castle. In addition to controlling a hero, the player has spells at his disposal with which he can alter the very structure of the castle.&amp;#10;In a Magus turn, a player can perform up to 2 normal actions (move, attack, play spells, among others) and any number of quick actions (use knowledge, advance missions, use relics, etc.) Each action has a cost that must be paid with energy from one of the two existing wells: Well of power (Green) and Well of control (purple). As the game progresses players will gain energy that they can freely assign to their power or control reserve as needed for one or the other action.&amp;#10;The Magus main play mode is competitive, each player will try to reach before the rest to the 10 dominion points using his hero and his spells to delay the advance of enemies. But there is also the cooperative mode, in which players must defeat the powerful archmage Ardeth. For this they must travel the castle accomplishing different objectives that reduce the dominion of the archmage before he arrives at the castle for the final combat.&amp;#10;In cooperative mode, the Dominion points are the way of measuring Ardeth's strength, which players must reduce as much as possible whilst preparing for his arrival. When the archmage appears in the castle players must face him, and the life of Ardeth will be determined by the dominion gained at the moment of his appearance.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Magus: Aura Mortis es una reimplementaci&amp;oacute;n de Magus: &amp;quot;Fortuna et nostis&amp;quot;. En Magus los jugadores encarnan a poderosos hechiceros que env&amp;iacute;an a h&amp;eacute;roes bajo su control a saquear el castillo de Ardeth, su mentor, ya que ans&amp;iacute;an los tesoros y secretos que all&amp;iacute; se esconden.&amp;#10;En una partida los jugadores deber&amp;aacute;n cumplir misiones y distintos objetivos hasta conseguir 10 puntos de dominio y as&amp;iacute; proclamarse el nuevo se&amp;ntilde;or del castillo. Ademas de controlar a un h&amp;eacute;roe, el jugador tiene conjuros a su disposici&amp;oacute;n con los que podr&amp;aacute; alterar la estructura misma del castillo.&amp;#10;En un turno de Magus un jugador puede realizar hasta 2 acciones normales (mover, atacar, jugar conjuros, entre otras) y cualquier cantidad de acciones r&amp;aacute;pidas (usar saberes, avanzar misiones, usar reliquias, entre otras. Cada acci&amp;oacute;n tiene un costo que debe ser pagado siempre fichas de energ&amp;iacute;a de alguno de los dos tipos existentes. Existe la energ&amp;iacute;a de poder (de color verde) y la energ&amp;iacute;a de control (de color violeta. A medida que avanza la partida los jugadores ir&amp;aacute;n ganando energ&amp;iacute;a que podr&amp;aacute;n asignar libremente a su reserva de poder o de control seg&amp;uacute;n la necesitar para una u otra acci&amp;oacute;n. &amp;#10;El modo principal de juego de Magus es competitivo, cada jugador intentar&amp;aacute; llegar antes que el resto a los 10 puntos de dominio vali&amp;eacute;ndose de su h&amp;eacute;roe y sus conjuros para retrasar el avance de sus enemigos. Pero tambi&amp;eacute;n existe el modo cooperativo, aqu&amp;iacute; los jugadores deben derrotar al poderoso archimago Ardeth. Para ello deben recorrer el castillo cumpliendo distintos objetivos que reduzcan el dominio del archimago antes de que este llegue al castillo para el combate final. &amp;#10;En el modo cooperativo los puntos de dominio miden la fuerza de Ardeth, y los jugadores deben reducirlo lo mas posible mientras se preparan para su llegada. Cuando el archimago aparece en el castillo deben enfrentarlo, y la vida de Ardeth estar&amp;aacute; determinada por la dominio acumulado al momento de su aparici&amp;oacute;n.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="5">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="4" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="80" />
						               				<minplaytime value="40" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="80" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="111" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="112" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="113" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="114" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="115" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1059" value="Maze" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="60627" value="Game: Magus" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="253110" value="Magus: Aura Mortis – El Soplo de la Muerte" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="176487" value="Magus: Fortuna et nostis" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="81891" value="Martín Oddino" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="99728" value="María Luz Cantisani Rovasio" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="99729" value="Lucas Charra" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="35941" value="RunDOS Studio" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="74" />
			<average value="7.53378" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.54987" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="11201" bayesaverage="5.54987" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.75209" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="117" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="15" />
			<numcomments value="15" />
			<numweights value="9" />
			<averageweight value="3.6667" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>