<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="225603">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HWSMPo81CTNk9Fztv7b6nw__thumb/img/OjR9pDZUCQMdUVZjq_7toOIbnFU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7032540.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HWSMPo81CTNk9Fztv7b6nw__original/img/P1GFAkngLe-lN0KNCJUcKi43Nq4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7032540.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Assault Red Horizon 41" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Assault &amp;ndash; Red Horizon 41&amp;#10;&amp;#10;is the first volume in a planned series of tactical level wargames in which players lead historical units into battle during Operation Barbarossa (June through October 1941). A Clash of Titans &amp;ndash; the German Army and the Soviet Army fighting one another in a life and death struggle with infantry, artillery and armored units.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Assault &amp;ndash; Red Horizon 41 is intentionally not intended to be a simulation, but rather it abstracts certain aspects in favor of playability and manageable game length to convey the feeling of comprehensive tactical combat situations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Read more about and find our Kickstarter page here:&amp;#10;Find more: https://www.facebook.com/assaultgamescom&amp;#10;Kickstarter: https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/rh41/assault-red-horizon-41&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Mechanics and rules: &amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Assault Game System is designed to be completely modular and to accommodate a wide range of preferences for those playing it. There are different scenarios that the players can choose from, and within these scenarios, the Order of Battle can vary through the use of Formation Cards. In each scenario, rather than being given a set Order of Battle, the players will randomly select Formation Cards (infantry, artillery, or armor/vehicle) based on the side they are playing.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Formation Cards give the player a certain number and type of units available for the scenario. This ensures both variation and regular surprises, since the make-up of your forces will change from game to game. Your High Command has assigned you certain units to achieve a particular goal; you will have to adjust your individual tactics based on the available units and the objectives you have been given!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Units in the Assault Game System are activated by Command points. Players receive a certain number of Command points, which are listed on the Formation cards. Before Command Phase, players secretly decide (behind a small screen or divider) which units to activate in the current turn. The Command point allowance lets the player activate approximately 75% of all available units. Thus, players must set priorities for the turn. Not only does this speed up the game play, since all units are not used in each turn, but it also makes for some exciting moments in the fight.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the Assault Game System, we have tried to minimize the counter stacking issue. With many game systems in the hobby, you can find towers of counters and markers on certain hexes of the game board. The overview is then quickly lost. In the Assault Game System, there is a clear limit of one unit counter per hex, with the exception being when units in are being transported. In addition, there is usually only one command and/or status marker.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Regarding Command and Unit State Markers, we have devised a simple double-marker system: each marker is double-sided and after the end of the round, in the Organization Phase, the markers are simply flipped or removed depending on their color. This helps to speed up play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In general, Assault has attempted to emphasize game flow. The fact that Command Points are assigned to activate units in the Planning Phase accelerates the game. Since the units to be activated are already established before the Action Phase, there is less for the player to think about and fewer opportunities for AP to set in.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Dynamic Campaign System: &amp;quot;Crossing the Narew&amp;quot; &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;It  is  the  end  of  June  1941,  when  the  German  Wehrmacht  begins  the  largest  land  operation  of  World  War II,  Operation  Barbarossa.  More  than  four  million  German  soldiers  are  in  their  starting  positions  on  the eastern  borders  of  the  German  Reich.  The  strategic  objective  is  the  capital  Moscow.  To  be  successful, the  operation  must  combine  strength  with  speed.  Key  to  this  will  be  seizing  control  the  bridges  that  lie between  the  German  Wehrmacht  and  its  ultimate  prize.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In  this  campaign,  players  take  on  the  role  of  a  company  commander  in  order  to  achieve  victory  for  their own  faction.  Each  serving  in  the  ranks  of  one  of  the  two  divisions  that  took  part  historically,  the  German 7th  Infantry  Division  and  the  Soviet  13th  Rifle  Division. The  campaign  consists  of  four  connected  battles  and  covers  the  period  24-25  June  1941.  This  campaign is  in  line  with  historical  operations  for  crossing  the  Narew  River.  This  crossing  was    important  and  had  to be  achieved  quickly  in  order  to  close  the  town  of  Bialystok  and  the  connected  basin.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Another aspect that sets Assault Red Horizons &amp;rsquo;41 apart from the competition is our Dynamic Campaign Systemwhich will be included in the base game. We have designed a system whereby multiple scenarios can be linked with a variable starting set up for each subsequent scenario dependent upon how many of the victory conditions each side achieves. The players conduct operations, each commanding a company of troops from regiments that actually served on the Eastern Front. The campaign includes 8 different plots for a high replay value.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="3" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="368717" value="Assault Red Horizon 41: TA/OAS Expansion" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameintegration" id="376753" value="Assault Sicily 43" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="100355" value="Wolfgang Klein" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="147472" value="Erich Rankl" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="101474" value="Ingrid Grillenberger" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="150027" value="Michael Grillenberger" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="36101" value="Assault Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="49" />
			<average value="8.57143" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.55205" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="11005" bayesaverage="5.55205" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="1715" bayesaverage="5.88365" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.07855" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="124" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="22" />
			<wishing value="74" />
			<numcomments value="26" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>