<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="227181">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/r2V8V2sEIBfeHcTOiimC0A__thumb/img/QxBOIQ7znH3a4HY9n9hZQ-t5m0o=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3557079.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/r2V8V2sEIBfeHcTOiimC0A__original/img/TUy1vmvfa2dFLnLsXlGDMe57dEs=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic3557079.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Lewt Ninja" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Description from the publisher:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lewt Ninja is a standalone card game that challenges 2 - 5 players to become Epic Fantasy Heroes and find treasure, weapons, armour, and Artifacts from the many monsters they encounter. But beware! Every Hero is out only for themselves and will try to swindle the winnings away from you and the rest of your group. Build your lootstash and take what is yours and theirs before they do. Are you ambitious enough to be the Lewt Ninja!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game Lewt Ninja includes&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1 Monster Deck &amp;ndash; The monster deck consists of 40 unique monsters and Boss monsters, players draw monster cards during the beginning of their turn. Each monster card will direct players to draw loot cards or additional monster cards. Some monster cards will have special rules that will effect players and prevent different player actions from being used during the round&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1 Loot Deck &amp;ndash; The loot deck consists of 58 treasure, weapons, and armor cards. Players will find their heroes armor sets and legendary weapons along with other many treasures needed to collect in order to win the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1 Player Deck &amp;ndash; The Player deck consists of 81 action cards; inside players will find Roll cards used to bid on the loot dropped by monsters. Roll cards have numeric values that simulate dice rolls, the player with the highest roll wins the treasure being rolled on. Along with the roll cards players will also find System and Player Action cards, these cards are used by players to stop players from rolling on treasure or steal treasure away from other players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;10 Player Mats &amp;ndash; The player mats included with Lewt Ninja are 10 different heroes that players will assume the role of during game.  Players can play as either a Mystic, Wizard, Holy Monk, Ranger, or Shield Knight. There are 2 versions of each hero that allow players to play as same class during gameplay.  Each of the classes have special abilities that can be unlocked by obtaining their heroes magic armor. These abilities can be used by a player when they begin the round&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To play Lewt Ninja have each player pick one of the hero class characters. Once everyone has picked a hero remove any armor set cards from the loot deck for any hero classes not in the game. Shuffle the 3 decks and place them in the center of the play area; deal out seven player action cards to all players and choose the player turn order.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lewt Ninja has 3 phases of game play. &amp;#10;At the beginning of the round players will draw one monster from the Monster Deck, this is called Pulling a monster. After pulling the monster the player read aloud the cards rule to everyone; players will then either draw a Loot Card or additional monster card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The second phase of the round called Looting; the player who started the round will draw the number of Loot cards indicated on the card. Players will then play their Roll cards for the treasure dropped by the monster. If more than one loot card has been drawn players will roll only on one item at a time. Roll cards are placed face down and only revealed once everyone has played a card. The player with the highest roll card wins the treasure.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Phase three, the Ninja phase is final phase of the round. During this phase players can play any of the System or Player Action cards to steal away treasure or protect treasure they have won during the round. Some System and Player Action cards can be played at any time allowing player to block other players from rolling during the looting phase or other actions like visit the traveling merchant to buy treasure by selling back won treasure to the loot deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once the round has been completed all players will draw a new card from the player deck and move to the next player in the turn order.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To win the game players must collect all 8 pieces of their armor, winning all a pieces is an automatic win the game. Should a hero lose any pieces of the armor to another player they still have a chance to win. Players will then need to steel away armor from other players and collect all of the loot cards they can. Once the final loot card has been one the player who has the most loot is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lewt Ninja also has two other game modes&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Legendary Mode: &amp;#10;In this mode of the game Players will not only need to win their 8 armor piece set but will need to also win their classes legendary weapon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Vote to Kick &amp;#10;Remove all of the all non-set loot from the Loot Deck. The object of Vote to Kick is to eliminate players from the game by stealing their Armor Set pieces. A Player is eliminated from the game when another player owns 3 pieces of the other player's class armor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="11" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="36" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="37" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="38" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="39" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="40" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2079" value="Variable Phase Order" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="100969" value="Dewayne Cameron" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="100970" value="Samuel Howard" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="36378" value="Grunt Games LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.17" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.83" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="10" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>