<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="227325">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Legends of Rome" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A card game for 2-6 Players themed around the History of Rome from its earliest Origins to the Fall of the West. Each player in turn takes control of the History of Rome.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 6 decks representing 6 consecutive ages, each played in turn: &amp;#10;1.  Early Rome&amp;#10;2.  Early Republic&amp;#10;3.  Middle Republic&amp;#10;4.  Late Republic&amp;#10;5.  Empire&amp;#10;6.  Decline&amp;#10;Cards are of 11 different types: Leader, Threat, Conquest, Politics, Culture, Build, Religion, Disaster, Defect, Origin and Battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players share common sets of Gold Coins, Ambition Tokens, Legion Markers, Fate Tokens, Faction Tokens, Threat Markers, Victory Tokens and Power Tokens.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players take turns with each turn comprising 19 Phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-  Destiny Phase. Gain 1 Fate Token. &amp;#10;-  Fate Phase. Flip over the top 2 cards from the current deck and place them face-up in their respective available card piles. If a card is an action card, place it in your hand. &amp;#10;-  Ambition Phase. Gain 2 ambition tokens. &amp;#10;-  Taxes Phase. Gain 1D6 gold plus 1 gold per conquest card you control. &amp;#10;-  Disaster Phase. If there is a major disaster card available cause a target player to roll 3 times on the disaster table. If there is a Defect card available cause a target player to roll once on the disaster table.&amp;#10;-  Leader Phase. If a Leader card is available you may take it for 1 Fate token.  &amp;#10;-  Senate Phase. Discard a Politics card to gain one of a range of benefits.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-  Legion Phase. Pay 1 gold per Legion you control. You may raise extra Legions for 4 Gold each. &amp;#10;-  Threat Phase. If there is a card in the Threat pile roll 1D6 and resolve.&amp;#10;-  Conquest Phase. If there are no cards in the Threat pile and there are one or more cards in the Conquest pile you may go conquering by paying 1 ambition token and 1 gold coin to attack one target conquest card in the conquest pile.&amp;#10;-  Politics Phase. If there are any Politics cards available, you may take all of them for 1 fate token.&amp;#10;-  Power Phase.  If you have a Leader that is not already in power, you may have him attempt to seize power by spending 3 ambition tokens and rolling 1D6 against a table and resolving.&amp;#10;-  Build Phase. If there are any Build cards available, you may purchase them for 1 ambition token and 4 gold each. Immediately gain 5VP. &amp;#10;-  Religion Phase. If there are any Religion cards available, you may buy them for 1 gold each.  Immediately gain 2 VP for each. &amp;#10;-  Culture Phase. If there are any Culture or Origin cards available, you may buy them for 1 fate token each. Immediately gain 1 VP for each Culture card and 3 VP for each Origin card. &amp;#10;-  Games Phase. Spend 1 gold to roll on the games table and gain corresponding benefits.&amp;#10;-  Scoring Phase. Any player who has a Leader with a Power Token gets 1 VP and 1 Gold. The Player with the most Religion cards gets 1 VP. &amp;#10;-  Corruption Phase. Discard Gold, Ambition, Legions, Fate and action cards down to their maximum permissible levels.&amp;#10;-  End Phase.  Roll 1D6 for each of your Leaders. On a roll of 6 a Leader is discarded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;An Age Ends when a turn starts and there are no cards left in the deck. All Leader and Origin cards controlled by players are discarded. All Available cards are discarded. &amp;#10;Each player scores 1 VP for each Build card they control. The Player with the most Culture cards gets 10 VP. The Player with the least Culture cards loses 5 VP.  &amp;#10;Break out the deck for the next Age.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends after the 6th Deck is used up. &amp;#10;Final scoring takes place and the player with the most Victory Points wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="126" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="127" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="128" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="129" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="130" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1050" value="Ancient" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5606" value="Ancient: Rome" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>