<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="228295">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Colonizers" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A space colonisation game for 2-5 players in which players attempt to establish high scoring colonies before their opponents.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players share a common deck formed of seven different cards types: Planets, Ships, Extractors, Protection, Distance, Events and Growth.  &amp;#10;&amp;#10;       Planet cards have 2 attributes: hazards and resources.  There are 8 types of hazard and 8 types of resource.&amp;#10;       There are 4 types of ship cards, representing 4 propulsion types and 4 corresponding levels of speed. Certain ships cannot be used with certain distance Cards. &amp;#10;       There are 4 types of Extractor card. Each type of extractor can successfully extract 2 types of resource. Additionally, each Extractor card has a secondary trait of colonist. There are 6 types of colonists each worth a different amount of points in settlement scoring. &amp;#10;       Each hazard has a specific type of protection card required to overcome it. Each protection card has a secondary trait of control. There are three types of control each worth a different number of points in settlement scoring. &amp;#10;       Each distance card lists a distance value from 7 to 30. Each distance card also has an obstruction attribute. There are five types of obstruction.  Each obstruction type may prevent the use of one specific ship type. &amp;#10;       Event cards have a wide range of game altering effects such as increasing or decreasing trip times; stealing or destroying colonies; stealing, gaining, or losing cards; stealing, gaining, or losing VP.&amp;#10;       Growth cards are added to a player&amp;rsquo;s existing colony. A single colony can have a maximum of one growth card attached. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To start each player is dealt 5 cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players take turns with each turn comprising eight phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1.  Draw Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;       Each player draws 1 card from the top of the deck and puts it in their hands. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.  Trade Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;       Players may trade cards from their hands. They may also trade ownership of missions and colonies.  &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3.  Event Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;       The current player may play 1 event card or 1 growth card from his hand. Discard event cards once they are played. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4.  Travel Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;       The current player places travel markers on his missions. &amp;#10;         A mission with solar sails adds 1 travel marker.&amp;#10;         A mission with gravity repulsors adds 2 travel markers. &amp;#10;         A mission with a ram scoop adds 3 travel markers. &amp;#10;         A mission with an antimatter drive adds 4 travel markers. &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5.  Launch Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     The current player may launch a mission. A mission consists of 5 cards: 1 planet card, 1 ship card, 1 extractor card, 1 protection card, 1 distance card. All cards in a Mission must be compatible with each other, for instance, the protection card must be specific to the hazard type of the planet card. The stack of mission cards are placed face-up and staggered so as to be visible to all players&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6.  Settlement Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     A Mission that has accumulated travel markers equal to or greater than the distance value listed on the mission&amp;rsquo;s distance card has arrived at its destination planet and set up a functioning, established colony. &amp;#10;     The player in control of the mission colony immediately scores a number of VP = the value of the resource type plus the value of the colonists type plus the value of the control type. &amp;#10;     Represent the conversion of the mission into a colony by discarding the distance and ship cards and the travel markers. Keep the Planet, extractor, and protection cards stacked face up in front of you. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;7.  Scoring Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     The current Player gains 1 VP for each colony he has in play. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;8.  End Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Current player max hand size = 8 cards.  Discard excess cards. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends as soon as ten colonies are in play.  Check for each of the 8 resource types.  The player with the most colonies of a type gains an extra 3 VP.  The player with the most Victory Points (VP) at the end of the game wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="141" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="142" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="143" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="144" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="145" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1113" value="Space Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>