<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="228286">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Battle Nations Outpost" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A deck building card game based on the Battle Nations Video Game. Each player controls their own outpost.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player gets his own small Imperial Basic Deck.  All cards in this deck have 2 basic Traits: Build and Fight. Build is used to recruit units, characters, and buildings. Fight is used to defeat threats. Besides the Build and Fight Traits, cards also have additional abilities including:  Draw, Store, Replace, Heal or Repair, Gain VP, and modifiers that increase their traits or the traits of other cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players also share three Common Decks:&amp;#10;Threat Deck (Missions and Invasions)&amp;#10;Building Deck&amp;#10;Unit Deck (Units and Characters)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-   Each player shuffles their Basic Deck and draws 5 cards. &amp;#10;-   Shuffle the 3 common decks. All decks are face-down. &amp;#10;-   Place the top 4 cards of the Threat Deck face-up in a line in the middle of the table.  These 4 cards are known as the Threat Spread. There must always be 4 cards in the Threat Spread. &amp;#10;-   Similarly make spreads for the Building and Unit Decks.  &amp;#10;-   As play proceeds each player will have a modified Basic Deck, a hand of 5 cards, their discard pile, a victory pile (defeated Threats), and a storage pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players take turns with each turn comprising two phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1.  Action Phase&amp;#10;-   Play cards from your hand (played cards are put in your discard).&amp;#10;-   Use Build points to recruit buildings, units, and characters from the Building and Unit Spreads.  The cost of a card in build points is its Recruitment Cost (RC).  When a card is recruited, place it in your discard pile. &amp;#10;-   Use Fight points to defeat threats from the Threat Spread. The cost to defeat a threat in fight points is its Threat Value (TV).  Place defeated Threats into your victory pile.  &amp;#10;-   At the end of the phase discard all un-played cards from your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.  Draw Phase&amp;#10;-   Draw 6 cards from your deck to form your hand for next turn. &amp;#10;-   If you have no cards left in your deck, shuffle your discard and draw from it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Victory tokens are earned by playing certain cards. Place VT into your Victory Pile along with defeated Threat cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends at the end of the turn any common deck is used up. &amp;#10;Add up your VT (Victory Tokens) plus the TV (Threat Value) of all Threat cards in your victory pile, deck, hand, and discards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the most victory points wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>