<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="228290">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bourgeoisie" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A card game for 2-4+ players. A game of social advancement in 17th century France in which players, by means of the purchase of ennobling offices, advance their bourgeoisie families into the aristocracy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player builds up 1 family at a time.  Once a family has been ennobled and has an income of 30+ silver per turn from investments, it is retired and the player must start a new family.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players share a common deck comprising card types:  Families, Trade, Bonds, Land, Offices, and Events. The Land, Bond, and Office types are collectively called Investments. Most cards have a value and may also have special characteristics.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The opportunity track has a place for the deck and 10 cards to be laid out: &amp;#10;Discard | 01 | 02 | 03 | 04 | 05 | 06 | 07 | 08 | 09 | 10 | Deck&amp;#10;A card&amp;rsquo;s position on the track is the cost in opportunity tokens to take it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 4 different types of Common Markers: silver coins, gold coins upgrade markers and opportunity tokens&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player starts with 1 random family card in play and with 1D10 Silver. &amp;#10;10 cards are laid randomly to each of the 10 spaces on the opportunity Track.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players take turns with each turn divided into 9 phases: &amp;#10;1.  Family Phase&amp;#10;-   If you have no family card in play you may put one in play from your hand at no cost. You may have a max of 1 non-retired family card in play at a time.  Cards in play are placed face up in front of you. &amp;#10;-   You may put a trade card in play for gold equal to its value. You may not put a trade card into play if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a family card in play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.  Revenue Phase&amp;#10;-   Gain Silver equal to the combined value of every card you have in play for your most current family.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3.  Fate Phase&amp;#10;-   Gain 1D6 Opportunity Tokens (OT).  OT can be saved from turn to turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4.  Opportunity Phase&amp;#10;-   You may buy cards on the Opportunity Track using your OT. Place these cards into your hand. A card&amp;rsquo;s position on the track is the cost in OT to take it. Some Event cards are resolved as soon as you buy them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5.  Capital Phase&amp;#10;-   You may discard one or more cards from your hand. Gain silver equal to the value of the discarded cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6.  Conversion Phase&amp;#10;-   Convert silver to gold. Every 10 silver converts into 1 gold. Keep the change.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;7.  Investment Phase&amp;#10;-   If you have a trade card in play with your current family, you may buy Land and/or Bond cards from your hand. These cost gold equal to their value. A family may have multiple Land and Bond cards in play. &amp;#10;-   If your current family has at least one Land in play, you may buy an Office card for gold equal to its value. A family may not have more office cards in play than land cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;8.  Noblement Phase&amp;#10;-   If your current family has at least 1 office and is making 30+ Silver per turn, it may retire. &amp;#10;-   If it is making 50+ Silver per turn, you must retire it, even if it has no office. &amp;#10;-   Set the retired Family aside in its own stack.&amp;#10;-   When retiring, you must discard all your gold.  &amp;#10;-   Next turn you may start a new family.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;9.  End Phase&amp;#10;-   Max hand size is 7 cards. Discard excess cards. &amp;#10;-   If there is a card in the 1 spot on the Opportunity track discard it. Then slide all the remaining cards down from 10 to 1 filling in all empty spaces on the Track.  Flip over cards from the deck to fill in empty spots (starting with the 10)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when a turn ends and there are no cards left in the deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Score Prestige Points (PP) for each of your families. A family gets PP equal to the value of its Lands and Offices. If a retired family has no Offices it gets -5 PP. Get an extra +5 PP for each retired family you have after the first.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the most Prestige Points at the end of the game wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2011" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>