<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="229608">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/SSyqcksyHGokD5Iq22g5GQ__thumb/img/a9otte9WDyyY_GeLp3FQYuo9408=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3607200.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/SSyqcksyHGokD5Iq22g5GQ__original/img/MQs8GVAAG4m46Plin--0rdiELnQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3607200.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Green Arrow" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A card game based on the TV series Arrow.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game starts with 2 decks: Arrow Deck (green cards) and Villain Deck (pink cards).  As the game progresses, players will create their own personal hero decks composed of Arrow (green) cards they have previously played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each card has a power level. Green cards range from 1 to 4. Pink cards range from 1 to 7.  Certain Green cards will also get extra power depending on their text.  Each card will also have usually 2 or more traits: Criminal, Guns, Archer, Petty, Brawler, Drugs, Psycho, Police, Tech, Government, Organization, Money, Political, Skill, Equipment, Action, Arrow, Romance, Ally, Friendship, Family.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each round has 6 phases, with players taking it turns to act first each round:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1.   Foundry Phase&amp;#10;-    At the beginning of each round flip over the top 3X cards from the Arrow Deck and place them face up in a row (Foundry Row). X = the number of players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.   Starling Phase&amp;#10;-    At the beginning of each round flip over the top 2X cards from the Villain Deck and place them face up in a row (Starling Row).  When you flip over a minor card (power of 1 or 2) flip over another card and stack the minor card with it. The stack counts as a single card on the Starling Row, but has the combined power of all of the cards in the stack. (The stack may contain several minor cards under the major card (power 3 or higher)).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3.   Hero Phase&amp;#10;-    Starting with the round leader each player picks one card from the Foundry Row and puts it into their hand. This continues until each player has picked 3 cards. If you pick a card that says draw 1 immediately draw one card from the Arrow Deck and put it in your hand. If the drawn card also says draw 1 then draw again and so on. If the Arrow Deck is used up draw 3 cards from your Hero Deck instead. At the end of the phase the lead player passes to the player on his left.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4.   Capture Phase&amp;#10;-    Starting with the (new) lead player, each player captures one or more cards (or stacks of cards) from the Starling Row and puts them into their Victory Pile. The total power of the pink cards you capture must be equal to or exceeded by the total power of the green cards you picked/drew this turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5.   Bonus Phase&amp;#10;-    Put a victory token in your victory pile if you have played in capture phase 2 or more skill cards, 2 or more money cards, 2 characters with a romantic relationship or 2 characters with a family relationship&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6.   Recovery Phase&amp;#10;-    Place all green cards you played this turn into your Hero Deck discard pile.  Any Villain card not captured remains in play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player has his own victory pile. During the course of the game players will acquire victory tokens and villain cards which they will keep in their victory pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when all the villain cards are captured. Players add up the value of all the cards and tokens in their Victory Pile. Each villain card is worth victory points equal to its power rating.  2 extra victory points are gained for each Super Villain captured. The player with the most victory points at the end of the game wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>