<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="229600">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rifle and Axe" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A worker placement game for 1-4 players themed on the Pioneer Settlement of Kentucky in 1780.  Settlements simulate places such as Harrods Fort, Logans Fort, and Boones Station with each player representing the settlement leader.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player has a Resource Board, a Structure Board and a set of cubes/tokens to track resources and activities.&amp;#10;-    The resource board is a 5x5 grid of 25 spaces and is used to keep track of the 25 different type of players&amp;rsquo; resources (Folk, Housing, Clothing, Happiness etc.)  Each resource has a specific starting value between 0 and 10 and will go up and down during the game as a consequence of decisions made and a range of random factors. Resources are used to expand and develop the players&amp;rsquo; settlement and their use will need to be balanced to ensure a positive outcome.&amp;#10;-    The Structure Board is a 4x4 grid of 16 spaces and used to keep track of a player&amp;rsquo;s structures.  Each player starts with 10 cabins and 2 corral pens but additional structures can be built to expand the settlement.  Structures will require varying combinations of resources (labour, wood and lumber) to construct but will generate benefits for the settlement once built.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players share an Action Board.  The Action Board is used in the action phase and consists of a 6 x 5 grid of 30 spaces representing the 30 actions that can be taken by players.  Actions (e,g, clear land, hunting, soap making etc.) represent the activities undertaken by the settlers.  Most actions have limits such as resource availability or need for specialists but, if requirements are met, will lead to additional resources and/or advancement of the settlement.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players can take their turns simultaneously with each turn comprising 2 phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1.   Growth Phase&amp;#10;-    Roll once on the Growth Table per 20 Folk you have. Results will result in births or the arrival of immigrants (with some additional resources)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.   Livestock Phase&amp;#10;-    Gain additional livestock per 5 livestock you own.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3.   Boon Phase&amp;#10;-    Roll 1D10 to gain benefits, normally in additional resources.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4.   Action Phase&amp;#10;-    Players get actions equal to their Folk resource score. Cubes are placed onto the action squares of the Action Board to reflect actions taken.  Adjust resource levels up and down accordingly.  At the end of the phase all cubes are removed from the Action Board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5.   Hardship Phase&amp;#10;-    Roll 1D10 on the Hardship Table and resolve.  Hardship will result in loss of livestock, grain, food or folk.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6.   Mishap Phase&amp;#10;-    Roll 1D10 twice on the Mishap Table and resolve. Mishaps result in the loss of resources.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;7.   Raid Phase&amp;#10;-    Roll 1D10 on the Indian Raid Table and resolve.  Results will be trade, fighting, theft of resources, and in certain cases the settlement might be overrun and the player eliminated from the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;8.   Consume Phase&amp;#10;-    Each of a player&amp;rsquo;s folk consumes 1 Food and every 10 folk consume 1 salt.  Insufficient food or salt may lead to folk moving away or dying.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;9.   Seasonal Phase&amp;#10;-    Each turn represents three months - keep track of the seasons - Spring to Summer to Fall to Winter.  If it is Winter roll once on the Winter Table and resolve.  Dependant on the severity of the winter additional fuel (wood and lumber) may be required and there may be a loss of livestock or folk.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;10.  Storage Phase&amp;#10;-    A player adds up the total number of Grain, Food, Lye, Salt, and Gunpowder units he has. If this number is more than the number of containers held he must lose the difference.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;11.  Happiness Phase&amp;#10;-    Gain 2D6 Happiness. Gain or lose happiness dependant on conditions within the settlement.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;12.  End Phase&amp;#10;-    Ensure all counters and tokens are correctly placed, and no phases or players were skipped.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game lasts 5 years (20 turns).  The Player with the most awards at the end of the game wins.  There are 5 awards: &amp;#10;-    Population Award: Most Folk&amp;#10;-    Happiness Award: Most Happiness&amp;#10;-    Builder Award: Most Structures + Plots&amp;#10;-    Prosperity Award: Most Money&amp;#10;-    Hoarder Award: Most Grain + Livestock + Food&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1086" value="Territory Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>