<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="230614">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Paranoia: Troubleshooters" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A card game based on the Paranoia RPG.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You live underground in a giant complex controlled by a paranoid computer. This complex is called Alpha Complex. The Computer is your friend. Traitors are executed. Good Citizens help root out Traitors. Mutants are traitors. Secret Society members are traitors. You are a Mutant and a Secret Society Member. You know very little because of your (Red) low security clearance. You have been assigned to a team of Troubleshooters. Troubleshooters shoot trouble. Stay Alert! Trust No One! Keep your Laser Handy!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player has a family of 6 clones. Every time your clone is killed, one of your remaining clones takes his place. When all six have been killed you lose and are out of the game. Players try to survive while killing off their opponent&amp;rsquo;s clones.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 2 decks: The Mission Deck and The Paranoia Deck.  Cards are of 4 types: Combat, Comprehension, Communication and Treason.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn has 4 Phases:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1.  Requisition Phase&amp;#10;-   Each player fills their hand to 5 cards from the Paranoia Deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2.  Mission Phase&amp;#10;-   Flip over the top card of the Mission Deck. This describes an encounter all players must face. The encounter will be one of three types: Combat, Comprehension, or Communication. Each player must play (discard) one Paranoia card of a matching type to survive. If a player cannot play a matching card his Clone is killed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3.  Action Phase&amp;#10;-   The current player may initiate one or more actions. Actions require the expenditure of Paranoia cards. He may continue doing this until he has no cards left in his hand.  The Actions include: &amp;#10;&amp;bull;   Situational Awareness: Discard 2 Comprehension cards to draw 3 Paranoia cards and put them in your hand. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;   Accusations: Play one or more Treason cards onto an opponent. The opponent may play Communication cards to discard Treason cards on a one to one basis.  If a player has 3 or more Treason cards and no way to discard them, that clone is immediately terminated by the computer. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;   Shoot the Traitor: The player picks a target opposing player who has at least &amp;#10;one Treason card. Both play combat cards from their hands. The player who plays more combat cards kills the opposing player. If both play an equal number of cards then roll 1D6: The higher roll wins. If still tied, both are killed. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;   Special Actions: Some cards allow for special actions when played. These special actions (SA) are described on the individual cards. &amp;#10;-    All played cards from Action Phase are discarded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4.  Debriefing Phase&amp;#10;-   Max hand size is 5 cards.  Discard any excess cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The aim of the game is to kill off all your opponents&amp;rsquo; clones and be the last one alive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="810" value="Lloyd Krassner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="873" value="Warp Spawn Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="7.4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.35647" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="17" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="9" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>