<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="234309">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JaeQBleLhQ_VRghb85X3BQ__thumb/img/XP862gMCMc9ufMTOth6E9AgVGfc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3766900.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JaeQBleLhQ_VRghb85X3BQ__original/img/Y0sfNytK9gDPSlh7Uol_jY82O_o=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3766900.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Redneck Madness" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In Redneck Madness, two teams are faced by the dominance of the drink that is consumed in the USA. On the one hand, there is the Mega-corporation Puke Cola, which with all its economic power and Human Resources is implanting a new drink very sugary that is becoming addictive to the population. This Mega-corporation will be controlled by a single Player who with his fleet of Delivery trucks must distribute the Puke Cola throughout the States of the USA, hire Employees for his company and form a Puke Cola dispatcher army, manufacture the different varieties of Puke Cola, reinforce its Headquarters with traps to avoid fortuitous incursions and, finally, to avoid that the side of the Redneck steal to them the secret recipe of the Puke Cola.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Against him is the team of the family of Rednecks, the Hickey. They were on vacation in Hawaii when the Puke Cola began to be commercialized. In this team of 1 to 3 players will have to cooperate and help each other. To be able to get Hawaiian Air Tickets to bring back all family members, knock down Puke Cola advertising banners and put up Beer Posters, bribe Puke Cola workers to reveal company secret information, or get drunk to the employees and leave them out of the game. All this while getting better objects and new members of the Hickey family to infiltrate the Puke Cola Factory. Since there will be epic clashes to see who sticks more drinking and who ends up collapsing first, if the members of Puke Cola for the excess of alcohol from the beer. Or the Rednecks for blood sugar overdose.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once they face the length and breadth of the US, everything will be decided at Puke Cola Headquarters where both teams will face for control of the drink. Will the Rednecks steal the Puke Cola recipe or will Puke Cola's loyal employees get the Redneck out of action for blood sugar overdose?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is developed over 10 rounds on a map of the USA in which as the rounds progress the player who manages the corporation of Puke Cola will incorporate in each turn a new delivery truck with which to move and conquer states and put the difficult things to the Rednecks locking up and making difficult the movement, as it conquer states it manages to recruit more distributors for its army that they incorporate to its factory to generate more Puke Cola that gives to him more force of attack for the battle final. Redneck will have to do different missions that will pick up from the deck of missions at the beginning of each turn and for which they will spend cards  of resources to move that will be obtained at the beginning of each turn and when completing missions in the form of rewards. Each mission that can complete an ally involves traveling to one of the 48 US states having to travel on a map of the US with more and more presence of Puke Cola trucks. Among the different types of missions we will have to recruit new Redneck, pay bribes with the money obtained from completing previous missions, combats the deliverymen to reduce their army, release states under Puke Cola control and thus reduce the power of the corporation. The enemy moves all of their trucks to an adjacent state on each turn while allies have to make use of the resources and rewards in the form of cards that they get as the game progresses. After the 10 turns on the map of the USA in which Puke Cola will have increased its army and attack power and the Redneck will see their resistance to the reduced Puke Cola will take place a direct confrontation in the factory of Puke Cola in the pure style Dungeon Crawler with simplified mechanics and fast combat between all the characters at once in each room. The fighting is resolved with a bidding system in which each side bets on all the plates that it picks from its bag which assigns to attack and defense and are compared with the bet by the opposing side, these bids can be modified by the different reward cards obtained in the previous phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1086" value="Territory Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="103103" value="Francisco Torres Fernández" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="103104" value="Adrián Torres Fernández" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="104032" value="UliOh" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="37266" value="APA BoardGames" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>