<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="235428">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/FmnVbxMBuW9oOnl0gPe6oQ__thumb/img/ztg8NdJP0uu2-iZA2EaZx8cf3R4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3757926.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/FmnVbxMBuW9oOnl0gPe6oQ__original/img/Z1pucm548Ea-PidgO-OPOYzKpPg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3757926.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Andrana Project" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>THE STORY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Year 2067: global warming is no longer a prophecy but a reality.&amp;#10;The world, as we know it, has changed. Cities, governments, and nationalities got diluted giving way to a single world power, the World Federation. This new order represents few privileged, citizens of former first powers who today live protected from the chaos and misery that invades the planet. The rest of humanity migrates aimlessly on the run from war, hunger, and destruction left behind by climate change.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Meanwhile, the new world, driven by state-of-the-art technology, raises its walls seeking isolation from chaos. Set in the form of Smart Cities and defended by machines, the new world order is forced to find a solution to uncover illegal immigrants who manage to cross its borders and disguise among its citizens. Andrana Project, a Nano chip implanted in the nape of its inhabitants is the new identity document. From this moment on, everything involving a person is linked to their nanochip: their identity, bank and medical details, properties, titles... everything.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Project Andrana is well received by the majority of the population, although many are opposed to its potential risks. In this context, an old ideological movement begins to acquire strength and prominence: The Neoluddites.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Convinced that technology has a negative impact on people, their communities and the environment, Neoluddites believe that social and ecological collapse condemns most of the world's population to live in misery. Although this ideology has been alive for years, its followers had just passively abandoned technology until the arrival of Project Andrana, after which they started to get organized to act as a group. Neoluddites are dispersed all over the world and they know no frontiers. There are different factions, some more pacifist, and other more radical ones, determined to end the hegemony of the World Federation, which has taken technological evolution to the extreme. In time, some citizens of the World Federation will join this movement, tearing their nanochip off, becoming exiles and preparing to fight the system.&amp;#10; Constant confrontations between the World Federation and the Neoluddites will shape the fate of humanity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;THE GAME&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is the plot of Andrana Project, an independent game that will be able to test your strategic ability, emotional intelligence, teamwork capacity and leadership skills.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Andrana Project is a phygital social game, this means that it is a group game, played face to face, supported on your smart phone or tablet.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To play Andrana Project you need a minimum of 4 players with smartphone/tablet and Internet connection. Every player needs to download the game, one of them will start the game and each of them will be assigned a team and a character.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Andrana Project there are two opposing teams: the Neoluddites and the World Federation. Players from both teams have to discover their opponents to shut them down. The game has different missions that will get upgraded depending on how much it&amp;rsquo;s played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player will be assigned a different character from each team, which means also different abilities and power inside the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These are the main powers of each of them (among many others):&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Neoluddites leader: As the Leader, he can recruit citizens. If he recruits a citizen he/she will become a Neoluddite and will fight for his team.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Neoluddites Doctor: As a Doctor, she can heal herself or any player she wants, so she can prevent that person of dying.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Neoluddites Citizen: As a citizen, they can save someone&amp;rsquo; life, giving theirs instead. If they save someone from their team will result in a lot of points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All Neoluddites have to be careful when stealing the access. If they steal the wrong person their identity will be revealed to that player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cybersecurity: As Cybersecurity, they can spy on one player to know his/her identity. They have the module, the Andrana server&amp;rsquo;s access. The Neoluddites want to steal them. The Agent knows who this person is and he will try to protect him.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;DCS Agent: A DCS Agent can arrest other players to disable them in the next round. They are the only one who can recharge their weapon and attack more than once.&amp;#10;They must protect Cybersecurity, being aware of shooting him, if they kill him their team loses the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CITIZEN: As a citizen, they can save someone&amp;rsquo;s life, giving theirs instead. If they save someone from their team will result in a lot of points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player needs to hide its identity from the rest, and at the same time observe their opponents to uncover theirs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="11">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="12">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="12+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1032" value="Action / Dexterity" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1084" value="Environmental" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2073" value="Acting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2027" value="Storytelling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="41489" value="Components: Digital Hybrid – App/Website Required" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="9" />
			<average value="6.85111" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.35983" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="16" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>