<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="235435">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/can4FJtPBGV5uAJyKkT4fw__thumb/img/Y46fRqyUaNowBUuk0R7Aitvnr7g=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3741098.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/can4FJtPBGV5uAJyKkT4fw__original/img/Rf5ypfHZBu4t8VzBVifI3qQMKeM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3741098.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Cypress Legacy" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Cypress Legacy: The Board Game is for 2 to 6 players taking place in one of the Cypress Mansions. Players will take on the role of trying to work their way through the massive mansion while trying to achieve their objectives, and prove to be Lorna's true friend. Each player knows of the other players that are within the mansion and views them as someone who is trying to steal what is there. The player to achieve the goals, will be considered the winner and thus the true friend of Lorna. You will have at times, skills that you can earn or possibly steal. You can also acquire assets and or weapons that will aid you in your task at hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Classified Prototypes are very hard to get but are extremely useful if acquired. One example of a Classified Prototype is being able to gain control over the Knights for one turn, be able to capture as well as then send adversaries to the Storage Room and be locked in.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The mansion has its own elements that are going to be hard to get around but with how it has been designed there are also a few very useful elements it also offers. One such benefit is the Security access key, that if acquired gives you additional passages to expedite your journey. Using these and planning your moves well are very important to locate and acquire the &amp;quot;Inheritances&amp;quot;. Once achieved then your next task is going to be getting all required items to get out without losing what you have and is needed to take back to Lorna.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each time a player has a turn, they will draw and event card prior to their role. This will effect their planning and next move or in some cases change everything with the fact the Mansion, Vonya and the Knights are a ever present factor. There are (158) Event Cards Alone.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Additionally in a players turn they can choose to have PVP prior to drawing or roll of dice, depending on cards you may hold and where the other player may be.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your movement, planning and deck building, will be key to your acquiring what you need and escaping the mansion! (327) Total Cards In Cypress Legacy: The Board Game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whether you are two players or six, from the first roll to success, the drama to acquire what you need and escape grows continually. This feature is in the game every time you play and with the design, also gives great replayability.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It has taken some time and a lot of changes especially over the last year and a half, but we do now finally have our first run in and are also taking in dealers now. The game has undergone a lot of revisions and art changes. We wanted to take the extra time to adjust the game play and have a very good balance to the game. Now we are very happy with the results and are beginning to get the game out. (Please note this is not a &amp;quot;Legacy&amp;quot; game, this is part of the title because of the overall story.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cypress Legacy: The Board Game is based on the Cypress Inheritance Saga.&amp;#10; OBJECTIVE: Use Weapons, Skills, Assets, and Classified Prototypes to be the first player to escape the Cypress Mansion with all the required inheritance items and be Lorna&amp;rsquo;s proven friend.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;STORY: The story you are playing within begins with Lorna Ritten just learning of Alfred Cypress, the grandfather she has never known. Lorna has always wanted to find out more about her biological family, which has always been a mystery. Her grandfather&amp;rsquo;s attorney, Phillip Brandt, tells Lorna of an inheritance, which includes one of her grandfather&amp;rsquo;s many mansions and its contents. Her desire to know more marks the beginning of a very unique and potentially dangerous situation. Lorna has no idea just how important this actually is to her and will be to others. As Lorna is studying some of the inheritance documents before visiting the mansion, she realizes there are objects that hold key information hidden throughout the mansion.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Also note the complete Cypress Legacy: The Board Game Manual in the files below. (Note the player versus player elements in the manual)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Novel Series has gone through a lot of changes as well and the first novel will be available soon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="360" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="360" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1093" value="Novel-based" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="25132" value="Cypress Inheritance LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="5.8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.03961" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="15" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>