<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="236273">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KN-fzz3p71cn6jLePCcH2w__thumb/img/KsKpp9hOxWveCNJtcSsWvX7VhNQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3761927.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KN-fzz3p71cn6jLePCcH2w__original/img/xib4vzcpS5WQWn423PbSFhz334o=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3761927.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Forgotten Times: The Forsaken" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;Story&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The year is 3082 and the Earth is dying. The Planetary Sovereign Alliance, or PSA, decided that humanity would take to the stars and inhabit a new world. However, this isn&amp;rsquo;t their story. The PSA would leave behind a group of outcast and criminals called the Forsaken, in hopes to not repeat the mistakes that were made on Earth. This is the story of the Forsaken during the Forgotten Times.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It&amp;rsquo;s been 500 years since the PSA left, and Earth is far from what it once was. The harsh conditions have forced the Forsaken to split among themselves and create three major factions in hopes for survival. Half would remain on earth and live underground in hopes to avoid the radiation. The rest would adventure into space to live in an old abandoned space station the PSA left behind. These are the factions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;Factions&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Nomads: They are the last known true humans left on Earth, and they in a low orbit space station called Celestial Horizon. They only venture down to Earth to gather resources and look for left behind tech.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Borrowed: They live on Earth in underground subways and caves. They were at one-point either human or animal but being exposed to harsh radiation levels they resemble more beast than man now. These are hyper-intelligent creatures and give the other factions trouble quite often.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Volg: There are a few stories about their origin. The most excepted theory is that they were soldiers left in cryo-freeze and the nanomachines that were keeping them alive eventually took over their bodies and mind. They have one main goal and that is repairing the Earth. They see all species other them themselves as threats to the Earth, and must be eliminated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Mercenaries: They aren&amp;rsquo;t considered a faction as they are a mix of all three factions and loyal to neither. As they are the outcast of the outcast, and will fight for anyone who will pay them the right amount of resources. They will even fight each other, if payed the right amount. The mercenaries make up a large portion of each faction fighting soldiers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;About The Game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Forgotten Times: The Forsaken is a brand new card game. The player can play as one of three factions (The Nomads, The Burrowed, or The Volg). Face your opponent head to head. Each player will have unique cards based on the faction chosen, and a group of mercenary cards to complete their deck. Each Faction will have three commander cards, 4 unique soldier cards, a city card [can be upgraded], and unique armor cards. The object of the game is to destroy your opponent&amp;rsquo;s city. To do this, the player will need to have a superior strategy while attacking with their soldier and commander cards. However, a game can change at any minute with the use of specialty cards. You can only have one copy of any specialty card, so it is key when you decide to play these cards. These cards can make or break your game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;Card Types&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Commander Cards: These cards are one of the most powerful in the game. Each time this card attacks the AP of the card increases by one. The max AP for this card is 4. Also, this card affects the soldier cards buffs. Each commander card has a different buff. The buffs to the soldiers are decided on the type of commander unit in play. A infantry commander will grant boost to infantry soldier cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Soldier Cards: These cards are the basic cards that will be used for attacking and defending. Some of soldier cards have powerful abilities that can be used when you play them or when they are killed. Read these carefully and try to make the best possible deck you can with them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Armor Cards: These cards help keep the soldier and commander cards alive much longer. The armor cards provide extra protection ranging from 2-16 in health, and must be destroyed before the card it is protecting can be hit and take damage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;City Cards: These cards are the most valuable. By valuable, we mean these cards are what keeps you alive in the game. There are three phases as seen below:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;         Town &amp;#226;&amp;#158;&amp;#167; City &amp;#226;&amp;#158;&amp;#167; Metropolis&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You can only get to the next phase if you already have the previous phase in play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Example: You draw a Metropolis card but you currently only have the town cards in play. You will not be able to play the Metropolis upgrade card until you have drawn the City card. If next hand your draw the City castle card, you will be allowed to play both the upgrade cards in one turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Specialty Cards: These cards are your lifeline in the game, and can turn the tables in a game in a matter of seconds. You are only able to have a max of 15 of them and there cannot be any duplicates. So, it is important that you choose wisely, and even more importantly, know when to play them. A specialty card can be played only during your turn, unless otherwise specified on the card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;Commander and Soldier Buffs&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Part of the strategy to the game is how you build your deck and how you will attack with it. You gain buffs and debuffs from the type of unit you use. Commander cards grant extra AP [Attack Point] to similar units as itself. Also, each unit type is strong against a certain type of unit and weak against another. The buff/debuff will be determined by the type of attacking unit and the type of defending unit. Below is a table:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;         UNIT TYPE&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         BUFF&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         DEBUFF&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;         Infantry&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         +1 AP against Air Defense&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         -1 AP against Aerial Unit&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;         Air Defense&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         +1 AP against Aerial Unit&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         -1 AP against Infantry&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;         Aerial Unit&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         +1 AP against Infantry&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         -1 AP against Air Defense&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The commander cards grant +1 AP per BF. Meaning you can get up to a +3 AP and additional +1 AP if the defending unit is weak against your attacking unit card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Example: You have the starter infantry commander card in play with 3 BF cards under it. You place an infantry soldier card that has a base of 2 AP. You decide to attack an air defense soldier card that has a base health of 6 HP. With your buff from your commander, the new AP will be 5. However, 1 additional AP is granted for the type of unit you are facing, bringing the final AP to 6 and killing your opponent's card in one hit, while only taking small amount of damage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="121" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="122" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="123" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="124" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="125" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>