<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="23719">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/tvEis3T4zokkIKn6m8ozMQ__thumb/img/3gbR2OwSeENPLeKM-qjR_kAz0rs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic128546.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/tvEis3T4zokkIKn6m8ozMQ__original/img/lx0mfs3XRCvqjMbwGpSXV_DooNc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic128546.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Sologames" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Created by H. David Jackson, &amp;quot;a computer programmer with long-time fascination for everything pertaining to games.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;ISBN 0-930256-10-7&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the book:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;12 Exciting new Board Games to be Played by One Person&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The complete instructions, game boards, and markers for playing all 12 games are included in this one book.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Animal: A group of animals have escaped from a zoo. It is your job to bring them back. The animals will try to outwit you!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Assailant: You have been challenged by an unknown assailant to a duel to the death!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--The Pits: An Ogre from the lower parts of the world has kidnapped Princess Alicia. Your mission is to find the princess and bring her back. You must outwit the ogre. He has killed many people who attempted to save the Princess! [A choose-your-adventure type game.]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Road Rally: You are the driver of a road rally sports car. You must move your car through a designated course in the shortest length of time without crashing. A very difficult task - you may be killed!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Challenge Cup: You are the skipper of a racing sloop competing in a challenge cup race. You must sail against obstacles to win.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Boarding Party: The German U-Boat 103 has been depth bombed and the crew has abandoned ship. They set a time bomb that you  and the crew of the USS Fletcher must disarm before the submarine is blown up. You may be killed in the process!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Medic: A member of your infantry unit is wounded. Your mission, Captain, is to have your medical corpsman retrieve the soldier; however, the enemy is determined that you will not do it, and will do everything possible to stop you!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Kamikaze: During a battle your carrier has become isolated from the main fleet. You are under attack by Japanese suicide squadrons that you must destroy before they sink your carrier. The odds are against you!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Tank Corps: The US Patton tanks against the German Panzers. You are the commander of an American Tank Squad that has met the killer Panzers and you must destroy them before they destroy you. They have very important advantages against you!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Three Day Battle: You are the Confederate General Lee attempting to break the famous fishhook line established by Union General Meade at Gettysburg. If you break through, then Washington falls. You must battle for three days. Your best chance for success is to win the first battle before Union gains strength. Will you be able to do it?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Iron Ships: You are the captain of the Confederate iron-clad ship Virginia in 1862. You must defeat the Union ship Monitor before you can enter the shipping lanes and sink the ships that are helping the Union cause. Can you break the Union blockade?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--Rescue: As the commander of a Federation Starship your shuttle is out on a mission. The shuttle was disabled by a Klingon Warship. You must rescue the shuttle, which is set as a trap for you, and return to the base with it for repair before your starship is destroyed. The enemy is waiting for you!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1982" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="101" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="102" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="103" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="104" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="105" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2055" value="Paper-and-Pencil" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="7183" value="H. David Jackson" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5513" value="Almar Press" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="15" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>