<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="237361">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HC-6mWmqJXB91DjkXmAjbA__thumb/img/dbz1H32ZQWN6MVruXQ0G_jk5mx8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3836078.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HC-6mWmqJXB91DjkXmAjbA__original/img/4xn5FfTfVN2cZXruVuPh5I8dLJY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3836078.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Cyberball 2072" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In the year 2065, people had grown bored of watching regular football. The athletes had devolved into overpaid, drug-addicted illiterates. Desperate to find a new impact sport for the masses, the TV networks sanctioned a think-tank of programmers, machinists, engineers, military experts, and game theorists. &amp;#10;Within two years, the game of Cyberball had been born.  &amp;#10;     &amp;#10;The whiny, mentally stunted athletes of football had been replaced by 18 feet tall gleaming robots, adorned with spikes and sponsor adverts. These robo-athletes did not complain, ask for more money, do drugs, or get arrested.....they just rocked! And rock they did. In little time, the Cyberball League far eclipsed the popularity of all other sports combined. The crunch of metal on any given Sunday combined with spectacular explosions garnered fans from every walk of life. Soon, the Cyberball League included dozens of teams from all over the world. The corporations pumped millions of credits into this monster they had created and reaped huge rewards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now the year is 2072, and Cyberball is the most anticipated sport on the planet. All teams compete for the Cyberbowl at season's end, where the two top teams slug it out for the coveted 'Assassin's Cup'. As a Cyberball coach, it is your job to secure the best sponsors and coach your team to the promise land. The season can be grueling for a rookie coach. Use earned credits to your advantage and field the best players, while destroying other team's star players. Embrace the thrill of giant metal machines mauling each other. Become a Cyberball coaching legend!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                                &amp;#10;                                                                            &amp;#10;                                                                        &amp;#10;                                                                    &amp;#10;                                                                &amp;#10;                                                            &amp;#10;                                                        &amp;#10;                                                    &amp;#10;                                                &amp;#10;                                            &amp;#10;                                        &amp;#10;                                    &amp;#10;                                &amp;#10;                            &amp;#10;                        &amp;#10;                    &amp;#10;                &amp;#10;            &amp;#10;        &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The futuristic and brutal world of Cyberball comes to life with this miniatures game. Choose a sponsor, upgrade your players, and prepare for gridiron mayhem.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The goal of this game is to outscore and brutalize the other team to receive monetary bonuses from the league and sponsors. Football fans will find themselves right at home with this 2 player game. To win games, you must score touchdowns. Once in possession of the ball, the offense has six plays to diffuse the ball by either passing midfield or getting in the endzone. The ball gradually heats up: cool - lukewarm - warm - hot - sizzling - critical. If a critical ball is not diffused, it will explode at the conclusion on the play. If a robo-athlete is holding the ball, they will be obliterated. The game is 7 on 7 robot football with a colorful cast of characters. Here are brief descriptions of the deadly participants:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;QB - The offensive captain is the linchpin of any good team. Unlike other robo-athletes, the Quarterback has legs which allow for quick lateral movement, but not flat out speed. The QB's weakness is its dreadful lack of armor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RB - An outstanding combination of speed and armor. The Runningback is often the workhorse of the offense. Many coaches find that an upgraded RB becomes a scoring machine.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PB - A new addition to Cyberball, the Powerback is gaining popularity across the league. Being able to run or pass the ball, make the PB an unpredictable asset.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WR - Perhaps the greatest offensive threat on the gridiron, the Wide Receiver is a true speed demon. Although lightly armored, a WR speeding down the field with the ball is rarely caught.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TE - Tight Ends are cheap to produce and make good supplemental blockers on the line of scrimmage. Some coaches are able to use TEs to good effect in a short passing game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;LM - Lineman are the bullies of the gridiron. Their main responsibilities are to block along the offensive line and make tackles along the defensive line. On tracks, they are slow but very maneuverable.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CB - The fastest player on the defense is the Cornerback. They are primarily charged with covering the elusive WRs and making an occasional blitz. What they lack in armor, they make up for with speed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SF - Safeties are equally good at stopping the run or covering the pass. With respectable armor and above average speed, a good SF can be counted on to stop the offense dead in their tracks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;LB - The intimidator of the gridiron, Linebackers have very think armor and decent speed. Although able to cover short passes, these monsters are better at dominating the line of scrimmage and dismantling opposing QBs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Teams in the Cyberball league utilize sponsors to supplement their income. It is a symbiotic relationship. Teams make thousands of credits each season for slapping sponsor decals onto their robo-athletes. Sponsors get valueable exposure on national TV. Deals are struck between each game and it is not uncommon to see a team switch sponsors frequently. Each coach selects one sponsor before the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This can be played as a stand-alone game as well as in season mode. In season mode, players can save up their money to buy bigger and better bots.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="11" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="121" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="122" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="123" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="124" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="125" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5640" value="Sports: American Football / Gridiron" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="104480" value="Gary Mayer" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="104481" value="Victor Niday" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="104482" value="Dan Rich" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="104480" value="Gary Mayer" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="37678" value="CORGS" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>