<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="237675">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jG3vnusKGB8mquk3vCQ-Dw__thumb/img/jrLwDUw9ffjak2zUlxr7MCwPF7M=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3801166.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jG3vnusKGB8mquk3vCQ-Dw__original/img/yxWyJvMzMLRKnKiLKtmnLp36FaM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3801166.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="3" value="A Weaver in the Forest of Wyr" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You are a Weaver of Wyr, responsible for herbal medicine and magic spells and potions. Your garden beneath the trees of Wyr grow the flowers and herbs you need for your craft.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the time of harvest you set out to gather what you will require for those you care for. You have a day to harvest all you will need while trying to stop the mischievous Keiju from causing havok in your Garden.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you can find the right combination of flowers and herbs to satisfy them, they will consider you a friend and move elsewhere.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To Win: &amp;#10;The goal of the game is to harvest all but one of the Nature cards from the Garden and entice all the Keiju to leave.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup:&amp;#10;Shuffle the deck of 8 Keiju cards and draw 4 of them. Remove the others from the game. Place these 4 drawn Keiju on top of the pile of 44 Nature cards and shuffle this deck of cards and lay them out face up in 4 rows of 12 cards each This area is the Garden.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Leave room for 5 cards below these rows. This area is the Basket.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You will also create a discard pile - the Harvest - during the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To Play:&amp;#10;You may choose one of any two matching cards from any of the rows if your choice is: two adjacent cards within the rows, sharing the same suit or number OR if there are exactly two other adjacent Nature cards between the pair you are choosing to remove one of (Note: A Keiju card may not be one of these in between cards).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Only one of these two cards is chosen and is then placed either in the Harvest or the Basket. Each time you remove a card from a row, slide any cards to the right or left of the removed card to fill in any gaps across the rows. Cards are moved from the bottom rows upward or the top row downwards as a gap is filled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Harvest - This is a discard pile, you will receive one point for each card in this pile at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Basket - Instead of placing cards in the Harvest you may place a card instead in one of 5 card &amp;lsquo;piles&amp;rsquo; in your Basket. Cards in your Basket are used to entice the Keiju in your Garden to leave.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Keiju must be removed in numerical order, lowest to highest. If, at any time, cards on top of the piles in the Basket match a request as shown on the next consectuive numbered Keiju card in the Garden, you may remove that Keiju to the Harvest where it is worth 10 points at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The four or five cards used to bribe the Keiju are then removed from the game and will not score any points. Keiju do not have suits. They will form blocked areas in the rows of cards which can affect how you remove the suited cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As you play cards to the Basket you will cover up previous cards played there, which can then only be revealed once they are used to entice Keiju.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring:&amp;#10;At game end you will receive:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1 point per Nature card in the Harvest.&amp;#10;10 points per Keiju in the Harvest.&amp;#10;Any Keiju left in the Garden are -5 points each.&amp;#10;Any Nature cards left in the Garden are -1 point each.&amp;#10;Cards remaining in the Basket count neither for nor against you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game can be played with a traditional card deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="74010" value="Series: Forest of Wyr" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23816" value="Air and Nothingness Press" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="17" />
			<average value="5.95882" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.07214" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="31" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="19" />
			<numcomments value="18" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>