<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="238191">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xxMYfbQPEjQb8QM2xr-WFA__thumb/img/wfFb35QYzjeQMjCCYMBXpDkBrRM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4057021.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xxMYfbQPEjQb8QM2xr-WFA__original/img/RhxPRe_dA7tGOAnqbhfytLYDr1s=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4057021.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Swip Swap Heroes" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In Swip Swap Heroes: The King of Baffleburgh has gone to the beach for a Holiday, but the tide has taken him by surprise, and he is now stranded on a tiny island, he even lost one of his slippers to the tide! Luckily for him that he brought his distress beacon. Beep.. Beep.. The Beacon&amp;rsquo;s signal went wide and far, and even a spaceship way out there received the emergency call. Now Heroes from all parts of the world are heading to the signal to be the first to escort the King out of the dreadful waters. Swip Swap Heroes: is a casual Tile based board building game, where the aim of the game is, to be the Hero that leads the lost King, back to safety. It might sound easy enough, but you will have to battle Trambambolins, Selfie Sticks, Monsters, other Heroes and much more in order to accomplish glory and fame in the kingdom of Baffleburgh.&amp;#10; In the Tile-laying game Swip Swap Heroes: There are monsters, utility and mechanical tiles to build with, and four Teams to choose from: the Space Monkeys from outer space, The deep diver Nemo and his Octopus, The Pirate Sisters and the Nerdy Adventureres, they all bring a set of unique Tiles to the game. Each player controls a Team of two Heroes. These Teams compete against each other by setting traps, pushing each other over the edge and manipulate the sea by placing Tiles.&amp;#10; In Swip Swap Heroes: your goal is to be the first Hero that brings the King back to safety, by getting to him, and carrying him back to your Team Island, or by holding the King when the enough Sand Tiles have been placed. The King starts in the center of the board (5x5 Tile Layout), and the four Team Islands are placed in each corner.&amp;#10; Each player has 3 dice in their own color, which are used to determine who goes first, and for resolving battles. In Swip Swap Heroes:, each game starts with building the Sea, 20 of the 70 adventure Tiles are evenly handed out between each player. The first player starts by placing the first Tile face down, then the player to his left places a Tile, and so on. When all twenty Tiles are laid down, the race against the tide begins. You have to remember where you placed the helpful Tiles that you have planned to move on and evade your own traps!&amp;#10; On your turn, you have two Heroes that you can act with, each of them can choose between two actions: move or build. When moving on a Tile, it is revealed and resolved. Entering traps or getting pushed over the edge by another player sends your Hero back to your Team Island, where your Hero will be ready again on your next turn. When encountering another Hero, a battle begins, each Hero rolls their dice against each other, the one with the greatest outcome wins, and the opponent falls into the Sea. When you win a battle against another Hero or monster, you earn Fame, Fame are one time use dice that you can collect and choose to use in need. Mechanical Tiles can help you move quickly into the center and the more the board is getting reveal the more strategic it becomes, should you move or build on top of your opponents path and send him into a trap or maybe you should let him get the King and then push him into the Sea?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The tide rises every time a Sand Tile is placed on top of certain used Tiles such as a Treasure Tile, When the last Sand Tile is placed in the sea the tide has fully risen and the Hero carrying the King at the end of that turn wins the game. Swip Swap Heroes: is a game that you grow into, the more you play, the more familiar you become with the Tiles and their combinations, it is a ever changing Sea, with new strategies and challenges in every game, enjoy and have fun.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2009" value="Trick-taking" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="104350" value="Brian Bak Jensen" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="105137" value="Paul Jules Hurtado Yonson" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="104350" value="Brian Bak Jensen" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>