<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="238271">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/IcisaWu91Zcl8wmjhNRkAg__thumb/img/XYhDXLz6no9zTynbqCY-4TySgc0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3822184.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/IcisaWu91Zcl8wmjhNRkAg__original/img/Uj1T0Y6W1uTwixn0dBwTj2B6rvY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3822184.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Shadows Upon Lassadar: Ruin &amp; Renewal I" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The first of the final 3 trilogy games in the Shadows Upon Lassadar world&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is a short, two player, battle-line style game in which the remaining Elder Wardens of Lassadar and their followers try and stop the incursions of Shadowmajik from the boundaries between dimensional planes. Events take place after the wars against the Grayking and Raven Consort and the invasions of the Barons of the South. Damage due to spell casting has caused rifts and tears between dimensions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup: &amp;#10;Players choose who will be the Shadowmajik player and who will represent the Wardens of Lassadar. The Location cards are shuffled and 7 are dealt face up in a row between the players. Rotate the Location cards as required so they are all in the same orientation with the Location name readable to the Warden Player. The remaining 2 cards are removed from the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A Player card is given to each player. They should orient it toward their side of the Location cards - Wardens or Shadowmajik.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players each take 4 dice and all 4 of either the white or black cubes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play: &amp;#10;Players take simultaneous turns in a round, competing in battle at the current Location card (as designated by the yellow cube marker) and contesting over it. Both players place one hand at the top of their Player card and then players roll their respective 4 dice and keep them hidden behind their hand. Dice are placed adjacent to the four corners of their Player cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2 Dice are Battle dice and are added together as the base Battle Number in that location.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1 Die is the Power die and may be used to gain additional Mana or Shadowmajik points on a player&amp;rsquo;s track (the die value is divided by 2 and rounded up for the total Mana or Shadowmajik gained). A player may never possess more MP or SP than the maximum (6) listed on the track.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1 Die is the Casting die and may be used to cast a spell as listed on player card. A player may cast a spell equal to the die value or exactly one value below die value and must pay the listed MP or SP to do so. Certain spells show a Resonance icon next to the die face. If the current location has a matching Resonance icon those spells cost 1 less MP or SP.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You may not use a Power and Casting die on same turn. Only one of these dice will be placed on a corner as an active die.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Both players then reveal their 3 placed dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the stronger Battle Number will place and/or move a cube on their respective track on the current Location card a number of spaces. This is calculated based on a nomograph table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players only have 3 cubes so, with 7 Locations, they must decide where to deploy forces and which Locations to contest.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once a Location is won (when a player&amp;rsquo;s cube moves to highest space on their track) that card will be slid towards the winner and they gain control over it. That Location will not be contested over again. The players take back their cubes from the card to their general supply. Location cards should be slid to fill in the gap left by the now controlled location.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After each round, the losing player decides the next location to move the yellow cube to.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game End: &amp;#10;Play continues until one player has gained control over 4 Locations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="52917" value="Contests: 9 Card Nanogame PnP" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="16846" value="Game: Shadows Upon Lassadar" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23816" value="Air and Nothingness Press" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="17" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>