<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="239971">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/54yJFmWZHT7mHa31Zpngcg__thumb/img/UhSm7_ChptIwjUrV4_s9Cjrupyg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3874377.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/54yJFmWZHT7mHa31Zpngcg__original/img/AjwTPWDyieMtQJfAus3XLK7k4sM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3874377.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="ATS Port-en-Bessin: 47 RM Commando 7-8 June 1944" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>PORT-EN-BESSIN, NORMANDY, 7 June 1944: Port-en-Bessin was a little fishing harbor west of Arromanches in Normandy, it was situated between two landing zones, Omaha Beach the American sector, and Gold Beach the XXXth British Corps sector. The 47th Royal Marine Commando came ashore east of Arromanches and progressed toward Port-en-Bessin; at night the Commando stopped a few kilometers from the objective. On 7 June the British launched the attack with fighter bombers support; about forty men were killed to capture the harbor's western side. On 8 June British commandos liberated Port-en-Bessin and linked up with Americans from the 29th I.D.&amp;#10;Welcome to ATS Port-en-Bessin! Even some of our vaunted tactical-level gaming compatriots may not realize that a house-to-house battle took place as part of the Normandy Invasion. The place was Port-en-Bessin, a small but important fishing town that was to be the objective for the 47 (RM) Commandos ... an amazing group of soldiers that would suffer heavy casualties in the operation. One source put it this way, &amp;quot; About two miles outside Port-en-Bessin, you'll reach a wooded hill with a grassy crown covered with orchids called Mont Cavalier. It was here that the surviving men of 47 RM Commando spent the night of D-Day, the twin peaks of the Eastern and Western features brooding ominously on the horizon. They had supplemented their weapons with German Schmeissers and Spandaus, captured in firefights along the way.&amp;#10;On the morning of June 7, they had got safely through the outer defences and headed into the port when disaster struck. While clambering up the steep slopes of the Western feature, one of their troops was caught out by withering fire from two German Flak ships, which were unexpectedly moored in the harbour. Eleven men were killed, 17 wounded and one &amp;ndash; George Amos &amp;ndash; captured. Meanwhile, back on Mont Cavalier, the unit's rear HQ was overrun.&amp;#10;By the evening of June 7, the Commando was in a desperate position: isolated and under constant threat of counterattack from numerically superior enemy forces; low on ammunition, depleted by heavy casualties and exhausted after two days' fighting with no more than two hours' sleep. And still those impregnable features loomed. &amp;quot;&amp;#10;To make things easy for you to get YOUR boots on the ground, a complete set of a set ofcombat counters is provided -- and a mission that will test your tactical-level mettle! OWNERSHIP OF THE ATS RULEBOOK 2014 plus standard small and large system markers is required to play.&amp;#10;Just bring your ATS Rulebook 2014 and system markers and you are ready to control every ... building to water's edge.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the publisher's website&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="112" value="Series: Advanced Tobruk System (Critical Hit)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="183899" value="ATS Rulebook 2014" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1592" value="Ray Tapio" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="928" value="Critical Hit, Inc." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>