<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="240411">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Malifaux: Doppleganger" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Doppleganger is an expansion unit for Malifaux. He belongs to the Neverborn faction.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Overview&amp;#10;The Doppelganger can be almost anything you need it to be. Doppelganger can (0) Mimic any action on a Non-leader models stat card or Upgrade as long as it doesn't list a model by name. It can be either an enemy or friendly model's action and there is no resisting if you want something from your enemy. Doppelganger can't declare Triggers with these actions but you can still make it a huge advantage, should you fail something important (Example: a Lure from a Beckoner, you basically get 2 more chances to that with the Doppelganger, if you get the right Trigger to Mimic (Tomes) you get to do the action 3 times).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Doppelganger also brings more than that to your crew, with Ill Omens you get the possibility to cheat the Initiative flip before you or your opponent use Soulstones. This can be huge as usually in every game comes a time when it's crucial to win the initiative.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If that's not enough the Doppelganger also has the Ability Don't Mind Me which allows it to make Interact actions while Engaged, which in the right Scheme Pool can be a great advantage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All this for a very reasonable price of 7 Soulstones becomes a bargain and should be considered in many Neverborn lists.&amp;#10;Mobility&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Doppelganger has a very respectable Walk of 6, which makes Doppelganger highly mobile to get where needed.&amp;#10;Offense&amp;#10;&amp;#10;While not having a very good offense with Fists (Ml5 and damage track 1/1/2) the Doppelganger can become furious in Offense with Mimic as you can copy the stats of the highest Ml beasts in the game. Should you get charged by a Ml oriented model and survive, you just Mimic the opposing model's offense and hit it back with its own damage track or Mimic another model within 8&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;Resilience&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Doppelganger has an average Defense of 5 and quite good wounds of 8. The main thing in its Resilience comes from Manipulative 14 which forces the opponent to pass a WP 14 Duel to target the Doppelganger. The good thing about Manipulative is that as long as you haven't activated the Doppelganger your opponent must make the duel with every action as you don't gain Immunity to it as you do with Horror Duels. This can deter a few models from targeting the Doppelganger.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Also, with (0) Blend In (Ca8 mask / TN: 15 mask) you can further up the resilience of the Doppelganger, with a 7 of any suit you get to choose from the following Conditions:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Chameleon: Sh Actions taken against this model receive a minus flip.&amp;#10;A Familiar Face: Ml actions taken against this model receive a minus flip&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing Against the Doppelganger&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Best time to go after the Doppelganger is after it has activated as there is no Manipulative to protect it and in a turn it has used (0) Mimic as then it can't cast (0) Blend In. After that it's quite easy to take down with a big hitter with only Df 5 and 8 Wounds.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="136" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="137" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="138" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="139" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="140" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="147537" value="Malifaux (Second Edition)" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="10053" value="Wyrd Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>