<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="240749">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/9lMjUnxCsJJigkr167wnSg__thumb/img/jqrmCgEavFekWh1PrHsGRwC8N_M=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4084574.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/9lMjUnxCsJJigkr167wnSg__original/img/K9KNgUkrmvkji9Pe2RSqxCmo7MA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4084574.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Reformers" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="ルターの宗教大改革" />
			
						               													<description>At midday on the 31st of October, 1517 in Wittenberg, Germany, an unknown monk named Martin Luther raised to question a total of Ninety-five Theses criticizing the Catholic Church for selling indulgences, among other issues. This courageous act was to become the beginning of the Protestant Reformation that would rock the entirety of Europe.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this game, you become one of four celebrated historical reformationists. You and the other reformationists will meddle with each others' affairs, all the while aiming for victory by trying to achieve the as many meaningful results as you can, building your way towards the Reformation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Before starting the game, create the action board by placing 12 tiles together in a ring. Each player will receive 5 cooperators and 1 disc. Each player's disc will be placed randomly on a tile on the action board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Luther player starts the game. The active player moves their disc to a tile of their choice that is 1-6 tiles ahead of their current location, moving clockwise.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If there are other players' discs stacked on top of your disc, keep those discs stacked on top as you move yours. If there are other players' discs below yours, leave those behind. If there is already other players' discs on your destination, stack your disc on top of the others.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After moving their disc, the active player must place 1 or 2 cooperators in their hand on the destination tile. Each tile has 3 cooperator spaces on which to place a cooperator. The active player can only place their cooperators on empty cooperator spaces on the destination tile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During this time, if there is a cooperator placed on all of the cooperator spaces on that tile, an action will be performed. The player with the most cooperators on that tile will perform the action and is called the action player. The action player is not necessarily the active player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 2 different actions printed on each tile. The action player is allowed to perform both of these actions 1 at a time in the order that they desire. They are also allowed to perform either of the actions or neither of the actions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player who had a cooperator on the tile for which the action was performed can declare Hallelujah and receive 1 blessing counter each. The action player does not receive a blessing counter through Hallelujah.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If an action and Hallelujah were performed, all cooperators on the tile will be removed from the cooperator spaces and placed in the center of the game board. If neither was performed, the cooperators will be left on the tile. Either way, the next player becomes the active player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;However, players that do not own any cooperators can no longer become an active player in this round and will have their turn skipped. Also, if there are no players with a cooperator, and nobody can become an active player, the round ends right then.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of a round, each player can return up to 3 of their own cooperators back to their hand. They can also return as many of their own cooperators placed on tiles as they please.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6 rounds are played in total. At the end of the 6th round, each player performs 1 action of their choice. Once everybody has performed their final action, the game ends, and points are calculated. The player with the most points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="80" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="80" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1115" value="Religious" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="11585" value="Masayoshi Imura" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29471" value="Kirisuto Shimbun Co." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="8" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>