<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="241432">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KiCnvHMvO6fF85xqR3PjGg__thumb/img/BKEuxe2mw4tEfTw7Xfl-sYcZa4k=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4232881.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KiCnvHMvO6fF85xqR3PjGg__original/img/6IzgBaraJxS-MuHVDspgKS97zPg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4232881.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Demons and Demigods" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The throne has remained vacant for far too long, demons assault the city, and the people have become desperate. You have travelled far to arrive in the city of Bloodstone. The desperate situation in the city has forced the Council to reach out to the powerful Demigods in hopes of finding a new ruler. You have five days to gain the favour of the council and the people. They are eager to be impressed.&amp;#10;    Your paths to victory are numerous: complete quests to gain favor and influence; slay the demons that spawn each night and harvest them for the riches that lay within; amass great wealth and purchase symbols of status to impress the masses. &amp;#10;        You are not the only hero to see this as their opportunity. Others have journeyed to the city and will fight to impede your progress at every turn. Can you win the favour of the Council and become the next Ruler?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Demons and Demigods is a deep strategy game with immense replayability. In fact, no two games will ever be the same.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players can all play with the same faction abilities by playing as &amp;quot;Civilians&amp;quot;, or each player can choose to play as a Demigod - a unique faction with special abilities and Rages. Play as a Warlock, Earth Elemental, Giant, or one of the other unique Demigods.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Throughout 5 days, players will track their time using a unique and intuitive time track. This track consists of 24 spaces. Each player begins with 12 time before the Midnight Oil ends their day, but through upgrades it is possible to improve Ambition and start the day with more time. Each movement through the city and actions at a building costs time, so plan your route and day wisely. Whoever has the most time remaining in the day will always play next - so player order is dynamic. Once you enter the Midnight Oil your day will end.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players move their characters throughout the game board using a one-of-a-kind worker placement mechanic. Your character blocks building action spaces. When you move, the building action space becomes available. Each game includes 9 randomly placed buildings. Depending on your strategy and immediate needs you may want to visit the Butcher to gain Bloodstones, or the Blacksmith to buy gear. You may wish to travel to the Market to make some important trades, or maybe you need to visit the Grand Palace to improve your influence. During all of this, your character is also tasked with slaying the demons that lurk at buildings and playing quests. Slaying demons and playing quests allow a character to gain influence at a building. This is tracked through a dynamic area control mechanic which makes use of a character's energy. Quests are also assigned to 1 of the 5 council members. Each member has specific themes attached to the quest, and at the end of the game, you are rewarded for having a variety of council members showing. This means you must diversify your strategies in order to impress the entire council.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each day players will try to improve their engine to maximize the income at Day's End. They do this by unlocking dormant cubes and visiting the Philosopher's Study for upgrades. Spend the Bloodstones you have collected from slaying demons to upgrade your character. Some upgrade examples are: Income (silver, gold, energy regeneration, etc.), and Ambition (more time).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your character starts with 18 energy cubes. These cubes are incredibly dynamic and will be used for combat with demons, upgrading abilities, area control influence, and more. How you manage your energy will greatly affect your chances of success.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of the game players will score points based on their demon slays, influence, council support, and resources.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Can you be the next Ruler of Bloodstone?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="150" />
						               				<minplaytime value="25" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="150" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2663" value="Turn Order: Time Track" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="111306" value="Patrick O'Neill" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="111307" value="Allen Symeonakis" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="64155" value="Tadas Sidlauskas" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.707107" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="10" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>