<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="243730">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ctMARK-2ELz0gOXcE1XFXw__thumb/img/1qZLTo6OGpyDBtSXoJl-6e3VsUM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4247020.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ctMARK-2ELz0gOXcE1XFXw__original/img/y_722Jq5ryza8izwjW-pDT1wnoQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4247020.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Tight Red Pants: The Card Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Crystopolis is ravaged by crime! Arch villains rule the streets, making life downright miserable and dangerous for our good citizens. Their only hope is a small band of local residents, dedicated to upholding the law, protecting the public and banishing the evil, marauding monsters from this once great city.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;No-one knows the true identities of these local heroes (except for Mrs McGinty, who knits their superhero outfits) and you, a member of the Tight Red Pants Alliance.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It's time to pull them up, and take them down! The villains that is. Tight Red Pants is a simple to play, fun super hero battling card game that will keep your little heroes and grown up ones entertained for hours. Comes with everything you need to play including the world's first flat dice! A game for 2-4 people aged 8 plus&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play Tight Red Pants the game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You control a bunch of home grown heroes and have to save the General Public (GPs) from evil villains before Teatime. The game ends when either: The Teatime card turns up 3 times or if all four locations are out with one villain and one GP or one hero wins 5 battles&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When setting up you remove the dice card and put all the green bus stop (GP cards) to one side, public side down. Choose a location card and place face up on the table. Shuffle the rest and deal three hand cards face down to each player, then place the remaining cards face down as the draw pile. Shuffle and use again when depleted. The discard pile will go next to this.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play. On your go pick up one card and play as many hand cards as you wish. Do not hold more than five. &amp;lsquo;Red Pant&amp;rsquo; cards are always played or discarded if no effect. Play goes clockwise&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MAKING A SCENE. As you lay cards fights break out all over the city (table) but first you need a location card then a villain and finally one GP from the bus stop. Place this on the location. This scene is then complete&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HOW TO FIGHT VILLAINS. Players then (on their go) use any hero in their hand to fight that baddie. Defeat the villain to collect and save the GP cards to eventually win the game. Save your GPs to one side. If you play all your cards pick up another three and have one more go. Move on after one fight.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PUNCH-UP Process Once a location, a villain and some GPs are in place any hero can battle the villain. Use the Dice Card to fight, adjust the stats for any item or henchmen cards added.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Note these stats down before fighting on the score pad.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now try to roll your Attack or below to hit. If you do, then roll again for damage to reduce the villain&amp;rsquo;s HPs to zero. Villains then roll in the same way. Ask another player to roll for them. Continue until either is defeated. If you win you get to keep the GPs, if you lose the villain stays on play and another GP is added to scene. You go is over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game continues in the same way each player challenging the villains at the locations. Collect and use your item cards to help your heroes and eventually the tea time will turn up 3 times.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then it's game over. The player with the most GPs wins or nobody wins if the villains overrun the city&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="17935" value="Theme: Superheroes" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="110449" value="Tim Sharville" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="110449" value="Tim Sharville" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="29032" value="Gunpowder Studios" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>