<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="245393">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="American Dreams" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Objective&amp;#10;Throughout history collect Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness cards. Each of these cards has a value, the player with the most points is the winner of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Deck Types&amp;#10;American Dream &amp;ndash; These are the Timeline Cards that will be played each turn to progress through American History, each play of the game will be the length of fifty years. Life, Liberty, and Pursuit of Happiness Cards &amp;ndash; These cards include special moments in your life that you have experienced during your time playing, collecting these cards are important to winning the game and finishing with enough points to obtain and maintain your American Dreams. Remember the player with the highest total from these cards is the winner of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup &amp;amp; Starting&amp;#10;Separate and shuffle the four different deck types, deal each player five American Dream Cards and one from each of the following decks; Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness. The player will have all Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness Cards face up in front of them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first card played in the timeline will be played by the oldest player, they must play their earliest American Dreams Card i.e. 1909.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player will take turns playing timeline cards and collecting or discarding Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness Cards based off the actions the American Dreams Card has them take.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For your turn you please note that you may only play a card 1 to 3 years after the previous card played. For example: If a player lays down 1925 and you are the next player, you may play 1926, 1927, or 1928&amp;mdash;if you do not have that card, your turn is skipped and discard an American Dreams Card of your choice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;History Behind the Game&amp;#10;Each play you will most likely lose or gain Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness cards each and every turn. The fluctuation mimics the point on the timeline when obtaining the American Dream was more difficult than in other years.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During Wartime players will find it most difficult to maintain their current point total, use your cards wisely during these time to ensure that you will have the most points when the Timeline reaches fifty years from the starting point. Winning And Losing The Game When fifty years has passed on the timeline, you may begin to tally the total from your Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness cards. The player with the highest total is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Alternate Rules&amp;#10;Century Play: Depending on which version of the game you will be playing with, this version of the game goes beyond fifty years, it will begin in 1901 and last the entirety of the American Dreams deck, all cards must be played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you play the card it must be the exact following year, if you do not have that card&amp;mdash;draw another card. You will not discard in this scenario. All American Dreams cards will be played on the timeline.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Example Of Play&amp;#10;Player One sets down 1904 to start the game, which causes them to collect one Happiness card, concluding their turn. Player Two sets down 1907 to follow, causing them to collect one Liberty card, concluding their turn. Player Three sets down 1910 to follow, causing them to lose one Life card. On Player One's second turn at play, they choose to use one of their Life, Liberty, &amp;amp; Pursuit of Happiness cards that has an action&amp;mdash;on this turn of play they have the option to trade a card with a fellow player. Player One chooses to take their 1 point value card and trade it for Player Two's 5 point value card. This action will help Player One going forward.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="76036" value="Rian Heist" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="76036" value="Rian Heist" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>