<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="246394">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KlBEYW40Vxkl0aNrFzAe9g__thumb/img/SVhH5jAEg9scFYEHu0x8nncJvCY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3980489.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KlBEYW40Vxkl0aNrFzAe9g__original/img/xXgcHilgNJqw4npCnOsd2zxOU1c=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic3980489.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="National Razor" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In the early morning&amp;rsquo;s mist, the clatter of the tumbril&amp;rsquo;s wheels on the cobblestone echo through the streets of Paris. It brings a gruesome feast -consumed in rhythmic chopping- the National Razor is the gluttonous ouroboros of the revolution. Over the paranoid whisperings in the breadlines, and plastered rumors on the broadsheets, you sense that the revolution hangs by a thread. Will you be able to draw it back from the abyss, or will the final thump on the scaffold see your head in a basket?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Giving careful homage to the themes of the period, play one of six factions vying for dominance of revolutionary France. Each faction has eight historical leaders to choose from and five unique asymmetrical agendas to push though in an attempt to gain control of the revolution.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game includes mechanics to coerce obedience, punish betrayal, or cooperatively reach mutual goals- allowing players to pick a path forward that best suits them. Each agenda proposed comes with a pool of 'largess' for players to distribute to win support for their machinations. Conversely, successfully sending an opposing faction's leader 'to the Chop' gains them, in addition the points scored, the trophy of a head on a pike.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;National Razor is played in five rounds. Each round begins with players simultaneously selecting a leader for their faction and secretly choosing what their faction will focus on that round. All players then reveal their leaders, and the leader with the best rank becomes the First Citizen to begin the game play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On a player's turn they can play any number of follower cards, buy improvements and titles, but they must play one of their five Agenda cards.  Agendas come with a pool of Largess -follower cards- that the active player proposes to give to players if her Agenda passes. Players then simultaneously vote on the fate of the Agenda using  Yes and No cards and may add modifiers if they feel particularly strongly about the outcome.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player decisions also advance a token along the Terror Track. When a Terror hits, the game state changes in unforeseen ways that encourage and reward aggressive behavior. The most aggressive behavior being attempting to send an opposing faction leader 'to the Chop.' This is done by proving that your incriminating evidence is legit by naming what the faction's chosen focus for the round is (thereby showing you have successfully infiltrated their faction). If the opposing faction is able to show the named focus from their unselected pile, the Chop attempt fails. If the named focus is correct however, the opposing faction leader is removed from the game, the accuser gets the bounty listed on the deceased character's card, and gains a  trophy card showing a head on a pike to demonstrate how brutal their faction is.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After all factions have taken a turn, the round is over. All players with leaders still alive reveal their chosen focus, gaining the special benefits they provide. If its the 5th round of the game, total VP's are added up, with the highest being  deemed the victor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="111" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="112" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="113" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="114" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="115" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1051" value="Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2017" value="Voting" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="5804" value="Ben Drain" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="25379" value="Nacho Head Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>