<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="247168">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8mFF_VV5fqqAUjPYEgxZHw__thumb/img/6StXaMya3mQy99zhS_brBm0iWcs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4414828.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8mFF_VV5fqqAUjPYEgxZHw__original/img/XMzxreZfhGffkuZ3GuwLf0VOfAo=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4414828.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="World Dumbination" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>For decades our planet has been monitored by alien species. Worried by recent events, enormous alien spaceships are sent towards earth. Announcing they come to save us from our self-inflicted fate, people rush to get on-board the spaceships. But the aliens will only let the smart people on-board, leaving the less gifted behind. Most of the leaders get in, but some didn&amp;rsquo;t make the cut, for more or less obvious reasons.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In World Dumbination you play as these five leaders that didn't make it on-board. You can choose to play as the leader of USA, Venezuela, Turkey, and Russia &amp;ndash; or, of course, North Korea! It&amp;rsquo;s never been easier to conquer the world. Will you make it to world domination, will you all destroy the planet in a nuclear super-shower, or will you collectively achieve world peace!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;World Dumbination is a fun asymmetric strategy game for 2 to 5 players. The game was inspired by world leaders arguing like small children sitting in a sandpit, and that is the idea for the cover art.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Even if there are a lot of military leaders remaining, you need to build your military forces from scratch. Reaching your first goal makes you able to draw stronger cards. Each nation has two first goals option and the goals are different for each nation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Find the best strategy to move your forces and build military bases (that decide the strength of your units). The players choose and place cards to reveal them all at the same time. Play action cards to attack your opponents to gain victory points, or play project cards to get some advantages as well as victory points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You also have to constantly watch your ego and popularity levels that you can control with card actions. With too little self-esteem you don&amp;rsquo;t dare to do any action. Too much ego makes you crazy and focused on only one target (you have to almost be crazy to use the nuclear bomb). If you get to unpopular, you as a leader can be overthrow by your own government. Getting very popular increases you income since your people work harder for you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are geniuses (those who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get on the spaceships) still hiding on Earth. Finding one or two of them would also help you in your quest for world domination. You can also find things that the aliens left behind.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In case the players get too clever, there are Dumbness cards in the mix to make sure some kind of stupidity will take place. Will anyone win the Nobel Peace Prize? Maybe some briefcases with secret codes got mix up during the last world meeting, or will the bombs fly uncontrollable around since none of the leaders have any knowledge of geography!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You win by having the most victory points in the end. The game ends when a player has reached 15 victory points, or when 4 nuclear bombs has been disarmed and removed from the game. Yes, this is a war game you can win by making world peace! You will also find a party alien, fake news, reality shows, abandoned spaceships and cute kittens threatening to start a nuclear war in this game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are some interesting new mechanics in the game, but the main thing in this game is the fun factor! This game is designed for a lot of interaction between players and the surprisingly events that shows up add a great deal to the silliness. And the more players, the more fun!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2017" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="50" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="56" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="57" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="58" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="59" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="60" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="70948" value="Digital Implementations: Tabletopia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="107151" value="Jan Richard Hansen" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="107151" value="Jan Richard Hansen" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="38751" value="Muzak Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="7.375" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.63459" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="11" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>