<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="248849">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/QHm8A027wrM-dmRSC9hcBg__thumb/img/KxziOHdAdaPRXB7MNTjfPdJXL_w=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5136148.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/QHm8A027wrM-dmRSC9hcBg__original/img/CP_XKIJlHjMPy06RfJKkTJvR_e8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5136148.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rex Ibéricus" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>During the Middle Ages, the Iberian Peninsula was divided into several small states, Christian kingdoms (in the northern half) and Muslim emirates (in the southern half). Over almost eight centuries, these two cultures went through periods of war and peace, intolerance and coexistence, and the fragile alliances between ones and others kingdoms changed overnight depending on the political interests of each sovereign. (Christians against Muslims, Christians against Christians, Muslims against Muslims), with the Jews as an economic force that exerted as a hinge. Likewise, foreign powers such as the Papacy or the Caliphate also played their cards in the peninsular contest. In &amp;quot;Rex Ib&amp;eacute;ricus&amp;quot; you will have to take control of one of the main six Iberian medieval kingdoms: three Christians (Kingdom of Castile, Kingdom of Aragon and Kingdom of Navarra) and three Muslims (Emirate of Cordoba, Emirate of Granada and Emirate of Valencia). Through political intrigue, diplomacy and war, as well as economic and cultural development, you will have to fight to make your kingdom or emirate become the most powerful on the Peninsula, and be named &amp;quot;Rex Ib&amp;eacute;ricus&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For this, you will have the opportunity to occupy villages, castles and walled cities, and then build farms, palaces, churches, mosques, synagogues, libraries, towers and lighthouses, which will magnify your kingdom. Likewise, you must recruit armies and build fleets to defend yourself from your dangerous neighbors, and in no case will you do well to neglect the basic nutritional needs of your subjects, since you could face brutal peasant revolts of unpredictable consequences. You must also ensure the defense of your coasts, since the fearsome Viking warriors could land on them and destroy all the wealth of your prosperous State. To help you with these challenges, you will have four historical leaders from each kingdom (Isabella, Ferdinand, Urraca, Abd al-Rahman, Boabdil, Zobeyda ...), each of them provided with special skills depending on the position assigned to them (King, advisor, ambassador, emir, vizier ...), and you can also use them to seal alliances with other kingdoms through marital links, which will make you join forces to protect yourself from more belligerent third parties, while allowing you to engender heirs (princes and princesses) to ensure the survival of your legacy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the same way, using your political influence and the support of your allies in the assembly, you will have the opportunity to reach the cusp of the Iberian Court (common to all peninsular kingdoms), which will allow you to control powerful elite units. Nor should you underestimate the power of the conspiracy, which will allow you to carry out espionage missions, instigate internal revolts and even kill rival monarchs. Finally, you can embark on exciting sea voyages to the East (Rome, Baghdad, Jerusalem and China) in search of external support to implement your political structures and deal with your enemies, although long journeys will never be without danger. Are you prepared to travel to the Middle Ages and enter an exciting world of castles, swords, religious conflicts and palace plots?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="107866" value="Miguel Candelas" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="107867" value="Catherine Proy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="107866" value="Miguel Candelas" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="107867" value="Catherine Proy" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>