<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="249539">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/oTOlrPMXMwtfmS-2s1Fv9Q__thumb/img/iUJjVtlmbIQOkijR0j6uBSLsyFg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4069037.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/oTOlrPMXMwtfmS-2s1Fv9Q__original/img/Jmt2VL2eaObiSZQ9XcIMxP4oTrk=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4069037.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Z Gate Crashers" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Z Gate Crashers is a 1 to 5 player monster hunting adventure (card game), where the goal is to survive an onslaught of invading monsters. Using various combinations of weapons and bonuses, players try to dispatch the monsters.&amp;#10;You and up to 4 friends are a band of mercenary monster hunters. Your job is to contain the evil abominations that come crawling out of large filthy stinking holes in the ground.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You and your team are deployed behind protective energy units called GATEs.&amp;#10;These GATEs are powered by a new energy source that&amp;rsquo;s harvested from killing the nasty monsters, called Soulbits.&amp;#10;Soulbits are your lifeblood and your currency. You use them to keep your GATE energized, and you protected from attack.&amp;#10;You can also trade in the soulbits you earn, for more weapons and bonus cards, to help you defeat even more nasties.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The object is simple, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to survive.&amp;#10;But more than mere survive, a successful GATEr needs to thrive by harvesting as many soulbits as possible.&amp;#10;The Player with the most soulbits at the end of the game wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when either all of the players or all of the monsters are dead.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monsters are distributed in Wave cards, that show the different types, distributions, and amounts of each invading wave of monsters.&amp;#10;During their turn, each player draws a wave card, and using monster cards and monster-life tokens, they line each up to create the monster attack track.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monsters typically emerge at the hole and during initiative, take a varied number of steps to get closer to the gate and do damage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player (typically) has first-attack initiative. Using acquired weapons and bonus cards, in various stacked, chained, offensive, and defensive combinations; the player tries to kill as many nasties as possible and collect those soulbits.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The monsters next get their move and attack actions, using initiative tokens.&amp;#10;An initiative token is placed under the monster card that will next act.&amp;#10;The initiative token (typically) moves sequentially down the track (and back around), with monsters getting 4 such actions in a &amp;ldquo;Normal Difficulty&amp;rdquo; game. The location and move-direction of the initiative token along the monster track can be altered based on certain Wave Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a monster card has initiative, all monsters on that card get to move (one step closer to the gate) and then if able, attack. &amp;#10;All monsters attack when at the gate but do so in a variety of different ways and with differing effects.&amp;#10;The player rolls to save against an attacking monster. A successful roll gains the player a bonus soulbit, but a failed roll will incur (sometimes cumulative) damage to the gate. &amp;#10;During initiative, some monsters also get a bonus attack that they take regardless of their distance from the gate.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a player survives, play moves on to the next player to see how they do.&amp;#10;A recovery session is granted at the end of each round, allowing players a chance to buy more loot, recover from various effects, and trade with other players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game difficulty and experience are controlled in the distribution of wave cards, allowing for highly dynamic and varied gameplay.&amp;#10;When wave cards run out, play continues in the same order until either all players or all monsters are dead.&amp;#10;The player with the most soulbits, at the end, wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="108087" value="George Misdary" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="108086" value="Steve Duffendack" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>