<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="249810">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/unKeQslAj59XJocKYZSlEg__thumb/img/59GyePJk3z9C8wdlekFIjxJT3OA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4065698.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/unKeQslAj59XJocKYZSlEg__original/img/KDp1xi1etcDbrDgpj9LmFi8T8eU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4065698.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Reign of Terror: The Protoan" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the publisher:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Welcome Battle Commanders! The future of your faction's survival is depending on you! Gain influence and expand your forces to strategically defeat the opposing faction. You win the battle when you reduce your opponent&amp;rsquo;s health to zero. However, a Battle Commander must be cautious if their opponent is off-initiative. Since Battle for Sularia is a round-based card game, if your opponent is off-initiative, they have the chance to strike back and reduce your health total below theirs and thereby defeating you and winning the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FEATURES/GAME PLAY INCLUDES:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Multiple Play Modes&amp;#10;To start play immediately, you can play with the pre-constructed 60 card play deck included in the box. Players can then play in our &amp;quot;60/90&amp;quot; constructed format by customizing their play decks with the additional cards provided in the box! If draft play is more your style, we suggest adding one box of Reign of Terror to our Battle for Sularia core set box, which also supports 2-4 player draft play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Construction Point Values&amp;#10;Unique &amp;quot;60/90&amp;quot; deck construction system. Each card has a construction point value of 1 to 4 points. Each deck must have a minimum of 60 cards and a deck cannot exceed a total construction value of 90 points. This system pushes the envelope on deck construction and maintains value and interests for all cards within the set &amp;ndash; not just a few select overpowered options.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two-resource System&amp;#10;Engaging two-resource system which includes influence and sularium. Influence increases once per round, while each player uses their influence to establish sites on their turn to help build their sularium stockpiles. Sularium is used to deploy combatants, which are used to attack your opponent's sites. The two-resource system in turn provides additional strategies for repeatable game play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Round-based Game&amp;#10;Simultaneous combat! The game runs on a round-based system, which allows each player to complete their turn before the round is over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lore and Art&amp;#10;In addition to our engaging game play, we've forged our own path in terms of game setting. This allows us to explore new content and visuals without restrictions, which in turn provides new players with a fresh start and removes the barrier of entry associated with older legacy games and stories.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SETTING:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Reign of Terror: The Protoan introduces a brand new faction to the world of Sularia. The Protoan were originally designed as a biological weapon alternative to the conventional weapons of their time. They were engineered to aggressively spread a viral infection that would pacify an opposing force or civilian population, while leaving the surrounding infrastructures and environment relatively unharmed. Of course, &amp;ldquo;relatively unharmed&amp;rdquo; is a very subjective point of view. Because, if the Protoan could not pacify an enemy with its virus, then they would simply devour them along with anything else in their way.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The breeding facilities of the Protoan were believed to be one of numerous lost technologies of the time before the apocalyptic event know as the Fracture&amp;mdash;nearly a millennium ago. Since the Fracture, they have evolved deep underground&amp;mdash;far beyond their original design. Furthermore, the bio-engineering developed to control their population no longer seems to be effective, as they continue to spread at a rate far beyond their original life expectancy perimeters. As if the power struggle between the Jotune and Synthien wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad enough, this new emerging threat puts the very survival of everyone on the planet at risk.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OVERVIEW:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Reign of Terror: The Protoan is a new stand-alone card game and core faction that is compatible with our other Battle for Sularia card game titles. The Protoan have their own unique game play strategies, as well as familiar options you would expect to find in a competitive card game. See the keywords for a list of new mechanisms.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;NEW KEYWORDS:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;VIRUS/INFECTION&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The VIRUS/INFECTION mechanism is a two-part ability. VIRUS is represented by counters that buff your Protoan combatants in some way. However, when those VIRUS counters are transferred&amp;mdash;through various methods&amp;mdash;to an opponent&amp;rsquo;s combatant, they become known as INFECTION counters. As the name implies, infection is not a good thing for your combatants. If your combatants become seriously infected, they will die.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CHALLENGE&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a Protoan combatant has the CHALLENGE keyword, it can single out an opponent&amp;rsquo;s combatant to defend against it. Whether through intimidation, mind control, or some primal subconscious response of the defender&amp;mdash;it also doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the defender is reset or activated&amp;mdash;it has to defend. While this may seem like a good idea by the defender for whatever reason, it usually results in it being completely devoured.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HARDENED&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Reign of Terror, we introduce HARDENED as a keyword that is linked to sites, however it's possible you will see this keyword on combatants in the near future. The ability is pretty solid, pun intended, as it prevents blast-through damage. So if you are familiar with the basic rules, you'll know how useful an ability like this will be in order to stay alive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Reign of Terror was divided into two parts&amp;mdash;Reign of Terror: The Protoan and Reign of Terror: The Exsularian. They are scheduled to launch in March and May 2018, respectively.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="48560" value="Game: Chronicles of Sularia" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="262241" value="Sularia Protocols (fan expansion for Ophidian 2350 CCG &amp; Battle for Sularia)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameintegration" id="168250" value="Battle for Sularia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="78814" value="Jesse Bergman" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="29654" value="John Kimmel (I)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="93439" value="Justine Cruz" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="76002" value="Filip Dudek" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="29654" value="John Kimmel (I)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="86223" value="Matthias Kinnigkeit" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="95639" value="Ceasar &quot;Wizyakuza&quot; Muyuela" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="71253" value="Artem Shukaev" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="65643" value="Brian “Tots” Valerz" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="28472" value="Punch-It Entertainment LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>