<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="249910">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/U0gv-ghD8vCxOnSlgcPLdw__thumb/img/gJS9MyPR-VL2b3CQijRuPbHnY_8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4066890.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/U0gv-ghD8vCxOnSlgcPLdw__original/img/BLxHO0DskpPAm0hsbmaHaNlmXVE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4066890.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Street League Sluggers" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Family friendly 2 player baseball game that uses a dueling dice rolling system. Draft your team, set your line up and outwit your opponent in this fast-paced 2 player game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player will take turns drafting players from a pool of 30 character cards, until they have filled their team. Each team will draft 9 batters and 3 pitchers each in any order they choose. You will need to set your lineup for your batters 1-9 and decide on which pitcher you will use to start the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each game is only 3 innings long. This is to keep the games shorter, kid friendly and gets you quicker into the next game. (We suggest you pitch a new pitcher each inning however, in advanced games you can play a full 9 inning game. In those cases it's suggested you pitch a new pitcher every 3 innings)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All players have a special power that can be activated when they roll a Crush/Dominate on their die roll while batting/pitching. This power often gives that character a huge advantage during that at bat to succeeded or in the pitchers case to get the batter out.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pitching &amp;amp; Hitting &amp;#10;Once you set your lineup and selected your pitcher, the game starts. Home team will pitch first and the visiting team will bat first. The goal of the pitcher is to get the batter out, either by strike out or through the contact deck in which the batter can hit into an out. The batters goal is to make contact with the pitch and draw from the contact deck to get a hit. Each player will pick one of the 3 colored dice that stand for each of the types of pitches in the game. The dice have numbers ranging from 1-5 and 1 CRIT Side. Both players pick 1 die to roll and then roll at the same time, then check the results. The Pitcher gets a +1 to their die roll if the batter did not match the pitchers colored die. This is for not guessing the right pitch in the at bat. However if the batter does match the pitch color they would receive the +1 to their die roll. If the batter meets or exceeds the pitchers roll they make contact with the ball and draws a single card from the hit deck. If the Pitcher exceeds the batters die roll the batter receives 1 strike. On 3 strikes the batter is out. If either player rolls the CRIT Side, that character activates their own power. It's often a hit for the batter and a strike for the Pitcher automatically but with card manipulation along with it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Hit Deck has 50 cards and it's filled with automatic hits like: Home Runs, Triples, Doubles and Singles. There are also Contact Play Cards where it's hit out into the field and the pitchers team must successfully make a play on the ball or the batter gets a hit. Not to forget the dreaded automatic outs as well as foul balls. Many special powers allow you to draw multiple cards from the contact deck to give you the best chance at getting on base.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game components:&amp;#10;30 Beautifully designed players, 24 Hitters with 6 Pitchers.&amp;#10;50 Card Hit Deck.&amp;#10;6 Colored Dice Pitching &amp;amp; Hitting: Fastball, Curveball &amp;amp; Changeup.&amp;#10;2 Standard D6 for Fielding.&amp;#10;10x10 Playmat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="86" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="87" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="88" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="89" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="90" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5586" value="Sports: Baseball" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="86463" value="Grant Giles" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="86462" value="Ryan Morgan" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>