<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="251641">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/136fm3zwRJaGAHaOEAcXmw__thumb/img/hPDzJkAJGAPALkCX469buRXK-Zw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4141503.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/136fm3zwRJaGAHaOEAcXmw__original/img/3ZEabqg3oXGGEV0yj62u4ZhAm-A=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4141503.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="MystiQuest" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>MystiQuest tells of epic clashes between ancient gods, fought on the banks of the Styx, the infernal river. Gods, heroes, monsters and mythological creatures battle with all their power, fighting during the day and spending the night celebrating.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Is a trading card game, but very close to the Living Card Games, thanks to the use of Planks, tokens and the possibility to implement long-term strategies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player has a board representing the fortress, on which he places the card of his Supreme Nume (or Prime) and the three heralds chosen to defend it. The heralds also represent Defence Points: if they are eliminated or used, the Prime is forced to take the field and expose himself in person. The winner first eliminates the Prime opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is interesting to note that the heralds can be chosen before starting the game and this allows you to plan very specific and different strategies according to the opponent you will have to face.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mystic energy is represented by plastic gems. After playing a card you must take the gems from your well and place them on it. The gems on the card indicate the attack value, the defense value and the card&amp;rsquo;s hit points. As a result, a card with three gems, deals three damage and can take three damage before it dies out, if it takes a damage it loses a gem and then inflicts only two damage from that moment.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During the confrontation phase the player on duty plays his own cards, sends them to the attack and uses his own prodigies to try to defeat the enemy ranks and force the Prime opponent to take the field.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of the turn there is the breath phase. Temples, Prime and some other specific cards &amp;quot;breathe&amp;quot; and give mystical energy back to their well, so you can add new gems. Then it is up to the opponent to repeat the same sequence until one of the two Prime is defeated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Another interesting feature is the possibility of playing in teams, even with &amp;quot;asymmetric&amp;quot; solutions: one against two, two against three, two against four, etc. thanks to the gaming system that automatically self-balances.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For the setting the mythological theme was chosen as an alternative to the now too widespread Fantasy. Currently it is possible to play with three Pantheon:&amp;#10;- Ancient Greeks&amp;#10;- Ancient Egyptians&amp;#10;- Vikings&amp;#10;The Japanese pantheon is already being prepared.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MystiQuest racconta di epici scontri fra antiche divinit&amp;agrave;, combattuti sulle rive dello Stige, il fiume infernale. Dei, eroi, mostri e creature mitologiche si danno battaglia con tutta la loro potenza, combattendo di giorno e passando la notte a festeggiare.E&amp;rsquo;  un gioco di carte collezionabili, ma molto vicino ai Living Card Games grazie all&amp;rsquo;utilizzo di Plance, gettoni e la possibilit&amp;agrave; di attuare strategie a lungo termine.&amp;#10; Ogni giocatore ha una plancia che rappresenta la fortezza, su cui posiziona la carta del proprio Nume Supremo (o Prime) e i tre araldi scelti per difenderlo. Gli araldi rappresentano anche Punti Ferita del Prime, infatti se vengono eliminati o utilizzati, il Prime &amp;egrave; costretto a scendere in campo ed esporsi in prima persona. Vince chi per primo elimina il Prime avversario.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;E&amp;rsquo; interessante notare che gli araldi possono essere scelti prima di iniziare la partita e questo ti permette di pianificare strategie molto precise e diverse a seconda dell&amp;rsquo;avversario che dovrai affrontare.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;L&amp;rsquo;energia mistica &amp;egrave; rappresentata da gemme di plastica. Dopo aver giocato una carta devi prelevare dal tuo pozzo le gemme indicate e posarle su di essa. Le gemme sulla carta indicano il valore di attacco, il valore di difesa e i punti ferita della carta. Di conseguenza una carta con tre gemme, infligge tre danni e  pu&amp;ograve; subire tre danni prima di estinguersi, se subisce un danno perde una gemma e quindi da quel momento infligge solo due danni.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Durante la fase del confronto il giocatore di turno gioca le proprie carte, le manda all&amp;rsquo;attacco e usa i propri prodigi per cercare di sconfiggere le schiere nemiche e costringere il Prime avversario a scendere in campo.&amp;#10; Alla fine del turno c&amp;rsquo;&amp;egrave; la fase del respiro. I templi, i Prime e alcune altre carte specifiche &amp;ldquo;respirano&amp;rdquo; e ridanno energia mistica al proprio pozzo e quindi puoi aggiungere nuove gemme.  Poi tocca all&amp;rsquo;avversario che ripete la stessa sequenza finch&amp;eacute; uno dei due Prime non viene sconfitto.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Un'altra interessante caratteristica &amp;egrave; la possibilit&amp;agrave; di giocare in squadre, anche con soluzioni &amp;ldquo;asimmetriche&amp;rdquo;:  uno contro due, due contro tre, due contro 4, ecc. grazie al sistema di gioco che automaticamente si auto bilancia.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Per l&amp;rsquo;ambientazione &amp;egrave; stato scelto il tema mitologico in alternativa all&amp;rsquo;ormai fin troppo diffuso Fantasy. Attualmente &amp;egrave; possibile giocare con tre Pantheon : &amp;#10;- Antichi Greci&amp;#10;- Antichi Egizi&amp;#10;- Vichinghi &amp;#10;E&amp;rsquo; gi&amp;agrave; in preparazione il panteon giapponese.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1044" value="Collectible Components" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6040" value="Collectible: Collectible Card Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="108904" value="Marina Longo" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="108903" value="Enrico Peduzzi" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="39191" value="Lega Giochi" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.63299" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>