<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="252063">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HW2s7x8TRKt13wH4y1i-_A__thumb/img/JKGNrj2h7YBZSr97SsF7fudWGIs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4760660.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HW2s7x8TRKt13wH4y1i-_A__original/img/_sD_CC7D8qDj4GmM5Qp3Bq4p7qY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4760660.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mosaic" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Laplace" />
			    				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="モザイク" />
			
						               													<description>Mosaic is a two-player board game like Go and Othello. However, what differs from Go and Othello is that it is a 3D game that extends the position not only in the plane but also in the vertical direction. You can solidify your footsteps first, expand the territory, or hold down the upper floors early to divide the opponent's piece or develop a complex bargain. And from the middle to the end of the game, the pieces of each other pile up at once, and a dynamic reversal play occurs. Once you play it, you should be able to understand the benefits.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game board has 7 x 7 = 49 holes, and a neutral piece is fixed at the center from the beginning.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two players each have 70 pieces. The game is as follows.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Starting with the first player, place your pieces one by one in the empty hole of the game board.&amp;#10;     If four pieces are lined up in the smallest square shape adjacent to each other, pieces can be placed on them.&amp;#10;     If four frames are arranged in a square, and three or four of the four are occupied by the same color, the frame of that color is automatically placed on it (apart from the turn).&amp;#10;     The piece fixed from the beginning to the center of the game board becomes a neutral piece which is not that of either player. When a square containing neutral frames is created, frames are automatically placed on top of the square only if the remaining three frames have the same color.&amp;#10;     Automatically placed pieces will create new squares, and if 3 or 4 of the squares are occupied with the same color, pieces will be placed automatically as well. In this way, pieces are stacked in a chain reaction. The pieces to be stacked may not only be the pieces of the active player, but also the pieces of the opposing player.&amp;#10;     In this way, the person who put the piece in turn alternately and who finished all his pieces first wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The fun of the game called mosaic is in the rule that &amp;quot;pieces are stacked in a chain reaction by putting one piece&amp;quot;. From the middle of the game, development accelerates at a stretch, and the situation changes rapidly. In the early stage, even if you allow the opponent to lead, I think that the feeling when the development of one-shot reversal at the last moment is reached is unique to mosaics.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay in Mosaic is identical to Margalith Akavya's Upper Hand, but with the action taking place on a larger initial playing area.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;--user summary&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Laplace is a two-player abstract strategy game in which your goal is to play all of your pieces before the opponent can.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played on a 7x7 grid, and the players each have pieces of a different color. A piece of a third color is placed in the central square on the game board. On a turn, a player places one of their pieces into an empty space on the grid. If a player creates a square of four pieces and at least three of those pieces belong to that same player, then the player immediately places another piece on top of those four pieces; if the placement of that piece also creates a square meeting the same condition, then they place a piece on top of that square.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Thus, as more pieces are placed, they collectively form a pyramid, with the bottom layer being 7x7, then the next layer 6x6, and so on. Whoever places their final piece first wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay in Laplace is identical to Margalith Akavya's Upper Hand., but with the action taking place on a larger initial playing area.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2043" value="Enclosure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2048" value="Pattern Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2940" value="Square Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="26432" value="Category: Combinatorial" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5607" value="Components: 3-Dimensional (3D)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="329537" value="Mosaic Mini" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="329536" value="Mosaic Quo" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42455" value="モザイクゲームズ" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="6" />
			<average value="6.33333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.24722" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="11" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>