<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="252621">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6qFeQ1nkCtVDjR25GSUD3g__thumb/img/Gp7oI1vT2clHqY98i12jBvQ9QCQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4617436.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6qFeQ1nkCtVDjR25GSUD3g__original/img/ZiLhbKwxMkTxDunqgPBnvqQAqoA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4617436.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Growl: 7 Sins + Undead" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>GROWL: 7 Sins + Undead is a double-expansion in one box, and the expansions may be played individually or combined with each other or other expansions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;7 SINS adds some light punishments and rewards to the game experience. It is recommended for 5-10 players.There are 7 sin cards and 7 virtue cards. After all players have been dealt their starting hands (but before preparing the Night cards), shuffle 5-7 cards into the deck. Then prepare the Night cards, and proceed as usual. Cards with a [SPELLS] icon in the upper right are called &amp;ldquo;spells&amp;rdquo; and never go to a hand; instead, when drawn they are placed face-up in front of another player. Their effects are ongoing for that player &amp;ndash; some good and some bad &amp;ndash; and must be taken into consideration at all times, especially when checking for death or turning into a werewolf.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Icons in the upper left of your [SPELLS] cards are considered part of your hand, and may negate (or be negated by) icons on cards in hand. In addition, some cards affect your neighbors to the left and right of you (skipping over any dead players)! There are virtue cards and sin cards; most of the virtues reward the virtuous players, and most of the sins punish the sinful.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When drawing a sin or virtue on your turn, you must give the card to ANOTHER player (even if you yourself would have qualified to receive it if someone else had drawn the card). If the card has only white text, give it to the player of your choice, to place face-up in front of them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;READING A JUDGMENT: The 7 Sins expansion cards contain two possible colors of text. The YELLOW TEXT is to be read aloud by the player who drew the card on their turn. (Just like in other aspects of the game, players must be honest when queried during a judgment. You may be asked, for example, about the total number of Gold icons you have, or the number of cards in your hand.) After giving the card to another player, they place it in front of them. The WHITE TEXT is the reward (or punishment!) that the player who received the card must accept. Most card effects are ongoing and permanent for the game (unless other cards move them, or move the players themselves). Once a sin or virtue card has been given to a player, they need to only reference the white text, plus any icons. It does NOT move positions, even if a new player would have otherwise qualified for it (for example, the player with Gluttony retains the spell, even if a different player later acquires the most cards).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TIMING: Conflicting cards are resolved clockwise from the left of the Start Player (1). If a single player has conflicting cards, they may resolve them in the order they wish.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;UNDEAD adds a third faction which allows dead players to take unique turns instead of being eliminated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is recommended for 5+ players. When playing with only 4 or 5 players: &amp;#10;&amp;bull; Remove the 2 Undead cards with the (6+) label in the lower left.&amp;#10;&amp;bull; Final Night cards that automatically would kill players instead only inflict a wound on them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SETUP: Determine in advance if you are playing with this expansion. Shuffle the Undead cards (they have a zombie on the back) and form a small face-down Undead Deck near the play area.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a player dies, they are no longer a human or a werewolf. They are now on the undead team, and can never win with the humans or the werewolves. The undead can&amp;rsquo;t change teams or return back to life, even if they give their Wound cards away. Since Undead players are still considered dead, they do NOT take part in Night Phase or draw cards from the main deck. However, during player turns, undead players instead get a special turn. When killed during the game, announce you are undead, place a green &amp;ldquo;I Died&amp;rdquo; card on top of your home tile, and await your undead turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;UNDEAD TURN: Draw a card from the Undead Deck and read it privately. You have two choices: 1. Resolve any yellow text (and if the card is a spell card give it to a living player to be placed face-up as an ongoing effect for them). 2. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like the card you drew, you may instead discard it and place any card from your hand face-up on top of the main deck for the next (living) player to draw. Then player turns (and undead turns) proceed as usual.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The undead win the game at any time if there are only 2 (or fewer) players left alive. When they win, the undead should make moaning noises or yell &amp;ldquo;...Brains....&amp;rdquo; The player(s) whose death triggered the ending do not win with the rest of the Undead.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If there are 3+ players still alive after you have resolved the Final Night, proceed to The Growl and determine the winning team (werewolves or humans) as usual.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;copy;Joey Vigour&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1023" value="Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="2989" value="Game: Werewolf / Mafia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="235451" value="GROWL" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="344658" value="그라울: 최후의 밤 - 확장 (GROWL: Expansions)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="68543" value="Joey Vigour" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="109267" value="Angelina Chernyak" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="82018" value="Rob Joseph" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="40735" value="Grzegorz Pedrycz" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="38176" value="Vigour Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="31" />
			<average value="7.08065" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.52079" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="5.52079" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.38597" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="433" />
			<trading value="16" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="28" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>