<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="253222">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/hPHOkkC1estAh3LbTkgjUg__thumb/img/Rb9ksCccwMiWrkr8UEd60jV1w8k=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4157528.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/hPHOkkC1estAh3LbTkgjUg__original/img/H4vWTDjCIfy2Mh-hNoTyi3lxkTo=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4157528.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Crime Chicky" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Crime Chicky is at it again! With her evil minions and wicked stink bomb eggs, she is out to make life difficult for the residents of Center City! It is your job as heroes of the League of Champions to thwart her insidious plots, save innocent bystanders, and capture her and her minions. The greatest Champion will receive the Key to Center City and the accolades of its grateful citizens.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aim of the Game!&amp;#10;To win, a player must gain the most Victory Points by capturing Crime Chicky and her minions, saving bystanders and foiling plots.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Needed to Play!&amp;#10;The 7 Crime Chicky Dice (4 Basic Blue Dice and 1 Yellow, 1 Red and 1 Black Die), 12 Power Tokens, 1 Center City board with a matching counter, player boards for each player to track victory points, 12 tracking counters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing the Game!&amp;#10;Each round, every player, beginning with the Starting Player, will take turns rolling 4 or more dice. A player must always roll the 4 Basic Blue Dice during their turn but they may roll the additional colored dice if they choose to. A Player may choose the Yellow Die (5 dice in total). If they choose the Red Die they must also roll the Yellow Die (6 dice in total) and if they choose the Black die they must also roll the Yellow and Red Dice (7 dice in total). The Yellow, Red and Black dice can give a player extra bonus Victory Points but they may also cause Crime Chicky and her Evil Minions to do extra dastardly things.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player rolls all of their chosen dice, setting aside any dice showing Crime Chicky, an Evil Minion or a Stink Bomb Egg. These dice may not be rerolled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The remaining dice may be rolled up to 2 more times, again setting aside those showing Crime Chicky, a Minion or a Stink Egg.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once the players have played eight rounds, the game is over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring! &amp;#10;In a two player game:&amp;#10;The player with the most Victory Points for capturing Evil Minions receives 2 extra Innocent Bystander Victory Points. If there is a tie, no extra Victory Points are awarded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the most Victory Points for capturing Crime Chicky receives 4 extra Innocent Bystander Victory Points. If there is a tie, no extra Victory Points are awarded.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In a three or four player game:&amp;#10;The player with the most Victory Points for capturing Evil Minions receives 3 extra Innocent Bystander Victory Points. The player with the secondmost Victory Points for capturing Evil Minions receives 2 extra Innocent Bystander Victory Points. If there is a tie for the most or secondmost captures, the tying players receive all extra Victory Points (3 or 2 depending).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the most Victory Points for capturing Crime Chicky receives 5 extra Innocent Bystander Victory Points. The player with the secondmost Victory Points for capturing Crime Chicky receives 3 extra Innocent Bystander Victory Points. If there is a tie for the most or secondmost captures, the tying players receive all extra Victory Points (5 or 3 depending).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In either case, the player with the most Innocent Bystander Victory Points (after totalling up all points) is the winner and receives the Key to the City. If there is a tie the player who has captured Crime Chicky the most times is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="42166" value="Todd Sanders" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23816" value="Air and Nothingness Press" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>