<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="254158">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/wRxbS0TaqSFxVT1ltlo7RA__thumb/img/DyHpWSdLfMVSbQufuwR8vMYQA3M=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4308711.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/wRxbS0TaqSFxVT1ltlo7RA__original/img/27ZaKBKstB1eLqMo6bC2BuoAb-Y=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4308711.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Monstrite" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>They are strong, quick, intelligent and tireless. The monsters are the latest technological discovery and the most popular item on the market. Just a few days after release, they are already being used in many areas, from industrial production to show business.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;However, you &amp;mdash; the scientists of the monster factory &amp;mdash; have a terrible secret: You wish to use the monsters you have created to help you conquer the world! You are just biding your time while the public becomes used to them, then you will call them back and spread panic! You should train your monsters in the arena to learn special tricks to use in the final battle. Sounds easy? It might be, but you must watch out for your colleagues who have the same evil plan as you. You will have to fight them first if you want to win and rule the world!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monstrite is divided into two game phases. During the first phase, players amass monstrite tokens and by using the machine cards they create monster tokens. During this phase, players earn victory points (VPs) by selling monsters based on the contract cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the second phase, they call the monsters back and fight each other in order to become the undisputed leader. During this phase, player earn VPs by battling with their monsters and winning battle cards. Battles are solved by using a special bidding system and by the utilization of trick cards. At the end of the game, the player with the most VPs wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;bull;&amp;bull;&amp;bull;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Sono forti, agili, intelligenti e instancabili. I mostri sono una grande scoperta tecnologica e il miglior prodotto sul mercato. &amp;Egrave; passato poco tempo dal loro lancio in commercio, ma sono gi&amp;agrave; utilizzati in molti settori; dalla produzione in fabbrica al mondo dello spettacolo. Ma non &amp;egrave; tutto oro quel che luccica. Tutti voi creatori di mostri nascondete un terribile piano; volete usare i mostri per conquistare il mondo. Sar&amp;agrave; sufficiente aspettare che la gente si sia abituata alla loro presenza per iniziare a seminare il panico. Nel frattempo potrebbe essere utile allenare segretamente i mostri facendoli combattere nell&amp;rsquo;arena, cos&amp;igrave; che possano apprendere nuove tecniche di combattimento per la battaglia finale. Sembra facile? Potrebbe esserlo. Ma meglio ricordare che anche altri scienziati hanno lo stesso obiettivo. Solo chi vincer&amp;agrave; la battaglia finale avr&amp;agrave; il mondo in pugno. &amp;#10;Gestisci la fabbrica, diffondi i mostri ovunque nel mondo e, una volta che sar&amp;agrave; iniziata la guerra, sconfiggi i tuoi avversari in una battaglia &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rsquo;ultimo mostro&amp;rdquo;!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monstrite si divide in due fasi di gioco. &amp;#10;Durante la prima fase i giocatori devono accumulano i gettoni Monstrite e utilizzarli per costruire mostri sempre pi&amp;ugrave; evoluti, grazie all&amp;rsquo;ausilio delle carte Macchina. Inoltre, in questa fase si ottengono punti vittoria vendendo i Mostri, in accordo alle carte Contratto, a settori diversi, come quello industriale, quello dello spettacolo o l&amp;rsquo;arena. &amp;#10;Durante la seconda fase i giocatori richiamano i mostri sinora creati e li utilizzano per scontrarsi allo scopo ottenere il dominio incontrastato. In questa fase si ottengono punti vincendo le carte Battalgia contro gli altri giocatori, grazie a un meccanismo di aste e all&amp;rsquo;ausilio di carte Trucchetto. &amp;#10;Alla fine del gioco, vincer&amp;agrave; il giocatore che avr&amp;agrave; conquistato il maggior numero di punti vittoria.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1088" value="Industry / Manufacturing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="109990" value="Riccardo Remo Appino" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="9483" value="Pierluca Zizzi" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="7716" value="Tim Huesken" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5530" value="Giochi Uniti" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3888" value="Stratelibri" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="14" />
			<average value="5.92857" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.25085" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="21" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="13" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>