<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="254501">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TPi6e22oPEyL_B97g-G8Uw__thumb/img/jKCWbAQO_qzGRqTRHjcMMyNMGrI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4202516.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TPi6e22oPEyL_B97g-G8Uw__original/img/qhJurZzaZcBjDuH8QbOBBihQpz8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4202516.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Welded Iron" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Lore:&amp;#10;In an alternate 19th century world created by artist Nicholas Maxson-Francombe, machines have been built to serve as soldiers. Fires burn in their heads, keeping their engines running and they survive a hail of bullets. Princess Feodora has taken control of London, which has now been turned into Clockwork City.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Machines were given more and more autonomy and control - punchcards passed between soldiers and seers. Now, the machines seem to have developed some sort of consciousness and no-one has heard from Feodora in years.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Edinburgh, re-engineering has gone awry and a new set of machines has arisen, wanting nothing less than the decimation of every potential problem in the land - including humans!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Clockwork City is being invaded, this is the moment for the human captives of Clockwork City to escape.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Welded Iron allows players to either play as the Imperial machines defending their tyranny over Clockwork City, or as human heroes who strive to escape.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Imperials want to keep the humans as slaves and keep their infrastructure intact. The humans want to avoid casualties and use the chaos to evacuate the city. In the end, everyone might survive but this is just the start of the war.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay:&amp;#10;Welded Iron is a tower defense yet competitive game of an uneasy asymmetric alliance between one player: the imperial machine overlords and the other human factions. The imperial machines will use iron and steel resources to build and maintain infrastructure, while also ensuring area control over regions where humans work and live. Each player will have asymmetric powers to reflect the differences in strengths and objectives. For instance, The imperials will have powers which help to quickly build up defense infrastructure from the invading machines of the North, while also utilizing passive human &amp;quot;resources&amp;quot; to help in those goals. The human factions will have formed an alliance with one another after the grueling human wars in a bid to overthrow their imperial overlords. Their objectives are at odds with the imperials, as they must extract and rescue as many humans in clockwork city, and beyond to win, yet also defending the city from invasion.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game utilities randomly allocated hex tiles with positions in which towers are built for defense and attack, with regions to place electricity to power these up. The hex tiles also contain unknown bonus resources, with higher more valuable resources closer to the invading camps of the north. The imperial and human factions must work together to defeat an AI controlled invasion force or face annihilation, while also working towards their own objectives to win.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Designed by acclaimed medium-heavy weight designer David Turczi, Welded Iron will please those looking for a new fresh take on tower defense games, with many miniatures available.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1088" value="Industry / Manufacturing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22185" value="Admin: Cancelled Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="39912" value="Category: Tower Defense" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="76227" value="Dávid Turczi" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="119850" value="Nicholas Maxson-Francombe" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="34033" value="Alley Cat Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="12" />
			<wishing value="128" />
			<numcomments value="6" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>