<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="256759">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/tA0Mmo_4mzhAAjQ5h3ONDQ__thumb/img/jp25GCXgb-1jUU8bqC6LSRz5ZSQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4227898.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/tA0Mmo_4mzhAAjQ5h3ONDQ__original/img/owrvXvOzN74g3amHCevum9xU0Mw=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4227898.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mr. Rhee: Surviving the Nightmare World" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Mr. Rhee: Surviving the Nightmare World is a 3-6 player asymmetrical card game, where the one plays the hero and the many are the villains. As a Villain, spend Greed to recruit and send your evil minions to take control of locations throughout Nightmare World from the innocents -- or use your character specific win conditions to seize the day. As the Hero, use Hope to gather Fight, Charisma, and Magic to hold out for six rounds -- the day and night of the Three days of Darkness that are consuming Nightmare World -- using your team and abilities to mitigate damage... and set the Villains at each other&amp;rsquo;s' throats. Fast-paced and wickedly fun, this game plays in about 30 minutes. Will you take over the Nightmare World, or just survive it?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay&amp;#10;Gameplay starts with the hero determining which villain should play first. That Villain spends Greed to recruit Minions, and place them in Locations. Placement happens either secretly (face-down where they will do team damage), or with fangs bared (face-up where they may single out a specific victim among the Innocents, Heros, or opposing Villain&amp;rsquo;s Minions). However, Greed is flipped to Hope, so the more actions a Villain takes, the more the Hero will be able to counter. The Hero then uses Hope to move to locations, and gather Fight, Charisma, and Magic. Each Hero abilities card costs more Hope than the previous, so the Hero determine what skills are worth the cost.&amp;#10;Once the alternating sides of Villain and Hero have each taken their turn, any Locations with conflict are resolved. This time, the starting Villain may choose which Location resolves first. The Innocents fight the Minions with the help of the Heroes, who now use their skills of Fight (brute force against the opposing side) Charisma (persuading a Minion to turn on his allies) Magic (targeting a single Minion to attack) while the Villains strategically use their Minions abilities and brute strength.&amp;#10;When the conflict is concluded, so is the round, and the fight begins anew. Either the heroes use their skills and special powers to hold off the terror for all 6 rounds (Day and Night of &amp;ldquo;The Three Days of Darkness&amp;rdquo;), or one of the Villains meet their asymmetrical win conditions to take the city by force, rule the world, and win the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Theme&amp;#10;In the graphic novel series NIGHTMARE WORLD we learn that once upon a time an Archangel named Lucifer, incensed with what he saw as a tyrannical reign over all Creation by God, organized a revolt coup that he hoped would give him control of Earth and all humanity. It failed. As a result, Lucifer and the angels who followed him were banished to the bowels of the Earth as punishment, forever banned from Heaven and Earth. Realizing that the numbers were on his side, Lucifer has since spent years organizing a plan for revenge &amp;ndash; this time relying not just on the Fallen Angels, but also recruiting Lilith and her countless demon spawn, Cthulhu and the Great Old Ones, rallying them together as part of one concentrated effort to occupy Earth and take control of Creation in a campaign of monstrous terror dubbed &amp;ldquo;The Three Days of Darkness.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;In the spin-off graphic novel series TALES OF MR. RHEE we learn that humanity is not without its defenses against the forces of darkness, both with the street-fighting magician Mr. Rhee as well as the covert cabal of magicians known as The P.R.O.M.I.S.E. Group. When &amp;ldquo;The Three Days of Darkness&amp;rdquo; erupt across the world, The P.R.O.M.I.S.E. Group, dedicated to the &amp;ldquo;Permanent Reduction Of Monsters in Society Everywhere&amp;rdquo;, emerge from the shadows to join forces with Mr. Rhee and a collection of other heroes who know they may not be able to win, but are nonetheless willing to sacrifice everything to make sure the forces of darkness won&amp;rsquo;t either.&amp;#10;Written by horror comic master Dirk Manning &amp;ndash; who also serves as a consultant on this game &amp;ndash; NIGHTMARE WORLD Volumes 1-4, the NIGHTMARE WORLD OMNIBUS, and TALES OF MR. RHEE Volumes 1-4 (so far) are all published by Devil&amp;rsquo;s Due Publishing and available anywhere comics are sold.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1116" value="Comic Book / Strip" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="91147" value="Julie Ahern" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="77159" value="Joshua Sprung" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="18615" value="Greenbrier Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="8.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.11803" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="11" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>