<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="257055">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/1spPEiuPFAziVAaLMCZKnw__thumb/img/3iyEb22gCh0rbT3_FbpQRsCHqj4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4267636.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/1spPEiuPFAziVAaLMCZKnw__original/img/OPbFnsLDYz4S5IfJ3KdSUVNmhbQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4267636.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="EverWyrd Fantasy Gaming" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="EverWyrd" />
			
						               													<description>EverWyrd is a Dungeon crawling adventure roleplaying game where you become the hero(es) in a constantly changing world. Using map cards randomly drawn from the deck, you and your friends will create worlds of adventure, peril, and battle; more importantly, you will collect and horde wonderous treasures while questing your way across the land and towards legendary status.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The 2020 update will include all-new, original artwork, different playable races, new cards, and an entirely new format. We will also have all creatures and example heroes as 2D print &amp;amp; play miniatures.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The world of EverWyrd had its origins with the Elves and Dwarves who forged a balance of work and life that allowed them to live in peace and harmony. The elves took the surface domains of Ral and Friijlant, while the dwarves toiled in the caverns and tunnels beneath Ashland Heights and Eryn. In order to survive, both learned the ways of the other, but only as a means to provide for each other. Thus, for thousands of years did they live in peace together; dwarves forging weapons and minting precious metals, the elves hunting, farming, and encouraging life to sustain and prosper above. &amp;#10;All this would change with men. Seeking a better life - an easier life perhaps - man moved north, across the marshes from the land of Ibros, to live amongst the elves and dwarves. Both peoples were curious about men. Those creatures were notoriously greedy and often cruel to one another. Could they learn to live in peace as the elves and dwarves had done?&amp;#10;&amp;#219;&amp;#157;   &amp;#219;&amp;#157;   &amp;#219;&amp;#157;&amp;#10;Each side believing in their cause, each side using powerful magic that would corrupt the lands in which they fought. Their wars would drive the elves from the land of EverWyrd, with the exception of a small band who would become the Sidhe, the last of the elves born with magical abilities and skill to them. The Sidhe built a stronghold in Calus, deep in the forest at the base of great mountains and shunned the human race.&amp;#10;The dwarves, who had made their home in the tunnels and caves underground found their homes collapsing from the heaving of the corruptions of magic. They tried in vain to fight against the power of the Warlocks, but they could not resist them. In the end, the dwarves died out or found safety in the more remote lands of EverWyrd, fearing their numbers would never recoup their loss. The dwarves, like the elves, would never be inclined to share with the human race again. From their icy tunnels in the Frigid Peaks, the dwarves watched man destroy itself.&amp;#10;As the armies of men clashed, great warriors, powerful magic-users, and assassins from the shadow rose and fell in great numbers. Such it was that the humans destroyed themselves. Those who fought were killed however possible, and those who did not die ceased to fight. After years of carnage, so few were left that they finally agreed to end their battles. Practicing the dark power of NecoMagia was outlawed, save for a select few who studied relentlessly and proved their value to the councils. Wyrd, being the purest form of magic became revered and the power behind the thrones of EverWyrd would forevermore be that of the powerful witches and wizards that thrived. &amp;#10;None recognized the damage they had done to the world itself. The tunnels and underground caves, the murky underworld of EverWyrd, had been forever transformed. Creatures that had never before existed now thrived in the corrupted magic left behind by the great war, and they became a threat to the people and other races that now sought to live their life on the surface of EverWyrd.&amp;#10;&amp;#219;&amp;#157;   &amp;#219;&amp;#157;   &amp;#219;&amp;#157;&amp;#10;Thus, does your story take place, a thousand years after that first group of men reached for a better life, only to find their future generations destroying everything they believed in. As man stretched its wings to discover the art of magic and use magic, so too did they actively destroy their own world. What lies beneath the ground for which thousands walk? Are you brave enough to find out? What other things might you learn if you delve into the reasons behind the thrones of EverWyrd? What magic, power, and riches might you discover if you&amp;rsquo;re brave enough to dare?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="113614" value="Shawn Hescock" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="111369" value="Liam Thompson" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="106591" value="Joselito Casula" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="14055" value="Rick Hershey" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="76118" value="Indi Martin" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44076" value="Geeks Collaborative Gaming" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>