<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="258370">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="RATH: Race Against The Horde" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>RATH&amp;#10;Race Against The Horde&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Goal: To be the first survivor of the zombie outbreak to complete 3 Survival Missions.&amp;#10; Premise: You are one of the few surviving humans in a zombie infested world.  Your town, once full of beautiful trees and parks is now decaying and run down. There are a few groups of fellow survivors with base camps set up around the town.  Through your walkie-talkie a distress call is heard requesting that a supply run be done as soon as possible. You accept the task and start off on your journey. Along the way you come across floods, fires, zombie hordes, and military fall out.  At the end of the journey, you are the hero that helped save mankind from annihilation.&amp;#10;     &amp;#10;Game Board: Movement can only be done on spaces that have grid lines. Players cannot move through bushes and trees or walk on water. The buildings can be accessed by any space surrounding the border.  &amp;#10;Daily Update Cards:  The Daily Update cards effect game play in different areas of the board.  Hazards in this zombie infested city slow down a players&amp;rsquo; travel time, move them back to their home base, or force detours from their original path.  Multiple grids on the map can be effected at once and each player must comply.&amp;#10;Survival Mission Cards:  Each player will have one Survival Mission at a time to fulfill.  Each player has a separate base camp of survivors they are trying to keep alive.  By completing the missions on the cards, each player saves human lives by delivering life sustaining goods such as food, water, weapons, or building supplies to repair dilapidated structures.&amp;#10;To Start: Shuffle Survival Missions cards and place on corresponding space on board. Shuffle the Daily Update cards and place on the corresponding space on board. Place each colored playing piece on the corresponding colored home base buildings on the map. This means each player will have a different starting position based on the color of their piece. &amp;#10;Each player picks a random Survival Mission at the beginning of the game. The mission does not start until the player reaches the first building to pick up supplies and the mission does not end until the player reaches the destination to drop off supplies. Once complete, the player turns the card over and picks another Survival Mission to start on the next day/turn.  Once a player has completed 3 successful Survival Missions, they are the winner of the game.&amp;#10;Player Movement: Each player can move a maximum of 5 spaces per day (turn) unless specified on the Daily Update card.  Players can move horizontal, vertical, and diagonal. &amp;#10;Game Play: One (1) Daily Update card is drawn per day (turn) and effects each player on the board for that day/turn only.   &amp;#10;The youngest player at the board is the first to draw a Daily Update card.  Each player moves based on the Daily Update card in a clockwise manner, starting with the card drawer first.  For example, player one reads the Daily Update card and is slowed from maximum movement of 5 spaces to 2 spaces. Their turn is over and now player two reads the same Daily Update card and makes their move.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2481" value="Zombies" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="111267" value="Brian Strickland" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="111267" value="Brian Strickland" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>