<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="259945">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pvLyQLIZbmzG7umEbUZTXg__thumb/img/AjdCphQk2JqncXQ6xQ3qc5YyW6I=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4298198.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pvLyQLIZbmzG7umEbUZTXg__original/img/3ytZY02T8UuG_PuvTmdNocikE7U=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4298198.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="NFL Showdown" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ever wish you could call all the plays for your favorite NFL team? Now you can! Choose your favorite NFL team (All 32 teams are represented) and outsmart your opponent by calling the play on both offense and defense. Choose the right play and get rewarded&amp;hellip; but you&amp;rsquo;ll also need a little luck. Roll the dice to see if that big gain will go for extra yardage or if a key play will result in a turnover. Each team comes with 2 specific &amp;quot;Big Play&amp;quot; cards that embody the core strengths of that team. Use each card only once per half to change the outcome of a play. Clock winding down? Line up for a field goal and take your chances at kicking the ball through the uprights.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In more detail...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Starting The Game&amp;#10;Choose Rookie or Pro Mode. The two game modes allow players at any skill level to get into the game!&amp;#10;- Rookie Mode- For newer NFL players.&amp;#10;- Pro Mode- For experienced players and fans.&amp;#10;Pick your team and grab your team's Scoring Footballs and Big Play cards!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Picking Your Play&amp;#10;The offense has 4 downs to either advance the ball 10 yards for a first down, score a touchdown, kick a field goal, or punt.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Both Offense and Defense choose a play card from their set of Playbooks. If the Defense correctly predicts what play the Offense is running it will result in a good outcome for them. However, if the Defense choose poorly, the Offense could pull off a big gain!&amp;#10;The Offense announces what play book both sides will be choosing from.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Running a Play&amp;#10;Each team chooses a play card and places it face down at the Line of Scrimmage. When ready, both players flip over their cards at the same time to reveal the outcome of the play:&amp;#10;Find the circled player on the offense card and follow the arrow down to the defense card to see the result.&amp;#10;Move the Line of Scrimmage marker the same number of yards as the result of the play.&amp;#10;Also, move the First Down marker and the Down Tracker Chip.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Distance and Passing Dice&amp;#10;Some plays may indicate that dice need to be rolled for the result of a play. Roll the indicated color dice to show the yards gained or lost on a play. The white passing die is also rolled to determine the outcome:&amp;#10;    Catch- The pass is complete, and the offense gains yards.&amp;#10;    Turn Over- The defense intercepts the pass and gains possession of the ball at the spot of the catch.&amp;#10;    X- The pass is incomplete, the ball remains at the current yard line.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Big Play Cards&amp;#10;Each team has 2 Big Play cards that showcase that team's strengths. Use these cards to make a big play during the game! Big Plays add or remove yards from the end of a play.&amp;#10;These cards are played after the Playbook Cards are flipped over.&amp;#10;Only ONE Big Play card can be played per down- the first player to place a Big Play on the game board gets to play the card.&amp;#10;Once a card is played, it is discarded for the remainder of the half.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Kicking Field Goals&amp;#10;Use the Flicker Kicker to literally kick the ball off the Line of Scrimmage on any down. Place the field goal posts behind the end zone, lined up between the lines marked on the game board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the kick is good- and passes through the field goal post uprights and above the crossbar, then that team scores 3 points.&amp;#10;If the kick misses- and does not pass through the field goal posts, then the other team starts their next possession.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Just line up the kick, pull back on either the tab or the kicker foot, and release to send the football flying through the uprights!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Officially licensed product of the National Football League&amp;#10;Includes all 32 NFL teams&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Contents&amp;#10;64 Big Play Cards&amp;#10;19 Playbook Cards&amp;#10;3 Distance Dice&amp;#10;1 Passing Dice&amp;#10;32 NFL Team Footballs for Scoring&amp;#10;1 Scoreboard&amp;#10;3 Scoreboard Clips&amp;#10;1 NFL Showdown Game Board&amp;#10;1 Field Goal Post&amp;#10;1 NFL Flicker Kicker&amp;#10;1 NFL Football&amp;#10;1 Line of Scrimmage Marker&amp;#10;1 First Down Tracker&amp;#10;1 Down Tracker Chip&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="59705" value="Misc: LongPack Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="66150" value="Sports Teams: National Football League (NFL)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5640" value="Sports: American Football / Gridiron" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="601" value="Buffalo Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="84" />
			<average value="6.2244" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.52668" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="14636" bayesaverage="5.52668" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.58911" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="228" />
			<trading value="10" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="24" />
			<numweights value="3" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>