<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="263980">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/2eC2sKYhFPL3uxKGOp4hfw__thumb/img/UulQ_IuIlaTfdb4TObNWTRu4nRg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5146309.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/2eC2sKYhFPL3uxKGOp4hfw__original/img/tGV7qmzbGnkkznHLQnomsmjPNC0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5146309.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Emporous" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>&amp;quot;At the heart of the Royal Blue Sea, a position in the Council of the Great City of Menhos, political and economic capital of the Kelonic archipelago is now vacant. The leaders of the smaller islands eagerly seek to obtain that seat by gaining more influence through commerce and production.&amp;#10;    Trof&amp;iacute;, the island of fishing and agriculture; Eide, the land of great sawmills; Calkino the island of bronze foundries; Latomeia, the quarry of the high seas; and Kras&amp;iacute;, producers of the best grapes; all of them try to gain their place among the families that rule the Council, the capital&amp;rsquo;s founding families of a long tradition of master craftsmen. In their efforts, the emissaries of these islands can take the advantage of the founding families&amp;rsquo; favour they obtain when gaining influence in the city or in exchange for a price.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;    &amp;quot;Emporous&amp;quot; tells a story in two chapters, the second one being a more complex option for players who enjoy bluffing and negotiating in a more intense way. We advice to play the First Chapter before proceeding with the Second one, but that's not mandatory.&amp;#10;    In &amp;quot;Emporous&amp;quot; you are the sailing emissary of an island -called  &amp;quot;Emporous&amp;quot;- dedicated to raw material production, islands that compete to have the most economic influence in the Capital city, Menhos. As such, you must find the fastest way to acquire influence points by fulfilling contracts, commissioning artisan works and gaining Masteries. The First Chapter of our Story, &amp;quot;Kelonic Islands&amp;quot;, is about these struggles.&amp;#10;    The game develops in a series of turns, in which you'll have to make a Trip, choosing whether to &amp;quot;Travel to your Island&amp;quot; to recover all your spent coins and bring back some raw materials your island produces; or to &amp;quot;Travel to the city&amp;quot; to perform one action, such as using your available resources to acquire different ones, to commission artisan works or fulfill your contracts. On the other hand, you can complete your objetives faster if you have the Council&amp;rsquo;s Seal, which grants you access to the benefits of having the founding families&amp;rsquo; favour, Seal which you can obtain by gaining influence in the city or by giving the Council one of your coins.&amp;#10;    The Second Chapter of our Story, &amp;quot;The Council of Menhos&amp;quot; tells the real reasons behind all the changes in the Council, in which our Emporous will get tangled in a more complicated web of relationships with the council and with each other. In this Chapter, you'll have to complete Clandestine Tasks acquired during the game before it's end, while trying to get influence as fast as possible. If you fail to fulfill one or more of these tasks, you'll lose influece for each one of them.&amp;#10;    The graphic design in this game has been specificaly though of and developed for being accessible for people with a colour blindness condition, especially for protanopia and deuteranopia.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;En el coraz&amp;oacute;n del mar Turqu&amp;iacute;, uno de los asientos del Concejo de la Gran Ciudad de Menhos, capital pol&amp;iacute;tica y econ&amp;oacute;mica del archipi&amp;eacute;lago Kelonico, ha quedado vacante. Los l&amp;iacute;deres de las islas m&amp;aacute;s peque&amp;ntilde;as buscan &amp;aacute;vidamente obtener ese esca&amp;ntilde;o ganando influencia a trav&amp;eacute;s del comercio y la producci&amp;oacute;n.&amp;#10;Trof&amp;iacute;, la isla de la pesca y la agricultura; Eide, la tierra de los grandes aserraderos; Calkino la isla de las fundiciones de bronce; Latomeia, la cantera de altamar; y Kras&amp;iacute;, productores de la mejor vid; todos intentan ganar un lugar entre las familias que dominan el Concejo, familias fundadoras de la capital y de una larga tradici&amp;oacute;n de maestros artesanos. En sus esfuerzos, los emisarios de estas islas podr&amp;aacute;n sacar ventaja de los favores de estas familias fundadoras que obtienen al ganar influencia en la ciudad o a cambio de un precio&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;    &amp;quot;Emporous&amp;quot; cuenta una historia en dos Cap&amp;iacute;tulos, siendo el segundo una opci&amp;oacute;n m&amp;aacute;s compleja para jugadores que disfrutan el &amp;quot;bluff&amp;quot; y la negociaci&amp;oacute;n un poco m&amp;aacute;s intensa. Aconsejamos jugar el Primer Cap&amp;iacute;tulo antes de proceder con el Segundo, aunque ello no es obligatorio.&amp;#10;    En &amp;quot;Emporous&amp;quot; eres el emisario navegante -llamado &amp;quot;Emporous&amp;quot;- de una isla productora de materias primas del archipi&amp;eacute;lago que compiten por obtener la mayor influencia econ&amp;oacute;mica en la ciudad capital, Mehnos. Como tal, deber&amp;aacute;s buscar la forma m&amp;aacute;s r&amp;aacute;pida de conseguir puntos de influencia a trav&amp;eacute;s de contratos, artesan&amp;iacute;as y maestr&amp;iacute;as. El Primer Cap&amp;iacute;tulo de nuestra historia, &amp;quot;Las Islas Kel&amp;oacute;nicas&amp;quot;, se trata de estos esfuerzos.&amp;#10;    El juego se realiza en una serie de turnos de jugador, en que deber&amp;aacute;s realizar un Viaje, decidiendo entre Viajar a tu Isla a buscar tu producci&amp;oacute;n y recuperar tus monedas, o Viajar a la Ciudad para realizar una acci&amp;oacute;n como usar tus recursos disponibles para adquirir otros, encargar artesan&amp;iacute;as y cumplir con tus contratos. Por otra parte, podr&amp;aacute;s completar tus objetivos mucho m&amp;aacute;s r&amp;aacute;pido si cuentas con el Sello del Concejo que te permite acceder a los beneficios de contar con el favor de las familias influyentes de Menhos, Sello que obtienes cuando ganas influencia en la ciudad o pagando una de tus monedas a las familias fundadoras.&amp;#10;    El Segundo Cap&amp;iacute;tulo de nuestra historia, &amp;quot;El Concejo de Menhos&amp;quot;, cuenta las verdaderas razones tras los cambios en le Concejo, en el que nuestros Emporous se ver&amp;aacute;n enredados en una red de relaciones m&amp;aacute;s complicada tanto con el Concejo como con los dem&amp;aacute;s jugadores. En este Cap&amp;iacute;tulo deber&amp;aacute;s completar Tareas Clandestinas adquiridas durante la partida antes de que &amp;eacute;sta termine, mientras intentas conseguir la mayor cantidad de influencia lo m&amp;aacute;s r&amp;aacute;pido posible. Si no consigues completar una o m&amp;aacute;s de estas Tareas, perder&amp;aacute;s influencia por cada una de ellas.&amp;#10;    El dise&amp;ntilde;o gr&amp;aacute;fico de este juego ha sido expresamente pensado y desarrollado para ser accesible para personas con daltonismo, especialmente protanop&amp;iacute;a y deuteranop&amp;iacute;a.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer (Spanish)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1050" value="Ancient" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2900" value="Market" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="70948" value="Digital Implementations: Tabletopia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="307421" value="Emporous: Roll &amp; Sail" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="113108" value="Nicolas Martinez-Conde" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="114541" value="Rodrigo Manríquez Jara" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="17" />
			<average value="7.85529" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.84685" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="32" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>