<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="264341">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/t3lmf7-4gIjVuiAzWWEWhQ__thumb/img/7hfPTEsCL0C6CJgTZMxrZDYLLw4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4683798.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/t3lmf7-4gIjVuiAzWWEWhQ__original/img/p6CwXtnqml8FZ-Ft2hZV7HuPOVQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4683798.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Captain&#039;s Orders" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Free game published in the August 2018 (GTM #222) issue of Game Trade Magazine.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game utilizes the Pairs game system and is designed with the Pirate Deck, though it can be played with any Pairs deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Story: You are mutinous pirates trying to gather a crew and overthrow the Captain. But the Captain and his allies hide among you, and they aim to foil your plans!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Captain&amp;rsquo;s Orders is a game of bluffing and deduction.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You Need: A Pairs deck and a way to keep score.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Definitions: The Captain is a secret player, the person holding the lowest ranked card. The identity of Captain can change whenever cards are played and passed. Sometimes there will be a tie for lowest card, so there may be more than one Captain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All non-Captain players are Mutineers. Mutineers can win the round either by discovering the Captain, or by accumulating the most points in their hands. (Cards are worth their face value in points.) The Captain can win only by running out of cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each Round: To begin the round, shuffle the deck and deal a hand of six cards to each player. Play begins on the dealer&amp;rsquo;s left and proceeds clockwise. Pass the deal to the left after each round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On Your Turn: Your options are different depending on whether there is an Order on the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;NO ORDER: If there is no Order on the table, you must do one of the following: play an Order, pass a card, ask for a card, or discover the Captain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play an Order: Play a card face up in the middle of the table. This card becomes an Order and you are its owner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pass a Card: Pass a card from your hand to another player, face down. That player must then discard one card face down.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ask for a Card: Ask another player to pass you a card from their hand, face down. Then you must discard one card face down.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Discover the Captain: If you think you know who the Captain is, you can accuse that player. This ends the round, and all players must immediately reveal their hands to find the true identity of the Captain(s).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you are a Mutineer, and you correctly identify the Captain, you win the round. Otherwise, you can&amp;rsquo;t win, and the other Mutineer with the most points wins the round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;STANDING ORDER: When an Order is on the table, your options are different. You must either follow or belay the Order, or discover the Captain as described above.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Exception: You do not respond to your own Order. If an Order has traveled all the way around the table, its owner simply discards it, and the turn passes to the left.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Follow the Order: Pass a card face down to the owner of the Order. The rank of the card you pass must be equal to or higher than the rank of the Order. (Note: there is no discard after this type of card pass.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Belay the Order: Play a new Order of a lower rank than the current Order. The old Order is discarded, and the new one belongs to you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ending the Round: The round ends when any player runs out of cards, or tries to discover the Captain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Running out of Cards: Whenever you empty your hand, either by passing a card or by playing an Order, you may reveal that card and declare that you are the Captain. This ends the round, and if you&amp;rsquo;re right, you win. If you were passing that card away, and you are not the Captain, then the card passes into that player&amp;rsquo;s hand for scoring.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ties for Captain: If more than one player holds the lowest card, then either of them can win by running out of cards, and Mutineers can win by accusing either of them. However, one Captain can&amp;rsquo;t win by identifying another one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ties for Points: If two or more Mutineers win with the same score, they each score a win for the round .&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning: The first player to win three rounds wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="86" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="87" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="88" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="89" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="90" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="55926" value="Series: Pairs Game series 2018 (Game Trade Magazine)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="39915" value="Series: Pairs Game System (Cheapass Games)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="61" value="James Ernest" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="12" value="Cheapass Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>