<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="267025">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KHRyp5kq7CGMRZG1EZlxaA__thumb/img/MAAdVce0Pi9L3NjdqTlpdTikphQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4469096.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/KHRyp5kq7CGMRZG1EZlxaA__original/img/06SUrXwRBTjDUVZTsW3pM0zmeSc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4469096.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ostroleka 26 maja 1831: Iganie 1831" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Iganie 1831 covers the battle of Iganie, one of the most brilliant victories of Poles over Russians during the November Uprising. It was fought between the Polish army commanded by General Ignacy Pr&amp;#196;&amp;#133;dzy&amp;#197;&amp;#132;ski and the Russian 6th Corps commanded by General Grigory Rosen. The battle was the final part of the Polish Spring Offensive. The goal of the operation was Russian army&amp;rsquo;s main depot in Siedlce, which supplied all Russian forces fighting in the Kingdom of Poland. After two first successful for Poles battles at Wawer and D&amp;#196;&amp;#153;be Wielkie (both on March 31st 1831) the pursuit for the defeated Russians was stopped. It allowed them to control chaos which appeared during the retreat, reorganize their units and bring reinforcements.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The battle of Iganie was the last try to broke Russian 6th Corps near Siedlce and capture the Russian main depot. Planned by General Pr&amp;#196;&amp;#133;dzy&amp;#197;&amp;#132;ski attack of three groups approaching from three different directions failed becaue of the lack of operational coordination and poor command of General Jan Skrzynecki. Two groups which had to cooperate with Pr&amp;#196;&amp;#133;dzy&amp;#197;&amp;#132;ski&amp;rsquo;s maneuver group did not appear during the battle and has come to the battlefield in the late evening or the next day. This caused that Pr&amp;#196;&amp;#133;dzy&amp;#197;&amp;#132;ski&amp;rsquo;s forces had to fight outnumbered by Russians. Russian forces also were divided into parts. General Rosen was bound by the orders from Field Marshal Ivan Diebitsch which urged him first of all to defend Siedlce and keep defensive position on the eastern bank of the Muchawiec river. That gave Pr&amp;#196;&amp;#133;dzy&amp;#197;&amp;#132;ski chance to beat the enemy situated on the western bank of the Muchawiec river before Russians combine all their units and destroy his group. The decisive moment of the battle was when Russians started to move battalions from the eastern bank of the Muchawiec river to its western bank where the battle was taking place. Pr&amp;#196;&amp;#133;dzy&amp;#197;&amp;#132;ski decided to seize the only bridge on the river. During terrific bayonet fight Polish 5th Line Infantry Regiment completely broke the elite Russian Jaeger Brigade (13th &amp;amp; 14th Jaeger Regiments), called Warna Lions (because of their fame gained in the recently finished war with Turkey), and captured the bridge. This cut off Russian units on the western bank of the river from the rest of their comrades. Finally Poles won the battle. The Russian losses are estimated between 3 600 &amp;ndash; 4 500 soldiers, while Polish one numbered 400 &amp;ndash; 500 soldiers. Tactical success of Poles was undoubted, however they did not decide to attack through the swampy river Muchawiec also because of the informations that the main Russian army is near and would join the Rosen&amp;rsquo;s forces the next day.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is an expansion for Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka 26 maja 1831. It means that Iganie 1831 uses system rules (also charts &amp;amp; tables) and markers which are in Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka 26 maja 1831. There are two scenarios in the game: the historical and the alternative one. The first one in more detailed way simulates the battle and all background of it, especially specific events and operational situation of both sides. The alternative scenario is more flexible, giving the players more possibilities to create their own strategy and modify the course of the battle. However this scenario also stays in historical frames. Although the game bases on Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka 26 maja 1831 system rules, there are few new rules for this battle only. The most important are command points and changeable phase order. In the rule &amp;amp; scenario book you will find also a detailed historical article on the battle and some additional system rules for Ostro&amp;#197;&amp;#130;&amp;#196;&amp;#153;ka 26 maja 1831 (especially an integrated table of artillery fire with round-shot and granades). The playing time varies from 2,5 to 4 hours, however there is an autowin option which can end the game faster.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components (all packed in ziplock):&amp;#10;- One mapsheet 42 x 30 cm &amp;#10;- 108 die-cut counters&amp;#10;- One rulebook and scenariobook (both in one book)&amp;#10;- One sheet with information on Russian artillery modifiers&amp;#10;- Two sheets whit unit rosters (for Poles and Russians)&amp;#10;- One sheet with turn track and command points tracks&amp;#10;- One sheet with mapsheet legenda&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="150" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="16" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="3">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1051" value="Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2710" value="Post-Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2079" value="Variable Phase Order" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58151" value="History: Polish uprisings – Russo-Polish Wars (1792-1794-1831-1863)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="188124" value="Ostroleka 26 maja 1831" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="84415" value="Ryszard Kita" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="87448" value="Szczepan Atroszko" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="84415" value="Ryszard Kita" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="102635" value="Tomasz Niedzinski" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="30961" value="Instytut Wydawniczy Erica" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="51" />
			<average value="9.02941" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.54609" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="5.54609" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="5.82782" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.71902" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="59" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="24" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="3.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>