<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="267296">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/etcT7mBpfI0OPi5SGeEwew__thumb/img/mj_xZlwBkgXgVTXQ6AHf4Wf8Wq8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4475134.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/etcT7mBpfI0OPi5SGeEwew__original/img/D0Gqx3erVDOKWHinxDOi6AuKsII=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4475134.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Solitary Journey" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Overview&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This played-in-the-hand solitaire game, played with ordinary playing cards, simulates a journey through fields and forests, oceans and mountains.  On the way you may meet helpful guides and mischievous fellow-travelers.  With some luck you may find enough treasure and magical tools to enable you to find the home of your dreams and live happily ever after.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game is played entirely in the hand, so there is no need for a table.  You can play it anywhere.  If you are interrupted, you can put it in your pocket and take it up later.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Set Up&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Remove the four Jacks from a deck of playing cards and shuffle the rest of the deck, including the two Jokers.  Arrange the Jacks face up in the order Hearts, Diamonds, Clubs, and Spades, with Spades in the back and Hearts in the front.  Place the rest of the deck face down on top of the Jacks.   The Jacks will act as counters to keep track of how many times you&amp;rsquo;ve gone through the deck; when they show up, put the first one behind the other three and continue playing.  When you reach the Jack of Spades you have gone through the deck four times and have finished the game. The Jacks also hold your items for you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Interpretation of the cards&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The four suits represent four kinds of landscapes.  Hearts are oceans, lakes, and rivers.  Diamonds are plains, fields, moors, and prairies.  Clubs are forests.  Spades are mountains.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The values of the cards represent various treasures, tools, items, landscapes, and people.   The &amp;ldquo;view&amp;rdquo; is the name for the four cards that are fanned face upward in your hand.  They are not only the cards you can view, but they also represent the things you can see as you look around you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Some of the cards represent first a location, and then, under the right circumstances, an item that you find at that location.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Goal&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Travel though various landscapes, collecting treasure and magical tools.  Eventually use the tools to find the home of your dreams and live happily ever after.  If you find your home, you have won the game.    But once the Jack of Spades appears, you have finished your journey, whether or not you have met your goal.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Terms&amp;#10;&amp;#10;View:  the top four cards fanned out face up on top of the deck.  In some situations there may be more cards in your view.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Discard:  place a card face down at the back of the deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Store:  place a card face up behind the face-up Jack of the same suit&amp;#10;&amp;emsp;&amp;#10;Gameplay&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Hold the deck face down in your hand, with the Jacks face up in the back.  Turn over the top four cards and fan them so you can see them all.  These cards form your current view.  If in the course of play your view becomes less than four cards, replace them with cards from the front of the deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You may discard any card from the view at any time.   At any time you may look to see what cards you have stored behind the Jacks.  They will be easy to find because they will be face up together, while the rest of the deck will be face down.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A complete description of the rules will be found in the files section.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="98" value="Components: Traditional Playing Cards" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="91826" value="Karen Deal Robinson" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="10" />
			<average value="7.8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.14455" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="26" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="17" />
			<numcomments value="16" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>