<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="269034">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/uP0m4A_IsqJ7BNOuzxa_NA__thumb/img/fttFo5s4-KknqSIn3S2zb3VeRPo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4530135.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/uP0m4A_IsqJ7BNOuzxa_NA__original/img/JvQsZ-i4bxHlfVAjbkHSFQjsa1M=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4530135.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Alliance: The Card Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Alliance: The Card Game is a fantasy, dueling card game with warring factions, fighting to become the new and true Alliance. Players can enjoy this simple-to-learn, two-player, battle game between armies to defeat your opponent's Leader and win the battle. The game of chance, simplified strategy, and fantasy warfare!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Zaldar's return from the dead, with a dragon army behind him, has shaken the world and now armies and factions of all kinds rally for war! The world needs a new Alliance, but who will form this new Alliance? Will Zaldar reign supreme? Or will it be...you?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Objective of Game: Battle between armies to defeat your opponent's Leader and win the battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components of Game: 35 Cards per deck, 6 sided die, Health Point Tokens, Game Board, Scroll of Rules, &amp;amp; stickers&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How To Play: &amp;#10;Leader Appears - place your Leader closest to you. The Leader will not be able to battle until the army in front of the Leader is defeated. &amp;#10;Shuffle - shuffle your deck and place your deck face down to your right.&amp;#10;Army Line Up - draw the top 5 cards from your deck and place them face up in front of your Leader. This is your army, ready for battle.&amp;#10;Roll Order - both players roll the die. Whoever rolls the highest number goes first. Each turn consists of a Placement Phase and a Battle Phase. &amp;#10;Placement Phase - if you have an army space open place the next top card from your deck in its place.&amp;#10;Battle Phase - you may attack twice per turn, but not with the same character. First declare who you're attacking by whom you're attacking with. Roll the die. If the number matches your character's Roll Number, you deal the character's corresponding Attack Number to your opponent's character's Health Points. If not, the attack misses and no damage is dealt. If damage is dealt more than your opponent's character's Health Points, then the character is slain and placed in the Slain Pile. If damage is dealt less than your opponent's character's Health Points, then Health Points are replaced with the correctly numbered Health Point Token. &amp;#10;Leader's Entrance  - Your Leader comes into play when your army is depleted and no Units or Generals stand in front of him. The Leader can now attack, dealing the most damage on the battlefield, but can also be attacked by your opponent. &amp;#10;Victory  -  Once your Leader's Health Points reach 0 you lose the battle. If your opponent's Leader's Health Points reach 0 you win the battle&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Classes: &amp;#10;Unit - bulk of army, 30 per deck, average attack and health points, &amp;amp; adorned with copper frame and tablet&amp;#10;General - more powerful characters on the battlefield, 4 per deck, stronger attack and health points, &amp;amp; adorned with silver frame and tablet&amp;#10;Leader - Leader of your army/Alliance, 1 per deck, strongest attack and health points &amp;amp; adorned with golden frame and tablet&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Battling: Roll Numbers &amp;amp; Attack Numbers&amp;#10;When battling roll the die. If your roll matches your character's Roll Number then you deal the corresponding Attack Number (below the Roll Number). If the Attack Number is higher than your opponent's character's Health Points, then it's Slain and sent to the Slain Pile. If the Attack Number is lower than your opponent's character's Health Points, than replace their Health Points with the correctly numbered Health Point Token.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Character Types: &amp;#10;Warrior&amp;#10;Beast &amp;#10;Mage &amp;#10;Beast Warrior&amp;#10;Beast Mage&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Health Point Tokens:&amp;#10;The numbered, circle tokens replace a character's Health Points after they take damage. If you character takes 3 damage, from your opponent, and your character's Health Points are 5 then you replace your character's Health Points with the Health Point Token numbered 2.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="35" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="114729" value="Cole Kornell" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="78110" value="Sutthiwat Dechakamphu" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="7.33333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.0548" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>