<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="272530">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RYYctklYng0pqwjF-_KkFw__thumb/img/q69vvJUY79udCIGsObxvOGD0TnI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4602525.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RYYctklYng0pqwjF-_KkFw__original/img/A9NjPW-26myYmadm2DaZeMMpyBE=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4602525.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bloody Big Balkan Battles!" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>For almost 600 years, from the fabled shores of the Bosphorus, the Ottoman Sultans ruled over a vast land in Europe, stretching from the Mediterranean to the Danube.  Sometimes enlightened, sometimes cruel, the rule of the Chalifs of Islam had steadily receded before the fury of national ideals and the rising might of European imperialism promoted by bayonet and capital. And yet it still survived, still stubbornly clinging to Balkan territories rich in history, industry and population. The &amp;ldquo;Great Patient&amp;rdquo; seemed to spite Greece, Bulgaria, Serbia and Montenegro; the states created by bloody struggle by those who once were termed the gavur rayahs of the Sultan. They saw with worry the growing appetite of aggressive great powers, all making claims to what they saw as their just inheritance. And then by coup and counter-coup, the fall of a Red Sultan, and the rise of a Committee, the rapaciousness of a young Great Power, and the entente of two old foes, the Balkan states saw danger and opportunity and struck. In the span of just a month of the greatest battles seen in Europe since 1871, the dream of Osman was shattered.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This scenario supplement for Bloody Big Battles! permits you to re-fight those great battles that saw the end of the Ottoman Empire in Europe and the formation of the basic modern borders in the Balkans. Nine scenarios cover some of the most important battles of the First Balkan War, covering the campaigns of Greece, Serbia and Bulgaria against the Ottoman Empire which would drive the Empire to the very gates of Istanbul/Constantinopole/Tsarigrad.  Five scenarios then cover the Second Balkan War, the conflict between the successful allies which pitted Serbia, Montenegro and Greece against Bulgaria over the legacy of the Ottoman Empire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each scenario provides a distinct operational and tactical puzzle for war-gamers to resolve. From straightforward assaults against fortified positions like the First Battle of Chataldja, to complex double envelopments like the Battle of Lule Burgas, from the extensive broad fronts of the Battle of Bregalnitza, to the knife fight in close quarters of the Battle of Bizani. There are small scenarios easily played in one or two hours, like the Battle of Dioran (the actual First battle of Dioran), and more substantive scenarios like the Battle of Kumanovo, still playable in an evening.  There are battles fought on rolling hills and plains, like the Battle of Kirkkilise, and battles fought in some of the worst ground people have ever thought of fighting each other in an organized manner, like the Battle of Kalimanchi.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You will see how these wars where similar and how they differed from The Great War. You will understand the crucial role of terrain as a military variable and grapple with key decisions of force to task distributions in an unforgiving strategic operational and tactical environment. You will see the last glory days of the bayonet charge, and the opening bloody howl of modern artillery.  There is challenge to satisfy all types of war-gamers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;An included overview of the historical events and biographies of many of the commanders whose roles you reprise on the table-top will provide you with the background to give you an inkling of the vast stakes and human drama associated with these battles. An annotated bibliography provides you both with the sources used to build the scenarios and further reading to enrich your understanding and experience. A figure guide helps you find suitable ways to represent the armies in almost all scales of miniature war-gaming.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A struggle for a vast future awaits! Take command and see how history was forged!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="16" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58171" value="History: Balkan Wars" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="63041" value="Region: Balkans" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="176992" value="Bloody Big Battles!" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="9602" value="Chris Pringle" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="115509" value="Konstantinos Travlos" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3899" value="Brigade Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>