<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="273762">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7QaH-uLhlc6fV_L1BeRXBQ__thumb/img/wb-9bj2egZcEfmAUUx11XAiVc5U=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4611771.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7QaH-uLhlc6fV_L1BeRXBQ__original/img/D-IWZPska9FJH2qbEpiLtOL67QA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4611771.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Zone Raiders: Deadly Skirmishes of the Post-Singularity" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>'Zone Raiders is a fast-paced tabletop skirmish game where small groups of hardened survivors battle against each other in an unforgiving post-technological world called the Matroshka. Within an unending world of inscrutable science, radiation storms and machines dedicated to exterminating life, players create narrative stories and rewarding tactical gameplay in an open-model skirmish ruleset.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Distinct in our design is an emphasis on mobility, vertical space, and accomplishing asymmetrical objectives before escaping to safety. Your tactical decisions and smart positioning will decide every encounter with the enemy. The world itself is lethal, but can you adapt your strategy, characters and exotic weapons to meet the challenge against both other players, and solo/cooperative scenarios?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combining inspirations from small-scale tabletop wargames, campaign skirmish games, RPGs and tactical turn-based video games, Zone Raiders is a fusion of what we love best about all of these.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;We wanted to strike the right chord between tactical depth of play, narrative campaigns and character development along with a commitment to streamlined rules while maintaining sophistication. Combined with a stunningly alien scifi setting that is vast enough to encompass many themes as a player's imagination can conjure, it's a game meant to scratch an itch we've felt for ages.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Or on a more direct note Have you ever wanted to play a game where you could...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Grappling Hook to tall ledges, snipe foes, then dive to safety?&amp;#10;     Wallrun up a steep slope, and kick a bad guy over a railing to their doom?&amp;#10;     Fight AI Monsters issuing from an automated factory, then lure them into a nest of explosive barrels before blowing the lot up?&amp;#10;     Open an cryo-vault to rescue an ancient survivor with lost knowledge?&amp;#10;     Project force-field bridges across vast gaps, only to turn them off when foes set foot on them?&amp;#10;     Combine versus and cooperative play into a single ruleset, with stealth and objective focused mechanics?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All of these are within the domain of Zone Raiders.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;We are an Open-Model game, meaning that the rules and setting are designed for what miniatures you may have and adore. There's numerous fantastic manufacturers out there, and many of us certainly have collections ourselves. Additionally, creating your own group and their stories is all the easier as inspiration can be drawn from all the beautiful models our greater gaming community has created.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Features&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Zone Raiders has a mixture of elements veteran players will both feel familiar with, and refreshed by. In our ruleset, you will find:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;      Rich, Easy to Learn Rules - Combine easy to learn core gameplay with mechanics that reward tactical positioning, maneuver, and applied firepower to outfox your opponents. Practical rule design ensures that no decision is without appropriate consequence.&amp;#10;      Tactical Team Skirmish - Build a Raid Team of 6-12 hardened survivors in your quest to endure. Equip each one with different weapons and specialized skills and watch them grow... or die.&amp;#10;      Dynamic Movement - Feel the mobility of our unique Dynamic Movement system, where your Raiders can be equipped to parkour, wallrun, grapple or powered vault across broken terrain and lethal gaps. Smash opponents off tall ledges, or create forcefield walls to trap them in place!&amp;#10;      Deadly Environments - Your opponent is not the only threat on the battlefield. Protecting ancient relics and scavenge are automated exterminator machines, psionic mind-scorchers, fierce nano-contaminant storms and radiation fluxes. When the lights vanish or unexpected snipers arise during a Dark Emergence Event, can your forces adapt?&amp;#10;      Diverse Factions - Command 7 unique factions with engaging playstyles, from the regimented Reclaimers, the agile Technomads, cunning Zone Stalkers to the evolving robotic NthGen, each force is dripping with flavor and tactical options as well as unique researchable doctrines and equipment.&amp;#10;      Campaign System - Lead your team beyond a single battle, but to victory in a campaign where your strategic decisions have great importance. Will you build up your team's tech skills, or abort the mission to retrieve an ancient cryopod? Should your team construct a mighty industrial robot, or develop maps of the battleground for a tactical edge? &amp;#10;      Asymmetric Missions - Winning a battle isn't the same as winning a war. Players can elect  different goals during a mission, from capturing prisoners to hacking an automated train. Perhaps it's worth it to cut your losses during a failed mission, or even change objectives mid game as a new, more valuable prize is discovered!&amp;#10;      Exotic Equipment - Featuring over 100 different types of weapons, armor and survival gear, you will have numerous options on how to equip and defeat your foes. &amp;#10;      Merciless AI Enemies - The Immunocytes are merciless machines that are anathema to all intelligent life. Destroy or outmaneuver their AI-controlled agents during battle, or perhaps even trick them to tie up your opponents!&amp;#10;      Cooperative Play System - Sometimes the enemy of my enemy is my friend. Join forces with other players to take on thrilling Cooperative Missions, where you must employ speed and stealth to defeat overwhelming numbers of AI foes to accomplish cinematic objectives as either single missions or campaign play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72016" value="Players: Wargames with Rules Supporting Only Two Players" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="41593" value="Fractal Basilisk Design Studios" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="16" />
			<average value="8.8125" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.66654" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="31" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="21" />
			<numcomments value="10" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="2.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>