<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="274437">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HChoLq50zAS54dgfRgypdQ__thumb/img/NlAM-ifhQHccqmjCBtuDyR_Iohc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4622413.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/HChoLq50zAS54dgfRgypdQ__original/img/AB5dojs_1BSNslgKEbmeF-OUPZ0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4622413.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Archers of Godfrey" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>An intense cooperative, dice-rolling, unique tower defense set in a medieval fantasy world for 1 to 4 players. Have you ever wanted to be an archer on a castle wall? Now is your chance because all players play as archers defending against four powerful armies all attacking at once. Will the small band of archers defend the great castle of Godfrey or will the four Captains of the armies gain control of the castle? It is up to you and your team of archers so, &amp;ldquo;Notch, Draw, Loose!&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How To Win:&amp;#10;Players win if all four Captains are killed before one reaches the Center of the Keep.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players lose if:&amp;#10;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; A Captain reaches the Keep at the center of the Inner Court. &amp;#10;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; All ten soldiers of any one army are placed on their quadrant in the bailey.&amp;#10;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; The Player&amp;rsquo;s Deck has no more cards left to draw.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;General Gameplay:&amp;#10;The goal of the game is to kill all 4 Captains before 1 advances to the Keep. Archers will be attacking the Captains with their arrows while eliminating the invading armies. Players will also use cards and purchase items from the Archer&amp;rsquo;s Equipment to accomplish this goal.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every normal arrow is worth 1 damage unless otherwise stated on the cards or with special abilities. Each archer has 5 arrows and 5 spaces to move each turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The 12mm dice are the soldiers of the different armies that are invading the castle. The health of a soldier is determined by what it rolls. Archers can ONLY attack soldiers in their row of their quadrant. Archers kill soldiers with their arrows by reducing the soldier&amp;rsquo;s health down to 0.  Archers receive an Archer Trophy for each soldier they kill during their turn. Archers will use these trophies to purchase equipment to help them defeat the Captains.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a soldier's health reaches 0, then remove that dice from the bailey and place it back on its army&amp;rsquo;s card in the Gathering Area. The soldier dice will be rolled again and placed in a future round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Archers do NOT receive an Archer Trophy if soldier dice are killed while being placed during the Enemy phase. However, Archers do earn trophies for soldier dice killed by barrels and cards that upgrade their arrows.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Most of the cards are split and have two options.  Players choose one option to play and then discard. Players CANNOT play both of the options on the split cards. Split cards are designed to help for the different situations that players find themselves in.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each round has two phases: Archer Phase and Enemy Phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Archer Phase&amp;#10;Each Archer Phase consists of all 4 archers taking their turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player&amp;rsquo;s Turn:&amp;#10;Draw 1 Card &amp;#10;Add to hand or follow the instructions if it is an Enemy Card. &amp;ldquo;Captain Advance&amp;rdquo; cards advance the Captain to the next space in their trail toward the Keep at the center of the Inner Court.&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;Extra Soldier&amp;rdquo; cards will add an additional soldier to be placed during the Enemy Phase of that round (&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2) Anytime during an archer&amp;rsquo;s turn they may:&amp;#10;Move 5 spaces and Shoot 5 arrows.&amp;#10;Play 1 card from your hand OR purchase items from the Archer's Equipment&amp;#10;If you purchase items, then you CANNOT play a card in the same turn.&amp;#10;If you play a card, then you CANNOT purchase items in the same turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3) Discard for hand limit&amp;#10;4) Pass the 1st player Castle Token to the person on your left (Clockwise)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player&amp;rsquo;s Movement:&amp;#10;Archers are allowed to move to any space along the castle walls with a yellow border. Only one archer is allowed on each space along the wall. However, two archers may be on a &amp;ldquo;Starting Position&amp;rdquo; at the same time while they are moving along the wall. And as archers move past another archer, they CANNOT shoot arrows in the row of the other archer as they pass over them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Stairs do not count as a space, the Archers just walk through them to the next space with a yellow border. Start positions do count as one space when the Archers are moving around to the other wall.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Enemy Phase&amp;#10;Each Enemy phase begins immediately following the Archer Phase. &amp;#10;The Enemy Phase consists of 3 elements:&amp;#10;Roll the d8 Captain dice and resolve.&amp;#10;Check what number you rolled with the Roman numerals on the 4 corner towers. Whatever number you rolled, the Captain in that quadrant advances one space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the Captain is in the bailey,then add a rolled soldier in the space that the Captain advanced from.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the Captain is in the Inner Court, then resolve any Barricades that they might have passed through. No soldiers are ever placed in the Inner Court.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If that Captain is dead, then nothing happens. Take a deep breathe. You DO NOT re-roll if you rolled to advance a dead Captain.&amp;#10;Roll the Soldier Placement dice for each of the 4 armies and place 2 soldiers on to each quadrant of the bailey.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roll 8 new soldiers (2 for each army) and place them on the two soldier positions of their army card. These will be placed in the next round during the Enemy Phase.&amp;#10;The highest health is placed in position #1&amp;#10;The lowest health is placed in position #2&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After rolling the NEXT soldiers and placing them on their army cards, then the Archer Phase of the next round begins&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="39912" value="Category: Tower Defense" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="116022" value="Jeff Leopard" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="116023" value="Martin Newberry" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>