<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="274448">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/MYVRmaZwFnAOZ1-Nwyh5Pw__thumb/img/hvlEagHBC5icUScmLajOfjyfpSA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4617042.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/MYVRmaZwFnAOZ1-Nwyh5Pw__original/img/JUDMKcr7ZXw9lA6R9YSsAbd_u78=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4617042.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Soulbound" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Paragon Studio's flagship game, Soulbound is a strategic battle card game experience unlike any other before it. Utilising the &amp;quot;everything in one box&amp;quot; model, everyone who plays Soulbound will be able to experience the game as it is intended to be, without the financial investment hurdle. Feel the thrill of commanding creatures of mythology to become the next Soulbound!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Along with creatures of mythology, Soulbound introduces a unique take on explaining what happened to these creatures that stoppped their existence in Modern Day planet Earth. Explore how the unknown war of the heavens and hell, known as &amp;quot;The Vanishing&amp;quot;, caused Pandora's Box to thrust creatures of mythology and Gods alike into an alternate reality of planet Earth, known as Axiom07 by the greater beings. To the local population, the planet is called Duhra, and they have no idea about the darkness that they will have to fight back in order to survive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Soulbound is the world's first battle card game that gives you the authentic Trading Card Game experience, while incorporating a heavy influence from Tactical Turn-Based Strategy Role-Playing games and a &amp;quot;Dynamic Resource&amp;quot; system. With Melee creatures, Ranged creatures and Support creatures, players will get to make new kinds of tactical decisions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every game of Soulbound comes with every card available. It also comes with two starter decks pre-configured so that players can learn that game before jumping in to the deck building aspect. In a box, 2 players can easily create two competitive decks. For the most competitive players, they may find they need a copy of the game for their own. With an abundance of available cards to build decks from, your ability to make the correct tactical decisions will be the biggest difference in a game. Skill should always determine the best player, not the player with the deepest pockets.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Soulbound is played over a series of turns in which you, an Animan of the planet Duhra, command creatures in battle against other Animan to work your way up to the title of &amp;quot;Soulbound&amp;quot; and be entrusted with fighting back the darkness that escaped from Pandora's Tome. Utilising your own Soul Energy, you begin your turn by building up your resource to Call creatures to the field. Creatures are able to act the turn they are played to the field which creates a very high tempo game. Having a strong offence is just as important as having a strong defence, as your resource also acts as your life force. Throughout a game, it can be attacked and fluctuates because of that. No linear resource growth here.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Through the many creatures' abilities and combat, players attempt to make tactical decisions to break through the opponent's defences and deal damage to the opponent's resource. A skillful players will be able to manage both their own resource and their opponent's resource to ensure they always can have the upper hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With outstanding table presence, outstanding art, and outstanding gameplay, Soulbound will keep you engaged and constantly creating new combos in your head. In the end, the only thing that matters is dealing 60 Soul Damage to your opponent and claiming your spot among the Soulbound.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="11" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1082" value="Mythology" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="41750" value="Paragon Studios MB" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="4" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>