<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="274827">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/hPl3ZEtoi2nUM1IdlTS8tQ__thumb/img/zINp5NUPAdvnlx_qxwlQxG2kGEI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4655896.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/hPl3ZEtoi2nUM1IdlTS8tQ__original/img/pLFsQklMti5PA3wGAKKpx8OThY0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4655896.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mix &amp; Mayhem" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Mix &amp;amp; Mayhem is a fast-paced family battling card game for 2 to 4 players. It can be played in 4 different ways, providing exciting variation and wide age range appeal.  One of the games aimed at young children is a simple mix and match stlye game. One of the other games is a Top Trumps style of selecting a category and the highest value wins. The other two of the game variations are trick taking games that involve trying to create the most powerful creatures and battling them against your opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game contains 72 cards, including 60 character cards and 12 special action cards.  The 60 character cards include 20 Head cards, 20 Torso cards, and 20 leg cards.  Combined in the right sequence, these cards create 20 fearsome characters ready to do battle, however, when the cards are mixed with cards from other characters they can create up to 8,000 unique characters each with their own unique name and powers. You will create crazy, scary, funny, unusual and wonderful characters to battle and try to defeat your opponents.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mix &amp;amp; Mayhem cards can be played in 4 different ways, You Complete Me, Wipe Them Out, Skirmish, and Bunch of Fives. The rules for each game are described below.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You Complete Me!&amp;#10;Preparation: Remove all of the Action cards. Shuffle the Character cards and place them in a pile&amp;#10;face down.&amp;#10;Playing the game: Decide who goes first, then each player takes it in turns to take a card from the pile and lay them face up in front of them. As the game progresses each player will be able to mix their cards to create weird and wonderful creatures as the game progresses.&amp;#10;The winner: The aim is to be the first player to create one of the 20 original characters made up of the set of correct 3 cards. If neither player is able to create one of the 20 original characters before the cards are all drawn then the cards are collected, re-shuffled, and drawn again until there is a winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Wipe Them Out!&amp;#10;Preparation: Split the cards into 3 separate piles for Heads, Torsos and Legs (including the Action cards which are also marked on the back of the card as Head, Torso and Legs cards). Shuffle each pile and deal the cards face down to each player so that each player has their own separate piles of Head&amp;#10;cards, Torso cards, and Leg cards. Each player should have the same number of body part cards.&amp;#10;To play the game: Each player picks up the top card of each pile of body parts so they have a complete character, with a Head card, Torso card and Legs card. If they pick up an Action card instead of a character body part they should keep this and draw another card from the top of the pile until they have a character body part. The Action cards that they may have picked up can be used during the game. Players hold the cards facing themselves, so only they can see them. Decide who goes first, then that player will select a category &amp;ndash; either Brains, Strength or Speed. Each player shows their card to reveal the value of the chosen body part. The player with the highest&amp;#10;value wins the battle and the player with the lowest value must discard the body part card that lost. Then the loser must pick up the next top card from their pile of the same category until they have a complete character again. The winner of the battle can keep the same cards in play. However, each card can only be used a maximum of 2 times to win a battle. After an individual body part card has won 2 battles it must be discarded and a new one drawn. Players will take it in turns to select a category. Both players must always have at least 3 cards in play, including a Head card, Torso card and Legs card in addition to any Action cards that have been collected. To create some extra mayhem the Action cards that have been drawn by players during the game can be used when it is their turn at any stage of the game. Once a player uses an Action card it must then be discarded.&amp;#10;The winner: The object of the game is to defeat your opponent by wiping out a pile of their cards so that they are no longer able to make up a full character and therefore unable to continue to battle. When a player is unable to make a complete character they are defeated and their opponent is the winner of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Skirmish!&amp;#10;Preparation: Shuffle all of the cards (Character and Action cards) into a single pile.&amp;#10;Playing the game: Each player will take it in turns to draw a card from the top of the pile. The cards are laid face up so they are visible to both players.  When both players have a complete character of a Head card, Torso card and Legs card they are ready for battle. Players can create the character of&amp;#10;their choice to battle with from any of the character cards they have drawn. Each turn, players have the option to challenge their opponent to a battle, or to draw another card to&amp;#10;try and create more powerful characters. Once a challenge to battle has been made by either player, the characters they both have created for the battle must be declared and put side by side. The total character score is calculated by adding together the brains, strength and speed values, and the player&amp;#10;with the highest total character score wins that battle.  If a player is able to create one of the correct 20 unique character sets then their overall character score is increased by an extra 10 bonus points. The player who makes the challenge may think they have the most powerful character because they&amp;#10;can see the values of their opponent&amp;rsquo;s characters, however, their opponent may create mayhem by playing one of their Action cards that they have collected to swing the outcome of the battle. A player can use one or more Action cards at any time. Once a player uses an Action card it must then&amp;#10;be discarded. The players continue to draw further cards and engage in new battles with new characters until all&amp;#10;cards have been drawn and there are no further complete characters in the remaining cards held by both players.&amp;#10;The winner: The player who has won the most individual battles once all the cards have been drawn&amp;#10;wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bunch of Fives!&amp;#10;Preparation: Remove all of the Action cards from the deck and deal all of the remaining character cards into separate Head, Torso and Legs piles. Each player will be dealt 3 Head cards, 3 Torso cards and 3 Legs cards, allowing each player to make up 3 separate characters. The cards are laid face down so they are not visible to the opposing player.  Each player should then privately arrange their cards to create 3 different characters with their own unique name and overall value.&amp;#10;Playing the game: Decide who goes first, then that player will lay down one of their characters to engage in battle with their opponent. The other player must then choose and lay down one of their characters. Whoever has the highest total score (by adding together the brains, strength and speed values) wins that hand. If a player is able to create one of the correct 20 unique character sets then their overall character score is increased by an extra 10 bonus points. Players will take it in turns to lay a character first. Once all 3 characters have battled the players will then be dealt another 3 Head cards, 3 Torso cards and 3 Legs cards for another round of 3 battles.&amp;#10;Following the second round of 3 battles there will be 1 final round of 3 battles, so there will be 3 rounds of 3 battles making a total of 9 battles. &amp;#10;The winner: The first player to win 5 battles is the winner of the game. It is possible therefore to&amp;#10;win the game outright after only 2 rounds without the need for the final round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2009" value="Trick-taking" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="31854" value="Simon Harrison" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="31854" value="Simon Harrison" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>