<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="274910">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-XQnigSgE_wArj_J9ICosw__thumb/img/tq3bmex6d_ds7TEoCQkVO3OlpiA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4653344.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-XQnigSgE_wArj_J9ICosw__original/img/BNFBIDdEuEohQAcNslRlCKPe7pM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4653344.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Wiz-Dom" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;Wiz-Dom&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roleplaying Game and educational tool that combines a kid-friendly fantasy game with problem solving.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Wiz-Dom is playable as either a collaborative tabletop- or an online game, where players assume to roles of young wizards, who enter the School of Magic where they solve problems, pass tests, and earn valuable items so they can ultimately fight the monsters in the Cave of Secrets in d20-based RPG-style combat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The spin is that the problems are based on school subjects, like math and history, so that while kids are playing the game, they&amp;rsquo;re also demonstrating their mastery of educational concepts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#10;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;&amp;#9;Gameplay&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Players choose their Heroes. There are 4 female and 4 male Heroes, each with their unique powers. Heroes are young witches and wizards, entering the School of Magic. A game session spans a semester of their life. Players get the Hero Card and the matching Item- and Spell Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. The Game Master (can be teacher, senior student, parent, etc.) assembles the Deck of Exercises. There are cards of 3 difficulty levels: Easy, Medium and Hard and a certain number must be selected from each category. Subjects include Math, History, Science and general Trivia, with curricula that matches education from age of 10 to 16.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3. The Game Master selects (or randomly draws) a Boss Monster for the game session. All other game components (Cards, tiles, tokens, sheets, etc.) are placed near the gameboard.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4. Players can move on the board by either rolling 2s6 (random mode) or use Movement Cards, giving a more strategic angle to the game. As players move on the board (from Field 1 to Field 30), the following steps will happen:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Depending on the Field they landed on, they either draw a single Exercise Card matching the symbol on the field (Easy, Medium, Hard), or a Fortune Card for every player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(a) If it was an Exercise Card, they get 3, 5 or 10 minutes to solve the Easy, Medium or Hard problems. They can use pen and paper, they can talk to each other - they can even ask for help from the Game Master. If they successfully solved the problem, they get rewards. Every player who successfully solved her exercise will get Rune Golds. If at least one player solved it correctly, they get Team Rune Golds. Red (Hard) cards yield Magic Items as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Also, every player with a successful solution can place a Dungeon Tile. Tiles will form the combat grid for the final battle. There are symbols on the tiles indicating that the player can draw an extra Spell or Item card when placing that Tile. And certain Tiles will summon monsters for the final battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(b) If it was a Fortune Card, each player gets one and resolve the effect immediately. There are supporting ones (gain bonuses, draw items, etc) and there are negative ones (lose bonuses, get cursed, etc).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5. The three corners on the Board (Classroom, Club and Magic Rental) are places where the team must stop, even if they would overstep it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(a) Classroom: they can select an Exercise Card of any difficulty to solve&amp;#10;(b) Club: they can either play a minigame (not included in the box, choose anything you like to distract players for a bit), or have a little break&amp;#10;(c) Magic Rental: after completing the mandatory Red Exercise on Field 30, players can spend their Rune Golds on Items and Spell. They are more than encouraged to collaborate and communicate, to figure out some kind of strategy before entering the final combat. The identity of the Boss Monster is revealed at this point.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6. Once they are well equipped, it's time for the Final Battle! Heroes descend to the Dungeons to defend the school from attacking monsters! Final Battle is a turn-based combat using cards and a d20 dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Heroes and Monsters take their turn, with the order depending on their Movement value. Monsters are controlled by the Game Master, following the behaviour detailed on the corresponding combat sheet.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(a) Movement: a figure can make a number of steps equal to its Movement value. It can step in any direction on the Grid, it can even overstep friendly figures, but cannot cross walls or hostile squares.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(b) Use Card: after or before the Movement is completed, Heroes can use a single card each turn. It can be a spell (usually turned face down after use), or a weapon (can be used any number of times in a combat). Ranged attacks must consider line-of-sight with walls and other objects blocking the way.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combat lasts until the last survivor, with Heroes getting extra Rune Golds as loot. They can use this during their next game session.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="3" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="86" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="87" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="88" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="89" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="90" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="16972" value="Crowdfunding: Indiegogo" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="32919" value="Liber Primus Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>