<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="275627">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jr7nowtGl1SFjf8RTsO1kw__thumb/img/y5072tHnm_38j9rNgKzjFPF6LyA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4645009.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jr7nowtGl1SFjf8RTsO1kw__original/img/cNBmPM1bHRKYbc_2kQ8O8LIHr0g=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4645009.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Necronomicon: The Card Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Necronomicon is a card game set in the dark worlds of H.P. Lovecraft where two players fight each other casting spells, summoning Mythos creatures and using firearms. The knowledge about the mythos can be learnt reading rare arcane books and the magical power can be increased to cast more powerful spells, but also the sanity of the character played will lose sanity progressively, leading to schizofrenia, agorafobia and other terrible effects.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to make the life points of the opponent reach zero. From the deck, 5 cards are dealt to each of the players and one card from the hand can be played each round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are three ways damage can be inflicted, by using conventional fire arms, casting spells and summoning Mythos creatures. Creatures do not block direct attacks from the cards and they don&amp;rsquo;t attack directly, instead they counterattack after your opponent has damaged you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards involving the Chtuhu Mythos (spells and creatures) have a sanity cost which is listed as a number in the card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Apart from the life points, there are four other parameters with a value that will change along the game: i) Elder sign, ii) Arcane power, iii) Taint of the yellow sign, and iv) Sanity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;i) Elder Sign is one defense against the Mythos effects. It can be increased through the use of certain cards. For each point you have, you will take 1 less damage from spell cards and monsters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ii) Arcane Power represents the magical power gained by the knowledge of the Mythos. Arcane Power can be increased through the use of certain cards such as reading Arcane books. For every point you have, you will deal one extra damage for all cards that show the symbol next to the damage number.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;iii) Taint of the yellow sign is a magical curse that can be inflicted using certain cards. Its effect is that for every tainted point you have, you will take one damage at the end of your turn. The only way to purge yourself of the taint is to use certain cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;iv) Sanity: cards related to the Mythos cost sanity points to use. Sanity is the cost for delving into de Mythos and some cards cost zero due them not being of an occult nature. If your sanity reaches zero you will be insane. There are various types of insanity effects, and one of them will be applied randomly:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Schizophrenia: At the end of each turn, Elder Sign and Arcane Power go to zero.&amp;#10;     Megalomania: At the end of each turn, add +2 Arcane and + 4 Taint.&amp;#10;     Xenophobia: your summon cards have no effect.&amp;#10;     Agoraphobia: you can only have 2 cards in your hand. Remove randomly any excess cards from your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2008" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="36" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="37" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="38" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="39" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="40" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5141" value="Theme: Cthulhu Mythos" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="116335" value="Graham Plowman" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>