<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="275826">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4ppjF-mZvN1qIVQPm93wpQ__thumb/img/o-3ciEkNUC-vKcy_vEFD4-ET-nM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4645785.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4ppjF-mZvN1qIVQPm93wpQ__original/img/gNLcBy6OF-8MQRwETJGfmxgo15Y=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4645785.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Crypto When Lambo" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In this game, not only you can build a crypto empire, but also you can try to manipulate the market to gain advantage for your own coin or invest and trade your opponents&amp;rsquo; coins to benefit from their success or failures.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Crypto When Lambo (CWL) board game was inspired by crypto fortunes that were made and lost overnight. Your goal is to build a crypto empire with your own crypto company and coin to become the most successful crypto investor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game takes place across the 8 cities of the world that contain 64 resource producing city tiles. You begin the game with 3 offices, 2 crypto company share cards (each representing 1 million coins), and 5 million game currency. The first player to reach 1 billion or 50 Winning Point Count (WPC) wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To gain WPCs, you must increase the number of your employees, build products, open new offices, complete your management team, ICO your coin, and list it on crypto exchanges. There are 5 resource types (Real Estate, Employee, Management Team, Product, and Crypto Exchange) in the game that allow you to perform various actions to gain points and make money. For example, using 2 Real Estate cards and paying 2 million, you can establish a new office. Each office placed on the board is 2 WPCs and each Product you produce is worth 2 WPCs. There are multiple paths to getting additional points such as by becoming the richest person in the crypto world or leading a crypto company to ICO with several products and employees dominating the markets.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How do you acquire these resources? It&amp;rsquo;s very simple. Each turn a player rolls the dice and the total determines which city production centers will produce resources. Different cities have different attributes. For example, New York and London have more management talent but real estate is harder to get. Hong Kong has a lot of employees that can be recruited. New York is highly regulated and harder to have Crypto Exchanges whereas Tokyo and Hong Kong have more Crypto Exchanges that are accessible.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How do you earn money? For example, 1 Product card can be traded for 5 million. Other resource cards can be traded for 1 million. You can also trade your resources with other players during your turn. You can also do Crypto Trading during your turn and risk some of your money for potential high reward. You can also make money by buying low and selling high your opponents&amp;rsquo; coins by manipulating the market with CWL Action Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In CWL, your most important asset is your crypto company shares. You start the game with 2 of 10 company share cards, each representing 1 million coins. In the beginning of the game your coins have zero value. This is tracked by the Coin Price ticker cards you have in front of you always visible to all players.  You must try to acquire as many as your company share cards as you can while they have zero value. You can also acquire other players&amp;rsquo; share cards before they go ICO to benefit from their ICO price hype. Picking the right time for ICO will determine the revenue you will get from your ICO. Number of products, employees, management team, and manipulation of markets will all affect the coin price. You should try to increase your coin price as high as possible before launching your ICO while trying to manipulate your opponents&amp;rsquo; coin prices. This is all done by using combination of resource cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In order to ICO, a player has to own at least 5 company share cards, a Board of Directors Management card, one of the C-level management cards (CEO, CFO, CIO or CISO) and at least one Employee card. One well timed successful ICO could take you from several million to well above 500 million. ICO is worth 10 WPCs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There is a strategy involved around placement of Offices on the board in the beginning of the game to trading and manipulation of coin prices to timing of the ICO to raise money. Every game develops differently due to actions of each player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CWL is full of fun with trading, resource management, market manipulation, and teaming concepts. It is simple to learn but hard to master with all the strategies available to you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Get ready for your first adventure on CWL. Have fun building your Crypto Empire!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="26" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="27" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="28" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="29" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="30" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2014" value="Betting and Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2005" value="Stock Holding" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="116389" value="E. Osmanoglu" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="41878" value="E.O. Breakers Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>