<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="275922">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="Die Lese-Ratte" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Learning to read in an exciting race: Who is scurrying stealthily through the bookshelf and nibbling on all the pages? A reading rat, of course! In this fast-paced educational game, ABC shooters take up the pursuit of the greedy rodent and learn very easily how to read and understand texts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To stop the voracious reading rat, all players have to read different task cards together. If they have understood the text correctly, they can slide the matching images together on the Turn game board. However, this must be done before the rat has gnawed its way through the shelf. Reading beginners from the age of 6 are just right here. The tasks come in two difficulty levels, so this entertaining learning game can be improved from time to time.&amp;#10;In the race against the reading rat, children immerse themselves in the world of letters, words and their pronunciation. This makes the game a welcome addition to school learning or the ideal preparation for it. Its great pedagogical value derives from the use of the Mildenberger syllable method, which has proven its worth many times over. The syllables highlighted in colour on the text cards lead to a faster comprehension of a word. If it is read syllable by syllable, a word sounds as we have heard it before. Children learn in this way spielerisch that reading makes fun and is not at all so difficult.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Great reading fun with pedagogical demands&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Improves text comprehension in scalable difficulty levels&amp;#10;     Increases the joy of learning and motivates teamwork&amp;#10;     According to the syllable method of Mildenberger&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher (translated)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Im spannenden Wettlauf das Lesen lernen: Wer huscht denn da verstohlen durchs B&amp;uuml;cherregal und knabbert alle Seiten an? Nat&amp;uuml;rlich eine Lese-Ratte! Bei diesem rasanten Lernspiel nehmen ABC-Sch&amp;uuml;tzen die Verfolgung des gierigen Nagetiers auf und lernen kinderleicht, wie das geht mit dem Lesen und Verstehen von Texten.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Um die gefr&amp;auml;&amp;szlig;ige Lese-Ratte zu stoppen, m&amp;uuml;ssen alle Spieler zusammen verschiedene Aufgabenkarten lesen. Wenn sie den Text richtig verstanden haben, k&amp;ouml;nnen sie die passenden Bilder auf dem Wende-Spielplan zusammenschieben. Das muss allerdings gelingen, bevor sich die Ratte durchs Regal genagt hat. Lese-Einsteiger ab 6 Jahren sind hier genau richtig. Die Aufgaben gibt es in zwei Schwierigkeitsstufen, sodass sich dieses unterhaltsame Lernspiel von Mal zu Mal steigern l&amp;auml;sst.&amp;#10;Beim Wettlauf mit der Lese-Ratte tauchen Kinder tief in die Welt der Buchstaben, W&amp;ouml;rter und ihrer Aussprache ein. Damit ist das Spiel eine willkommene Erg&amp;auml;nzung zum schulischen Lernen oder die ideale Vorbereitung darauf. Seinen gro&amp;szlig;en p&amp;auml;dagogischen Wert erh&amp;auml;lt es aus der Anwendung der vielfach bew&amp;auml;hrten Mildenberger Silbenmethode. Die auf den Textkarten farbig hervorgehobenen Silben f&amp;uuml;hren zum schnelleren Erfassen eines Wortes. Wird es n&amp;auml;mlich silbenweise gelesen, klingt ein Wort so, wie wir es schon einmal geh&amp;ouml;rt haben. Kinder lernen auf diese Weise spielerisch, dass Lesen Spa&amp;szlig; macht und gar nicht mal so schwer ist.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ein gro&amp;szlig;er Lesespa&amp;szlig; mit p&amp;auml;dagogischem Anspruch&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Verbessert das Textverst&amp;auml;ndnis in skalierbaren Schwierigkeitsstufen&amp;#10;     Steigert die Freude am Lernen und motiviert zur Teamarbeit&amp;#10;     Nach der Silbenmethode von Mildenberger&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher (translated)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="34" value="Ravensburger" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="16" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>