<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="276594">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/u6f9V-bfdSjaBHJVIhophA__thumb/img/Avfqz0QiX2SlZ8BXmSrR1KkM6Uw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4659166.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/u6f9V-bfdSjaBHJVIhophA__original/img/oW05lOWTc-89DXBOLNLfENy3u8U=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4659166.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rally Point Volume 16: A World at World War 1937-1945" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Rally Point Volume 16: A World at War 1937-1945 is a set of 10 all new scenarios that are set in World War II. These scenarios were originally scheduled to appear in Schwerpunkt Volume #24. Production of future volumes of Schwerpunkt is on hiatus for the foreseeable future, so the Tampa ASL Group decided to publish them in the pages of Rally Point instead. Each scenario was handmade and play-tested to the high standard players expect from the Tampa ASL Group&amp;rsquo;s fine craftsmen. Each scenario is presented in the Schwerpunkt easy-to-read format on high-quality card stock.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT151 Luodian Lament &amp;ndash; LUODIAN, China, 23 August 1937: Nineteen squads from the Chinese 66th Regiment attack to clear the defending 44th Japanese Regiment (11 squads) from the village on boards 10z and 70. This medium-sized 5.5 turn scenario is a tense all infantry action that features Chinese OBA.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT152 Shaken Not Stirred &amp;ndash; VILLERS-MAREUIL, France 29 May 1940: Six R35 tanks and seventeen squads conduct a rare French combined arms attack to seize five buildings from twelve defending squads of the German 57th Infantry. This 4.5 turn scenario is set four half boards: 64, 65, 67 and 70.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT153 Run Gurkha Run &amp;ndash; ASUN, Malaya, 11 December 1941: The title says it best. A company of Gurkha infantry is forced to withdraw across boards 17 and 72 while being hotly pursued by thirteen squads of the Japanese 11th Infantry Regiment and three supporting Ha-Go tanks. This 5 turn scenario has lots of exciting action that usually culminates in a Banzai charge near the end.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT154 Mars Begins &amp;ndash; GREDIANKO, U.S.S.R., 25 November 1942: If you like fighting in the snow, this Eastern Front gem is for you. Twenty Russian squads supported by Lee, KVI and T-34 tanks attack to clear eleven German squads from the buildings on board 3a. This action-packed, 5 turn scenario (Designed by Mike Augustine) features German OBA and Russian rocket artillery.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT155 Schutzstaffel Shindig- GRUSCHKI GRAVE, West of Kharkov, Ukraine, U.S.S.R. 31 August 1943: In this 5.5 turn, medium-sized scenario, a company of ten Russian tanks (T-34s and a KV-2) from the 2nd Tank Corps attacks with infantry riders to clear two StuGs and two PzIVF2s supported by panzer-grenadiers of the 5th SS Panzer Division &amp;ldquo;Wiking&amp;rdquo; from the hills overlooking the roads on boards 18 and 61. This tank battle will test your nerves and require you to use all your tank fighting skills.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT156 Wiking Rescue- ZERCZYCE, and STACJA-NURZEC, Poland, 22 July 1944: Veteran Tampa ASL Group member, &amp;ldquo;Mountain Man&amp;rdquo; Dave Brown makes his designing debut with this unique scenario in which both sides get to attack. A full SS panzer-grenadier company mounted in halftracks and supported by Panther tanks from the 5th SS Panzer Division &amp;ldquo;Wiking&amp;rdquo; attacks to clear a farmstead and relieve the besieged Penal Battalion 560. Will the fifteen Russian squads and six SU-76ms from the 44th Rifle Division overrun their village before help arrives? This is an action-packed, 5.5 turn, scenario that uses boards 9a, 16 and 43.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT157 Ozarks and Frundsbergers &amp;ndash; RURDORF, Germany, 2 December 1944: A company of American infantry from the 102nd &amp;ldquo;Ozark&amp;rdquo; Infantry Division with five supporting Sherman tanks tries to out-flank and cut off the retreat of seven squads, an SPW251/22 and a PSW 234/3 from the 10th SS Panzer Division &amp;ldquo;Frundsberg&amp;rdquo;. This fast playing, 5 turn scenario is set on boards 53 and 72.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT158 Hungarian Hetzers &amp;ndash; EBED, Upper Hungary, 6 January 1945: Eight Russian squads, four T-34s and an SU-85 from the 22nd Guards Tank Brigade attack to clear the village on boards 1a and 9a. Here, the Hungarian Division &amp;ldquo;Szent Laszlo&amp;rdquo; is defending with six squads and three Hetzers, one of which must exit the board. This 4.5 turn scenario is perfect for tournament play and has lots of tense action that is sure to go down to the last CC Phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT159 Lesson Learned in Lessin &amp;ndash; LESSIN, West Prussia, 25 January 1945: The Soviet 9th Tank Corps attacks with a company of infantry, two IS-2s and four T-34/85s to clear elements of the 7th Panzer Division from buildings along a frozen lake. Hidden JgPz IV/70s on the opposite shore pour deadly flanking fire upon the attacking Russians, making this an exciting Eastern Front action in the snow. Mike Augustine designed this 5.5 turn scenario that uses boards 75 and 79.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RPT160 Willie und Fritz &amp;ndash; MUSKAU, Poland, 10 March 1945: Elements of the Soviet 112th Rifle Division (17 squads) with two ISU 122s and four IS-2s execute a two-pronged attack to seize five buildings. Fallschirm Grenadier Regiment Hermann G&amp;ouml;ring defends this town with thirteen squads along with three Panthers and must simultaneously prevent the Russians from exiting two AFVs. This 5.5 turn scenario has multiple victory conditions and a unique tactical situation that provides a lot of re-playability. It is set on boards 2, 3b and 79.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="126" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="127" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="128" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="129" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="130" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2663" value="Turn Order: Time Track" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="79254" value="Decades: The 1930's" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="62" value="Game: Advanced Squad Leader" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="243" value="Advanced Squad Leader" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8506" value="Sherry Enterprises" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="8.33333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.24722" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="19" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>