<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="277052">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vq-hPJUngDSwwfaRqMG4vg__thumb/img/pZnGN0HKU1mhivr-ezsJX3gn32E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4684866.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vq-hPJUngDSwwfaRqMG4vg__original/img/zgeWcIvVR6cwYOQ5rTDlwPlWHFc=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4684866.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dopeman" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Dopeman is a not-so-family-friendly board game. Play as a power-hungry drug dealer trying to get rich quick. Deliver goods to your customers but watch out for the cops and rival dealers. They&amp;rsquo;ll try to take you down as you negotiate, bribe, and scheme your way to the top. Make the most money before time&amp;rsquo;s up, and you win!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The board is your block. To move forward, you&amp;rsquo;ll move your game piece around the sidewalk clockwise. You&amp;rsquo;ll also find a road that the cops drive on, a jail in the middle of the board, and apartments where you will deliver drugs. Your game piece moves based on the white die and the Cop Car moves based on the black die. The person who most recently did drugs goes first.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are four drugs in the game: Weed, Molly, Coke, and Shrooms. Before the game begins, you&amp;rsquo;ll select one type of drug. There are four Suppliers on the board &amp;mdash; one for each type of drug. Suppliers sell you drugs, which you&amp;rsquo;ll then sell at a higher price to your Clients for a profit. Each player has one Supplier from which they buy their designated drug exclusively. You can buy baggies of your designated drug for $10 each from your Supplier every time you land on, or pass over, your Supplier&amp;rsquo;s tile. You may buy as much as you can afford.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You&amp;rsquo;ll receive a Text Message card every time you land on or pass over, a notification tile. There are two types - those from Clients who would like to buy drugs (this will include which drugs they want, how many baggies, and which apartment to deliver them to), and those from Informants who give you advantages throughout the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To sell drugs:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Pass over, or land on, your Client&amp;rsquo;s apartment (indicated by their Text Message).&amp;#10;     Burn Text Message card.&amp;#10;     Discard sold drugs to the box.&amp;#10;     Pick up $50 per drug sold from the box.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There is a Cop Car that travels around the board trying to bust dealers. If at any point, you have possession of drugs and the Cop Car lands on the adjacent tile to your game piece, you&amp;rsquo;ll go to Jail. (You will only be arrested if you&amp;rsquo;re in possession of drugs.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are two ways to avoid being arrested:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Bribe the Cops with $50. (The money should be put back into the box.)&amp;#10;     Blackmail the cops with an appropriate Text Message from an Informant.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you go to Jail, you must discard all of your drugs and weapons. To get out, you must complete a loop around the Jail with your game piece.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If on your turn, you land on a tile shared by another dealer&amp;rsquo;s game piece, you have the option to rob your friend, potentially stealing their drugs. Both players roll one die (the number you roll represents your Attack Strength), and the highest Attack Strength wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On your turn, you may buy weapons - Brass Knuckles, a Switchblade, and/or a Pistol. Weapons increase your Attack Strength during a robbery. You can continue to use your weapons until they&amp;rsquo;re confiscated by the police.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You can also buy an Associate. Associates follow you around the board, allowing you to increase your attack strength during a robbery and increase your movement around the board by +1.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On their respective turns, players may trade Text Messages, drugs, weapons, or cash. There are no rules around trading &amp;mdash; all is fair in love and drugs. If, at any point, you run out of cash, you&amp;rsquo;re out.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When time is up, each player is given one last turn, starting with the first player of the game. When the last player completes their turn, each dealer should count how much cash they have. If you have a weapon, or unsold drug baggies, you may liquidate them for the price you paid. Once each player has tallied their liquidated assets and cash, the player with the highest total wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="18" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1118" value="Mature / Adult" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42042" value="A Moral Company" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="15" />
			<average value="6.16667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.21282" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="20" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="9" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>