<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="277033">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/IRqBuEVBV6u0jQzIRAZIyQ__thumb/img/M92Ahq8LOQqS87Sv0LDi2xX9ebs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4779113.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/IRqBuEVBV6u0jQzIRAZIyQ__original/img/Fe6jC-Ug3pQ0wZRUUofYQyV0src=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4779113.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Drunkgeon" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>INTRODUCTION&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Drunkgeon is a strategic drinking board game where a barbarian, dwarf, mage &amp;amp; elf fight monsters &amp;amp; each other in an ever-changing maze-like dungeon. Each players life is their drink of choice. Players must use their skill in beer mat flipping to be the first to get to the treasure &amp;amp; win the game. However, keep your wits about you as when your drink runs out. you're dead!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;STORY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Welcome to the drunkgeon!&amp;#10;You're with a group of heroes roaming the lands searching for adventure and coin. You come across the Labyrinth of the Old Gods rumoured to contain a great treasure at its heart. The local people warn that the domain within is ruled by ancient forgotten gods. Those that go in never come out and only their cries of madness have given any clue to what awaits inside. As seasoned adventurers, you know more than most that often these rumours are tall tails and laughing among yourselves you enter the labyrinth.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As you walk through the door it slams behind you and in the dark, you hear a voice in your head, &amp;quot;Who dares to enter our realm? You must pay a tribute of blood for a chance of reward and release!&amp;quot;. Torches suddenly light and you find yourself alone in an ever-changing maze of torment. You discover blood is indeed power, for if you sacrifice it you&amp;rsquo;re granted the power to perform ancient magic and great physical deeds. However, the more blood spilled the more drunk on the power you become. What horrors are within these walls? Will you be sober enough to recognise friend from foe? Will you reach the treasure and escape the labyrinth? Head down you plunge into the depths of the labyrinth ready to take on all that awaits&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WINNING AND LOSING THE GAME&amp;#10;&amp;#10;'WIN THE GAME' - Collect at least 3 trophies and each key colour to enter the treasure room. Then defeat the dragon to win the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;'LOSE THE GAME' - If your glass is empty you die. Remove the empty glass from the dungeon and place all your mats on to the space you died. Other players can pick up the mats by landing on that space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SETTING UP THE GAME&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I. The game is played with 2-4 players. Each player gets a 'dungeon key mat' and a 'key token mat' of the same colour. Remove the unused 'dungeon key mats' and a 'key token mats' from the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;II. Randomly place the 'dungeon mats' into a 6 by 6 grid/dungeon. Note: 'dungeon mats' can BE placed in any ORIENTATION.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;III. Place the 'cleared dungeon mats', 'trophy mats' and the rest of the 'key tokens' into piles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;IV. Layout all the 'magic mats' so they can be seen by all players and study them before the game begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PLAYING THE GAME&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pick the first player. A player may do the following three things in any order during their turn. When complete the player to the left now takes their turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I - Insert 'dungeon mat' - The first player inserts their 'dungeon mat' into the dungeon with any orientation. They keep the 'dungeon mat' expelled from the opposite side. IF it is the first turn this must be done before a glass filled with beverage is placed on their 'dungeon key mat'.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;II - Move Their Player - The player may now move by flipping the 'event mat'. They move the number under the majority of their leftmost finger.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- All moves must be used.&amp;#10;- You cannot move diagonally.&amp;#10;- You cannot move through walls.&amp;#10;- A player must move forward in the direction they started moving this turn unless they hit a dead end.&amp;#10;- When the path forks any new direction can be picked.&amp;#10;- If you land on or move over another player, monster(s) or trap you trigger an 'event' (see Events).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;III - Buy a 'magic mat' - To buy a 'magic mat' spend the cost listed on it. You buy it by drinking that many fingers of your beverage. However, another player(s) may contest the purchase by drinking more fingers of their beverage. The player who drank the most fingers takes the 'magic mat' and can use it as and when described. There is only one of each 'magic mat' in the game and so only the 'magic mats' still on the table can be purchased. Once a 'magic mat' has been cast it is placed back on the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EVENTS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;An event is triggered if a player lands on or moves over the following;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;I - Dungeon Key- If they don't already have a 'dungeon key token' of the same colour they can take one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;II - Another player - The player whose turn it is fights the other player. Both players flip the 'event mat(s)'. Whoever has the highest number wins the fight. Re-Flip on a draw. If the player whose turn it is;&amp;#10;- Wins - They may pass or land on the other player's mat. The winner may move the losing player one legal move away.&amp;#10;- Loses - They must stop in the position prior to the player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;III - Monster(s) or Trap - The player flips the 'event mat(s)' and must get the number or more displayed on the monster(s)/trap mat. If the player;&amp;#10;- Wins - They win a 'trophy mat' (see Trophies p4). The monster/trap 'dungeon mat' is removed from the dungeon and is replace with the equivalent 'cleared dungeon mat'. Player movement continues.&amp;#10;- Loses - They must drink the number of 'fingers' from their beverage as achieved from their 'event mat(s)' flip. They must also stop in the position prior to the monster(s) or trap.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;IV - Treasure room - A player can only enter the room if they have collected a key of each colour. IF so the player flips the 'event mat(s)' and must get the number or more displayed on the 'treasure room' mat. If the player;&amp;#10;- Wins - They slay the dragon, take the treasure and win the game.&amp;#10;- Loses - They must drink the number of 'fingers' from their beverage as achieved from their 'event mat' flip. They must stop in the position prior to the 'treasure room'.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TROPHIES&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players can gain 'trophy mats' by defeating monsters and traps. On the reverse side of a 'trophy mat' is an 'event mat'. this is so trophies can be stacked on top of the 'event mat' to form a stack. Whenever there is an 'event mat' flip for combat or movement the player may choose to flip a stack of 'event mats' with the trophies they have won. Each additional 'event mat' adds one to the result i.e. Flip and catch a 2 with a stack of 3 'event mats' to get a 4.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FINGERS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A forfeit in this game is performed by drinking 'fingers' of your beverage. this is done by holding that many of your own fingers against the glass and drinking that volume of your beverage. if there is a dispute in measuring an event mat can be used with one row equalling one finger.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;DIFFICULTY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Beginner - If new players are finding flipping beer mats hard then they can use a 6 sided dice instead. &amp;#10;Note: The game for those players will lose the skill aspect for catching values they need.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Intermediate - 'Event mat(s)' can be flipped until caught. Note: This can slow down the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Advanced - If 'event mat(s)' aren&amp;rsquo;t caught you&amp;rsquo;re fined a finger and the result is treated as zero.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SINGLE PLAYER&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A single player game is played in exactly the same way as playing the normal rules. However there is some reduced setup, as there is no key collecting required so all key token mats can be removed from the game. As there are no other players all 'magic mats' can also be removed from the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The 'magic mat' 'rejuvenate' can optionally remain. If it stays you're committing to potentially more then one drink. IF is removed, as with the 'just the one' variation, the game becomes more about beating the game with a single  glass of beverage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;VARIATION: JUST THE ONE&amp;#10;&amp;#10;the 'rejuvenate' spell can also be removed to add extra difficulty to the game. It also puts a one drink cap on how much will be drunk in a game. This is a useful variation to implement when the player group only wish to have the one pint.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;VARIATION: HALF PINT DUNGEON&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Instead of playing with a 6x6 dungeon try playing with a 5x5 or 4x4 dungeon. Simply build the dungeon and place the remaining &amp;lsquo;dungeon mats' into a stack. After inserting your dungeon key place the expelled 'dungeon mat' to the bottom of the 'dungeon mat' stack Then on future turns draw a mat from the top of the 'dungeon mat' stack and insert it into the dungeon, and again place the expelled 'dungeon mat' to the bottom of the 'dungeon mat' stack. This variation is useful when you have limited table space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAME LINKING MULTIPLE DRUNKGEONS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you have multiple copies of Drunkgeon then they can be joined together to make up to a 6x12 dungeon by combining the 'dungeon mats'. Then use just one set of 'magic mats' and play the normal rules. The game will also now support up to 8 players i.e. two players of each colour.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FAQ&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: Is Drunkgeon designed to get people drunk?&amp;#10;A: No. The game is designed to be a fun first drink management game. A good player will carefully consider the best way to maximise their beverage, whereas other players may blindly run into fights and use magic to replenish their loses. Either style can work but the more sober player is more likely to win.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: How do i shuffle the 'dungeon mats'? Are 'dungeon mats' inserted in a specific orientation?&amp;#10;A: rotate the 'dungeon mats' as you shuffle because they can be inserted into the dungeon in any orientation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: Do you have to drink alcohol? what happens if glasses are different sizes?&amp;#10;A: You may drink any beverage. Ideally everyone should use the same sized pint glass and beverage. However, if different make an agreement among yourselves i.e. a player drinks more glasses or uses smaller or larger 'finger' sizes. If anybody under the legal drinking age is playing the game then all players should drink non-alcoholic drinks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: How do you move the 'dungeon mats' with glasses on them?&amp;#10;A: It is advised to remove the glasses while a row or column of 'dungeon mats' is being moved.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: What happens if i am on a 'dungeon mat' that is pushed out the dungeon?&amp;#10;A: The player is moved onto the 'dungeon mat' that was just inserted on the other side of the dungeon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: Players have blocked the 'treasure room' or are holding a 'dungeon mat' or 'magic mat&amp;rsquo;?&amp;#10;A: Don&amp;rsquo;t let a player get all the 'magic mats' as there are spells that help with these situations. Read the magic mats carefully before playing the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Q: I have picked up another 'dungeon mat' from a dead player?&amp;#10;A: You may now choose either of your 'dungeon mat' to insert during your turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1059" value="Maze" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="72380" value="Rodolpho Langhi" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42039" value="Flaming Troll Board Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42543" value="Flaming Troll Board Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="13" />
			<average value="6.76923" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.77776" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="44" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>