<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="277016">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Y-Ly_dvemSMkuYJ6bOrHHw__thumb/img/VxeW4k79HrtCatoUG8TqoioGxms=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5420319.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Y-Ly_dvemSMkuYJ6bOrHHw__original/img/7ju1mVaxwLLxecRBd55ygYXcLYE=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5420319.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dicecathlon" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A competitive dice-based event for 2-4 players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Released in the February 2019 Board Game of the Month Club $10+ package.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components:  3 Cards (provided), 5 dice per player and up to 10 tokens per player for keeping score.  Each set of dice and tokens should be in a unique color.  A set of Tenzi dice and some tiddlywinks should do the job.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup:  Shuffle the cards and flip one to the dice side, and the other two to the event side.  Place them in a column with the dice on top 10 events showing below.  Choose a player to start.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Choose an event:  The starting player (or the winner of the last event), gets to choose the event that is played.  The numbers below the event shows how many dice are needed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning an event:  When a player wins, they will place their token onto the event space.  In the event of a tie, all winners may place a token onto the event space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;End of the game:  The Dicecathlon ends when all 10 events have been played.  Players will earn a point in each of three categories:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Row: Each row will be checked to see which player has the most wins in a row.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Column: Each column will be checked to see which player has the most wins in the column.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Color: Each color will be checked to see which player has the most wins in that color.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If tied in any category, all tying players will receive a point.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Place the winners on the gold silver and bronze spaces to celebrate the victory!  If tied at the end of the game, the victory is shared.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Events:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Red Events:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Most Through Field Goal (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup a field goal with two household items. Flick dice from an arms length away. The player that gets the most of their dice through wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Drop Closest To Coin (1)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Place a single coin on the playing surface. Players must hold their die out at eye level and drop it to the table. The closest to the coin wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Build A Tower Together (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player must stack a die on top of the previous player's die until there are no more dice. If the pile falls, the other players win.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Flick Closest To Coin (1)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Place a single coin on the playing surface. Flick dice from an arms length away. The closest to the coin wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roll Die Closest To Edge (1)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Choose a side of the playing surface. Players must roll their die and try to get close to the edge without going over. If all players go over, restart the event. The player closest to the edge wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Flick And Hit (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The starting player flicks their die onto the table from the edge. The next player must flick a die from the edge and hit their opponents die. If they hit, their die stays on the table. If they miss, it is removed from play. Once all dice are on the table, players can choose any die of theirs to flick. Knocking an opponent's die off of the edge of the table will remove the opponent's die from play. The last player standing wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Yellow Events:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Highest Sum Of Dice (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players roll all of their dice at once and total them up. The highest roll wins! In the event of a tie, tying players roll again. Play until there is a single winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Call Your Roll (1)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players call the number before rolling a die. If correct they stay in play. If incorrect, they are out. Play until there is a single winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Which Hand Is It In (1)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player places one die into one of their hands and one by one, they will guess which hand has a die on the player to their left. Each incorrect player is removed from the event. Play until there is a single winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Guess The Die (1)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player places one die onto the table with any face up, but covering up the die faces with their hand. One by one, they will guess which die face is on the player to their left. Each incorrect player is removed from the event. Play until there is a single winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lowest Sum Of Dice (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players roll all of their dice at once and total them up. The lowest roll wins! In the event of a tie, tying players roll again. Play until there is a single winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Raise The Bluff (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will simultaneously roll their 5 dice and cover them. The first player must state a number that they rolled. Any player may challenge their claim. If challenged the roll is revealed and if they lied, they are out. If they were truthful, their accuser is out. They'll re-roll their dice and continue. If nobody challenges, the next player clockwise must say a higher number. Play until one player remains.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Green Events:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First To Stack In Order (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Simultaneously, all players roll their dice and then race to stack them in order from low to high. Tying numbers will go on top of each other. If the stack ever falls, the new faces will determine the order they need to be stacked in. The first player to stack all 5 wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First To Stack In Order (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Simultaneously, all players stack their dice. The first player to stack all 5 wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First To Balance On Fingers (5)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Simultaneously, all players try to place one die on each finger, palm side up. The first player to have a die on each finger wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First To Roll 1 2 3 4 5&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Simultaneously, players will roll 1 die at a time trying to roll a 1. Once a 1 is rolled, they will try to roll a 2 with their next die. The first player to roll 1 2 3 4 5 with their dice, wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First To Roll 1 2 3 4 5&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Simultaneously, players will roll 1 die trying to roll a 6. The first player to roll a 6, wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First To Add Up Dice&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Simultaneously, players will roll all 5 of their dice and add them up in their head. The first player to correctly state the sum of their dice, wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="26997" value="Jason Tagmire" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="116802" value="Leon Tagmire" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="26997" value="Jason Tagmire" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="26991" value="Button Shy" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="5.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.11803" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="57" />
			<trading value="3" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>