<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="277148">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/BJ6jFDE_RLpjZoQ7v7xvTg__thumb/img/fAqeqhJ5zkvIpbgg_RlD395U-tU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7493255.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/BJ6jFDE_RLpjZoQ7v7xvTg__original/img/ztQGUh6b0PrRCTSdLssdmvfPeJI=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7493255.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Battleground Lanka" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Objective&amp;#10;Battleground Lanka is a team-based strategy game. Players take turns attacking their opponents. A team is declared the winner when all players on opposing teams have been eliminated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards&amp;#10;There are 3 types of cards in the game: Character Cards, Action Cards and Health Trackers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Character Cards&amp;#10;Each character belongs to one of 3 teams, indicated by the symbol on the upper-right hand corner of the character card:&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Team Orange&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Team Purple&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Team Neutral aka &amp;quot;double agent&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Action Cards&amp;#10;There are 6 categories of action cards:&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Attack&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Defense&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Health&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Theft&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Luck&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Power&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players and Setup&amp;#10;The game can be played with 2 - 9 players. Players choose characters and join their respective teams.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For Odd Number of Players: Choose an equal number of characters from Orange &amp;amp; Purple, plus the Neutral character.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For Even Number of Players: Choose an equal number of characters from Orange &amp;amp; Purple.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Choosing Character Cards: Players should be seated in a circle. Each player chooses a character, keeping in mind that adjacent players cannot be on the same team. Place your character card faceup for everyone to see, overlapping the Health Tracker&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Distributing Action Cards: Before the game begins, Action Cards are shuffled and the deck is placed facedown. Each player is dealt 5 cards facedown. Players pick up and view their cards, but may not show them to others.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay&amp;#10;The game begins with the youngest player at the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On each turn, in the order stated below, players shall:&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Draw 2 cards from the deck and add them to their hand. Players may also choose to forego drawing cards on any turn.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Play as many cards as they wish (zero or more) from their hand. Only 1 attack turn card can be played per turn. Players may play other types of cards before and/or after an attack. Played cards are placed faceup in a common discard pile.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  End their turn and discard any unwanted cards (see below)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ending your turn&amp;#10;Players may end their turn at any time, even without playing a single card. However, at the time they end their turn, they must discard any cards of their choice until they hold at most 5 cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Holding More Than 5 Cards&amp;#10;Players may end up holding more than 5 cards outside their turn. This is permitted. Example: A player holding 5 cards draws a 6th card when another player plays brahma [Fortune].&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Managing the deck: If the deck runs out, shuffle the discard pile and place the cards facedown. Continue playing.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Attacking&amp;#10;Every attack card has an associated attack damage and attack weapon. Players play attack cards to deal damage to their opponents. On each turn, a player may play a maximum of 1 attack card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Defending&amp;#10;When attacked, a player can defend themselves by playing a defense card in real-time, out-of-turn. Each defense card includes the attack weapon, that it can defend against. Some power cards or Superpowers can also assist in defending.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Losing and Restoring Health&amp;#10;If players are unable to defend an attack, they lose health equal to the damage, included on the attack card. Players can restore health by playing a health card during their turn to heal themselves or other players. (Illustration to the right shows how to track health)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player Revival: At the time that a player&amp;rsquo;s health goes to zero, any player may play sanjeevani [Herbs] in real-time, out-of-turn, to revive this player back to 1 health.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player Elimination: If a player reaches zero health and isn&amp;rsquo;t revived in real-time, they are eliminated from the game and must flip over their character card. The attacking player receives all in-hand cards from the defeated player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Stealing&amp;#10;Players use theft cards to strategically weaken their opponents. Note: When stealing from another player&amp;rsquo;s in-hand cards, you must choose that card facedown.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Superpowers&amp;#10;Each character has a unique skill, or Superpower, listed on their character card. Superpowers supersede Action Cards. Example: The Superpower of rama [Protector] allows players to enhance jatayu [Shield] as a defense against either attack weapon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Power Cards&amp;#10;Players play power cards during their turn by placing them in front of their own or another player&amp;rsquo;s character card. Power cards supersede Superpowers and Action Cards. Example: If a player has lakshman rekha [Palisade] placed next to them, any attack on the player must first be evaluated against this power.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Chaos Mode&amp;#10;Once you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the regular gameplay, try out Chaos Mode for a faster-paced experience. It&amp;rsquo;s most fun with 5+ players. The group must decide on this mode before the game begins.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Attacks: every player may play up to 2 attack cards in a turn&amp;#10;&amp;bull;  Defense: any player may play a defense card in real-time, outside their turn, to protect the player being attacked. Note: If someone else defends a player, Superpowers of neither the player being attacked, nor the one defending the attack apply.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Revivals&amp;#10;Each player is entitled to 1 revival per game. That is, when players reach zero health, they revive back to full health in real-time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="9" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1050" value="Ancient" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1082" value="Mythology" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1037" value="Real-time" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="116821" value="Priyank Singhal" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42052" value="Battleground Studios" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="8.83333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.64992" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>