<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="277808">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Macau Wars" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Macau-Wars Variation&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Macau Wars It&amp;rsquo;s a major game variation of the Macau card game based on the Macau (card game) Macau Plawno Variation, still being in development on github.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2 or more players are dealt 5 cards each; after that, the top card from the deck is then placed on the table. Play starts to the dealer's right.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The next card played must be of the same suit or the same value as the card on the table. For example, If a 7 of spades was on the table, the player can play a 9 of spades or a 7 of clubs or any other card that matches 7 or spades. If the player cannot play a card, he must draw from the deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards cannot be played in runs, i.e. 5 of Spades, 6 of Spades, 7 of Spades, 7 of Hearts, 8 of Hearts, 8 of Clubs, 7 of Clubs but a minimum of two or more the same value cards can be played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When an action card is played, the player next (or previous depend on the action card) in the sequence must complete the action or add to it to pass it onto the next player in sequence. When down to a single card, a player must say &amp;quot;Macau!&amp;quot;. If a player forgets to call &amp;quot;Macau&amp;quot; before the next players move, the player must draw 5 cards. The winner of the game is the first player to have no cards; in instances of more than 2 players, gameplay continues until only one player is left with cards. In case of Macau Championships once the first player to have no cards wins and the game stops. The winner shuffles the cards and the new game starts. One point is then assigned to the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For the avoidance of doubt: If the player plays King of Spades and King of Hearts with King of Hearts on top the next player will pick up 5 cards as the top card takes precedence in this case.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;War&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this game, a scenario called a war and deception can be created when players consecutively play 'special cards' to make other players increase their card count.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;War is started when 2, 3, King of Spades (to a previous player) or King of Hearts is played. Causing players to pick up cards. When a war starts, players can play any 2s and 3s as the suit and value are being ignored during the war. Players can also play King of Spades and King of Hearts regardless of the suit currently on the deck and value of the cards as long as they are 2, 3 or mentioned Kings. Queen of Hearts can be played anytime during the war to stop the war causing the player to not pick up any cards. In this variation of the game, players can often pick up as many as 20 cards (they all add up, e.g. 2+3+2+King of Spades+King of Heart=17).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When King of Spades is played the previous player must pick up 5 cards or play another action card (any 2, 3, King of Hearts, King of Spades (to a previous player)). After the previous player, the game goes back to the player who played King of Spades.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Any queen can be placed at any time on any war card regardless of the current suit. See below section for the action of each Queen.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Action Cards&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2, 3, King of Spades, King of Hearts - War cards that cause players to pick up cards (2,3,5 respectively).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a Jack or Ace is played, the player placing the Jack or Ace can call for a non-action card value (in case of Jack) or a suit (in case of Ace). The difference is that the suit is ignored and any Jack can be placed on any Ace, and any Ace can be placed on any Jack, therefore, ignoring the requested suit or value of the previous player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Queen of hearts - stops the war and causes the player not to pick up any cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Queen of diamonds - the next person is skipped (also during the war).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Queen of spades - order of play switches directions (also during the war).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Queen of clubs - player can chose who play next (cannot chose her/himself) (also during the war).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a 4 is played the deception part starts, and all the players must miss a go, unless they have a 4 (if they don't have a 4 or they chose not to play the 4, they don't pick a card from the deck), in which case they can add this to the original 4, and all players in sequence must miss a go, unless someone has a 4, in which case they can add this to the original 4 and so on. If no one else has a 4 then the last player, who put 4 plays as many times as there are 4s. For example, if there are four 4s after the last player played the 4, the player must play four times. Note: the last player will play four times against him/herself, that also include all the action cards which will apply to the player him/herself. The deception is when someone doesn't want to play a 4 but has it and can play a 4 after everyone said they don't/have a 4 causing this player to have more turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Joker replaces any card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Open Cards&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The more difficult version of Macau Wars (and any Macau variation) is a game played with open cards. That means that all the players cards and the draw deck is shown. This is similar to Chess where by knowing all the cards players must think about strategy and future moves. Open cards variation might take hours to finish.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="1" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1023" value="Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="98" value="Components: Traditional Playing Cards" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>