<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="277800">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_r-fHegMdl2GP19ORpqJrA__thumb/img/uxRdpA0kpxK8jBawKXwtCAJw9tE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4763367.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_r-fHegMdl2GP19ORpqJrA__original/img/ys-91CXAKIKiS17Ig3FvBj_C660=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4763367.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rainbow Cats" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In Rainbow Cats, players compete to claim as much space in the house as possible for their favorite cat while making sure their least favorite cat's objects are nowhere to be seen.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the start of play, players draw two cat cards to establish their favorite and least favorite cats, information they need to keep secret! If a player somehow draws the same cat for both their favorite and least favorite cats, that player will not have a least favorite cat. The house consists of a 5x5 grid made up of items from seven different cats, each representing a color of the rainbow.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Seven Cats:&amp;#10;Phoenix&amp;#10;Ginger&amp;#10;Daisy&amp;#10;Jade&amp;#10;Azul      &amp;#10;Iris      &amp;#10;Violet&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Contents: &amp;#10;14 Cat Identity Cards&amp;#10;140 Cat Item Cards&amp;#10;9 Grid Goal Cards&amp;#10;25 Starting Grid Cards&amp;#10;Last Played Card Token&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 7 cats total and 20 item cards for each specific cat within the item deck. During game play, players will take turns placing item cards on  a 5 x 5 grid. Players will also have  secret guide showing anywhere from 1-5 points for each spot on the grid. The player earns points for every preferred item card placed and loses points when their least favorite cat&amp;rsquo;s items are on the grid. Each player has a different guide, meaning each player can gain or lose points for different spots.  The player with the most points at the end of the game wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Types of Cards:&amp;#10;Cat Identity: Each player gets 2 of these. Keep them secret. &amp;#10;Grid Goal: Each player gets 1 of these. Also keep this secret.&amp;#10;Cat Items: Players will get a lot of these throughout the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Set Up: &amp;#10;To start the game , first distribute the starting grid cards face up on the table, revealing 25 colorful spaces where players can play item cards. Then shuffle and give each player 2 Cat Identity cards, 1 Grid Goal card, and 5 Item cards. Play will start with the person who has the most cats. If there is a tie then rock paper scissors should suffice. Players DO NOT select a favorite and least favorite cat at this time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During the beginning stages of the game, players will take turns drawing 1 item from the items deck and playing 1 item within the 5 x 5 grid, not placing any cards on top of existing Item cards within the grid. &amp;#10;They also must place cards at least 2 spaces from the last card played if able.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When they place an Item card on the grid, that player will also place the token to show the last played Item card. If there are no spaces available 2 spaces from the last card played then place anywhere an Item card has not been placed. Once 25 item cards are placed on top of all starting grid cards, players must select their favorite cats by placing it face down in front of them and adjacent to the 5 x 5 grid. The cat card left in their hand is their least favorite cat. Remember that if both are the same then they do not have a least favorite cat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play: &amp;#10;At this time shuffle the remaining item deck and deal each player 10 additional item cards in order to build individual decks. From this point forward, players will draw and play from their individual decks. Players will continue to draw 1 item card and place 1 item card on top of existing item cards until all players have no cards left in their individual item decks. There is no limit to the number of cards that can be stacked on top of other cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget: Players can only place item cards 2 or more spaces from the last played item card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;End of Game: &amp;#10;After all item cards have been played from the players&amp;rsquo; individual decks, players will reveal their favorite cats and calculate their points based on their secret grid card, giving positive points for each item of the cat on the grid. Players will then reveal their least favorite cat and referring to their goal grid card, deduct points from their total for each item on the grid from their least favorite cat. The player with the highest total points wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Single Player Variant:&amp;#10;In the single player variant of Rainbow Cats, you will shuffle all 140 cards and make a 5 x 5 grid with 5 item cards in each space. The remaining cards will become your deck. You will then shuffle your deck and deal yourself 5 cards. Next, you will shuffle and deal yourself two cat cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unlike the multi-player version, you cannot have the same favorite and least favorite cat and will need to draw another cat card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The goal of this game is to remove all 20 items for the favorite cat. You remove 2 items from anywhere on the grid as long as they belong to same cat. The only items you cannot remove are from your least favorite cat. You can also peak at as many item cards on the grid as you&amp;rsquo;d like to help plan where you want  which cards to move. You can however move any item card from 1 space to another when you collect 2 of your favorite cat&amp;rsquo;s items.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For example, if Phoenix is your favorite cat and there are 2 red items for Phoenix showing, you will remove those 2 items and the items make a pair. When you remove a pair of items from your favorite cat, you can also move . Cards in hand can also be used. When cards in hand are played, it is replaced with a card from the remaining deck. The goal is to get all 20 items for your favorite cat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="7334" value="Animals: Cats" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="106679" value="Josh Hipsher" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="118285" value="Amy Barr" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>