<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="278304">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JFMi_CHDmQ67Z6Jegj3Z1g__thumb/img/KOpu4uv6X2Xra705-pKlapPnhtc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6298729.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JFMi_CHDmQ67Z6Jegj3Z1g__original/img/VQq5bTvXwQJ_IiSFtH0tnkQVO3M=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6298729.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fief: France Edition" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>FIEF: France is a game of dynastic ambition in which players assume the roles of nobles in the 15th century kingdom of France. Each player strives to become the most powerful ruling force in the kingdom by gaining control of Fiefs and Bishoprics. In turn, they acquire Royal and Ecclesiastical (church) titles which give their families influence to elect the next Pope and King. Players strengthen their positions by negotiating marriage alliances between their families, setting the stage for love, treachery, and deception!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FIEF is a classic game and this edition includes a new board (FIEF France: Gameboard)!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game board represents the Kingdom of France in the Middle Ages. Villages have square outlines that are connected by roads that allow Lord and Troop movement. The villages are grouped into eight colored background areas that represent individual Fiefs, which are domains given to Lords to preside over. Fiefs have different colored backgrounds. Each village also belongs to one of five church Bishoprics; each Bishopric is outlined with a heavy border line and is numbered between 1-5 along the edge of the board inside a Bishop's Mitre. Bishoprics include several different Fiefs' villages.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player controls up to four family members, comprised of male and female nobles. These family members will rise in power by gaining Royal and Ecclesiastic Titles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In FIEF France edition, a player may attempt to gain control of all the villages in a Fief to gain the Royal Title of Baron, Earl, or Duke. For each Fief a player controls, they gain 1 VP. These Titled Lords may now take part in the election for the next King. They may even be a candidate to become King, thus bringing 1 VP and more power to the family! Other members of your family may follow the calling of the Church to gain the Ecclesiastical Titles of Bishop and then Cardinal. These titles allow you to Tithe Bishoprics, taking the Church's (i.e. &amp;quot;your&amp;quot;) fair share of income from other Fief Lords! The highest goal your clerical family member can attain is to be elected Pope, bringing 1 VP and special privileges to your family!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You win the game as soon as you have 3 VPs. This is easier said than done and you may need to form alliances with other players through diplomacy and marriage to attain your goal. When one of your family members marries a noble of another family, the two of you become allied. You now win the game together with 4 VPs and cannot win alone, unless your marriage is annulled by the Pope or your spouse is &amp;quot;mysteriously&amp;quot; murdered or dies by some other foul means!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In addition to being wary of your fellow players, you draw event cards that can quickly change your destiny. Bounty Event cards are beneficial to the Player and include &amp;quot;Good Harvest&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Good Weather&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;Added Taxes&amp;quot; cards. But some cards are Disaster Cards that can randomly affect all players in specific Bishoprics. These include &amp;quot;The Plague&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Heavy Rain&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Famine&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;Peasant Uprising&amp;quot;!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Income can be increased by players imposing church tithes on their opponent's villages or taxing their own Fiefs. Players may purchase new Fief titles, improve their village incomes with mills, and fortify their cities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will also need to protect their land and castles. Men-at-Arms and Knights can be purchased, as well as Archers and Bombards. If you feel that other players are not running their Fiefs as well as you can, you may try to invade their territories! But you must risk one of your family members to lead the troops into possible battle, where they might be killed or taken prisoner. If two opposing armies are in the same village square, a Battle may be initiated. The players assess the size and strength of their armies, which determine the number of Battle Dice each may roll. Each &amp;quot;f&amp;quot; rolled is a hit. Men-at-Arms are defeated with one hit, while Knights require three hits to be removed from the battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="6">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="4" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="4" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="5" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1086" value="Territory Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2017" value="Voting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="11006" value="Country: France" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameaccessory" id="280603" value="Fief: France – Metal Coins" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameaccessory" id="277568" value="Fief: France – The Lords Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameaccessory" id="280605" value="Fief: France – The Lords Miniatures – Kickstarter Extras" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameaccessory" id="280604" value="Fief: France – Thematic Expansion Titles Set" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="152470" value="Fief: France 1429" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="702" value="Philippe Mouchebeuf" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="51907" value="Patrick Dallanegra" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7186" value="ASYNCRON games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="115" />
			<average value="7.57478" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.59749" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="8095" bayesaverage="5.59749" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.48595" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="298" />
			<trading value="6" />
			<wanting value="17" />
			<wishing value="141" />
			<numcomments value="37" />
			<numweights value="9" />
			<averageweight value="3.8889" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>