<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="282034">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/bG0oP2MHSm5-c04-V4JFkA__thumb/img/n8CP2DozM1Qy0Vdor-72txT5fM0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4822832.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/bG0oP2MHSm5-c04-V4JFkA__original/img/Wl75joEgPHDoaT5fDR-JkueMTWY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4822832.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Sailing Race by Lite Lion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A new age board game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Played with or without dice&amp;#10;     Large, rollable gaming mat suitable to play on the table, floor or beach sand&amp;#10;     Fast forward way to play, no step by step snail moves&amp;#10;     Suitable for travel, at the beach, fast to begin and not necessary to beware few drops of water&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Sailboats sail downwind or move upwind, depending on wind side. Tough completion is causing bumps time to time.&amp;#10;But the Finish is so close!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game suits any age. The youngest ones can be helped a bit to follow the route. Children learn some maths and logistics along the route. Fun parlour game for whole family from 4 year old.&amp;#10;The package includes:&amp;#10;- Gaming mat, made of anti-slip polyester fabric&amp;#10;- 4 pcs sailboat pawns, one Player can have two fleets&amp;#10;- Manual&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Idea&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;Sailing Race is a realistic game, where the realities of competitive sailing are combined with fun of a board game. While playing, the participants learn, that a sailing boat does not always have an opportunity to move straight forward, but have to take into consideration tailwinds and headwinds, reefs and whirls to make its way to the Finish.&amp;#10;Player are all captains in the game, but everybody had to subdue to the winds the dice draw. The wind direction changes sometimes very rapidly, quicker that real life afford. But it is the game for fast. Dice can be used in the game but the draw can also be enforced with the Players&amp;acute; hand marks. &amp;#10;Game duration is 10-30 min depending on the number of Players. The first one to reach the Finish line is the winner.&amp;#10;(picture)&amp;#10;How to navigate with dice:&amp;#10;The Player throw dice to get the number to move to.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Boats on collision course:&amp;#10;If the spot if occupied with other&amp;rsquo;s Player&amp;rsquo;s boat/fleet, the newcomer has to change the course. If the intersection area is busy and there is no bypass, the newcomer has to slow down and wait for new turn to move ahead. But the first to come to the intersection area should take on moving ahead rapidly: more than two turn on the same place will lead to disqualification (the boat has to start from the beginning again).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to Begin&amp;#10;Roll open Lite Lion Games family friendly rollable Sailing Race - gaming mat. The Players choose a boat from four available color. If there are only two players, each player can have a fleet of two boats. In this case approximate duration of one game prolongs. &amp;#10;Each Player places own boat to the Start. The beginner can be chosen randomly, with a coin draw and etc. In according, the other players have one extra turn in the end of the game, if the beginner finishes the first. So, the game can end as a drawn match.&amp;#10;When playing with hand marks, Players are advised to be the opposite side of the table, so the moves are less clear and predictable for the opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Turns&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;How to navigate with dice:&amp;#10;The Player throw dice to get the number to move to.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to Navigate by fingers:&amp;#10;The Players move ahead according to the numbers on the gaming mat. For each turn a random number should be drawn in between numbers 0-3. The best way is to use fingers. The number is determined by amount counted on fingers of both players once shown. (The hand can be hidden behind the back or under the table and when released, the amount can be counted on fingers as shown). The gross number is the spot to navigate to. The boat can go straight ahead or diagonally toward Finish. Backward movement is not allowed. The course can be changed only at the cross of course lines: on the solid line the boat can move only straight ahead, but on intersection it is possible to navigate to the most favorable course of the possibilities open.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Prize Spot &amp;ndash; Finish&amp;#10;The Prize Spot or Finish can be reach only with drawing 1, 3 or 6. Other numbers do not allow to move to the Spot. Just as waiting for the right wind to navigate to the home harbor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="5" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1008" value="Nautical" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1098" value="Number" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="56512" value="Series: Board Games (Lite Lion Europe)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="118601" value="Esa Honkaneva" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="118601" value="Esa Honkaneva" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42545" value="Lite Lion Europe" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>