<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="282156">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/5-DcIpy-R3yui-ttsQ9xMQ__thumb/img/SHu0yFQL8uJQ-kGABx3y_fxDvWU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7160244.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/5-DcIpy-R3yui-ttsQ9xMQ__original/img/asJpm2ounaYLSTNkSBT01-F8EOM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7160244.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Magic: The Gathering – Dragons of Tarkir" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Magic: The Gathering – Les Dragons de Tarkir" />
			
						               													<description>Khans of Tarkir is a Magic: The Gathering block consisting of Khans of Tarkir (September 26, 2014), Fate Reforged (January 23, 2015), and Dragons of Tarkir (March 27, 2015). The block's setting is based on a mix of cultures of Central and East Asia. It is the last block to have three expansion sets.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Sarkhan Vol is successful at preventing Ugin's death, though Ugin is forced to retreat into a hibernative state to recuperate. Satisfied, Sarkhan travels back into the &amp;quot;present day.&amp;quot; But the Tarkir he finds, as chronicled in Dragons of Tarkir, is drastically changed. The eponymous dragons, no longer extinct, have proliferated, and are now on the verge of wiping out all other life; in particular, the five god-dragons worshiped by the clans are now the leaders of those clans, with the human (or humanoid) characters who led them in the original timeline serving in other roles. In this new future, each of the clans focuses on allied pairs, with the enemy colors of the original wedges abandoned entirely; likewise, each clan retains the modified watermark of their dragonlords, first introduced in the previous set. Morph returns as &amp;quot;Megamorph&amp;quot;; the two mechanics are identical except that creatures with Megamorph gain a +1/+1 counter when flipped. Dragons also creates the peculiar structure of Tarkir Block drafts: Fate Reforged is designed to be drafted with either Dragons or Khans, but the two large sets, representing alternate timelines, are not intended to be drafted together. To that end, Dragons retains the two altered clan mechanics from FRF and replaces the three that remained.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Dromoka Brood (Green, White) is what the Abzan Houses have become. Dragonlord Dromoka leads and they retain the Bolster mechanic from Fate Reforged. Anafenza, no longer their leader, was martyred for apostatic religious beliefs, but lives on as a ghost associated with a spirit tree.&amp;#10;The Ojutai Brood (Blue, White) is what the Jeskai Way have become. Dragonlord Ojutai leads and their mechanic, new to the Tarkir block but returning from Rise of the Eldrazi, is &amp;quot;Rebound,&amp;quot; which lets spells re-occur at the beginning of the player's next turn. Narset, their former leader, has ignited her planeswalker spark, and is one of the two planeswalkers in the set (the other being an alternate version of Sarkhan Vol).&amp;#10;The Silumgar Brood (Blue, Black) is what the Sultai Brood have become. Dragonlord Silumgar leads and their mechanic is &amp;quot;Exploit.&amp;quot; When a creature with Exploit enters the battlefield, the player may sacrifice a pre-existing creature to gain extra benefits from the Exploiting creature. Their former leader, Sidisi, exists as an undead thrall to Silumgar.&amp;#10;The Kolaghan Brood (Red, Black) is what the Mardu Horde have become. Dragonlord Kolaghan leads and they retain the Dash mechanic from Fate Reforged. Their former leader, Zurgo, has been reduced to a mere ceremonial bellringer, and is often bullied by his clan.&amp;#10;The Atarka Brood (Green, Red) is what the Temur Frontier have become. Dragonlord Atarka leads and their mechanic is &amp;quot;Formidable,&amp;quot; which provides bonuses if the controlling player controls with total power 8 or higher. Surrak, their former leader, serves as the brood's Hunt Caller, in charge of feeding Atarka and renowned for punching a dragon.&amp;#10;Sorin Markov, arriving at the altered version of Tarkir, awakens Ugin from his hibernation. Ugin agrees to help fend off the Eldrazi, though he insists that first he and Sorin seek out Nahiri, the Lithomancer, a planeswalker who helped him seal the Eldrazi away the first time. Sarkhan, meanwhile, learns that he is the only person who remembers the version of Tarkir where he himself was born, and consultation with both Ugin and Narset reveals that, in this continuity, no Sarkhan Vol ever was born. Though both he and Narset are capable of planeswalking anywhere else in the multiverse, both decide to remain on Tarkir.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1044" value="Collectible Components" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="463" value="Magic: The Gathering" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="13" value="Wizards of the Coast" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="12" />
			<average value="7.13333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.85173" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="31" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>