<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="283715">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RWkf0OFZP54SKLuZkWkJmQ__thumb/img/tmmSPr9J-iabAnMsoZi9up4G-AI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4936363.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RWkf0OFZP54SKLuZkWkJmQ__original/img/j6Ui9ndbuRMZzm3e8mOoYGT-ryU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic4936363.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Tóu-shì" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>&amp;#233;&amp;#170;&amp;#176;&amp;#230;&amp;#152;&amp;#175;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;'T&amp;oacute;ush&amp;igrave; - the Dicegrid puzzle game'&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Overview&amp;#10;The goal of the game is to fill in as many squares on the grid as possible, completed rows and columns will give bonus points when scoring.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During play, you roll dice to move around the grid and mark off squares. Every round but the first is much the same. You roll a die and use it to solve the grid puzzle and mark off two numbers from the lists of numbers, one for the type of die you use for the roll and one for the type of die you choose to mark on the board. If all numbers of a die type are used, you could no longer choose to roll this type of die or write that die type to the grid.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The die roll will be used both as the limit of movement and the number to cross off. You do not have to write the same die type on the grid as you roll, but the number used, must be within the range of the die type. Remember that there may not be two of the same die type written into any row or column.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are three bonus actions to use during the game (the star symbols on the gameboard). Be aware that using them all will end the game, regardless of whether or not there are squares left to fill in. Resolve any movements before ending the game, after the last bonus action is used.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first round will be different.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First round&amp;#10;Chose a number from any list of numbers, mark this off and place your first mark on the board in any square on the grid. Write either a number, symbol or letters to remember what die type you chose. At the sides of the grid, there is die type symbols for all columns and rows, to help guide you, you could mark these off as well. This marked square is your starting position. The following rounds movements must start from the position of the previous round. You may not end a movement in a previously marked square.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Any following round&amp;#10;Start the round by choosing one die of any type.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mark off a number of own choice from the list of numbers the same die type as the die type you use.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roll the die, and use this number shown to move, and to mark off a number from any list of numbers (associated with a die type), this is the die type you mark to the board. It has not to be the same as the die type you rolled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Rolling a one&amp;#10;If you roll the number one with any die, you either chose to reroll or use one bonus action. Unused bonus actions are worth four points at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Bonus action&amp;#10;If you use a bonus action after a roll of one. Cross out one of your three bonus markers and mark one square anywhere on the grid with a die type of your own choice. This will be your starting position next round. Remember to cross out one number of that die type as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The bonus action could also be used as a reroll of any die roll during play. If you use the last bonus action for a reroll, resolve the roll and movements, mark a square and off number if possible before ending the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Movement&amp;#10;You move by subtracting from your die roll. For each square you move, reduce the die roll with one. You could not go down to zero or below.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You may not move diagonally. You may move over and past marked squares as long as you do not end movement on a marked square.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You do not have to move in a straight line, you may do as many turns as you like, as long as you do not cross a square twice or move diagonally.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Marking a square&amp;#10;The square you end your movement in is marked with letters (T+number) or the die type symbol of the chosen die, from which number list you also mark off a number. Remember that there may not be two of the same die type in any row or column.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Example&amp;#10;If you roll a four and move two steps, you now have the number two to mark off from a die list of numbers (and remember to mark this die type in the square you ended up in). You may choose any die type as long as this number is within its number range and is available to mark off in the list of numbers of that die type.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game ends&amp;#10;The game ends when either one of these conditions is fulfilled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player had used the last (of three) bonus actions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Is unable to move to an empty square (due to the result of the die roll and/or available numbers to cross out).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All squares are filled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring&amp;#10;Each filled square equals to one point. (up to 36 points)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each filled column equals to three points. (up to 18 points)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each filled row equals to three points. (up to 18 points)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each saved (unused) bonus action equals to four points. (up to 12 points)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Grid&amp;#10;The dice icons next to the grid is for ease of gameplay, just to keep track of dice type per column and row&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="25" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="25" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1028" value="Puzzle" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="62615" value="Components: 6 x 6 Grids" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="99769" value="Jonas Lidström Isegrim" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="99769" value="Jonas Lidström Isegrim" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.54951" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="14" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>