<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="285920">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/zJPcTBARa_WKn2yKc8UyOA__thumb/img/RzXGF4G_VBmh1DsxXZOyfwsZObM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4882067.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/zJPcTBARa_WKn2yKc8UyOA__original/img/qTDeYZB7pjN7i5E7f7gH3JvU2tU=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4882067.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Batman: Gotham City Chronicles – The Sewers &amp; GCPD Maps Expansion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This map-focused expansion for BATMAN&amp;trade;: GOTHAM CITY CHRONICLES offers a new double-sided game board representing two unique and iconic locations. Wage viscous battles amid the reeking waters of the Gotham City Sewers, and defend justice at the GCPD Police Headquarters. &amp;#10;In the accompanying booklet you will find 10 new missions for Versus mode for use with these new maps as well as the expansion boards found in Season 1 (Arkham Asylum, The Joker&amp;rsquo;s Funhouse and Wayne Manor). &amp;#10;Additionally, for when the Dark Knight needs a little extra power, this set includes a new double-tile for Batman&amp;rsquo;s Trasher Suit.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Sewer&amp;#10;The sewers spawn a game board with a tight almost claustrophobic environment, obstructed lines of sight, a warren of walls and snug quarters full of villainy.&amp;#10;However, a section of the board is higher than the rest, which opens up lines of sight into many of these otherwise hidden zones, while providing the promontory bonus. But that aside, you are still going to have to sneak through the maze of abandoned quarters to look your opponent straight in the eye as you shoot.&amp;#10;These flophouses are excellent hiding spaces but achieving mission objectives will require you to hunt down evil in its&amp;rsquo; lair, then melt away before the tide of approaching goons overwhelm you.&amp;#10;The board is separated into four large areas, the sluice clearly delineates 3 boundaries and the height difference between the zones adds another. Getting around the board requires a significant amount of movement, crossing the stinking sewers or jumping across takes a toll.&amp;#10;If you want to move about this board, better keep some cubes in reserve. Smooth area movement is a strategic requisite, hindering can shut your mobility down hard, so maintaining control of area boundaries is essential.&amp;#10;All this restriction is counterbalanced by highly mobile or parkour talented characters. They can easily navigate over the torrenting sluice and continue onwards, while highly mobile characters, like Killer Croc or King Shark can cross the board with ease as if the water wasn&amp;rsquo;t there allowing them access to an impressive amount of the board. &amp;#10;These characters are a valuable asset on this board, as the open up the possibility of sneaking behind enemy lines or quickly providing reinforcement to overrun areas, in other words, it&amp;rsquo;s Blitzkrieg time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Police Headquarters&amp;#10;With this brand new game board we are presenting another important and exciting location in Gotham City. This building serves as a bastion of law and order and a shield against chaos. From this location, brave men and women organize and mobilize to ensure the innocent are protected and the wicked are brought to justice. Under the dedicated watch of Commissioner Gordon and his trusted officers, the GCPD prevails time and again against the looming threats of the criminal underworld. &amp;#10; The Police Station allows you to play through new adventures, such as protecting (or destroying) compromising evidence or ensuring the safe release of significant prisoners.&amp;#10; This board is organized into several sections, spanning several levels. On the ground floor, a long hallway allows characters to benefit from various lines of sight; but there are also intermittent columns which create advantageous cover. &amp;#10; Some areas, however, are more confined. These are ideal for the placement of objectives, such as cells, interrogation rooms, and the medical examiner&amp;rsquo;s facility. These areas are more difficult to access and well protected, so players will need to carefully consider the best routes to securing scenario objectives. &amp;#10; Each level offers different gameplay opportunities. On the first level, there are chief inspectors. This office, completely surrounded by walls, offers a necessary refuge for when the police station is under siege. The second floor overlooks a large corridor offering many tempting lines of sight. The archives sector, however, is a more enclosed space, offering only limited lines of sight. Those who can breach walls will, of course, have the option to cross over into adjacent rooms. Finally, the statue and columns of the police station allow particularly agile characters to quickly and easily access different levels and to avoid opponents&amp;mdash;should that be of strategic benefit. &amp;#10; Because of its difficult terrain and the hidden paths created by columns, this board favors mobile characters. Centralized areas can be very dangerous due to the various lines of sight, and those attempting to cross should do so with caution.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;10 Versus missions&amp;#10; This new game boards pack comes with:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     A booklet with 10 new missions for the Versus mode expansion which allows to play new skirmishes on these two new game boards and on those of the expansions:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;bull;2 missions on the police station game board.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;2 missions on the sewers game board.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;2 missions on the Wayne Manor game board (Wayne Manor expansion)&amp;#10;&amp;bull;2 missions on the Arkham Asylum game board (Arkham Asylum expansion)&amp;#10;&amp;bull;2 missions on the Joker&amp;rsquo;s Funhouse game board (Arkham Asylum expansion)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     8 new tokens that represent new types of objectives and allow to play with hidden objectives.&amp;#10;     Since many of you requested, one of these new missions for the Versus mode is to be played with double tiles. This is why you will find in this pack the double tile of Batman Trasher Suit (from the Wayne Manor expansion) as well as its life points marker.&amp;#10;    All the new Leader powers for all the new miniatures from season 2 (expansions, picking zone...). Those powers allow the new characters to be selected as Leaders when playing the Versus mode expansion.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1116" value="Comic Book / Strip" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2689" value="Action Queue" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2079" value="Variable Phase Order" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61748" value="Comic Books: Batman" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5427" value="Comic Books: DC Universe" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="25158" value="Components: Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="48227" value="Game: Batman – Gotham City Chronicles" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="17935" value="Theme: Superheroes" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="222514" value="Batman: Gotham City Chronicles" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2617" value="Frédéric Henry" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="69238" value="Georges Clarenko" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="66266" value="David Demaret" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="46203" value="David Finch" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="46225" value="Jim Lee" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="27147" value="Monolith Board Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="40" />
			<average value="8.4725" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.55356" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="5.55356" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.42636" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="782" />
			<trading value="5" />
			<wanting value="10" />
			<wishing value="28" />
			<numcomments value="24" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>