<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="28688">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cJfXvewupzk_rW6hz6DsBg__thumb/img/NhtxC5sKNbcAzPO99UMtPjbT1PI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic195484.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cJfXvewupzk_rW6hz6DsBg__original/img/8sXDb2aFZ9Ep2XI-qR1HVEe6Fpw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic195484.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="OPORD" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The game is on the market.  Anyone attenting RECON in Orlando is welcome to stop by the Flaming Monkey Games booth for a quick demo.  :)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OPORD is a game designed specifically to allow players to experience the sensation of launching a coordinated combined arms attack.  The game challenges a player with modern land warfare based upon existing tactical doctrine at the battalion level, but condensed in such a way as to make the make exiting and playable.  Players develop and execute operations to affect a coordinated tactical victory over their opponent.  To win, a player will have to successfully execute the instructions on his Mission Card while keeping the opponent from doing likewise.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In modern warfare, there is no shoot, maneuver sequence, as all shooting and maneuvering is simultaneous.  This is a key difference between modern warfare and that of WWII, and thus a main component of OPORD.  Movement is continuous, and shooting is sustained.  This is a key concept built into the OPORD game engine.  The variable turn sequence forces tactical forethought beyond the old &amp;ldquo;my turn, your turn&amp;rdquo; design mentality, and as a result players get a sense of fluidity of motion throughout the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Another key aspect of OPORD is the mission card driven objectives.  Players are not playing to slay each other&amp;rsquo;s armies, since this is akin to senseless banzai charges with no real aim other than to roll dice.  Rather, the game is set around typical &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; sorts of missions that soldiers are given to accomplish.  Seize this hill, secure this route, recon in force here, set up a defense there&amp;mdash;all of these are typical missions you&amp;rsquo;ll see in your mission cards.  And like the real world, you job is to use your troops and support elements to accomplish the mission.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In short, OPORD is a game that very closely relates the gaming experience to that of a real life Battalion Commander but in a fun way.  Receive your orders, allocate your troops and resources, design your plan, execute your plan, and complete the mission.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A typical turn.  Both players dice for initiative and turn sequence.  Initiative is obvious, winner goes first.  Sequencing dice determines the player's turn sequence.  Sequencing can be shoot/move/fight or move/shoot/fight.  the initiative winner goes first in the first two phases, while in the third phase &amp;quot;fight&amp;quot; all combat is simultaneous.  Movement variables are factored into the terrain boards, so there is no worry about modifiers for moving.  In combat, units shoot/fight collectively if in the same sector, or individually if in separate sectors.  Essentially both players dice (attack dice for phasing player, defend dice for non-phasing).  The interactive nature of every phase of every turn means no players are passive, which gives both a sense of fluidity.  Results are based upon combat dicing.  Units can be depleted, eliminated, or forced to withdraw.  The object of the game is to accomplish your mission and deny the enemy his.  While there are some mission cards that are all out attacks, most of the missions require you to combat in support of your own mission or to deny the other's.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Terrain boards are modular, so there is no limit to the size map one can create.  But a game comes with six maps.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2007" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2018" value="Campaign / Battle Card Driven" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2079" value="Variable Phase Order" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="8453" value="Boyd Bruce" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="6642" value="Flaming Monkey Games, LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="5.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="4.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>