<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="288288">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Campus in a Box" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Let&amp;rsquo;s build our own college together! Lead a department of student workers to enact your strategic plan across campus. Construct buildings in your name and convince your friends to visit them. Convene surprise committees and focus all the attention on you because it&amp;rsquo;s a race for whomever will have the biggest measurable impact on campus before the end of the school year! Lead a department and assign your student workers to gather resources. Use these resources to complete your department&amp;rsquo;s strategic plans and graduate students to have the biggest measurable impact on-campus. The goal of the game is to earn the most Contribution Points (CP)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Assets&amp;#10;These four sets of tokens complete Strategic Plans, earn additional student pawns, and graduate alumni. There is a hard limit on how many assets tokens there are (23) and once they are taken no more can be taken from the Public Supply until players return them. These are the four assets: Blue Labor, Red Satisfaction, White Prestige, and Yellow Approval.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Money&amp;#10;Use Money to construct buildings and enact Strategic Plans. There is no limit to how much money can be in the game. If players must use more than what is provided, keep track in any other way.&amp;#10;Special Regulations&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Strategic Plans&amp;#10;These cards can be held face down or face-up at the discretion of each player. Keeping them confidential ensures other players don&amp;rsquo;t strategically monopolize resources you need. To complete a Strategic Plan, return the asset and money cost from your personal supply to the Public Supply or bank and retrieve the listed reward. Draw from the four face up cards unless instructed otherwise. Always replace a drawn Strategic Plan card with a new Strategic Plan. Put completed Strategic Plan cards under your Department Identity card and these remain secret until the end of the game.&amp;#10;If instructed to reset the Strategic Plans, shuffle the face-up four plans back into the deck and draw four new ones.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Committees&amp;#10;These will give you benefits or hinder other player&amp;rsquo;s progress. Go to the Alumni Center to play these and discard them after use. Players have a hand limit of 4 Committee cards and must discard down to 4 immediately whenever they exceed this limit. When the draw deck is exhausted, shuffle the discard pile to create a new one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Constructing Buildings&amp;#10;Player 1 chooses a building to discuss. Starting with Player 1 and going clockwise, each player commits any amount of money towards the construction of a new building. Continue to go around until all players are satisfied with their contributions. If the total money committed meets or exceeds the building&amp;rsquo;s listed cost, move all contributed money to the Bank and build the building. Otherwise, return all player&amp;rsquo;s money and discard the building in question.&amp;#10;Continue this until all three buildings have been discussed.&amp;#10;When the draw deck is exhausted, shuffle the discard pile to create a new one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1029" value="City Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="58262" value="Dan Chou" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="21795" value="CHOU! Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>