<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="289738">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Island of Dr. Culebra" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>THE STORY&amp;#10;On an island far from humanity lies a secret facility run by a mad scientist. She is the most evil person&amp;mdash;the most cunning, the most horrific (and did I mention evil?) person known to woman. Her facility consists of a laboratory, a torture chamber, holding cells, and a labyrinth.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The laboratory is where the doctor performs her illicit experiments. She has kidnapped people around the world to be her test subjects. She not only has figured out how to clone her subjects but has figured out how to crossbreed animals with humans and vice-versa. One of her successful experiments was of a human and a rat. These hideous creatures are known as BREEDERS. They are half the size of an average human. They are fast, hard to detect, and only come out at night to feed on unexpected prey.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The loud sounds you hear could only be the screams and moans of agony coming from the torture chamber. The torture chamber is where the doctor analyses each subject's tolerance to pain and suffering. She will push their limits until they break or die. Out of the hundreds of corpses that did not pass the test, only six have made it thus far.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These six subjects are known as REAPERS. They are creatures that take on the form of a human and an animal that have been genetically modified and mutated. They are in their holding cells where they await to be released into the labyrinth and unleash their terrifying acts of evil. They are trained to prey on human flesh and they will stop at nothing until they do.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;While these are some of the ghastly things to come out of the doctor's laboratory, it does not end there. Some of her experiments consist of chemical solutions that alter one's abilities. Thus, giving them supernatural powers. This supernatural ability can range from running five times faster than a cheetah to being undetectable like a Chameleon. This chemical solution is called GEN-13. GEN-13 derives from 12 separate chemical solutions plus one unknown. When the unknown is used on a creature, it becomes the ELEMENTAL. The ELEMENTAL has the power to claim all 12 chemical solutions if present.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The doctor is now looking to abduct new test subjects around the world to continue with her GEN-13 experiments. This evil doctor is known as Dr. Culebra.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OVERVIEW&amp;#10;In The Island of Dr. Culebra, you play the role of one of Dr. Culebra's test subjects. You and the other test subjects will need to plan, strategize and work together to escape the labyrinth. You and others will be injected with a serum that has a chemical solution that alters your abilities. You and others will use your new ability to overcome obstacles, traps, and creatures in hope of finding a way out of the labyrinth. Will you and others be able to meet the challenge and escape the Island of Dr. Culebra?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OBJECTIVE&amp;#10;The object of the game is to escape from the labyrinth of Dr. Culebra's Island. The labyrinth consists of obstacles, traps, and creatures. You will need to find the exit before the time runs out.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22783" value="Admin: Better Description Needed!" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="37663" value="Blue Gear Games LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>