<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="290878">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/AelQjVHR9eIIUySQ9GZBug__thumb/img/JBum0rSFh7r5OqlQHI1BtNj1i8I=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5411081.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/AelQjVHR9eIIUySQ9GZBug__original/img/PmYtyKZhnXmEUvOAWB4lBOSmSwo=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5411081.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Jogakbo" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="조각보" />
			
						               													<description>In Jogakbo, a.k.a. &amp;#236;&amp;#161;&amp;#176;&amp;#234;&amp;#176;&amp;#129;&amp;#235;&amp;#179;&amp;#180; (Korean for &amp;quot;patchwork&amp;quot;), you are a member of the Seolbo Artisan Group &amp;mdash; &amp;quot;&amp;#236;&amp;#132;&amp;#164;&amp;quot; (seol) referring to both harmony and a piece of silk &amp;mdash; and your group has been challenged to assemble a beautiful quilt from whatever silk pieces they have available in their shops. Who will create the most harmonious quilt that satisfies the client's demands?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To set up, each player receives their own 8x8 game board, playing on either the easy or normal side of the board. The board features a 2x2 central space as well as a number of holes and spots for ornamentation. You lay out two main order cards and one secondary order card at random, along with 5-9 pieces of silk cloth in the four colors, adjusting the quantity based on the player count. Additionally, you have high-quality silk patches that cover either a 1x1 or 2x1 space, with these pieces being of a fifth and sixth color. Place one piece of silk of the main four colors on the matching spaces on the market board. Give each player three coins, with the start player taking an additional coin.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On a turn, you can either move the token on the market board to a different color and take the silk piece and any coins from this space, or pay 2 coins to choose any silk piece from the main four colors, whether from the market board or in the reserves. (The start player can place the token on any of the four colors on the first turn.) You then place the silk on your board. Your first piece must cover at least one square in the center of your game board; each subsequent piece must lie orthogonally adjacent to a piece already on your board, and pieces of the same color cannot be adjacent to one another!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you cover an ornament space on your board, you can pay a coin to take a high-quality silk piece and place it on your board. If you cover another ornament space, you can do this again. To end your turn, (if needed) choose a silk piece from the reserve of the same color that you took and place it on the market board, then place a coin from the bank on any market space that doesn't have the token in it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whenever you achieve a secondary order during play, such as covering a hole with high-quality silk or placing a second piece of the same shape, you receive a bonus immediately.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After eight rounds, the game ends. You receive a bonus based on how well you completed the main orders, such as creating a silk-filled square or filling the diagonals of your board. Additionally, each filled vertical or horizontal line is worth 3 points, each uncovered ornament 1 point, each hole -1 point, and each coin 1 point as long as you have at least three coins. Whoever has the highest score wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="36" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="37" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="38" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="39" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="40" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1028" value="Puzzle" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="121714" value="Syou (しょう)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="43729" value="Show House Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="6.875" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.24373" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>