<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="290900">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/hCPXgSpnYf475hqQGMZkxg__thumb/img/GHLmJQGwQm4400fSUH3d_t5IycY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5006631.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/hCPXgSpnYf475hqQGMZkxg__original/img/xJIR4qn7k1kLMonZw08G81JtjuY=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5006631.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Reboot" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>After a Roborg or Robotic Battlefield Operator for Recon and General purpose had raised against human and destroyed all humanity, but something important for the Roborg also disappears.&amp;#10;That is &amp;ldquo;Energy&amp;rdquo; enough to operate all Roborg. So all Roborg have started the new war to take control of the last man made energy source. Every Robrog has to fight it out there is only 1 left and also try to survive through all the disasters that happen. If they shut down once they will never start up again. Which Roborg will able to survive and take all the energy?  maybe REBOOT is the only thing Roborg&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After the battle with losing of humanity, all the Roborgs still not having the &amp;quot;Energy&amp;quot; they wish to survive.&amp;#10;The war of Roborgs for the last energy source begins again, but not only to fight each other, they also have to fight with natural disasters which had all the Roborgs cornered.&amp;#10;Maybe &amp;quot;Rebooting&amp;quot; is the only thing all Roborgs need...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Set up&amp;#10;1. Place Main Board on the table and distribute  Roborg Board to each player and put their energy marker on the 12 slot&amp;#10;2. Place 4 wall on each middle spot of the SAFE ZONE(middle section) edge and place 1 wall on other borderline(yellow line)  and then randomly place &amp;#10;   all the wall and any line except inside or borderline of SAFE ZONE &amp;#10;   a. Each wall can only connect to 1 another wall&amp;#10;   b. You can&amp;rsquo;t make the close space &amp;#10;3. Randomly place 5 Retrieve Component Tokens on every section except in SAFE ZONE and on the start point of this round &amp;#10;4. Player who have the most robot will take the 1st player cube and be the first to choose his/her spawn point (depending on the player size) and next player in clockwise order choosing until every player have done&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Item Card &amp;#10;1. Card Type&amp;#10;     a. Equipment Melee Weapon/Shield can&amp;rsquo;t hold in hand you must equip it immediately if you already equipped that type of Equipment you can decide &amp;#10;        to either discard the newly draw one or replace current equipment and put the old equipment at the bottom of the drawing deck&amp;#10;           i. Shield can take only damage form the attack&amp;#10;     b. Ranged Weapon when use place it at the bottom of the item deck&amp;#10;     c. Reusable Ranged Weapon If successfully make an attack with this card return this card to your hand if fall  place it at the bottom of the &amp;#10;        item deck&amp;#10;     d. ENERGY can use in 2 ways&amp;#10;           i.  When you fail on you attack you can discard this card to +1 of your dice result you can use as many energy as you have&amp;#10;           ii. In your turn you can spend 1 action to play this card and increase your ENERGY equal to number on the card and then place it at the &amp;#10;               bottom of the item deck&amp;#10;2. This card can make an attack through the wall&amp;#10;3. This indicate the dice value you need to roll to make an attack&amp;#10;4. This is the range for the attack&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    Each player never have item card in their hand more than 4 cards and they must discard until they have 4 cards before continue playing&amp;#10;         If card used &amp;gt;&amp;gt; place it at the bottom of the item deck&amp;#10;            If card unused &amp;gt;&amp;gt; place it at the discard pile&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Action &amp;#10;In each round start from a player with 1st player cube, Player can spend a maximum of 3 actions the same action can be repeated after players finished their turn player the player on their left starts their turn. When every player finished their turn, The player with the 1st player cube flip all face down disaster tokens and random select 1 disaster token and place on any section except SAFE ZONE after that reveal 1 event card and resolve its effect (detail on page 7). Pass 1st player cube to the player on the left and start the next round&amp;#10;     &amp;#10;   1. Move&amp;#10;      a. Use 1 action to move 1 space orthogonality can&amp;rsquo;t move through the wall&amp;#10;   2. Use energy card&amp;#10;      b. Use 1 action to play ENERGY card from hand to increase Roborg ENERGY equal to value to on the card then put it on the bottom of the deck&amp;#10;   3. Attack&amp;#10;      a. Player must first declare an attack and select a target and then select a weapon card(* * these symbols) and place it face down in front of &amp;#10;         you if you want to attack with Melee weapon you can select any card on your hand instead  after you finish the target can decide to do a &amp;#10;         counter-attack and select a card from their hand but they can also select  an ENERGY card instead to increase their ENERGY after attacker &amp;#10;         finish their attack&amp;#10;      b. When both players ready, reveal their face-down card at the same time if you decide to do an Unarmored or Melee attack take your face down card &amp;#10;         back to your hand without reveal it. Start from the attacker rolls a die if die value equal or exceed requirement on the card that attack &amp;#10;         is successful defender receive damage indicate on the card and if the attack is successful the defender is being knock back 1 space and then &amp;#10;         start a counter-attack if their attack still in range&amp;#10;      c. When an attack failed you can use ENERGY card to +1 value of a die you can use multiple ENERGY cards at once&amp;#10;      d. When you roll a 6  it&amp;rsquo;s a CRITICAL HIT, your attack deal x2 damage but  5 + 1 ENERGY card does not count as CRITICAL HIT&amp;#10;      e. When Roborg Energy go below 0 they&amp;rsquo;re destroyed and don&amp;rsquo;t do a counter-attack&amp;#10;      f. After player finishes an attack their turn ends even if they still have action left&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roborg got attacked with ** and must lose 5 ENERGY but he has armor with 4 value so and decides to put 2 damage on the armor by put Broken Armor Tokens on the armor and lose 3 ENERGY and if a number of broken armor token equal the value on card remove it from player board and place it at bottom of the deck&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A1 SEXY ROBOT GIRL declare an attack on LUCKY ROBO BOY and roll a die successfully make an attack and LUCKY ROBO BOY get knock back in the same &amp;#10;         direction of the attack 1 space&amp;#10;      A2 LUCKY ROBO BOY didn&amp;rsquo;t has any armor so he loses 3 ENERGY and left with only 1 ENERGY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A3 LUCKY ROBO BOY use ENERGY card as a counter-attack so he gains 2 ENERGY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;B1 SEXY ROBOT GIRL declare an attack on SATAN MACHINE and successfully roll&amp;#10;&amp;#10;B2 SATAN MACHINE doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any card on hand so he can&amp;rsquo;t counter-attack, but he has armor so he decides to put 3 Broken Armor Tokens on &amp;#10;         armor instead of losing his ENERGY&amp;#10;   Type of Attack &amp;#10;      1. Unarmored Attack&amp;#10;          a. Range 0&amp;#10;          b. Damage 1&amp;#10;          c. No knock back&amp;#10;          d. Can only use when you don&amp;rsquo;t equip a Melee weapon&amp;#10;          e. No dice roll&amp;#10;      2. Melee Weapon Attack&amp;#10;          a. Range 0-1&amp;#10;          b. Damage 2-3&amp;#10;          c. Knock back&amp;#10;          d. Don&amp;rsquo;t discard when used&amp;#10;      3. Ranged Weapon Attack&amp;#10;          a. Range 0-3&amp;#10;          b. Damage 3-5&amp;#10;          c. Knock back&amp;#10;                i.  If attack successful take it back to your hand&amp;#10;                ii. Can attack through wall or other Roborg&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Knock back from the attack&amp;#10;    When Roborg get hit they will always get push 1 space but can&amp;rsquo;t push out of the main board or though the wall if after got pushed and the attacker not in range of the attack anymore, it counts as your attack missed&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. If attack from the same space(Range 0) attacker can decide where the target will get knock back to&amp;#10;   2. If you use Weapon Attack Target will get knock back 1 space in same direction as the attack&amp;#10;   3. There will be no knock back there a wall behind the target&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Free Action&amp;#10;   1. If you are in the same space with a Retrieve Token you can reveal it and resolve it effect&amp;#10;   2. You can discard any number of cards you want to the discard pile and then put Lost Component Token on your space &amp;#10;      a. You can't discard when your space already have any token on it&amp;#10;   3. If you are in the same space with a Lost Component Token you can take it and randomly draw an item from the discard pile &amp;#10;      a. You can&amp;rsquo;t take Lost Component Token that  just adds on this turn&amp;#10;   4. When you have no cards in hand When in the Search space you can draw 2 cards from the deck you can only use this action once per turn and if &amp;#10;      you draw an Equipment card you must equip the newly draw one &amp;#10;      a. You can&amp;rsquo;t discard or place a token on this space&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         In each section can only have 5 tokens at once and each space can only have 1 token&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Disaster Token&amp;#10;    When everyone finishes their turn playing with the 1st player cube randomly select a disaster token and place it face-down on any section except SAFE ZONE and reveal the previous face-down disaster token &amp;#10;    When the disaster token is revealed each Roborg in that section lost ENERGY equal to the value of tokens in that section &amp;#10;    When Roborg enter the section with revealed disaster token (either by a move in or get knock back ) will lose ENERGY equal to value on tokens in that section &amp;#10;    When the last disaster token is revealed place the addition -1 ENERGY tokens on each section except SAFE ZONE and remove 4 walls around SAFE ZONE out of the game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Red 1&amp;#10;In the 8 round of the game player with the 1st player cube select last disaster token and place it face-down and reveal the previous face-down disaster token, Yellow and Purple each lost 1 ENERGY because they section have revealed token, Red and Green didn&amp;rsquo;t lose ENERGY yet&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Red 2&amp;#10;In the 9 round of the game player with the 1st player cube reveal the last face-down disaster token and then place -1 ENERGY Token on each section except SAFE ZONE and remove the walls around SAFE ZONE then every Roborg outside SAFE ZONE lost ENERGY equal total value of Tokens&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Event card&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After player place disaster on the main board and resolve effect from revealed disaster tokens draw an event card from event deck and reveal it to all players and resolve it effect starting from player with 1st player cube and still have effect until the next round card is revealed. You don&amp;rsquo;t draw new  if there is no disaster token placed down&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Each player randomly stole a card from the hand of the player on their left at the same time&amp;#10;   2. Each player randomly stole a card from the hand of the player on their right at the same time&amp;#10;   3. Each player lost ENERGY equal to the number of cards in their hand&amp;#10;   4. Player with the 1st player cube place an addition disaster token with the same rule&amp;#10;   5. Take all cards from each players hand and shuffle then deal it back to player starting from a player with the 1st player cube and go clockwise&amp;#10;   6. Every Roborg gain 2 ENERGY&amp;#10;   7. Each player can move to any location on the main board starting from the player with the 1st player cube and go clockwise&amp;#10;   8. Every Roborg lost 2 ENERGY&amp;#10;   9. In this round, every player have +1 Action&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game End&amp;#10;   &amp;bull; When each player Roborg have ENERGY = 0 or below that player lose and leave the game and if this Roborg die from an attack the attacker gain 2 &amp;#10;     ENERGY but if Roborg die from the Disaster after got knock back the attacker didn&amp;rsquo;t gain any ENERGY &amp;#10;   &amp;bull; When Roborg die discard all cards from that player hand and all equipment card to the discard pile and place one Lost Component Token on the &amp;#10;     spot that Roborg die if the Roborg don&amp;rsquo;t have any equipment or any card in hand don&amp;rsquo;t place the token and if this token place in the same place &amp;#10;     as the attacker, He/She can take it immediately &amp;#10;   &amp;bull; The last Roborg standing is the winner&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Team Variance&amp;#10;    After deciding who is the 1st player deal team card to each player. Players that have a card with the capital letter are the team leader and always reveal their team card to all players. Player with the lowercase letter is the team member and keep their card face down&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Team card setup&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4 players&amp;#10;5 players shuffle and randomly remove 1 member card&amp;#10;6 players 2 team&amp;#10;6 players 3 team&amp;#10;&amp;#10;And in this team mode, there is special free action once per turn if there are other Roborg in the same space they can exchange or give cards from  their hand to other Roborg in same space&amp;#10;If Roborg get destroyed by your own team leader reveal your team card to all players otherwise keep your team card hidden which team have the last Roborg standing win&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Shorten Manual&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup&amp;#10;1. Place the Main board and distribute Player board&amp;#10;2. Place Walls&amp;#10;3. Place Retrieve Component Token&amp;#10;4. Choose 1st player / Spawn point&amp;#10;5. If desired.Deal team cards to each player&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Turn Sequence&amp;#10;1. Start from 1st player use his action and go clockwise&amp;#10;2. Place Disaster Token face-down in 1 section except SAFE ZONE&amp;#10;3. Reveal the previous Disaster token(s)&amp;#10;4. Draw an Event card&amp;#10;5. Pass the 1st player cube to the left&amp;#10;6. Resolve event card effect&amp;#10;7. Go back to the 1st step&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After every section have revealed disaster token add -1 ENERGY token to each section and remove walls from SAFE ZONE&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The last Roborg Standing Win&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1032" value="Action / Dexterity" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22232" value="Theme: Robots" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="121538" value="Supakit Chapoom" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="121537" value="Anatchai Chinsuvapala" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="121539" value="Tripuck Supawattana" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="40164" value="BGN" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="7.625" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.81968" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="12" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="3" />
			<averageweight value="2.3333" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>