<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="291382">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/k7kQuX50qFkThpRLwngxMw__thumb/img/xRb2hATu7bC5b1RUW0PX2HdBumk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic4998843.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/k7kQuX50qFkThpRLwngxMw__original/img/lQlLK-mGdU6Ogw4sq2b35VC888c=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic4998843.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Strategist Strategy" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="軍師軍略" />
			
						               													<description>&amp;quot;Who would have thought that we would have to face each other in battle like this...&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two strategists, who had once been fellow disciples and studied under the same master, find themselves devoted to carry out the most refined battle of wits, bearing the burden of protecting their home country.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A strategist, however, will never enter the battlefield themselves. &amp;#10;They send out instructions to the Shogun in action based on the information provided by the messengers rushing back and forth from the battlefield.&amp;#10;Figure out the other player&amp;rsquo;s intention with the help of the time lag in-between to aim for victory.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game begins with 3 kinds of game pieces, Infantry, Archer and Cavalry taking position. &amp;#10;How do you establish an advantageous battle formation as you go into battle?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The key to victory is to understand how to properly utilize the special command, the Chain Message, which allows game pieces of the same kind, positioned next to each other in a vertical or horizontal direction, to advance in the same way and in the same turn.&amp;#10;Be conscious of coordinating your military forces and never dividing your formation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WHAT KIND OF GAME IS IT?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Strategist Strategy is a strategy game for 2 players. The goal is to take down the Shogun of the other player by moving your own pieces, similar to Chess or Shogi.&amp;#10;However, it has the following distinctive features.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     You are free to place the soldier pieces anywhere you want at the beginning of the game. The players take turns, placing 1 piece per turn. The placement of the pieces shall be determined with ever-evolving strategies while watching the moves and battle formation of the other player.  &amp;#10;     There are only 3 different kinds of soldier pieces.&amp;#10;     You are not able to move the pieces immediately during your turn. You may only move them according to the commands issued by &amp;ldquo;cards&amp;rdquo; in the previous turn. It is not guaranteed that the game pieces will move as expected. &amp;#10;     When pieces of the same kind are aligned next to each other, either in a vertical and horizontal direction, you may move them together in the same turn, up to more than 2 pieces at once. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For example, 3 Infantry pieces in a row may move forward at the same time or multiple Archer pieces may shoot arrows at the same time. In order to win, it is key to establish a good set-up/formation for yourself and break up the set-up/formation of the other player. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;     After the initial placement,  the players decide in secret which game piece will become the Shogun piece, which is the defining piece for winning or losing the game. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is crucial to predict the Shogun of your opponent during the game play. &amp;#10; In order to get a taste of being a real military strategist, we created this game for 2 players and added game elements that will hopefully remove unrealistic game elements that we had experienced in other strategy simulation games.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2940" value="Square Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="319097" value="Gunshi: The Art of Strategy" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="101258" value="Satochika Daimon (大門 聖史)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="121359" value="Cossack" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="36565" value="Grandoor Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="9" />
			<average value="7.38889" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.993808" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="26" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="11" />
			<numcomments value="13" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="2.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>