<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="295880">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Huu6cu_4uuF3ssDw9aBWXQ__thumb/img/MAQ9RnqEGE6l95wOhbpVemjHV4U=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5103165.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Huu6cu_4uuF3ssDw9aBWXQ__original/img/BMxkB0grVsI_Bm6AlSp7HGUfau4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5103165.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Arise: The First Colony" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You are galactic colonists who have crash landed on your destined planet. You must work together to survive, rebuild and defend against the aggressive aliens hellbent on your demise.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Thrive is a 1-6 player cooperative game that is a 1 to 2 hour immersive experience. Each player takes on the roll of a crew member venturing out to the planet to complete tactical missions, and rebuild the colony. You will feel the tension as you race against time to keep your colony safe and provide your crew food and resources&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is broken into various Seasons. Each Season is comprised of a Mission Phase and a Colony Phase&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Thrive really feels like a race against time. Threats increase as moral erodes. Food runs low as the number of alien activity increases. You really feel like you're working to protect and build up your fledgling colony, on the verge of a breakthrough or total defeat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During Mission Phases players choose a mission together. Every mission will provide different opportunities to gather resources and complete objectives to score victory points. Victory points represent your ability to eliminate the aliens, and secure your territory. They can also represent your ability to study and understand them enabling you to live alongside them or even communicate with them!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The goal of winning the game is to earn 15 victory points. Simple. But, in order to do this you must survive the threats and perils of this new world, while maintaining the healthy morale of the crew.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Morale is one of the three tracks that affect gameplay. The game will be lost, if morale drops to zero.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The second track is the Threat track. As Threat goes up, more morale is lost every Season. Players can improve these two tracks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The final track is the spawn track. The Spawn track increases every Season. It shows players how many aliens spawn from spawning points during the battle for each Mission Phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After each Mission Phase, crew members must return to the colony to complete the Colony Phase. A random event card is drawn that either adds more challenge, or provides a small benefit. Each player then places their crew tokens onto one of the 7 colony stations to perform its action.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All 7 stations can be accessed by any two crew members, or by one of the four specialists linked to that location, either a Commander, an Engineer, an Agritect or a Medic. The Perimeter lowers Threat level. The Training Grounds improves morale. The Med Bay creates medicine and regains lost health. Stasis Pods awake new crew members that can help in the colony next Season. The Bio-Dome is used to grow food. The Command Center earns valuable victory points. The Workshop is used to make new weapons and equipment. Every station can be improved to be more efficient.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Thrive has a fast-pace single die combat and skill system. It just takes one roll to determine if a hit is successful and how much damage is done. Damage and success are inversely represented on the dice, giving great balance to every roll.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aliens are controlled by a clever and easy to use AI algorithm. The AI is predictable, but adapts automatically to the combined tactical choices of the players, creating a challenging puzzle of movement.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All player actions in are taken simultaneously, allowing for minimal downtime between turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Characters are all unique and balanced with 3 basic attributes, 3 pools of trait cubes used for actions, focusing and health. An expansive selection of skill tokens also improve each character after each of the first 3 missions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The variable event deck, the randomly selected skill tokens, and the randomly drawn missions ensure that no two games will ever be the same.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The spawn track is a natural gameplay timer. It increases difficulty and provides thematic tension, making every game fun, fresh and exciting.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The most satisfying element you will find in Thrive is the interconnected puzzles between every Mission Phase and Colony Phase. They are challenging and rewarding. It is a great balance between tactics and strategy. Every choice is meaningful to the team&amp;rsquo;s end results&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2850" value="Events" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2947" value="Movement Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2946" value="Pattern Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2954" value="Relative Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2822" value="Scenario / Mission / Campaign Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2897" value="Variable Set-up" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2874" value="Victory Points as a Resource" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2933" value="Worker Placement, Different Worker Types" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="122774" value="Jason Zmuda" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="122890" value="Jason Zmuda" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="122775" value="Garrett Hamon" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>