<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="296793">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-YJpLQ7nl5oh5txC3aPMCg__thumb/img/xAq-9NN8qEjQsxq3MjhYLzNzkLs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5129057.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/-YJpLQ7nl5oh5txC3aPMCg__original/img/JCmwMuOIl1PS6U-hw4aFtdeNHts=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5129057.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Elementals Unleashed" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The chemical elements make up all the things around us (including us!) &amp;ndash; they are the building blocks of nature. Now you can use the elements like never before &amp;ndash; and Battle, Steal, Block and Heal your way to victory with Elementals Unleashed! The game that brings the Periodic Table to life!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Featuring 32 chemical elements of the Periodic Table, each turned into unique characters (Elementals) with their designs and skills based on their chemical and physical properties, and history. These properties also determine whether an Elemental is classed as Battle: duel another player&amp;rsquo;s Battle cards; Steal: Attempt to steal from another players hidden hand or Chemical Battlefield; Block: Try to stop the steal!; Heal: replenish your hand with cards from the deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player starts with 4 cards from a shuffled deck, which are hidden from the other players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first player draws a card, and depending on what Elementals they have, can either battle, steal, or heal. The success of this depends on the level of the card, and the skill of the Elemental. After a player has used a card, it moves to the Chemical Battlefield in front of the player, becoming visible to all players. However, the cards in the Chemical Battlefield still count towards the players total score.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Battle Elementals are the warriors of the game and are used to duel with other players. When the active player uses a Battle Elemental card their chosen opponent must also produce a Battle Elemental card. Battle Elementals are revealed at the same time and the card with the highest level wins, unless the other Elemental&amp;rsquo;s special skill gives it an advantage. The winner receives their opponent&amp;rsquo;s Battle Elemental into their hidden hand, then places their used card into the Chemical Battlefield. When an opponent doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a battle a card, the active player may take a random card from the opponent&amp;rsquo;s hidden hand.&amp;#10;Steal Elementals are the thieves of the game and are used to steal other players&amp;rsquo; cards. Cards can either be stolen from both the hidden hand &amp;ndash; a random selection - or the Chemical Battlefield - where players can choose the card they want. The Steal Elemental will be successful unless their opponent has a Block card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Block Elementals are the police of the game and are used to prevent the theft of cards. When a player tries to steal from the hidden hand, Block Elementals will always stop any Steal Elemental.  However, a Block Elemental can only prevent stealing from the Chemical Battlefield when the Block level is higher than that of the Steal Elemental.  Block cards must be used when an opponent attempts to steal and are revealed at the same time as the steal card, then moved to the player&amp;rsquo;s Chemical Battlefield.  In the case of Steal cards with Elemental skill 2x steal, two Block cards must be used. When a player has only Block cards in their hand, they may pick another card from the deck and immediately play it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Heal Elementals provide the support of the game and allow a new card to be taken from the top of the deck, unless otherwise specified by the Elemental skill.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a player is asked to battle, or is being stolen from, and they don&amp;rsquo;t have an appropriate card to retaliate (Battle vs Battle, Block vs Steal), they may take the top card from the deck. If the player can use it, they must do so immediately, however, if not, the card is placed into their Chemical Battlefield.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When there is a draw (Battle vs Battle, Steal vs Block), both cards are moved to the relevant Chemical Battlefield, and the active player&amp;rsquo;s go is then over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards taken from another player (through stealing or battle) go into the hidden hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is over once the deck has been depleted, but the last player to draw a card may still play a card from their hand. The players must then count their total points in both their hidden hand and Chemical Battlefield, and the player with the highest score wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="123034" value="Rowan Clark" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="123034" value="Rowan Clark" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="6.25" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.86138" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="25" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="6" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>