<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="298315">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cFY2OWGi0o2PiplqjnpD5w__thumb/img/0PVHMXdphfAnnkzU9r13DADlDiA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5291616.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cFY2OWGi0o2PiplqjnpD5w__original/img/pb2V-4V_EQt_QU_TYfuELSVdb-8=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5291616.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mint Tin Treasure Hunter" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>An easy to play fast-paced card game where players discover and collect valuable treasures to gain points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But beware any treasures that are CURSED!  They will subtract points from your total score.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Collect the Loot Cards and pass the Cursed Cards on to other players and win!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play:&amp;#10;2 players: 20 rounds, keep all cards in game, reshuffle Discovery Cards when all are used.&amp;#10;3 players: 13 rounds, remove 1 standard Loot card, reshuffle Discovery Cards when all used.&amp;#10;4 players: 10 rounds, keep all cards in game, reshuffle Discovery Cards if needed.&amp;#10; Items needed to play not included: pencil and paper to keep track of player scores.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Getting Started: Prepare Loot and Color Card Decks based on number of players. Keep cards types separate and shuffle each deck thoroughly.&amp;#10; Stack the Loot and Discovery Decks in center of play area next to each other and within easy reach of all players.&amp;#10; Being Play: The youngest player starts by drawing three cards from the Loot Deck and places them face up on the table in front of them. Then, going clockwise around the table, each player also draws three Loot Cards and places them face up in front of them on the table.  This is done so everyone can see who drew what from the Loot Deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The youngest player starts the Game Round by turning over one Discovery Card and placing it face up on the table next to the Discovery Deck.&amp;#10; Each player must then stash into their personal stash pile one Loot Card that color code matches the Discovery Card that was overturned.&amp;#10; If a player does not have a Loot Card that color matches the Discovery Card displayed, they must discard the lowest point rated card in their hand into the stash pile.&amp;#10; &amp;#10;            Cursed Loot Cards are also color coded Blue, Yellow, Green, and Wild, and must be discarded if that is the &amp;#10;        &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;only card in the player&amp;rsquo;s hand that matches the displayed Discovery Card.  Cursed Loot will subtract points!&amp;#10; Once each player has stashed one of their loot cards into their own stash pile (this is how you gain or lose points), they then choose one card from their hand to pass to the person of their left. Players cannot pass in the same round a card that was given them by another player in that same round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once each player has stashed one card and passed one card, they should have one card left on display.  They then draw two more cards from the top of the Loot Deck.&amp;#10; Once each players again has three cards on display the current game round ends and the next round begins with a new Discovery Card being overturned.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Wild Cards: Any Loot card can be stashed when the Wild Discovery Card is displayed, unless a player is holding the Cursed Wild Card, which must then always be stashed.  It is possible for the Cursed Wild Card to be in game play until the last round &amp;mdash; players beware!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ending A Game:  When no more cards can be drawn each player should have one card left before them. That last card is added to their stash pile. If their last Loot Card color matches the last Discovery Card players can add an extra 50 bonus points to their total score.&amp;#10; Scoring: Each player adds up their total Loot Points and the end game bonus point if it applies, then subtracts any Cursed Loot Points to get their total score.  High Score Wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="46064" value="Game: Treasure Hunter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="123612" value="TD Bauer" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="124238" value="Nancy Bauer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44542" value="Asgard Gamewerks" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>