<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="298409">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/U_O0xVj-i98H0amwl04szg__thumb/img/hUfkLS7hwUr7dRdWoRhmxdeb_Lg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5177559.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/U_O0xVj-i98H0amwl04szg__original/img/X7d6fshkC-uAD6eGNyseZDbhmFY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5177559.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Pippinzip" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Pippinzip is a square board connection game for 2-3 players. Various sizes of boards are possible, from short games on a 5x5 grid played with pencil and paper, to longer games on a Go board (9x9, 13x13, or 19x19). &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;THE BASIC IDEA:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game begins with an auction phase -- a sort of mini-game of chicken (reminiscent of Unlur), in which an initially empty board is gradually seeded with a growing number of initial stones.  The auction phase determines who will play the role of &amp;quot;Pip&amp;quot; (using black stones) and who plays the role of &amp;quot;Zip&amp;quot; (using white stones).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After the auction phase ends and the roles are thereby determined, the players take turns playing stones of their color to the board.  Play continues until a winning condition is reached. (Draws are impossible.)  Pip wins by connecting any TWO opposite sides of the board via a chain of orthogonally-adjacent black stones.  Zip wins connecting all FOUR sides of the board via a chain of 8-way-adjacent white stones. (&amp;quot;8-way-adjacent&amp;quot; = either orthogonally or diagonally adjacent.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;IN MORE DETAIL:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are two varieties of play, &amp;quot;Zipline&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Pipline&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pipline:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is the standard version of the game. The game begins with an empty board and an &amp;quot;auction phase.&amp;quot; In this phase, on his/her turn a player places 1-3 BLACK stones onto empty points on the board. (Each player has a free choice of whether to place 1 black stone, or 2 black stones, or 3 black stones on his/her turn.) Players alternate turns, playing black stones exclusively in this phase of the game, until one player on his/her turn says &amp;quot;take&amp;quot; instead of placing any stones.  This taker is henceforth known as &amp;quot;Pip&amp;quot; and will play a SINGLE black stone on each future turn.  The opponent (i.e. the non-taker) is &amp;quot;Zip,&amp;quot; who will play a SINGLE white stone on each future turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Immediately after &amp;quot;take&amp;quot; is announced, the non-taker (i.e. Zip) has his/her turn and places a single white stone, followed by a single black stone from Pip, then a single white stone from Zip, etc.  Turns alternate in this fashion until one player achieves his/her win condition (or until one player resigns). Zip wins by connecting all FOUR sides of the board with a chain of white stones that are orthogonally and/or diagonally adjacent; Pip wins by connecting any TWO opposite sides with a chain of black stones that are orthogonally adjacent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pencil-and-Paper Play: Pipline is the recommended version of the game for pencil-and-paper play (draw four vertical lines and four horizontal lines to make a 5x5 grid, as depicted here: https://boardgamegeek.com/image/5173760/cdunc123)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Zipline:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is an alternative version of the game. To start the game, on each turn a player places 1-3 WHITE stones in the auction phase. (Each player has a free choice of whether to place 1 white stone, or 2 white stones, or 3 white stones on his/her turn.) Players alternate turns, playing white stones exclusively in this phase of the game, until one player on his/her turn says &amp;quot;take&amp;quot; instead of placing any stones.  This taker is henceforth known as &amp;quot;Zip&amp;quot; and on future turns Zip will play a SINGLE white stone per turn.  The opponent (i.e. the non-taker) is known as &amp;quot;Pip.&amp;quot; On future turns, Pip will play TWO black stones per turn, with the following restriction:  Pip's second black stone of a given turn is NOT allowed to be placed orthogonally adjacent to the first black stone of the turn. (Placing two diagonally adjacent black stones in the same turn IS allowed. Also, note that in the extremely rare case where ALL remaining empty cells are orthogonally adjacent to first black stone, the second black stone is forfeited.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Immediately after &amp;quot;take&amp;quot; is announced, the non-taker (i.e. Pip) has his/her turn and plays two black stones, followed by a single white stone played by Zip, then two black stones from Pip, then a single white stone from Zip, etc.  Turns alternate in this fashion until one player achieves his/her win condition (or until one player resigns).  Zip wins by connecting all FOUR sides of the board with a chain of white stones that are orthogonally and/or diagonally adjacent; Pip wins by connecting any TWO opposite sides with a chain of black stones that are orthogonally adjacent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Freestyle&amp;quot; Variant: For variety you can play Zipline with free placement for Pip's two black stones, that is, with no ban on orthogonally adjacent placements in the same turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Three-Person Pippinzip: The Zipline version of Pippinzip can also be played as a 3 player game.  In 3 player Zipline, the taker plays as Zip and the two non-takers play as a single Pip team.  Each non-taker plays a single black stone on his/her turn, for a total of two black stones for Pip for every one white stone for Zip.  Roles are determined in the auction phase using the same process described for 3 player Unlur in this thread: https://boardgamegeek.com/thread/1706872/unlur-three-people.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MISCELLANEOUS NOTES&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Before the game, players should agree whether to place stones on the intersections of the game board grid (as in Go) or alternatively, place stones within the cells of the game board grid.  Either mode of play is fine; it is a matter of personal choice.  &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     The board starts out empty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Placement must always be to an EMPTY intersection or cell (depending on which mode was agreed before the start of the game).  So, only one stone per intersection / cell is allowed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Once placed, stones never move.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     If during the auction phase, a player creates the win condition for the color being used in the auction phase, then that player wins the game.  (However, this won't happen if both players play competently!)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="3" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2048" value="Pattern Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="26432" value="Category: Combinatorial" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="66694" value="Craig Duncan" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3829" value="João Pedro Neto" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="9249" value="Bill Taylor" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>