<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="299422">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Throw Down!" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>An edge-of-your-seat card and dice game that lets you brawl with 2-4+ players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Choose your action and your target opponent, then throw down your cards and see who gets hit.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Roll for Damage, then pick up your cards and the next round starts, choose again!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Rounds continue until only one player has health points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player starts with a hand of 5 action cards: Uppercut, Body-slam, Leg Sweep, Guard, and Dodge.&amp;#10;Each player also has a card representing each opponent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Basic Game Rules &amp;#10;Players start the game with a Pain Limit of 20. Rounds are played with each Player acting simultaneously. Each round has three phases: Playing Action cards(and Target cards for 3+ players) face down; revealing cards and determining hits; and finally, rolling and gaining Pain.  Whenever a player is hit by an attack they gain 1d6 of Pain. When a Player's Pain value meets or exceeds their Pain Limit, that Player is knocked out. When all but one Player has been knocked out, that Player wins the game! &amp;#10;1 V 1 Duel &amp;#10;All games of ThrowDown eventually end up here, but some games start out here. &amp;#10;When down to just two Players, they each start the game with only the Leg Sweep, Uppercut, and Bodyslam cards in hand. Players take their turns at the same time. For each round, the Players choose an Action Card and place it face down on the table. When both Players have placed their Action cards, they reveal them at the same time. The Actions are compared to determine which player hits. That Player rolls 1d6 and the other player gains that much pain. Then the cards go back to their players hands for the next round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3 or more Player Throwdown&amp;#10;Throwdown can be played with as many Players as you have cards for! With 3 or more Players, each plays with one of each Action Card in their hand, as well as a Target card for each player other than themselves. &amp;#10;Rounds play out in the same 3 phases mentioned above and outlined here: &amp;#10;Choose your action and which Player you&amp;rsquo;re going to Target, then place the chosen Action Card and Target card face down in front of you. When all players have done this, move to phase 2.&amp;#10;Everyone reveals their choices at the same time. Figure out who is targeting who, whether any moves are negated by its counter-move, and note any defensive Actions. &amp;#10;If a Player has chosen the Dodge action and two or more attacks have targeted that Player, the dodging Player chooses one of the attacks targeting them to be negated.&amp;#10;Any attack Actions (Leg Sweep, Bodyslam, Uppercut) that haven&amp;rsquo;t been negated score a hit! Those Players each roll 1d6 and inflict that much Pain on their Target. The Targets track the Pain they&amp;rsquo;ve gained on their Pain Limit trackers [or a d20 if ya nasty ;) ]&amp;#10;If two Players target each other with the same attack Action, they both roll 1d6, whoever rolls higher inflicts Pain on the other equal to the difference of the dice values. If the dice are a tie, neither Player gains any Pain.&amp;#10;    Then all Players return their Actions and Target cards to their hands, and those who still haven&amp;rsquo;t reached their Pain Limit proceed to the next round. Rounds continue until one Player is left.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Action Cards&amp;#10;Leg Sweep = Deals 1d6 Pain to a single target, negates Uppercut Attacks targeting this Player&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bodyslam = Deals 1d6 Pain to a single target, negates Leg Sweep Attacks targeting this Player&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Uppercut = Deals 1d6 Pain to a single target, negates Bodyslam Attacks targeting this Player&amp;#10;(1 vs 1 style play only uses these three cards for each Player&amp;rsquo;s hand.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Guard = Cause no Pain and take half Pain from ALL  attacks targeting you this round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dodge= Cause no Pain, and also avoid Pain from ONE attack of your choice, targeting you this round.&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;Guard and Dodge actions do not use a Target card, but for the game to work you still need to play a Target card when playing either of these Action cards. If you don&amp;rsquo;t play the Target card, the other Players will know that you are not using an attack Action.     &amp;#10;Example 1: Player 1 plays a Bodyslam and Player 2 plays a Leg Sweep targeting Player 1; this resolves with Player 1 rolling to dole out 1d6 of Pain and Player 2&amp;rsquo;s attack being negated. &amp;#10;        &amp;#10;Example 2: Player 1 and Player 2 each Target each other with Uppercut. Both Players roll 1d6. Player 1 rolls a five, Player 2 rolls a two. Player 1 will inflict three(five minus two) Pain on Player 2&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Target Cards:    A set of cards in each Player's hand that they use to pick their targets in a 3+ Throwdown. Target cards will have a single number on one side. Players will have a Target card in their hand for each opponent. During the first phase of each round, a Player lays down a target Card with the same number as the Player they are wanting to attack. The Target card with their own Player number on it goes face up in front of that Player, for the duration of the game, as a visual reminder of which number is used to Target them. Normally Players don&amp;rsquo;t hold on to the Target Card with their own Player Number on it. No real sense in targeting and inflicting pain on yourself.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pain Trackers And Player Tokens: Players use the Pain trackers with Player Tokens to keep track of the Pain Value. Players Start the game with the tokens on 0 and as they accrue more pain they move their Player Token up the Pain Tracker.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1d6 per Player for Pain rolling&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer (updated 1/26/23)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="101" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="102" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="103" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="104" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="105" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2003" value="Rock-Paper-Scissors" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="123911" value="Coleman Antonucci" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="123868" value="Will Tippin" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44666" value="Rainy Day Roll Play" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>