<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="299790">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7tkY54IG4NpFlYBlBC_4xQ__thumb/img/hr2uO3DbKMDZWFm1Eojn8ebbopY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5190605.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7tkY54IG4NpFlYBlBC_4xQ__original/img/HbEBSXWJJA8YP6WUePI6fktjCEs=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5190605.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Advanced Salvo! European Theater: Tactical WWII Naval Combat Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Advanced Salvo! European Theater is a solitaire, tactical naval strategy wargame that enables players to recreate World War II naval battles between individual allied and Axis on the table top.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The design uses the Salvo! game system, adapted to a WW2 setting. (Great War Salvo! 3rd ed. is its World War I counterpart.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game consists a 20-page rule booklet, containing all rules, game tables, advanced rules and options, scenarios, and designer's notes.  Game components make up the rest of the package, with Scenario Cards, Reference Card, Sea Display, and eight warship counter sheets (sections #1-8), including ships from Great Britain, Germany, France, and Italy, 144 ship counters in all, drawn to scale. Using historically rated warships (BB, BC, PB, CA, CL, AMC types), rated in a variety of offensive and defensive categories, players can assess at a glance the relative strengths and weaknesses of each ship.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Advanced Salvo! European Theater is primarily a ship vs ship solitaire game, but rules are included for two-players as well, with one or multiple ships on a side.  All the major warships from each country are provided (see list below), allowing players to recreate any number of actual and hypothetical Second World War encounters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game may be played with counters, or your own ship miniatures.  The game is adaptable to miniatures on the table top, with scales of one turn equaling several minutes of real time, and each range band representing approximately 5000 yards (2.5 nautical miles).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Originally published in 2015, Advanced Salvo! European Theater is now available in PDF format.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;LIST OF INDIVIDUALLY RATED SHIP COUNTERS INCLUDED&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GERMANY:  BB: Bismarck, Tirpitz.  BC: Scharnhorst, Gneisenau.  PB: Graf Spee, Adm. Scheer, Lutzow.  CA: Prinza Eugen, Adm Hipper, Blucher.  CL: Nurnberg, Konigsberg, Koln, Karlsruhe, Leipzig, Emden.  AMC: Kormoran, Atlantis.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FRANCE:  BB: Bretagne, Provence, Lorraine, Richelieu, Jean Bart.  BC: Dunkerque, Strasbourg.  CA: Duquesne, Tourville, Suffren, Foch, Colbert, Dupleix.  CL:  Gloire, Galissonni&amp;egrave;re, Jean de Vienne, Marseillaise, Montcalm, Leygues, Bertin, Jeanne d'Arc, Duguay-Trouin, Lamotte-Picquet, Primauguet.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ITALY:  BB: Cavour, Cesare, Duilio, Andria Doria, Littorio, Roma, Vittorio Veneto.  CA: Bolzano, Zara, Pola, Gorizia, Fiume, Trento, Trieste.  CL: Abruzzi, Garibaldi, Duca d'Aosta, Savoia, Montecuccoli, Attendolo, Giussano, Barbiano, Bande Nere, Colleoni, Cadorna, Diaz, Pompeo, Regolo, Scip. Africano.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GREAT BRITAIN:  BB: King George V, Prince of Wales, Anson, Duke of York, Howe, Nelson, Rodney, Resolution, Revenge, Ramillies, Royal Oak, Royal Sovereign, Queen Elizabeth, Warspite, Valiant, Malaya, Barham.  BC:  Hood, Renown, Repulse.  CA: Kent, Cumberland, Suffolk, Berwick, Cornwall, Australia, Canberra, London, Susses, Devonshire, Shropshire, Norfolk, Dorsetshire, Exeter, York.  CL: Leander, Ajax, Achilles, Neptune, Orion, Perth, Hobart, Sydney, Arethusa, Galatea, Aurora, Penelope, Southampton, Glasgow, Sheffield, Birmingham, Newcastle, Gloucester, Manchester, Liverpool, Belfast, Edinburgh, Dido, Argonaut, Hermione, Sirius, Euryalus, Fiji, Kenya, Nigeria, Newfoundland, Bellona, Black Prince, Spartan.  AMC: Rawalpindi, Asturias, Cilicia.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="4">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="3" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1008" value="Nautical" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2975" value="Line of Sight" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2949" value="Measurement Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2055" value="Paper-and-Pencil" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="50153" value="Continents: Europe" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="11515" value="Country: Italy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8164" value="Players: Wargames with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="59736" value="Series: Salvo! naval system (Minden)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="30080" value="Advanced Salvo! 1939-1941" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2831" value="Gary Graber" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1889" value="Minden Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="9" />
			<average value="8.11111" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.42941" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="20" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="27" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="5" />
			<averageweight value="2.8" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>