<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="303279">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/H4T_0tV7ZMmTa6qAyOKmNQ__thumb/img/z6cc8urS9Zz68SMt6kXlgIB7gXE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5278090.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/H4T_0tV7ZMmTa6qAyOKmNQ__original/img/oIqrfzrce0sFue01pw6Popg-n8c=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5278090.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="City of Glass" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In this fast-paced worker placement and resource management game, you'll play as one of the best craftsman in the Kingdom contending for the Noble position of &amp;quot;Royal Jeweler&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You will need to be smart, fast &amp;amp; tactical if you want to beat the competition!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Send your workers to bid on chosen custom jewelry contracts.&amp;#10;     Collect raw materials (Gems, Ore, Pearls) to use when making jewelry so you can fulfill your chosen contracts. Fulfilling a contract will gain you experience.&amp;#10;     Use your experience to attract and befriend Noble's who want to use you for heirloom pieces and who will spread the word about you to their friends, which will earn you the much coveted &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;     Build up enough &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; to take home the prize and become the &amp;quot;Royal Jeweler&amp;quot;!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;    Game Setup#&amp;#10;     Each player choose a color and collect the 3 worker meeples of that color, then take a work station card and place it in front of them.&amp;#10;     Place the raw material card within reach of all players. Place all gems in their spots.&amp;#10;     Shuffle the Noble cards and place a number equal to 1 plus the number of players to form the top row of the &amp;quot;board&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;     Shuffle the Contract cards, cut the deck in half and flip one side, then shuffle again and deal out 3 contracts face up in rows below each Noble to complete the &amp;quot;board&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;     Begin (Use your chosen method for deciding who takes the first turn).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Steps of each turn&amp;#10;Place/Move Workers - to bid on contracts. In this step you will send each of you available workers to bid on a specific contract.  If you have no available workers, you may move 1 worker from an uncontested contract and reassign it to any other contract. (Uncontested means that your worker is the only worker bidding on that contract.  If another player has placed a worker on any contract that your worker is bidding on, it becomes &amp;quot;contested&amp;quot; and neither worker can move until one of the players fulfills the contract)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gather Raw Materials - Roll the 3 dice and either collect those 3 raw materials, or sacrifice one of the 3 dice and re-roll the remaining 2 dice.  Then either collect those 2 raw materials or sacrifice 1 dice and re-roll the remaining 1 dice and collect the raw material from the result.  (This indicates you going deeper into the bazaar in search of the perfect gemstone, but often you won't find it and you will never get the best deal)          &amp;#10;Place all raw materials onto your work station in the appropriate space&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Main Step - During the Main step of your turn you will choose from 1 of 4 potential actions. (Limited to a single action per turn)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Complete a contract - If you have the required raw materials on your work station, you may choose to complete one of the contracts that your worker has bid on.  Once you complete a contract, you will take it and place it under the lower part of your workstation so that only the &amp;quot;Experience&amp;quot; section remains showing (See Action Shot).  Then return any workers that were bidding on the contract back to their owners and replace the contract by dealing one from the &amp;quot;Contract&amp;quot; deck.&amp;#10;     Befriend a Noble - If you have collected enough &amp;quot;Experience&amp;quot; to befriend a Noble, you may do so.  Do so by taking the Noble that you want to befriend and placing it beneath the top portion of your work station so that only the gold star &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; symbol is showing (See Action Shot).  Then replace that Noble with one from the top of the &amp;quot;Nobles&amp;quot; deck. If the Noble you befriend adds enough &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; for you to win the game, you win as soon as you befriend him/her and the game ends.  (Shuffle up and play again)&amp;#10;     Bribe a Noble - For the low cost of twice the &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; rating of a Noble (Payable using any gems or gold from your stockpile), you can bribe them to leave the board and be replaced with the top Noble from the deck.  This tactic comes in very handy if, for instance, you see that your opponent is going to win or close to being able to befriend a Noble that may turn the game to their advantage.  Also good to help clear Nobles that aren't a good fit for the current &amp;quot;board&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;     Pass - Occasionally there is nothing that you can do with your current worker placement or workstation stockpile.  When that happens, you can simply pass and end your turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning the game&amp;#10;Solo Mode - Playing this game solo is a race against the clock!  You will play &amp;quot;Easy, Normal or Hard mode&amp;quot; by trying to reach 3,4 or 5 stars of &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; faster than the creator's best score AND before the 12 turn clock ends and you lose the game outright!  Keep track of your personal best scores using the space allotted in the back of the rule book.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Normal Mode (2-6 Players) - When playing with other people, the goal is to become the most famous jeweler before they do.  The objective will be to reach a level of &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; equal to 1 plus the number of players. **EX.**3 players is 1+3=4 stars of &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; to win.  The first person to reach the &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; amount required wins immediately after befriending the Noble whose &amp;quot;Fame&amp;quot; rating puts them over the top!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1070" value="Renaissance" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2913" value="Bribery" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="124290" value="Roger Kolikas" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="124290" value="Roger Kolikas" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44845" value="Munchkin Metropolis" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>