<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="303970">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JCgixpHaWjRT4oGZwW89vQ__thumb/img/jUIePstTMMamP5Z8llLVZdXVPJU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5271981.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/JCgixpHaWjRT4oGZwW89vQ__original/img/Fs-DW-xjVPqafnwjCyyFGjFxtuk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5271981.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Castle Rooms" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Will you be the most skilled castle builder in the kingdom?&amp;#10;Place room cards to grow your castle, but be careful!&amp;#10;The other builders could use dragons to block your construction!!!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PURPOSE OF THE GAME &amp;#10;Be the most skilled castle builder in the kingdom. You will have to place the room cards of the castle by matching the stairs and the corridors of entry with those of exit of the previous card placed on the left.&amp;#10;The player who manages to put 10 room cards in a row wins first.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PREPARATION AND DEVELOPMENT &amp;#10;For 4 players you have to use all 64 cards&amp;#10;For 2-3 players you have to remove 2 Dragons and 2 Knights of your choice&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Shuffle the cards and deal 2 face down to each player, the remaining cards are placed in the center of the playing area to create the draw deck.&amp;#10;The player who last visited a castle begins the game and continues clockwise. During his turn, each&amp;#3;player draws 2 cards to add to his hand and creates his own row or row of room cards in front of him starting from the left and adding other cards only to the right of the previous one. Each player can play as many cards as he wants from his hand, the important thing is that to pass the turn he does not have &amp;#3;more than 2 cards in his hand. If you have 3 or more cards in your hand you cannot pass the turn but &amp;#3;you will have to play them until you remain with 2 cards or less. &amp;#3;WARNING: if you have 3 or more DRAGON or KNIGHT cards in your hand and you cannot use them, they will be discarded until you have 2 cards in your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CREATING A ROW OF ROOMS&amp;#10;The rows of rooms are created starting from the first card on the left and adding the other cards always to the right of the previous one, by matching the stairs and the entrance corridors with those of exit of &amp;#3;the previous card, it is not possible to add cards to the left of the row. All room cards have two identical symbols, positioned on the top and bottom sides and are an HELMET and a couple of CROSSED SWORDS. &amp;#3;When building a row of rooms, it is mandatory that all symbols face the same direction, therefore, if you start a row with the HELMET facing up, all the cards that make up the row must have the HELMETS facing up. If you have no cards in your hand that can be added to a row that you are building and you &amp;#3;have more than 2 cards in your hand, then you cannot pass the turn, you will have to start a new row, always matching HELMETS and CROSSED SWORDS, therefore, if your first row has the HELMET symbol facing upwards, the row that you will build must have the same symbol facing downwards. There is no limit to the number of rows of rooms you can build.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;USING DRAGON CARDS AND KNIGHT CARDS&amp;#10;DRAGON cards can be used against an opponent, during your turn they can be placed to the right of a row of rooms to block the construction, because from this moment the opponent cannot add ROOM CARDS on his own row. The KNIGHT cards instead must be used on their own row of rooms where a &amp;#3;DRAGON card has been placed to remove it and be able to continue building on that row. Once played it must be discarded together with the removed DRAGON card, these cards can no longer be used.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WINNING THE GAME&amp;#10;The player who first creates a row of 10 ROOM cards wins the game. If the cards in the draw deck finish,&amp;#3;and no one had made a 10-card row, in this case the player who made the longest row of rooms wins, if there is an equal merit, whoever has made the second longest row, if there is still a tie, will check the third and so on.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2956" value="Chaining" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2883" value="Connections" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="316700" value="TIC TOC" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="125101" value="Giampaolo Razzino" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="124439" value="Marco Salogni" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44898" value="Little Rocket Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="11" />
			<average value="8.59091" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.22137" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="30" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>