<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="305484">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Corporate Sharks" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Welcome to the quiet pristine country of Unincorporated, a small country that's never allowed foreign corporate business within their borders. Until now. Unincorporated is quickly going bankrupt and has voted to finally allow these businesses to take root and help grow this small land into a thriving group of metropolises.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You will be taking charge of one of these opportunistic corporations looking to establish a foothold and to dominate this untouched land of new opportunity. Bid on shares of the various cities to earn big profits. Control how your corporation does business by purchasing and implementing different Corporate Structure tiles giving you new abilities, additional income and other bonuses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Auction System&amp;#10;Every Round players will have the opportunity to bid on a select number of City Shares. Collections of these Shares will grant their owners additional income that came be ever increased to help you in your victory. Spend your hard earned Credits on these valuable divides to earn more credits later as you gain complete sets. There's no limit to the bidding so be careful your opponents aren't just inflating the price for you!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Buildings&amp;#10;The cities provide those Corporations with sets of Shares with additional Credits every Income Phase based on the buildings already built in the city by yourself or other Corporations. Make a city into a profit hub, or donate public spaces to gain Positive Public Opinion. Some buildings even provide special abilities to shareholders!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Corporate Structure&amp;#10;Each corporation's Structure starts with their Corporate Structure Board. It includes 1 ability unique to that corporation and 2 branches to start your Corporate Structure Tree. Buy new tiles from the Corporate Structure Store and add them to your tree of abilities and bonuses. Infrastructure Tiles will provide additional income, provide the ability to expand your tree, and help you to find Building Materials and Corporate Structure Tiles. Corporate Espionage Tiles with let you to attack and sabotage your opponents with a variety of dirty business practices. Defense Tiles will help to protect your corporation against attacks and keep the general public in your back pocket.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Game That Plays Back!&amp;#10;In Corporate Sharks you aren't just playing against your corporate rivals but against the game itself. The last ditch effort of Unincorporated to allow corporations entrance hasn't gone over well with the public. Most are fearful that these conglomerates will turn their beautiful country into a giant fast food shack and are quick to boycott and protest any corporation they feel is taking advantage. To quell these annoying profit interruptions, donate public spaces, with you logo proudly displayed of course. Or use your Corporate Structure to add employee day cares to show your dedication to providing for these fine people. Keep them extremely happy and they may even help you win the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1029" value="City Building" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2840" value="Action/Event" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2902" value="Income" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2005" value="Stock Holding" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="109640" value="Halldor Sigurdson" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="109640" value="Halldor Sigurdson" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="39407" value="Flying Fish Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>