<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="306272">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6I80vG1FYcjr8uQojwbxng__thumb/img/keOYCaSlIw0E9Omc_6fDG71cnMU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5428647.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6I80vG1FYcjr8uQojwbxng__original/img/QCzK4cLfd5FlD9vyamidOQ5mhTI=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5428647.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Godzilla Rampage: Kaiju Unleashed" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Game Objective &amp;ndash; Players choose Kaiju and battle each other in an all-out melee till one player has defeated all of the other player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju and is declared The King of the Monsters!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Starting the Game &amp;ndash; Taking turns, one at a time each player chooses one Battle Kaiju for their team till all players have a total of 3 Battle Kaiju chosen.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    One at a time each player chooses a section of the game board. Place them together to form a (4-part, section) game board.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Players start at opposite ends of the board with their characters spaced apart.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Play rock, paper, and scissors to decide which player goes first. Game play then continues with the player to the left.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Shuffle and place face down off to the side of the board within reach of all players the Kaiju Assist Cards. &amp;#10;o    Each player may draw 1 card and keep it hidden from all other players. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Each player takes 3 Rampage Counter Cards and places them next to their kaiju. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Place 2 Military Vehicles on the game board in the designated areas. Refer to Military Vehicles below for placement/respawn info.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    If you have a kaiju that can either fly or burrow, take a Burrowing &amp;amp; Flying Counter Card for each kaiju.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Round &amp;ndash; After each player has had all of their kaiju go, a round has passed. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    During a turn, each player&amp;rsquo;s kaiju goes. Players may choose to do nothing with a kaiju on their turn if they wish to not move it or do a battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;What to do during your Turn&amp;#10;At the start of a player&amp;rsquo;s turn, they must announce which one of the following actions they are going to do to start their turn for that particular kaiju.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Battle &amp;ndash; Each player rolls 2 dice and the highest die roll wins. The defender wins ties.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Each Battle Kaiju Card and some select Kaiju Assist Cards have a Wound Counter on them to keep track of when a Kaiju receives a hit. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Once a player&amp;rsquo;s Battle Kaiju receives a KO, that Kaiju is no longer in play. Remove that Kaiju from the board and flip over its Kaiju Battle Card. &amp;#10;o    Kaiju Assist Cards: Some require being defeated. Once defeated, follow the same rules as above for Kaiju Battle Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Grab/Throw &amp;ndash; Grab a Building/Vehicle; roll 4+. To throw a grabbed object; roll the die, the die amount rolled is the x number of spaces you may throw that object. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Destroying Buildings &amp;amp; Bridges: They are destroyed when a player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju attacks them.  Attacked Buildings/Bridges are destroyed on a die roll of 4+.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Once a Building/Vehicle or Bridge has been attacked or used as a ranged attack they are no longer in that space and are considered destroyed. Place a game logo chip on that space.&amp;#10;Hint: Use objects as ranged attack against other player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju. A player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju takes a hit from a building on a die roll of 3+ and a hit from a vehicle on a die roll of 5+.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Melee Attack (Punch/Kick) &amp;ndash; A standard attack against another player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju. Refer to Battle for info.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Kaiju Battle Card Special Ability &amp;ndash; An attack unique to that Kaiju that can be done against another player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Range Attack Ability: Some characters can perform range attacks. These characters can aim at an opponent&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju that are in line of sight.&amp;#10;o    Line of Sight is an imaginary line drawn from the center of one Kaiju&amp;rsquo;s head to the center of another Kaiju&amp;rsquo;s head. If any part of the imaginary line touches or crosses a Kaiju or a building, the Line of Sight is blocked.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Kaiju must wait x number of rounds before they can regain their range ability back; depending on distance they used their attack.&amp;#10;o    Each Kaiju who can perform a Range Attack has a Range Ability Counter on their card to help players keep track of when their Kaiju can perform the ability again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Movement &amp;ndash; Roll the die and see how many spaces you can move a particular Kaiju. This action can be combined with any of the above on a player&amp;rsquo;s turn.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Players can either use regular movement or burrow/fly movement on the board and then either do battle, grab/throw or a range attack.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Sharing Spaces &amp;ndash; Only a player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju may share a space with one other Kaiju they are using at a time. Other players Kaiju may not move onto space with another player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Tails &amp;amp; Wings: Some Kaiju figures have tails/wings that extend into an adjacent square. The Kaiju is NOT considered to be in the square which its tail/wings occupy. If another Kaiju moves into the tail/wings occupied space, either move it off the side to make room or turn the Kaiju figure in the opposite facing direction.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Military Vehicles &amp;ndash; These vehicles are sent to defend the city against Kaiju. They seek out the nearest Kaiju and battle them.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    During setup, place only 2 Military Vehicles on the game board two spaces away from the middle and facing opposite ends of the board.&amp;#10;o    There will only ever be 4 Military Vehicles on the board at once.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    During a player&amp;rsquo;s offensive turn, the other player or players (defense) move the Military Vehicles. Any time a Kaiju moves visible to a Military Vehicle, that Military Vehicle will move two spaces towards that Kaiju. Buildings and other Kaiju block Military Line of Sight.&amp;#10;o    If the Kaiju moves out of view of a Military Vehicle, that Vehicle will not continue to pursue the Kaiju.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Military Vehicle Firing (attack) distance: May fire (attack) any Kaiju from a distance of 3 spaces away; long as they are in line of sight.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Destroying Military Vehicles: They get hit by a Kaiju&amp;rsquo;s Melee/Ranged Attack, including Thrown Objects or a Kaiju enters the same Space they are in.&amp;#10;o    Military Vehicles will spawn at beginning of every round (unless the max number is already on the board) at one of the game setup locations. Player(s) who destroyed a vehicle the previous round or have the fewer number of kaiju on the board will be the one to place a vehicle on the board.&amp;#10;Hint: Use Military Vehicles as projectiles against other player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju. A player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju takes a hit from a Military Vehicle on a die roll of 5+.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Kaiju Assist Cards &amp;ndash; Players can only have 1 Kaiju Assist Card at a time. It can be played at any time, depending on what is written on the card. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    After a Kaiju Assist Card has been played or is no longer in play, place it in a discard pile. Once all of the cards have been used, shuffle the cards and place them face down like at the start of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    If a player draws a Kaiju Assist Card that they do not wish to use or hold on to, they can discard it at the end of their turn. At the start of the next round and it is their turn, they will draw a new card like normal.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Rampage Mode &amp;ndash; As a player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju wins offensive battles, its Rampage Counter will go up 1 level. After Winning 5 Battles that player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju will reach Max Rampage Level. &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    On your next turn (or any other offensive turn) go on a Total Rampage against the opponent's Kaiju! &amp;#10;&amp;bull;    You have 3 Battle Energy to use within your kaiju&amp;rsquo;s Rampage. A standard Battle (Punch/Kick) is worth: 1 Battle Energy and ability off your Kaiju's Battle Card is worth: 2 Battle Energy.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Each player has a Rampage Counter Card next to their Kaiju Battle Card to help you keep track of your Kaiju&amp;rsquo;s Rampage level.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Burrowing &amp;amp; Flying Kaiju Special Abilities &amp;ndash; Some Kaiju have the unique special ability to be able to either burrow or fly. When a player uses this Kaiju&amp;rsquo;s ability, they can ignore Buildings or Bridges that may be in there way.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    At the start of the player&amp;rsquo;s turn, they must announce which Kaiju they&amp;rsquo;re going to use and if they&amp;rsquo;re going to use the Burring &amp;amp; Flying ability prior to rolling the die for movement.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Kaiju cannot end their turn under or top of bridges, buildings or water spaces. A player may end either turn on the same space an ally kaiju only.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    In addition, a player&amp;rsquo;s Kaiju can do pass through another player&amp;rsquo;s kaiju that is in a space.&amp;#10;o    This ability cannot be used during Capture the Flag scenario.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    Player&amp;rsquo;s will keep track of when they can use this special ability by using the Burrowing &amp;amp; Flying Counter Card. A player&amp;rsquo;s kaiju will need to wait up to 6 rounds (depending on the x-number of spaces traveled) before using this special ability again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Water Spaces &amp;ndash; If a Kaiju is passing through water spaces -1 is subtracted from their die movement. Kaiju using the flying ability can ignore this rule.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Military Vehicles, Kaiju Assist Cards and Rampage Mode are all extra optional game features to Godzilla Rampage: Kaiju Unleashed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="101" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="102" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="103" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="104" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="105" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5615" value="Creatures: Monsters" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="69476" value="Movies: Godzilla" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="24569" value="Theme: Kaiju" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="311224" value="Godzilla Rampage: Kaiju Unleashed – The Heroic Ultraman Supplement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="310637" value="Godzilla Rampage: Kaiju Unleashed – The Wrath of Daimajin Supplement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="306336" value="Godzilla Rampage: Attack of the MUTO Supplement" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="176561" value="Godzilla Rampage: Invasion of Gamera Supplement" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="129513" value="Godzilla Rampage" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="63999" value="Elliott Monroe" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="23557" value="Warrior Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="8.9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>