<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="306286">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8fz_EITlrSNDlAQB09Fa8Q__thumb/img/x8W_orHGaTVoElOr1Hwhq9ilvKc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5322307.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8fz_EITlrSNDlAQB09Fa8Q__original/img/XCi0ppVzu9FBIJonTOAN_XHpJOk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5322307.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="ETEREA" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Originally it was Time, a tumult of uncontrollable energies, then Space, an infinite fabric in search of a foothold, then Matter arrived as a parasite ready to infest the rules of the Game. Finally she came, blossomed by a tear of light, which gave rise to all living beings, now she has been imprisoned by her power-hungry children and you will have to free her. ETEREA princess has been chained to the heart of the first world, her children, custodians of the six dimensions , they overturned the throne determined to master the fundamental principles to be able to reign over the entire universe. What was once a thriving planet is now a distant memory, that place where life was born has died out, the Vital Essences, now lost, they no longer generate beings and the thread that binds all the galaxies is corroded and close to splitting. The last hope is a handful of Architects, faithful heralds of the princess, designers of all perceptible dimensions and im palpable. Only they will have the ardor to undertake a mission to the limit of the impossible to try to subjugate the six tyrants, take their keys and free ETEREA from an unacceptable fate; if they fail, everything will be lost, the universe, as we know it, will cease to exist giving way to despair, chaos, ruin.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In ETEREA you are one of the architects who will attempt the enterprise to recover the keys, guarded by the six Bosses who govern the six dimensions: Water, Fire, Wind, Earth, Cosmos and Oblivion, to free the princess and save the whole ETEREA is a game divided into two parts: in the first you will have to wander through the six dimensions trying to reconstruct the Requirements, now swept away by the tyrants, to repopulate them; doing this will allow you to acquire Requirement cards and Artifacts, which are essential to succeed in the mission; to create the Requirements you will need careful planning in the dice roll and a careful use of certain skills or Vocations. In the second part you will have to face the Bosses and recover the keys, in doing so you will have to build your dice set , thanks to what I learned in the first part, and launch yourself in a desperate attempt to defeat them in an unequal duel, but thanks to a careful strategy, nothing will be impossible. There is more, always keep an eye on the time that passes , you will only have eighteen hours, a single day on ETEREA, then everything will be lost. Only an Architect will be able to succeed in the heroic action, but everyone will be able to perish in battle leading everything known to ruin. Good luck, that the glow of ETEREA accompany you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2948" value="Resource to Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="125101" value="Giampaolo Razzino" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="124439" value="Marco Salogni" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="44898" value="Little Rocket Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="18" />
			<average value="7.34444" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.38752" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="31" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="6" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>