<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="307192">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jkQI-qs5-FhWp0wZDGAuRA__thumb/img/5wTVR-0K2f2B7uhWeQEZdTLUh5E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5504237.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jkQI-qs5-FhWp0wZDGAuRA__original/img/lPVR31oQjluQlq8QGo3Fovk50NU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5504237.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Tiwanacu" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The players are architects who, over nine rounds, will compete to build the greatest temple that the god Inti has requested. Each player will be drafting tiles, in order to score the most points at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Will you build the legendary temple Tiwanacu and be rewarded by the gods?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played in 9 rounds. Every round, each player will receive  tiles that he must place in his temple, to try to score the most points. At the end of the 9th round, players will add up all their points and the player with the most points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each game two random God cards will be picked that will change some of the basic rules or add ways to score points at the end of the game. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Round structure&amp;#10;1.    Place tiles in each turn order position as indicated in the current round marker. The tiles that are where the row selector is, will be the active tiles and are available to purchase this round. The other tiles will be available next round. &amp;#10;2.    Starting with the player in first place and following player order, each player takes his turn.&amp;#10;3.    All the tiles available in the active row that were not picked, are returned to the box. &amp;#10;4.    Move the row selector to the next group of tiles (if it was on top, move it to the bottom. And vice versa) &amp;#10;5.    Move the round marker to the next space.&amp;#10;After 9 rounds, the game ends.Player turns&amp;#10;On their turn, each player in player order will the following: &amp;#10;1.    The player moves his piece from their current order position to an empty position in the player order track. &amp;#10;2.    He pays (or receives) the amount indicated on the position. If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have enough money to pay, the player will get a loan token and 10 coins. &amp;#10;3.    Takes the 3 tiles from that position and place them next to their temple board.&amp;#10;4.    The player must put the 3 tiles he has next to his player board. The rules for placement are as follows:&amp;#10;a.    He can place in any position in his grid. &amp;#10;b.    He can choose the order of placing the tiles, but the 3 tiles must be placed this turn.&amp;#10;c.    If he wishes, he can pay 1 coin to place it on top of a previously placed tile. &amp;#10;d.    The grid can have empty spaces.&amp;#10;e.    After placing a tile, it cannot be moved for the rest of game.&amp;#10;Note that some God cards and rounds may change the number of tiles you need to place and change some of the tile placement rules. God cards rules always take precedence over the rules above. &amp;#10;5.    After he has placed all his tiles, the next player in player order does the same.&amp;#10;End of game&amp;#10;After the last player has finished his turn in the 9th round, the game will end. The players will add up their scores and the player with the most points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring&amp;#10;At the end of the game, players will score points depending on the layout of their board and the god objectives. Each type of tile score in the following way.&amp;#10;Color Tiles (Red, Blue. Yellow and Green)&amp;#10;Red tiles scoring in two ways:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     1 point per color tile, regardless of figure. If a player has more than one colored area, they only score for their biggest one.&amp;#10;     Points according to the number of figures and multipliers. If there are Multiplier tiles next to a colored tile (that have the 2x in the same coloredbackground) they will multiply the number of figures on the tile by 2 for each multiplier tile surrounding it. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monolith Tiles&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Monolith tiles score depending on how many different ones you have in a set. There are  6 different monoliths designs, an a set of 1/2/3/4/5/6 will score 1/3/7/12/18/25 respectively. &amp;#10;     If a player has more than 1 set of monoliths, each one of them will be scored separately. For example, if a player has 2 sets of different monoliths, one with 3 tiles and the other with 2, he will get 10 points (7 for the first one and 3 for the second one). &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Extra scoring&amp;#10;After all types of tiles have been scored, each player will receive additional points for the following criteria:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     1 point per Gold coin still in their possession. &amp;#10;     1 point per tile in their biggest zone (can coloured tile or a monolith tile).&amp;#10;     10 points if they have at least one tile of each of the five colours (red, yellow, green, blue) and a Monolith. If a player is missing of the types, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t receive any points. &amp;#10;     Points awarded by completing God cards, if applicable)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Penalties&amp;#10;Each player will receive negative points for the following criteria&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     -15 points per Loan token.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Final score&amp;#10;Each player will add up their points and the one with most points at the end of the game, will be the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1028" value="Puzzle" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2826" value="Turn Order: Stat-Based" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="126054" value="Mauricio Flores" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>