<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="308428">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/AG3xzq3Gxlcdi1bF2sr1_w__thumb/img/DVNCMtNZdwzTag1fq7NU4-olz48=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5380836.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/AG3xzq3Gxlcdi1bF2sr1_w__original/img/Lmps6eMMsQxRslSrChIOsO0M0zg=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5380836.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Papyrus The Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ancient Egypt, 2,512 BC, a group of Apprentice Priests discovers a scroll bearing some indications written by the Supreme Priest about the search for the ancient hieroglyphs of the Gods: whoever finds more of them shall take his place next to the Pharaoh. It is now time to undertake a journey to retrieve them. Will you be able to do it before anyone else?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;RULE BOOK&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components&amp;#10;- 1 Ancient Egypt board game&amp;#10;- 150 coloured pyramids (30 each in Red, Blue, Yellow,&amp;#10;Green, Black)&amp;#10;- 186 Illustrated cards:&amp;#10;              - 110 movement cards (24 for each symbol: Light, Dark,&amp;#10;                 Nature and Water + 14 &amp;quot;Eye of Horus&amp;quot;)&amp;#10;              - 36 Gods Cards&amp;#10;              - 40 Event cards&amp;#10;- 1 bag for hieroglyphics&amp;#10;- 300 hieroglyphs&amp;#10;- 75 beetle tokens (15 for each player)&amp;#10;- 5 Player scrolls&amp;#10;- 5 hieroglyphics holders (1 for each player)&amp;#10;- 5 pawns (1 for each player)&amp;#10;- 5 scorekeepers (1 for each player)&amp;#10;- 1 rule book.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PREPARATION OF THE GAME&amp;#10;Place the board in the middle of the table.&amp;#10;Each player chooses a color. Each player is given 30 Pyramids, 1 pawn, 1 scorekeepers of the chosen colour, 1 player scroll, 15 scarab tokens and 1 hieroglyphic holder.&amp;#10;Each player places his marker token on the Start square of the marker, and places his pawn on the Pyramid of Hours square; it will be the starting square for all players. &amp;#10;Before you start the game, distribute it to each player: &amp;#10;- 4 movement cards&amp;#10;- 3 Gods cards&amp;#10;- 10 hieroglyphs &amp;#10;Now place the Movement card deck, the Gods card deck, the Event card deck and the hieroglyphics bag next to the board. &amp;#10;You are now ready to begin.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OBJECTIVE OF THE GAME&amp;#10;The aim of the game is to get the highest number of points. You earn points when you reach on the board the pyramid corresponding to the God card in your hand and you have previously formed the name of the corresponding God with hieroglyphics. (Example: the God Card HORUS is formed by the hieroglyphics corresponding to the letters H , O, R, U, and S. If you reach the &amp;quot;Pyramid of Horus&amp;quot; box on the board and you have the necessary hieroglyphics [see the conversion of letters into hieroglyphics on your player's scroll], you will have conquered the HORUS Card and you will be able to advance on the scoreboards with the value of the Card: in this case Horus is formed by 6 letters and therefore worth 6 points. &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TURN OF GAME &amp;#10;The older player starts first. The game then proceeds clockwise. Each player in his turn can make 1 of these moves (only one):&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- draw 2 movement cards;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- move on the map - The player can move on the board using the movement cards. Each movement card corresponds to the 4 colors on the map and the player must use the exact color and quantity indicated on the boxes to move on the board. (Example: the pyramid of Horus and Anubis are connected by 4 blue &amp;quot;water&amp;quot; squares + 2 yellow &amp;quot;light&amp;quot; squares; then the player must play 4 water movement cards + 2 light movement cards, for a total of 6 cards).&amp;#10;           - If the player reaches the pyramid of the God card in his possession and has previously formed his name with hieroglyphics, he can put his coloured pyramid on top of the pyramid square. He then moves the scorekeepers along the number-marker corresponding to the value of the card, places a scarab token on his player's scroll. Finally, he discards the newly conquered God Card and can draw a new one. The hieroglyphs he used to form the name must be discarded, and the player may draw the hieroglyphs from the bag of the same number as the newly discarded ones. &amp;#10;          - If the player reaches any pyramid on the map without having the right to        conquer it, nothing happens and his turn ends.&amp;#10;         - If the player reaches the Event square, draw 1 Event card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- Draw 1 hieroglyph from the bag, but first he must pay by placing an uncovered hieroglyph in front of the bag. (or the player can choose 1 hieroglyph from those already uncovered, always paying with his own hieroglyph).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;END OF THE GAME&amp;#10;When the Gods card deck is finished and one of the players wins his last God card, the final round begins for all players (except for the same player who has already finished the game).&amp;#10;After the final round, the game ends and the players move on to calculating their final score.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SCORING&amp;#10;Players should have already marked on the scoreboard the points earned by winning each God card. Each player must then add 5 points for each scarab token they have previously deposited on their personal scroll. &amp;#10;In addition, the player who has conquered more than 2 or more &amp;quot;sons of Horus&amp;quot; has bonus points:&amp;#10;2 sons of Horus: 5 bonus points&amp;#10;3 sons of Horus: 8 bonus points&amp;#10;All 4 sons of Horus: 10 bonus points&amp;#10;The player with the most points wins the game. If two or more players have the same number of points, the player who has won the most sons of Horus wins the game. In the unlikely event that they are still in a draw, the player who has won the &amp;quot;Amon-Ra&amp;quot; card wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1-PLAYER-VARIANT: &amp;#10;In the 1-player variant, the Gods Cards, the hieroglyphics, the scarab tokens, the player scroll and the movement cards are required. &amp;#10;The player at the beginning of the game has 3 Gods cards and must form his name with hieroglyphics in order to win the card. To buy a hieroglyph you must use an element card without distinction (in the normal version they are called movement cards).&amp;#10;Once the name is formed, the corresponding God card will be discarded and another card can be drawn. For each God card won  you need to apply a scarab token to your Player scroll.  &amp;#10;The game ends when the Gods card deck ends (you can decide at the beginning of the game if you prefer to play with fewer Gods cards).&amp;#10;Calculation of points and winnings: After you have formed the name of the last God of the deck, proceed with the calculation of the score (5 points for each scarab token + the specific points of each God card).&amp;#10;If the totalized score is higher than the number of the element cards paid, you win the game, otherwise you lose.&amp;#10;You can also play this variant with more players!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1082" value="Mythology" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2847" value="Advantage Token" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2875" value="End Game Bonuses" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2939" value="Track Movement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="126589" value="Stefania Messina" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="126588" value="Federico Carlo Pizzardi" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="126588" value="Federico Carlo Pizzardi" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>