<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="30937">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/2qe4RqsNb2lgAWe0eBnczw__thumb/img/ZAycm9jqNE9RjjwjAlkJTutPZPE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic246333.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/2qe4RqsNb2lgAWe0eBnczw__original/img/2DSPRmkazmnfqZL4KUCGiMx341w=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic246333.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Inside Blitz Football" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the website:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Inside Blitz is a football simulation like no other.  After playing many others in my life I set out to take all the good and get rid of all the bad I saw in those games.  That along with some innovative game play makes this game something special.  The game play is simple yet captures every aspect of the game of football.  Players perform just like they did in the season recreated.  Using a combination of Fast Action Cards and dice plays develop using the personnel on the field.  Your linemen can get called upon to make a play, the defensive secondary may have to stop the run or your linebackers may have to break up a pass.  If it is inside the game of football it is in Inside Blitz.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With defensive players rated in 7 categories, you can see the strengths and weaknesses of all the players.  From coverage skills in four depths of passes to their run defense you will see the weak links.  Not all pass rushers and ball hawking DBs were created the same and here you will see who those players are.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Linemen, receivers and runners are rated for run and pass blocking.   Your sieve of an offensive line will allow more pressure while those staunch linemen will protect your QB like Fort Knox.  You will see the blockers blast running lanes or fail to get room for your runners.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Quarterbacks have 4 different throwing depths so the deep ball guys will perform as such.  Those dump off guys will get their shots downfield but when pressured they will look to their comfort dink passes. The pass rush and scrambling system can really bring out the anticipation of those type plays as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Receivers are rated for pass catching ability in three depths down the field.  All receivers have their own 6x6 cards for each depth of pass with the ability to bust one for a longer gain if they can get loose.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Runners are rated for inside and outside running making each runner completely different.  Along with each players own 6x6 card for each type of run you will see where the home-run-hitter type runners will get the all or nothing yards while your consistent bull of a back will get his yards no matter but don&amp;rsquo;t expect a big one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You have never seen a solitaire system like this one!  Play calling takes into account down, distance and the style of play of both the offense and defense.  Using all this also gets defensive platoons into the game without any hassle on the gamers part.  The distribution of who gets the ball is taken care of with ease.  You won&amp;rsquo;t be seeing a bomb to your clod-footed TE but your track star will be targeted more often at that depth.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Special teams, penalties and propensity to fumble are not overlooked in this game.  Each coverage team is given ratings to reflect the way they played on the season.  Teams are rated separately for penalties which is a very important aspect of football that gets glossed over with many games.  Finally each player is given their own fumble rating to show how each player took care of the ball.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All this is presented in a professional and quality way making Inside Blitz the game of the new generation.  Come on inside!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2005" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2055" value="Paper-and-Pencil" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5640" value="Sports: American Football / Gridiron" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="4016" value="Chris Davis" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7352" value="Inside Sports Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="26" />
			<average value="8.08846" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.07751" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="43" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="5" />
			<wishing value="24" />
			<numcomments value="9" />
			<numweights value="3" />
			<averageweight value="2.3333" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>