<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="309563">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/9iOdD_uDBFqtdp1FFJ7j2w__thumb/img/ZhVjnfNO2aQvjUwvWPC8Ul7L8ms=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5420893.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/9iOdD_uDBFqtdp1FFJ7j2w__original/img/R7lsjv9h4did1ef251GQ-JX0L7A=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5420893.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Gamot" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>&amp;ldquo;Before you looms the dimly lit entrance of the most feared dungeon in the land. It is called the GAMOT. Within the Gamot lie dangers untold, for no hero has yet returned from its deep depths. The journey here has not been an easy one. You dismount from your trusty steed and ready your sword and shield. If you conquer the Gamot, you will earn the greatest glory in the land and with it a place among the King&amp;rsquo;s personal guard. A worthy position for a hero such as yourself!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As you approach the entrance to the Gamot, you can smell the foul stench of death and are overcome with an unexplained dread. While you steel your nerves against this dark air, you hear the sound of hoof beats behind you. Your horse has fled in fear&amp;hellip; You are truly alone now. You step into the entrance of the Gamot, filled with determination. As you do so, however, the floor gives way and you find yourself suddenly tumbling down an incline. You hit the ground below with a hard thud. After taking a moment to regain your bearings, you search in the darkness for your sword and shield. They are nowhere to be found! Rising to your feet, you see that you have fallen into a long corridor lined with doors. A haunting laugh echoes in the dungeon. The only thing that stands between you and whatever horrors await you in the dungeon is your will to live and your desire to prove yourself the greatest hero in the land&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Will you survive the Gamot?&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gamot is a solitaire dungeon crawling card game, designed to be quick and playable on-the-go. You take the role of an adventuring hero as you attempt to navigate the perils of the dungeon. You will search for weapons and items in which to defend yourself, while fighting fearsome monsters and drinking potions to keep your health up! No two games are ever the same!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Arm yourself with swords, bows and warhammers, or locate powerful weapons such as the Golden Trident!&amp;#10;     Use special items like the Magic Ring to rearrange the shape of the dungeon!&amp;#10;     Choose wisely when to face a threat head on and when to run!&amp;#10;     Face monsters such as werewolves, black knights, great worms and the dreaded and deadly lich!&amp;#10;     Search the halls of the dungeons for potions to help you recover from your wounds suffered at the hands of these brutal beasts!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gamot is the perfect game for on-the-go players! Gamot requires little space to play, plays as quickly as you can make decisions and can be carried in your pocket. Designed to be played while waiting in lines, travelling on buses or trains, or on your break at work, Gamot also works for filling in time while you wait for your turn at the gaming table. With only a deck of 54 standard playing cards (and some small counters that you can easily replace with your memory or a scrap of paper and a pencil), and developed to appeal to both your mind and your wallet, Gamot provides a great and inexpensive dungeon crawling experience that won't break the bank!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gamot is easily learned, but tough to master. Gamot is also family-friendly, and requires only basic math skills to get started.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2016" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2962" value="Move Through Deck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="59218" value="Category: Dungeon Crawler" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="73039" value="Category: Print-on-Demand" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="62001" value="Game: Scoundrel" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="126972" value="Mike London" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="126973" value="Marissa Kirby" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="126972" value="Mike London" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51414" value="@GorillaPressComics" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="10" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.1619" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="28" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="6" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="1.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>