<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="309757">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Q3-nuTqhRTtQ5-8QHMmEbg__thumb/img/w6hC2J47dp5--v7OGmb_uUAgS2I=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5416263.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Q3-nuTqhRTtQ5-8QHMmEbg__original/img/AD398MKpV2OCq1nTAVSqpMx7ttU=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic5416263.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="REACTOR" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Join the global community and manage your resources as you build your nation&amp;rsquo;s Economy, Global Engagement, Military, Human Progress, and Satisfaction. Can you lead your country to an age of happiness and prosperity?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;REACTOR is a light, quick playing civilization building strategy game commissioned by NSquare and designed for use in the classroom to create teachable moments highlighting the dangers of nuclear weapons.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay&amp;#10;Each turn consists of 3 phases in this order: Infrastructure, Action, and Aftermath&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Infrastructure Phase&amp;#10;Starting with the first player, everyone chooses one category to raise up 2 levels.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Action Phase&amp;#10;Each player secretly chooses which action they will take by playing the corresponding card face down in front of themselves. There are 5 possible actions. Economic Progress: Add resources to any category. Global Responsibility: Create an alliance and/or generate resources. Human Achievement: Add resources to your lowest category. Satisfaction: Convert military resources to any other category and get bonus resources. Military: Invade or Nuke another nation. All actions are explained in greater detail below.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once all players have locked in a choice, the cards are revealed, and the actions are resolved starting with the first player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aftermath Phase&amp;#10;Players with an active alliance automatically produce additional resources which can be placed anywhere. Allied players receive 1 resource per alliance at level 2, 2 resources per alliance at level 5, and 3 resources per alliance at level 10.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then the first player marker is moved clockwise from the current first player and a new round begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;End&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of the game, any nations with a total score of 30 or more points from all categories, except Military, (or with a Satisfaction level of 8+ and total score of 25 or more points) are considered winners unless all remaining nations have winning totals in which case the player with the lowest Satisfaction score loses. If players have a tie for lowest Satisfaction score then break that tie with their point total from the other three categories.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If all nations have been Nuked, then everyone loses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If only 1 Nation remains, that nation is technically &amp;ldquo;the winner&amp;rdquo; but they are now the sole survivors of a nuclear wasteland.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Among younger demographics, the nuclear issue is abstract and distant&amp;mdash;a problem of previous generations. There are more resonant issues like social injustice, global warming, or economy disparity that, while still daunting, are far more comprehensible and consequential.&amp;#10;Reactor, engages high school students in the classroom about the nuclear weapons threat by connecting this issue to more visible social matters through an interactive and accessible medium. By breaking down the complexity of this problem with play, students cultivate a sense of understanding that drives engagement, helping foster new generations that feel empowered and responsible to take action.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;About NSquare: &amp;#10;In 2014, five of the largest peace and security funders in the United States joined forces to develop a new, collective approach to incentivizing and rewarding innovation in the nuclear threat field. What emerged was N Square, a path-breaking initiative built on the idea that new forms of cross-sector collaboration&amp;mdash;combined with the sheer ingenuity of an engaged public&amp;shy;&amp;mdash;will accelerate the achievement of internationally agreed goals to reduce nuclear dangers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1015" value="Civilization" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2915" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="69233" value="Matt Fantastic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="80252" value="Nick Nazzaro" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="73542" value="Blaise Sewell" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>