<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="316347">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Benidorm Bar Crawl" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Build your Benidorm Empire as you acquire bars, add shows &amp;amp; obtain hotel partnership deals to maximise the spend per visit for each of your venues until the other players go bust and you own it all.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Purchase bars as you land on them then then increase the income you receive per visit by adding shows and hotel partnership deals.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Shows can be purchased and added to any of your bars immediately and can be moved between your venues each turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Hotel partnership deals can be purchased when you have 4 or more bars in the same district that will multiply your bar's earnings.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you land on an area with Jager Bombs you must draw a card from the 'Power of Jager' deck which have good or bad consequences.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Benidorm Bucks are the in-game currency that is used to trade venues, shows, contracts &amp;amp; pay bar fees as the bar crawl continues.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Props can be employed and placed at any bars when you own the bar next door, visitors must then visit both bars on the same turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Preparation&amp;#10;To begin, place the game board on the table. Each player selects a player piece. All players then place their player piece on the cash point square of the outta section of the game board. All players roll the dice, the player with the highest dice roll is the Banker, who distributes assets from the Bank to the players. Each player is given 3,000 in cash divided as follows: two 500s, ten 100s, ten 50s and twenty five 20s. All remaining cash and other equipment go to the Bank.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;General&amp;#10;On a player&amp;rsquo;s turn, the player roll the dice and move his/her player piece forward the number of spaces as rolled on the dice. If the player owns any Shows or Props, they can move these between their owned bars during their turn.&amp;#10;If the player lands on an unowned bar, the player may buy it for the price listed on that bar&amp;rsquo;s space. The money is given to the Bank in exchange for the Property Acquired Card for that premises. Shows can be purchased immediately and added to the premies, increasing its earn when visited. Props can be added when a player owns 2 properties next to each other and Hotel Deals can be purchased when a player owns 4 properties in the same district (colour).&amp;#10;When players land on a property owned by another player, they must pay the player the amount stated on the Property Acquired Card including extra charges if the premises has Shows or Hotel Deal added.&amp;#10;If the player lands on his or her own property, nothing happens.&amp;#10;When players land on Lotto spaces they must contribute 100 Benidorm Bucks to the prize pool in the centre of the board, any fines, the money will be also added to this prize pool.&amp;#10;When players land on Jager spaces, they must draw a card from the Power of Jager Deck, this will either have good or bad consequences.&amp;#10;If the player is sent to &amp;lsquo;The Beach&amp;rsquo; to sleep it off, they must roll above a 6 to wake up and continue playing, unless they have an &amp;lsquo;Energy Drink&amp;rsquo; card to play.&amp;#10;If the player lands on &amp;lsquo;The Beach&amp;rsquo; space, he or she is &amp;ldquo;Just Passing Through&amp;rdquo;. No penalty applies.&amp;#10;If the player lands on the &amp;lsquo;Spin Out&amp;rsquo;, he or she must move his Player Piece directly to &amp;lsquo;The Beach&amp;rsquo;.&amp;#10;Every time a player passes a Cash Point they collect 200 Benidorm Bucks from the Banker.&amp;#10;You may sell Shows or Props back to the Bank for the full purchase price or sell properties to other players via mutual agreement at any point during the game.&amp;#10;Players can loan other players money and make agreements during the game.&amp;#10;Doubles&amp;#10;When doubles are rolled, the player gets to play again during the same turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Beach&amp;#10;If instructed to &amp;lsquo;Go to the Beach to sleep it off&amp;rsquo; via either landing on the space stating that or drawing a Jager Card with that instruction, the player must enter the beach and roll above a 6 to continue playing, they can try once per turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whilst passed out on the beach, if other players enter &amp;lsquo;The Beach&amp;rsquo;, just passing through, they can challenge the player for a bar of their choice, each, and the higher roller wins both bars.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lotto&amp;#10;Ant ime a player lands on a Lotto space, they must pay 100 Benidorm bucks to the Prize Pool in the center of the game board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Bottom Line&amp;#10;Each turn, try to foresee where players will land after your turn to maximise income and bankrupt your competitors.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="6" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="7" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="8" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="9" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="10" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72071" value="Admin: Unreleased Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="10310" value="Country: Spain" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="69641" value="Theme: Pub, Bars, Bistros..." />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="110882" value="Daniel Hayles" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="110882" value="Daniel Hayles" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="39831" value="Stampede Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>