<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="316678">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/k44tzYFQHIXcHAkUaGjHmg__thumb/img/Y2rt8UJ9u-KVNCvYVjn-I9GiP34=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5618085.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/k44tzYFQHIXcHAkUaGjHmg__original/img/hIetM4uLjpQlxz1vjat91Be8i50=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5618085.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Alpha Steel" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Out on the planet of Ibun, the Bots have created an advanced station. Here, the Bots must show their strength at the Alpha Steel Arena and decide who is the Last Bot Standing. The winner becomes the leader of the Elite Bot Army. The Age of the Human is over, the Age of the Bot begins! Go Droid!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Alpha Steel, players control futuristic bots on the planet of Ibun. The goal is to defeat all other bots and remain the last player standing, inside the arena.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Everyone starts outside the arena with 1 rookie bot, 70,000 Azol (Azol- the currency in the game), 10 energy tokens, and 2 power cards. Each player starts with a rookie bot but can purchase a master bot during the game. On your turn, you will roll both dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From each dice you can: gain energy or 30,000 azol or attack other players&amp;rsquo; bots. If you roll the same on both dice, you get double! For each attack you roll, your bot deals damage to other bots. The amount of damage you cause is written on your bot card. If you&amp;rsquo;re inside the arena, you attack everyone else. But if you&amp;rsquo;re outside the arena, you will only attack whoever is inside.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the start, everyone is outside and the first player to roll an attack, enters the arena. All the other bots suffer damage. If you wish to leave the arena, you must wait till someone attacks you. Then, you pay the damage and exit. The player who had attacked you, must enter the arena.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you stay in the arena for one whole round, you get 30,000 Azol after your dice roll. When you are inside, you can never gain health.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Power cards give your bots special strengths. you can play only one power card on your turn and must give it up after use. Some power cards can be played anytime. At no point can you have more than 2 power cards with you. Each power card has cost price and a profit or loss percentage mentioned in them. So, when you sell a card you do so either at a profit or a loss. All power cards sell at 50% loss, while all rookie bots sell at 50% profit. You can buy only one power card or a bot at the end of your turn. But, if you are inside the arena, you can buy a power card or bot anytime. If another player attacks you and you cannot pay Azol, you can sell your power card to get azol, otherwise you are eliminated. If you ever run out of energy tokens, you are eliminated!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When only two players remain in the game, it is the final duel. Both their bots enter the arena. You cannot buy any power cards or bots. you also cannot get energy or azol from dice.However, you can use the power cards you already have. The duel continues till a player is eliminated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A round of play:&amp;#10;Your turn begins by rolling both dice. Then, you can play your power card. Other players cannot play a power card unless it is a play anytime card. Now, resolve the dice roll. remember if you are inside, you attack everyone. if you are outside, you only attack the person inside. Next, you can buy a power card or a bot. the player inside can buy anytime, other players can buy only on their turn. If the player inside wants to exit, they must do it now. If they exit, you must enter the arena. A player cannot exit if you did not roll an attack. Your turn ends.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Alpha Steel is a strategy based board game that is perfect for all ages. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s game night with friends, weekends with family or to combine the power of learning and play for kids, the board game provides an awesome experience for all. Enjoy as you use your robot&amp;rsquo;s special powers and tactics to vanquish other bots and lead the entire bot army.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2838" value="Action Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2856" value="Die Icon Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2900" value="Market" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="46293" value="Luma World" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>