<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="316702">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qyYXJ8Hqfqz4ia9lOvvyyA__thumb/img/fn0CQ_E_zi7rHatcdFcYdPwzrrM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5618124.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qyYXJ8Hqfqz4ia9lOvvyyA__original/img/X6CjI4lDsoXItpmRy5N8ETP7QCs=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5618124.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fracto" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In the jungle, all the animals are gathering. They demand that all resources be divided rightfully among them. The stronger ones are taking more than the weak. That&amp;rsquo;s wrong! But, who will ensure that peace prevails? The winner of this battle of wits will be the King of the Jungle!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fracto is a 3-in-1 card game to learn operations with fractions. It has a set of 80 playing cards. There are 3 kinds of fraction cards - number cards, image cards and word cards.When the sum of two fraction cards is equal to 1, it is called a whole pair. For example:  &amp;#226;&amp;#133;&amp;#147; + &amp;#226;&amp;#133;&amp;#148; = 1 : so, the fractions &amp;#226;&amp;#133;&amp;#147; , &amp;#226;&amp;#133;&amp;#148;  together forms a whole pair. where as &amp;#226;&amp;#133;&amp;#154; + 2/6 = 7/6, so the fraction &amp;#226;&amp;#133;&amp;#154; + 2/6 does not form a whole pair. Remember, here you can make whole pairs using only two fraction cards. The three different gameplay of fracto are: Whole-in-1, Deck of Fortune and Memory Hero. &amp;#10;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the first gameplay: To play Whole-in-1, shuffle the cards and distribute 8 cards to each player. These are the hand cards. The main deck is placed face down in the centre of the table. Check your hand cards if you can make any whole pairs. if you can, then place the pairs face down on the table in front of you.At any given point in the game, you must have even number of hand cards. Pick the top card from the main deck. place it face up on the table. This is the discard pile. The player on the left of the dealer starts the game and it continues clockwise. On your turn, you can either pick up the top card from the discard pile or the top card from the main deck. Check if you can make a whole pair using the new card. if yes, then place the whole pair, face down, in front of you and discard any card from your hand cards into the discard pile. if you cannot make a pair, then put any of your hand cards into the discard pile. The turn moves to the next player. You must call out &amp;ldquo;fracto&amp;rdquo; whenever you have only 2 hand cards. This is applicable even at the start of the game. if you do not call out &amp;ldquo;fracto&amp;rdquo; and you are caught by another player, you must draw four cards from the main deck. You finish when you have made whole pairs with all your hand cards. There will be one card remaining, which will be discarded into the discard pile. When you have made all the whole pairs, you must show the whole pairs to the other players. If you have  made a wrong whole pair, you need to draw four cards from the main deck. you must also pick up the incorrect pairs and the game continues.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the second gameplay: To play Deck of Fortune, shuffle the cards and distribute equally until all cards are over, amongst all players. All the cards are dealt face down. you are not allowed to see your cards. The player to the left of the dealer starts the game. The game continues clockwise. On your turn, you pick up the top card from your player deck and place it face up on the table. This is the discard pile. You check whether the card placed forms a whole pair with the card below it. if it does, you pick up the entire discard pile and place it below your player deck. if it does not, the game continues and the next player places their card. This continues until a player completely finishes their player deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the third gameplay: To play Memory Hero, remove the red cards from the deck. Make a deck of blue and green cards. shuffle the two decks separately. Distribute 7 blue cards to each player. These are the hand cards. you can see your hand cards. Take 16 green cards and arrange them, face down, in a grid of 4 by 4.These are the table cards. The remaining green cards are kept separately as the main deck. The player to the left of the dealer starts the game and the game continues clockwise. On your turn, you will open any one table card, so that everyone can see it. If the table card forms a whole pair with any one of your hand cards then pick up that card, show the pair to everyone and set the pair aside. If you cannot form a whole pair, you keep the card back facing down. the game continues. Once a table card is used you must replace it with another card from the main deck, facing down. You can only combine one hand card with one table card. You can open a table card only on your turn. The game ends when a player completes all their hand cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The perfect educational family entertainer with three engaging games packed in a single set! Fracto provides your kids with a blend of academics, life skills and moral values while they have loads of fun. Your kids will enjoy this fantastic 3-in-1 learning experience with their family and friends. Sit back and see them become conceptual masterminds right before your eyes!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2857" value="Card Play Conflict Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2991" value="Speed Matching" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="46293" value="Luma World" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="8" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>