<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="317952">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/zfzyZrrwGdt7Ct6vjNyG6Q__thumb/img/bHRjYk0QNBdf7rPaoaezBoxi24w=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5631295.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/zfzyZrrwGdt7Ct6vjNyG6Q__original/img/sB3ol65aOOwKE7Tfk_rXiempPQk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5631295.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Soccer Blast Pro Soccer Game: International Football Legends Expansion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This amazing new card set was created by soccer aficionado and historian Bill Hild.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Included innovations such as &amp;quot;doubled qualities&amp;quot; for a few super-star players&amp;mdash;which bringing added depth and realism to the cards and elevates the performances of the greatest-of-the-great.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 22 teams, each with 20 players and three goal keepers. A few of the world&amp;rsquo;s dominant soccer nations&amp;mdash;Argentina, Brazil, England, for example&amp;mdash;have had so many great players over so many years, they were allotted two teams in this set. (Rosters for each team are shown below.) &amp;#10;Over 500 of the greatest soccer stars who ever took the pitch, each team presented in &amp;ldquo;national&amp;rdquo; colors.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Includes:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ARGENTINA I: S. Marzolini, C. Sosa, R. Perfumo, J. Olguin, J. Salomon, J. R. Delgado, J. Carrascosa, L. Monti, N. Rossi, A. Rattin, A. Gallego, A. Sastre, R. Bochini, A. Di Stefano, R. Orsi, F. Loustau, J. M. Moreno, A. Pedernera, A. Labruna, O. Sivori; GK: A. Carrizo, U. Fillil, A Tesoriere.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ARGENTINA II: J. Zanetti, A. Tarantini, O. Ruggieri, D, Passarella, R. Ayala, J. Sorin, W. Samuel, F. Redondo, E. Cambiasso, J. Mascherano, O. Ardiles, J. S. Veron, J. R. Riquelme, D. Maradona, A. Di Maria, L. Messi, C. Tevez, S. Arguero, G. Batistuta, H. Crespo; GK: S. Goycochea, S. Romero, M. Andujar.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;BRAZIL I: D. Santos, C. Alberto, N. Santos, D. Da Guia, L. Pereira, Junior, M. Ramos, Zito, Clodoaldo, Didi, Gerson, Zizinho, Revelino, Dirceau, Garrincha, Jairzinho, Pele, Tostao, Ademir, Leonidas; GK: Gilmar, E. Leao, Barbosa.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;BRAZIL II: Jorginho, Cafu, D. Alves, Maicon, R. Carlos, Lucio, T. Silva, T. Cerezo, Dunga, Falcao, Socrates, Zico, Rivaldo, Kaka, Robinho, Ronaldinho, Neymar Jr., Bebeto, Romario, Ronaldo; GK: R. Ceni, C. Taffarel, J, Cesar.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ENGLAND I: J. Armfield, E. Hapgood, E. Hughes, N. Franklin, B. Moore, J. Charlton, R. Wilson, B. Wright, N. Stiles, D. Edwards, A. Ball, M. Peters, J. Haynes, B. Charlton, S, Matthews, T. Finney, K. Keegan, D. Dean, T. Lawton, J. Greaves; GK: R. Clemence, F. Swift, G. Banks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ENGLAND II: A. Cole, T. Adams, S. Campbell, D. Beckham, J. Terry, R. Ferdinand, P. Neal, B. Robson, D. Platt, P. Scholes, S. Gerrard, F. Lampard, G. Hoddle, P. Gascoigne, P. Beardsley, W. Rooney, A. Shearer, G. Lineker, M. Owen; GK: P. Shilton, D. Seaman, J. Hart.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FRANCE: M. Amoros, L. Thuram, B. Lizarazu, M. Desailly, M. Tresor, L. Blanc, D. Deschamps, P. Vieira, J. Tigana, P. Pogba, R. Kopa, M. Platini, Z. Zidane, F. Robery, R. Piantoni, E. Cantona, J. Fontaine, J. P. Papin, T. Henry; GK: F. Barthez, J. Bats, J. Darui.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GERMANY I: B. Vogts, M. Kaltz, K. H. Schnellinger, P. Breitner, P. Janes, W. Schultz, F. Beckenbauer, H. Syzmaniak, R. Bonhof, G. Netzer, W. Overath, F. Walter, F. Szepan, A. Kupfer, H. Rahn, H. Schafer, M. Morlock, H. Haller, U. Seeler, G. Muller; GK: B. Trautmann, S. Maier, J. Croy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GERMANY II: A. Brehme, P.Lahm, K. H. Forster, J. Kohler, M. Sammer, G. Buchwald, H. P. Briegel, S. Khedira, L. Matthaus, S. Effenberg, M. Ballack, B. Schweinsteiger, T. Kroos, T. Muller, R. Voller, M. Klose, J. Klinsmann, H. H. Rummenigge, O. Bierhoff, K. Allofs; GK: H. Schumacher, O. Kahn, M. Neuer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ITALY I: T. Burgnich, G. Facchetti, P. Rava, A. Foni, C. Gentile, V. Rosetta, G. Scirea, G. Antognoni, G. Ferrari, V. Mazzola, G. Rivera, S. Mazzola, G. Bulgarelli, R. Benetti, G. Meazza, G. Boniperti, S. Piola, L. Riva, R. Bettega, A. Baloncieri; GK: G. Combi, D. Zoff, E. Albertosi.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ITALY II: A. Cabrini, P. Maldini, C. Ferrara, F. Cannavaro, G. Bergomi, A. Nesta, F. Beresi, M. Tardelli, D. Albertini, G. Gattuso, D. De Rossi, C. Ancelotti, A. Pirlo, R. Mancini, B. Conti, R. Baggio, A. Del Piero, F. Totti, C. Vieri, P. Rossi; GK: G. Buffon, W. Zenga, G. Pagliuca.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;NETHERLANDS: W. Suurbier, R. Krol, F. DeBoer, J. Stam, R. Koeman, C. Van Der Hart, R. Israel, R. Gullit, F. Rijkaard, J. Neeskens, C. Seedorf, E. Davids, W. Van Hanegem, W. Sneijder, A. Robben, J. Cruyff, D. Bergkamp, R. Van Nistelrooy, M. Van Basten, R. Van Persie; GK: E. Van Der Sar, H. Van Breukelen, J. Van Beveren.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PORTUGAL: R. Carvalho, A. Correia, Hilario, Germano, H. Coelho, A. Cardoso, J. Pinto, P. Sousa, M.Coluna, R. Costa, Deco, J. Travacos, J. Garcia, Nani, J. Augusto, L. Figo, C. Ronaldo, J. Aguas, Eusebio, F. Peyroteo; GK: M. Bento, V. Baia, J. Azevedo.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SPAIN: J. Camacho, J. Quincoces, M. A. Nadal, F. Hierro, G. Pique, C. Puyol, S. Ramos, S. Busquets, C. Fabregas, P. Guardiola, X. Alonso, Xavi, A. Iniesta, D. Silva, E. Basora, F. Gento, Raul, T. Zarra, D. Villa, F. Torres; GK: R. Zamora, I. Casillas, D. De Gea.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;URUGUAY: V. R. Andrade, J. Nasazzi, S. Gambetta, Santamaria, D. Pereyra, P. Montero, A. Ancheta, J. L. Adndrade, O. Varela, P. Rocha, E. Francescoli, M. Andreolo, A. Ghiggia, A. Recoba, H. Scarone, J. Schiffino, D. Forlan, L. Suarez, P. Petrone, P. Bengoechea; GK: L. Mazurkiewicz, R. Maspoli, R. Rodriguez.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ASIA-AUSTRALIA-AFRICA: F. Terim, A. Ercan, K. Toure, M. Zitouni, R. El-Fanagili, H. Myung Bo, J. Marston, Y. Toure, J. Okocha, Y. Benayoun, T. Cahill, A. Pele, O. Kofi, R. Milla, D. Drogba, S. Eto'o, G. Weah, S. Keita, C. Bum-Kun; GK: T. N'Kono, B. Grobbelaar, M. Schwarzer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;BRITISH ISLES: D. McGrain, A. Hansen, J. Carey, D. Irwin, P. McGrath, B. McNeill, D. Mackay, G. Souness, R. Keane, D. Blanchflower, S. McIlroy, B. Bremner, J. Baxter, D. Law, K. Dalglish, G. Best, J. Charles, R. Giggs, G. Bales; GK: H. Gregg, P. Jennings, N. Southall.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EUROPE EAST: V. Bessonov, A. Demyanenko, A. Shesternev, M. Khurtsilava, G. Sarosi, G. Lorant, W. Zmuda, V. Voronin, J. Bozsik, K. Deyuna, N. Hidegkuti, G. Orth, F. Cherenkov, F. Bene, S. Kocsis, L. Kubala, F. Puskas, O. Blokhin, R. Lewandowski; GK: G. Grosics, L. Yashin, J. Tomaszewcki.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;NEW WORLD: C. Gamarra, E. Figueroa, H. Chumpitaz, A. Escobar, R. Marquez, I. Cordoba, A. Vidal, C. Valderrama, T. Cubillas, Romerito, J. Rodriguez, L. Alvarez, L. Donovan, A. Sanchez, L. Sanchez, A. Lalas, A. Erico, H. Sanchez, A. Spencer, R. Falcao; GK: J. L. Chilavert, R. Higuita, B. Friedel.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SCANDANAVIA: O. Bergmark, E. Nilsson, B. Nordqvist, F. Tarp, M. Olsen, N. Middleboe, R. Bratseth, N. Liedholm, M. Laudrup, B. Larsson, S. Lerby, A. Sigurvinsson, S. Andersson, G. Stromberg, K. Hamrin, B. Laudrup, C. A. Praest, J. Litmanen, G. Nordahl, Z. Ibrahimovic; GK: P. Schmeichel, R. Hellstrom, T. Ravelli.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EUROPE SOUTH: R. Jarni, M. Ivkovic, N. Vidic, G Popescu, V. Vasovic, B. Stankovic, B. Oblak, Z. Boban, L. Modric, N. Dobrin, G. Hagi, R. Prosinecki, D. Stojkovic, B. Zebec, D. Dzajic, H. Stoichkov, D. Sekularac, P. Mijatovic, D. Suker; GK: V. Beara, F. Glaser, M. Soskic.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EUROPE WEST: S. Minelli, E. Happel, J. Popluhar, V. Kompany, E. Gerets, S. Henchoz, L. Verbiest, E. Ocwirk, G. Hanappi, J. Mosopust, H. Prohaska, A. Panenka, E. Scifo, J. Ceulemans, P. Medved, E. Hazard, M. Sindelar, P. Van Himst, H. Krankl, P. Bican; GK: F. Planicka, M. Preud'homme, P. Cech.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2018" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5551" value="Sports: Football / Soccer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="160524" value="Soccer Blast Pro Soccer Game" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3806" value="Keith Avallone" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="2667" value="PLAAY" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>