<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="31904">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/0jBJyxt5dbzx7PmhKw9IKA__thumb/img/mq4SqNirc4YUxNqezHPEL744Bg0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic344240.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/0jBJyxt5dbzx7PmhKw9IKA__original/img/gMbSCfZmLXYo9oUDGtdf61emFd0=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic344240.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Jamboree" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Up to eight people can play as individuals. Eighteen people can play as partners. Each person (or partnership) is randomly assigned an occupation: manufacturer, planter, jeweler, broker, inventor, doctor, lawyer or publisher. Each player begins the game with a wad of cash. Each player will move one&amp;rsquo;s own playing piece along the game board&amp;rsquo;s track. Players move along the gameboard according to a pair special dice, which, together, yield a random number from, zero to six. Along the way, each player must buy all six sections of an assigned possession as a victory condition.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The gameboard is divided into six sections. No player may advance to the next section until all the players have completed the previous section:&amp;#10;Paths of Fortune - Each player moves along a separate path using only one die.  Players may pay and collect money from each other. Each player has a guide card, which says what to pay or collect and from whom as one advances along the path.&amp;#10;The Trading Area - Four trains, four planes, four ships and four buses are placed on random Purchase spaces in this area. Here players can buy transportation for use in the next section for price determined by a spinner or barter with other players.&amp;#10;Transportation Department - If a player owns the method of transportation on the space landed there is no penalty. If the player does not own the method of the transportation landed on that player must pay all the players who possess that vehicle. The penalty escalates with the number of vehicles of the designated type owned.&amp;#10;The Jamboree - Whenever two or more players land on the same space, all the players on that space spin the spinner and the player who gets the lowest number pays the penalty the space assigns.&amp;#10;&amp;lsquo;Round and &amp;lsquo;Round Circle - If a player has yet to own all six parts on the assigned possession, the player must buy the remaining parts at double the price spun on the spinner. Advancing in this section means paying other players because of their occupation or because one lacks the transportation mode the space asks for. Players continue in this section until rolling doubles.&amp;#10;The Pay Off - Players sell their possessions back to the bank for whatever space on which they land.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When all the players have reached the end of The Pay Off section, each type of vehicle is sold back to the bank for values as determined by the spinner. Bank loans are paid back at 50% interest. The player with the most money wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1936" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="9046" value="William Longyear" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="359" value="Selchow &amp; Righter" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="11" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>