<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="319785">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/MjLZbxZJ4BZYLh6_jvPURQ__thumb/img/OqDIpLPavHM74AKusELG9wCMnTY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5663453.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/MjLZbxZJ4BZYLh6_jvPURQ__original/img/Te9BDdd0x1IoHthVFPaImhbrcuc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5663453.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="BelloLudi: Strategy Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Welcome to the strategy game by BelloLudi! Nice that you have taken an interest in wargaming. These rules have been developed for people who have no previous experience in wargaming, yet like to play games. BelloLudi designed these rules especially for teambuilding purposes. During our sessions we received feedback that people liked our game, but it was initially too complicated. Now, we have a ruleset of eleven pages, no more than the game of RISK. From page thirteen on, we included some extra rules. You will not be needing them at first, but we can imagine that you would like some variations as your experience grows. Start with that page when you have some battles under your belt.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is designed as a multiplayer game but will work just as fine with only two players. The same goes for the number of miniatures involved. We have collected huge armies over the years but, as you are new to the game, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably do not. Do not fear! The army structure that is presented in this writing, can be easily adapted to the number of miniatures that you have available. Albeit that a large army look suitably impressive. Hopefully, playing the game will encourage you to create your own armies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This rules-set simulates battles in the period of 1700 to 1900, the age which historians call the long 19th century. Units were drawn up in line in order to maximise the effect of their weaponry. The musket, the type of gun that the troops were supplied with, was only accurate on short distances. During a volley all muskets were fired simultaneously at the same target. Off course, this required iron discipline of the men. Soldiers of that age were drilled to fight formed up into line formation and to march in columns. During the game, your troops will do likewise.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In an ideal scenario the enemy was pinned in place by fire of artillery, the threat of cavalry or the fire of infantry. Once the enemy was pinned, other units could deliver the coup de grace. Tactics were therefore based on teamwork. Not only within a brigade, but also between brigades, or even armies. Every unit would have its own specific task and if they executed their tasks in unison, success was often achieved. The aim is not to annihilate the enemy unit to the last man, but to inflict so much damage, indicated by chips, that morale is brought down and the unit will become shaken or will run away in panic and removed from the table top. By a clever combination of movement and shooting, dashing cavalry charges and carefully positioned artillery pieces, this can be achieved. The tactics are based on teamwork. Not only within a brigade, but also between brigades and as such, the whole army.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your role will be that of a brigadier in a nineteenth century army. Should more players be available, one of you will play the part of Commander-in Chief or general. Should any disagreement arise concerning the rules, we suggest you roll a dice. The one who rolls the highest number has it right, for now.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1051" value="Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2710" value="Post-Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2949" value="Measurement Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="130301" value="Peter van Dop" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="46616" value="BelloLudi" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>