<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="32151">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qV3CjiOHzo4zLbwUyvIH5g__thumb/img/C_wM7MMcy7TXGgJeoI3XXWEehDM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3749110.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/qV3CjiOHzo4zLbwUyvIH5g__original/img/HO9si215c7fhHJ6h0WgbQFf5HEE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3749110.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bold Adventure" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From back of box:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Three centuries ago, a man named John Bunyan wrote an adventure narrative called Pilgrims Progress that has captured the imagination Western Christendom like no other book since the Bible.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Rock Harbor Creations has now brought the dramatic highlights of that perennial bestseller vividly to life in an exciting new board game called Bold Adventure.  Like the book's hero, Christian, you leave the City of Destruction behind on your way to the Cross, and ultimately to the Celestial City.  Like him, you'll go slowly at first, using the lower numbers on the inner circle of the spinner (there are no dice).  But once you reach the Cross and leave your burden there, again like him, you'll find your pace increases, as you shift to the higher numbers on the outer circle of the spinner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Along the way, you'll meet Mr. Evangelist who'll warn you to avoid such perils as the Slough of Despond and Beelzebub's Castle, and beware the enticements of Vanity Fair.  Once you've made your way past Doubting Castle, and Giant Despair, you get a glimpse of your destination from the peak Delectable Mountain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Designed to appeal especially to youngsters, bold adventure is a fast playing game for two to six players, taking no more than 30 to 45 minutes per game, on the average.  It is also easy to play; all you have to do is the old enough to read instructions and follow the directions on the board.  And, it is fun to play: the game is designed so that the lead will change frequently, and no one will be left too far behind.  There are also some interesting lessons to be learned in route.  For instance, if someone else lands on your space, instead of him having to go back to the beginning (disease or sending you there), you, being a good pilgrim say, &amp;quot;Please go ahead of me,&amp;quot; and he moves one space in front of you.  Similarly, lest you get discouraged at how far ahead the others are, there are three squares along the way marked &amp;quot;The last shall be first&amp;quot; -- land on one of these, and you immediately move one space in front of the leader.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Nor are you necessarily the winner if you arrive at the last square first, for there is still the River of Death to cross.  There are two ways to attempt that, as indicated on the River of Death cards in two random piles.  Draw a card and see if you: ford the river and enter the Celestial City, or except the invitation of Captain Vain-hope, to avoid getting your feet wet, and let him ferry you across.  Alas, if you choose the latter, his boat capsizes and you are swept down the river and over the falls into Perilous Pool.  When you climb out, you'll find that you have a fair ways to go before you again attempt across the river.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first player to ford the river wins, but all pilgrims may enter the Celestial City if they embark on the bold adventure set before them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1982" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1115" value="Religious" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="9443" value="Everett Sahrbeck" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7511" value="Rock Harbor Creations" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="6.75" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.30036" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="8" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>