<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="329139">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/n0y-WlKT4kuz_bPHKIhjtA__thumb/img/lPud2suo_8CqzQcV7krhSsxanEg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6072046.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/n0y-WlKT4kuz_bPHKIhjtA__original/img/qFydJHdAYRljAqeodfIa35iRz1A=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6072046.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Scrolls of Maega" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Scrolls of Maega is a board game of tactical confrontation &amp;amp; strategic movement set in a dark fantasy universe. It's an asymmetric tactical RPG for 3 to 6 players, with a modular board. Players have limited actions to prepare &amp;amp; cast spells, manage their hand &amp;amp; resources, and survive the maze.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;LORE - SETTING:&amp;#10;Players are power-hungry sorcerers in search of a long lost divine scroll of power. They will need to foil their opponents and the dangers of the maze to find the key, retrieve the artefact and race back to the exit; knowing that anyone left behind could be waiting on their way back.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;OBJECTIVE:&amp;#10;Players will attempt to retrieve the Scroll at the end of the dungeon and make their way back out with it. However, they must first find the Relic (key) among the hidden items randomized on the Treasure tiles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;SETUP:&amp;#10;Players start by choosing their game mode: Battle Royale or Team battle (or Cooperative, coming in an expansion). The game is played in 4 phases of 3 turns each, for a maximum of 12 turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At first, players set the tiles to create the board, using a recommended or custom layout. Treasure tiles (items to collect) and Wall tiles (restricting movement/targeting) are safe to walk on, but most tiles bare Runes that will damage the players health &amp;amp; mana.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;They then select their characters, using the starting deck provided or customizing their strategy (for experienced players). Each begins with the same number: a free spell, 7 spells in-hand, 1 trap card in hand, and 1 trap card in their personal discard pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players then order their 4 Divination cards, each offering them cumulative bonuses during one of the game's 4 phases. And once the turn-order is decided (by drawing numbered tokens), the first player can enter the maze. The game begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAMEPLAY:&amp;#10;Players aim to find the Relic among the hidden items, going to each Treasure tile and getting stronger in the process. With the Relic in their possession (secretly or not), they can take the Scroll from the shrine. But any item can be stolen from other players, so escaping with it will be challenging.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players have 4 actions available per turn (moving up to 2-3 tiles, preparing a spell, casting any number of prepared spells, using an item, healing health or mana, etc.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mostly, players use their actions to prepare spells in advance (one action by level, up to 3); or to cast one or more spells they had prepared, so players will always need to anticipate their future needs. Spells are used to attack, move yourself or others, heal, or disable opponents. Only a disabled opponent can be looted.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Trap cards (Tenacity cards) can be used for free in reaction to a spell targeting them. Once used, it is removed from the game. Each player has two Tenacity cards (one in hand and one in the discard pile at the start of the game).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Except for your free spell, all used spells are then discarded. However, a tenacity track goes up with every health or mana lost or spent, allowing you to retrieve cards in your personal discard pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a player falls to 0 HP with mana remaining, it's not over just yet. Next turn, they'll be disabled and will need to exchange their mana for health. But more rarely, if a player falls to 0 HP &amp;amp; Mana, they'll die for good; winning is now out of reach, but as a vengeful spirit with limited actions, the player still has a role to play (either haunting its murderer or helping its team).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends as soon as a player gets back to the starting portal with the Scroll in hand. So, select your character, build your strategy around their unique playstyle, and rush to the scroll or wait to steal it. In the end, only one Maegan will get the Scroll.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="21" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="22" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="23" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="24" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="25" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1059" value="Maze" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2887" value="Catch the Leader" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2837" value="Interrupts" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2947" value="Movement Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="133266" value="Louis-Philippe Tremblay" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="47703" value="Reservoir Productions" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>