<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="330968">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vxLENCUw-V0cgcNkLUU8SQ__thumb/img/Y6LAMFSsW6tO0wbQcJMwsA94hos=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7062789.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vxLENCUw-V0cgcNkLUU8SQ__original/img/iHj2rqD3AMw29T8HeUPwq9X25mg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7062789.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Psychopath" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>PSYCHOPATH&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A Killer Card Game for 1 to 4 Campers and One Psycho!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Psychopath is a &amp;lsquo;One vs. Many&amp;rsquo; card game where one player acts as the Psychopath - a deranged killer attempting to hunt down and kill the Camper players using a variety of Actions and Items at his disposal. The Camper players try to survive the Psychopath&amp;rsquo;s attacks and hope for rescue using the Actions, Items, Allies and Skills available in their deck of cards. If the Psychopath manages to kill all the Campers, he wins the game! However, if at least one Camper survives or manages to become rescued, the Campers win! Psychopath can also be played as a Campaign, with both sides scoring points over a predetermined number of games.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Psychopath is presented with a campy B-Horror Movie flavor splashed with inane commentary and featuring over-the-top, and sometimes gruesome, imagery!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Play:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Psychopath is played in rounds. At the start of each round all players secretly select a card from their hand to be played as their starting card and place it face down on the table. When all players have done so, cards are then revealed to show the location each players is at: the Lake, the Cabin, the Shed, or the Woods. Campers unlucky enough to be at the same location as the Psychopath enter into a Struggle with him.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During this Struggle, the Psychopath and Campers take turns playing cards from their hand and using Keep in Play cards they have on the table they have previously put into play. Campers can play Allies, Skills, Items and Actions to bolster their defense, attempt to Escape or become Rescued, and to thwart the attacks made by the Psychopath. The Psychopath will play Items and Actions to cause Wounds to the Campers in order to weaken or kill them. After players in a Struggle have played all the cards they wish, Struggles are resolved with Campers losing cards from their hand of cards equal to the number of Wounds they suffered. If a Camper suffers more Wounds than the cards in their hand, they are killed! The Psychopath suffers his Wounds by discarding that number of cards from the top of his deck of cards. If, at the start of the next draw Phase, the Psychopath has no cards remaining in his deck, the surviving Campers escape and the game is over!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After all Struggles are resolved, if there are two or more Campers at the same location and they are not at the Psychopath's location, they may Collaborate by giving each other Items and Allies, and by strategizing (Campers cannot otherwise discuss strategy during the game). A new round then begins with the Campers each drawing a card from the Camper deck of cards and the Psychopath drawing cards from his deck to fill his hand of cards to its starting limit. Hand management is an important aspect of Psychopath; deciding when to play cards and when to save them in your hand for later use can mean the difference between Survival and Death!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Contents:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;126 Thick Game Cards (60 for the Psychopath, 66 for the Campers)&amp;#10;    1 Rulebook&amp;#10;    1 Nice Shiny Box including a 4-Way Plastic Divider for the cards with Extra Space to hold Upcoming  Expansions!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designers&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="17" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2857" value="Card Play Conflict Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2967" value="Hidden Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2820" value="Semi-Cooperative Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="10378" value="John J. Perry, Jr." />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8122" value="RealmsMasters Game Forge" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="8.16667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.43372" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>