<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="333157">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/DDOYjimP_V1_eA_-9onYgw__thumb/img/q-eBIXIygnlcKMsqPO1YbNxtoKg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6030028.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/DDOYjimP_V1_eA_-9onYgw__original/img/x024cWpmVInC_Zed0Dvir7s4guw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6030028.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fighting Class! Battle of Aircraft Carriers" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="格闘級！航空母艦の戦い" />
			
						               													<description>Fighting Class! Battle of Aircraft Carriers is a war game that reproduces &amp;quot;Aircraft Carrier Battles&amp;quot; by fleets centered on aircraft carriers that occurred in the Pacific War.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each unit is one warship or one aircraft squadron (nine aircrafts), however, the damage is in units of one aircraft. Bombs and torpedoes are also handled in units of one shot. 4 hours per turn (aircraft operation unit is 1 hour). In addition to the &amp;quot;Operation Maps&amp;quot; (90 nautical miles per hex) used for fleet movement and search, there is also the &amp;quot;Tactical Map&amp;quot; that is rare in Japanese aircraft carrier battle board wargames.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Operation Maps are prepared for each of the Japanese and Allied forces, and it is divided by &amp;quot;partition&amp;quot; so that the opponent's fleet is not known where it is (this is called &amp;quot;double blind system&amp;quot;). In order to search for this invisible enemy fleet, each aircraft squadron unit is flown from the aircraft carrier or base to search for enemies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At this time, there was a problem in the conventional aircraft carrier wargames that &amp;quot;if you tell the opponent where you are looking for, your whereabouts will be revealed&amp;quot;. Therefore, in order to avoid this problem, the &amp;quot;fan-shaped search&amp;quot; that was carried out in the actual carrier battle could not be done, and the players had to carry out a search pattern different from the actual one. However, in &amp;quot;Fighting Class! Battle of Aircraft Carriers&amp;quot;, you can search for enemies without exposing your whereabouts by using cards together. As a result, it has become possible to carry out search enemies based on the same thoughts as in actual aircraft carrier battles, such as &amp;quot;fan-shaped search&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In addition, a system that reproduces the &amp;quot;resources invested (in the case of aircraft carrier battles, the number of aircraft for searching and the time spent on searching) and the amount and accuracy of information that can be detected are proportional&amp;quot; as shown in the &amp;quot;search theory&amp;quot; has also been introduced into the search rules. Players are also required to have the skill to guess &amp;quot;which is the main force including the aircraft carrier&amp;quot; by combining the fragmentary information that can be obtained gradually.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On the Tactical Map, aircraft squadron units move hexes to attack warship units. At this time, the possibility of success depends on the direction in which the warship unit is attacked (whether it is from the front, the rear, the diagonal front, or the diagonal rear). Therefore, the attacking team will charge the tactical map toward the warship unit aiming at the &amp;quot;deadly shooting point (attacking direction)&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On the other hand, the warship unit not only shoots down attacking aircraft with anti-aircraft fire, but also incorporates &amp;quot;turning&amp;quot; (a movement that changes the course of the ship), which has not been taken up in previous aircraft carrier battle games, into the rules. This allows the warship unit to turn around from the &amp;quot;deadly firing point&amp;quot; that the attacking team is aiming for and avoid the attack. In this way, the Allied Forces shoot down the attacking team with &amp;quot;powerful anti-aircraft fire&amp;quot;, while the Imperial Japanese Navy dodges the enemy's attacks by turning with &amp;quot;skillful ship maneuvering&amp;quot;. It is now possible to reproduce different ways of fighting, similar to the actual aircraft carrier battles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="360" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="360" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2965" value="Multiple Maps" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="109627" value="Kazuya Nagahama" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="39400" value="Jibsail Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>