<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="333525">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/fdHzOPelBbZJBp_HIkxG0w__thumb/img/ku-tT9e5aZBVCBW6hluTS7Ay3KM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6102312.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/fdHzOPelBbZJBp_HIkxG0w__original/img/J7_JmL87D0ttF09IEUgH4qhj23M=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6102312.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Project HUNTER" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>They came from space. From within meteors they broke out and caused devastation. With corporations and security companies concerned only with the elites, the people pleads for world government action. The president of the world is then forced to finance mercenary giant robot pilots, paying for each head of the giant monsters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Project HUNTER is a minimalist solo print-n-play roll-n-write game in which you drive a giant robot in order to defeat the giant monsters that have invaded the earth. You will need to print these sheets and get some dice, pencils and eraser.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Objective&amp;#10;The main objective of this game is to defeat at least one monster of each of the six species. However, you must survive until then! Your giant robot is destroyed if its chassis is completely damaged or if it overheats, which will cause an explosion. You also lose if you run out of money after a hunt.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Hunting Kaijus&amp;#10;To face a monster you first roll three dice. Each die will indicate a monster avaliable. Of these three you will have to choose one to face. If you don't want to face any, you will have to spend $ 50 on the maintenance of your robot to be able to wait another day. So you can roll the three dice again. You start the game with $ 300 in cash (write it down).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combat&amp;#10;As soon as you choose a monster to face the combat starts. The combat is separeted between the turn of the monster and the turn of the robot. The monster always starts first.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Monster Turn&amp;#10;On the Monster turn you must roll a number of dice equal to the Monster Attack value. Each die is treated individually and allocated somewhere in the robot sheet. Each die that landed at number 6 causes 1 Overheat. Each result less than 6 can be absorbed in some armor of the robot. See in the diagram of the robot that there are squares for you to write down the result of the die you want to allocate there. You can place it wherever you want as long as there are already any other results linked to it, it must obey the rule (see below). If you cannot allocate any die in the sheet this die becomes 1 damage in the Chassis.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Armor&amp;rsquo;s Rules&amp;#10;In the diagram of the robot you will find several blank boxes to record the result of a die. Each of these boxes has an arrow. If the arrow is facing the box, it means that it has some rule. Each symbol on the black circle will indicate he rule.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Robot Turn&amp;#10;On the Robot's turn you will be able to choose if you want to attack normal with your weapons or if you want to overload the shots. If you choose to attack normal, roll the dice equal to the number of weapons you have (initially you only have one weapon). Add up all the results of all the dice and write down the amount of damage the monster has taken. If the monster loses all hit points, it is defeated (see below).&amp;#10;If you choose to do an overloaded attack, you will roll twice the attack dice but will cause 1 point of Overheating.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2870" value="Re-rolling and Locking" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="57124" value="Tiago Junges" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="57124" value="Tiago Junges" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="21435" value="Coisinha Verde Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>