<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="333508">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/h2rPDyc2w1dNDSa6HT6VGQ__thumb/img/MhtnrwZYrWh5lVNuUOli0zD2uJY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6052879.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/h2rPDyc2w1dNDSa6HT6VGQ__original/img/CobnE7EP3JKrRBcR8mP5V2LXz3g=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6052879.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="American Catur" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>American Catur is a new ground-breaking warfare strategy game. The game is well balanced between skill and luck making it very competitive. Playing Time 30 - 120 Mins Recommended Age 5 and Up. Number of players required is 2 players one on one, 3players two against one or 4 players, two teams of two players in which you can communicate with your partner during your turn. In American Catur your partner and you will be taking on the roles of the government leaders (WE THE PEOPLE) who has been empowered by the Constitution to go to war, when you hear the word &amp;lsquo;strategy&amp;rsquo; you can picture your partner and you strategizing as the generals of the armed forces with your President in a war room looking sternly at the earth board, preparing your next best step for combat. Deciding where to engage the enemy and what maneuver are going to make sense to help achieve this goal. It will be your team strategy- to win by controlling all of the Armed Force troop&amp;rsquo;s (Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine, Coast Guard) in a battle to force the opponent&amp;rsquo;s President in a position of no escape, or to capture him or to eliminate him.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is your tactics to consider all the factors involved and apply this knowledge of the troops strength and your team determination to make decisions that would result in controlling the center of the earth board. Each team of two begins with a total of one President and 29 troops that each player on a team shares by alternating turns. One player controls the black triangle space to travel on with their piece and the other partner controls the white triangle spaces to travel on. The other option to play is by alternating turns one player controls the area in front of them and then the other player controls the area in front of them. The line that divides the area is between the army and President. You will be alternating turns taking one action at a time over the course of setting up your strategic plans of controlling the earth board. You need to evaluate your earth board during each move. It will help you keep tracked of all projectile chips used and all troops&amp;rsquo; movements.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This earth board is your map where you need to go, and what you have to conquer. And around the perimeter of the earth board, you have two rows to have the ability to launch your offensive or defensive attack with projectile chips by rolling the dice to capture, eliminate pieces or use the chips as an obstacle for your opponent&amp;rsquo;s pieces to go around. Beware that sometimes a roll of a launch can become a misfire that captures or eliminates your own pieces. The winner is the one who forces the President in a position of no escape(DEFCON1), or eliminates him with a projectile chip. There is one more major part of the game if the President is in checkmate or stalemate, we go into DEFCON 1 in which all unused projectile chips are launched alternating turns to see how the game unfolds.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Both sides White/Black are equipped with four types of projectile chips; 16 poison gas that captures one-piece that travels on the triangle space, 8 biological gas that can with one strike captures up to two-pieces that travels on the square space and 16 atomic nukes that eliminates one-piece that travels on the triangle space, 8 hydrogen nukes that can with one strike eliminate up to two-pieces that travels on the square space. If you can&amp;rsquo;t determine a winner after exhausting all the launching of the projectile chips at the end of the game the President that is in checkmate loses, if it is a stalemate then count the total points of just captured (POW)pieces to find out the winner of the game. Do Not count the pieces that were eliminated or on the board. There are no draws. Who do you control!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;www.americancatur.com&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Eric Jude Egypt Curtis&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="140" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="140" />
						               				<minage value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="136" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="137" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="138" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="139" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="140" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1050" value="Ancient" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2978" value="Grid Coverage" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2940" value="Square Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="4024" value="Traditional Games: Chess" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="5.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="4.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="3" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>