<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="336683">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Kit" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Kit is an easy to learn game and fun for the avid card player or if you're a beginner. Rummy style game where you make kits or runs, make the right combinations, and be the first to go out - then watch your opponents scramble to cut their losses. The goal of the game is to be the player with the lowest score at the end of the 10th round by making your entire hand into kits and/or runs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game consists of two 44-card decks. Each deck has four WILD cards and four colors: Blue, Gold, Green, and Purple. Each color has ten cards, 3 through 12. Wild cards can be considered any number or color that you wish. There are also rotating wild cards that change every round. The rotating wild cards depend on the number of cards dealt that round. When 3 cards are dealt, the 3&amp;rsquo;s are wild, when 4 cards are dealt the 4&amp;rsquo;s are wild and so on until the last round when the 12&amp;rsquo;s are wild.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A kit is three or more cards of the same number and can be any color. You can have as many wild cards in a kit as you want. A run is three or more consecutive cards of the same color. A wild card can replace any card in a run. You can have as many wild cards in a run as you want and they can be adjacent to one another.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dealing: &amp;#10;1. Shuffle both decks of cards together. &amp;#10;2. For the first round deal 3 cards to each player, dealing one card at a time. Note: For each round of play, the number of cards dealt increases by one card. In the second round 4 cards are dealt, in the third round 5 cards are dealt, and so on until dealing 12 cards to each player in the final round. The dealer position rotates after each round. &amp;#10;3. Place the remaining cards in the center of the table and turn over the top card. The stack of cards is the draw pile and the card turned up is the start of the discard pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing: &amp;#10;1. The player to the left of the dealer goes first and play continues clockwise. &amp;#10;2. Start your turn by taking the top card on the discard pile or drawing a card. &amp;#10;3. Complete your turn by discarding one card. &amp;#10;4. Continue to make kits and/or runs until you are able to go out. &amp;#10;5. Going out: Once all of the cards in your hand are part of a kit or run, lay down all of your cards face up on the table before discarding your last card. &amp;#10;Note: you must be able to make kits and runs from the exact number of cards dealt in the round. You must have one card left to discard. You can go out on your very first turn. &amp;#10;6. Once a player has gone out, all other players have one final turn. Start your turn as normal and after discarding, lay down your kits and runs. Any cards that do not fit in a kit or run will count toward your score. &amp;#10;7. The cards that are in kits and runs do not count toward your score. Players add up only their unused cards. The card values are equal to the number on the card and Wild cards are worth 20 points. The player that goes out first gets a score of -5. The scorekeeper records and adds up the score for each player. &amp;#10;8. The player to the dealer&amp;rsquo;s left shuffles all of the cards and deals the next round. &amp;#10;Note: Increase the number of cards dealt by one card and keep track of the rotating Wild cards&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="56" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="57" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="58" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="59" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="60" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="135659" value="Jared Townsend" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>