<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="337973">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xCmt1RBxVrNpegyqocmDgA__thumb/img/3pCzNDOLKciVwyS9U3BQglPn4fY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6170562.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/xCmt1RBxVrNpegyqocmDgA__original/img/9gZxZRiXeFe9TJv9cnZeHeUYwoQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6170562.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Earth Under Siege: Flashpoint" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Earth Under Siege: Flashpoint is a 1-4 player, co-op, sci-fi dungeon crawler where players complete covert missions against an invading alien force bent on subjugation of the entire Earth.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setting:&amp;#10;The world is in chaos. Alien enemies are assaulting military bases all over the globe, obliterating any resistance before them. They attack indiscriminately and they show no mercy. They call themselves the Xethan, but where they come from is a complete mystery. They were simply not here one moment and initiating global conquest the next. If they came from space, there are no signs of it. None of the expected indicators of aliens traversing the stars, such as starships in orbit, have been observed. Indeed, the Xethan seem to possess no vehicles in their assaults at all. Instead, they rely on short range portal technology far beyond anything we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, which allows them to teleport short distances bypassing many of our defenses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But the situation is much worse than just that. These Xethan are being aided by an insurgent faction of human terrorists that call themselves the Vormacht who seem to be working with these alien invaders and betraying their own species.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It has only been six months since the Xethan first appeared and they have already conquered large numbers of military bases all across Europe. If their momentum is not halted, the human race may well fall to these alien invaders. Someone must stop them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;We are that someone. Now is the time. While the world is still reeling from this unexpected assault, we have not been idle. We have come together, as a species, in recognition of this greater threat to our existence. We are no longer just splintered factions of rival groups; no longer separated by our differences. Humankind has never stood so together, united, arm in arm, moving together towards this one mission. We have become AEGIS, an allied force drawn from countries all over the Earth to stand against this threat. No longer will we stay on the defensive. Now is the time we stand up and show these Xethan that humankind will not fall so easily. Now, at this flashpoint in history, we fight back.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay:&amp;#10;Earth Under Siege: Flashpoint missions are heavily focused on stealth, covert actions, and sabotage. Players are Operatives of AEGIS, and their missions are focused on infiltrating enemy facilities, using every method available, such as cutting the power, using the ventilation shafts, making use of silenced weapons, and hacking into the enemy database.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players develop their Operatives and HQ over the course of a 30+ mission campaign as they follow the story deeper and deeper until they uncover the true nature of the Enemy and where they came from.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each round, players perform actions with their Operatives by exhausting one of their six action tokens until they run out of available tokens, or choose to pass. But players must be judicious in their use of their action tokens, because they normally only recover three of them each Refresh Phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each Operative comes with a unique deck of Tactics cards which gives them access to powerful actions and effects. Each Player will develop these decks over the course of the campaign allowing them to tailor their gameplay to a particular style or focusing on specific combos.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="4">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="3" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="11" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="12" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="13" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="14" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="15" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="48877" value="Components: Game Trayz Inside" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="70948" value="Digital Implementations: Tabletopia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="98440" value="Steve Kozlowski" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="140018" value="Todd Ulrich" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="48723" value="Dark Horizon Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="14" />
			<average value="8.82143" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.27625" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="20" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="17" />
			<wishing value="124" />
			<numcomments value="24" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="3.75" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>