<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="33823">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/scziutTlSCe87YWsO1-sUQ__thumb/img/0kdG0zalvjHOxLgfe7nmq_AwaEQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic564082.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/scziutTlSCe87YWsO1-sUQ__original/img/y5k_EVyVPkvcYse0hdDN1ev4Gt4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic564082.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Inside the Crease Hockey" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the publisher's website:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Inside the Crease (ITC) hockey is a tabletop simulation of the fast-paced game of pro hockey.  In keeping with the pace of the sport of hockey this game uses double-sided Fast Action Cards (FAC) to move the game right along.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From the first face off players will perform on the ice like no other simulation out there.  Skater&amp;rsquo;s cards are broken down with four separate offensive columns based on whether your team is at even strength, in the power play, shorthanded or the column for rebounds and great feed passes.  These cards don&amp;rsquo;t just tell you whether a player takes a shot but the quality of the shot as well.  Some guys will be shooting at the twine with quality shots most of the time while others will just be putting the puck towards the net.  The slick-passing skaters are not left out here as a good play maker on the ice can set up much higher shooting opportunities.   Players are also rated on the frequency of giving away the puck.  In ITC a bone-headed pass that loses the puck isn&amp;rsquo;t just a turnover it can be a chance for a breakaway for the opposition.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Defense is covered equally in depth with four separate defensive ratings to set players apart.  The ability to takeaway the puck, block shots, check players off the puck and a general defensive ability all can force the action of the offense.  You will be able to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; a great defensive play stop a would be shot.  Blocking a shot or forcing a shot wide with a defensive stop can be a goal saver.  Controlling loose pucks can be a real game turner in ITC with this ability captured in the ratings as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;No hockey game would be complete without the ability to capture the penalty aspect.  In ITC the players are not just rated for penalty frequency but the type as well.  Whether it be a minor, major or misconduct you will know when it happens.  If a fight breaks out you will watch the two combatants head to the box.  When a minor is called you will get an actual penalty name (elbowing, holding, etc) for added flavor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The goalies are created with the ability to stop shots in the six different shooting categories.  You will be crushed to watch a weak slapshot trickle through for a goal but be ecstatic watching your goalie thwart an excellent scoring opportunity.  In ITC the  ability of the goalie to control the action after a shot is also taken into consideration.  You will see your goalie simply give up a rebound shot, hold the puck or be able to pass it off to a teammate.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If strategy is your game ITC delivers with a simple and unobtrusive way to handle your coaching choices.  If you push more forecheckers up the ice for better scoring chances you are leaving yourself open on the back end.  It is your choice how to play it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2007" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5628" value="Sports: Ice Hockey" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="4016" value="Chris Davis" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7352" value="Inside Sports Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="23" />
			<average value="7.52174" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.43313" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="48" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="4" />
			<wishing value="8" />
			<numcomments value="9" />
			<numweights value="5" />
			<averageweight value="3.2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>