<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="340913">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6eqq9AJKdE-4is5gydo9Yg__thumb/img/cY8GbrcayLDxD_jK4nOkOkfTpfQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6235043.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6eqq9AJKdE-4is5gydo9Yg__original/img/lSYF_WL62hJTYPHKLEVZJbYN52k=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6235043.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Shadow Kingdoms of Valeria: Kickstarter Edition" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Every Kickstarter copy of Shadow Kingdoms of Valeria will include Rise of Titans - 4 Advanced Expansion Modules packaged inside the base game's box. They publisher will sell these modules on their website but these modules will not be available in the retail edition.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Module #1: Shrine of the Titans&amp;#10;This is a 6th Shrine that occupies the cavern at the center of the game board. After each battle, you will place your highest value Troop die into the Shrine of the Titans. &amp;#10;The Shrine can hold a number of Troop dice equal to the number of players. On your turn, you can move your Warden token to the Shrine of the Titans and buy up to 3 dice...if you have enough Gold. This module also includes 5 additional Troop dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Module #2: Great Battles&amp;#10;This is a set of 10 oversized Battle Plan cards in which all the players can participate. 2 Great Battle cards are always available throughout the game and each time you complete a regular Battle Plan, you check your dice to see if any of them match the Troop Types noted on the Great Battle cards. If there's a match, you add the lowest strength matching die to one of the Great Battle cards along with one of your Participation Markers. You immediately gain the reward on the Troop Position chosen.  &amp;#10;When all 5 Troop positions are filled on a Great Battle, the card is resolved and each Participation marker on that card earns you a share of the Victory Points for that Great Battle. This module also includes 20 Participation Markers and 5 additional Troop dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Module #3: Ancient Spells&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is a set of 28 cards (44x68mm) with 2 of 6 unique and powerful actions spread throughout the cards in every possible combination. During setup, shuffle the cards and give 3 to each player. &amp;#10;At any time during your turn, you may play an Ancient Spell card from your hand to perform one of the two available powers. It's important to note that playing an Ancient Spell card is a free action along with your regular action. These spells are meant to augment and boost specific actions, dice, etc.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Module #4: Wraith Dice&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is a set of 5 purple custom dice (16mm - same size as the other dice in the game). During setup, just toss the 5 Wraith Dice into the bag along with the usual dice needed for your number of players. Each die has Strength of 1, 1, 2, 2, 3, and 3, (opposite sides always add up to 4) so they are weaker than the regular Troop dice, but this also means that they're more likely to give you better Discounts if you draft them at the Tactics and Champions Shines, and more likely to pay out more gold if you draft them from Gold Shrine. &amp;#10;Wraith dice are considered WILD when completing any Battle Plan. So, even though they're weak, they can be any Troop Type you need. Wraith dice are also wild if you put them on a Great Battle card (Module #2). When you draft a Wraith die, it DOES NOT take up a Troop slot on your Player Board! You just set it somewhere on your Camp and use it when you need it most. The flexibility of these new dice will add lots of new play options to your game of Shadow Kingdoms of Valeria.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;About the base game:&amp;#10;For years the humans, elves, and dwarves have been slowly encroaching on your territories and slaying your kind in the name of progress. They've built their citadels, keeps, and villages as they push you further into the darkness. Now is the time to rally your troops and lay waste to their kind and bring forth the reign of the Shadow Kingdoms!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You are a Warden hungry for the destruction of Valeria. You must outwit the other Wardens to earn the right to command an army for the Shadow Kingdoms. Visit dark Shrines to gain minions, magic, gems, and gold to fuel your war machine. Command monsters into battle to conquer the lands and earn Victory Points. The player with the most Victory Points at the end of the game will be declared the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On your turn, you must move your Warden from its current location to a new location. When your Warden enters one of the 5 Shrines, you first take any available die from the Shrine and place it on your player board, then perform the Shrine action associated with the Shrine.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are 5 troop types (die colors) in the game: Goblin (green), Orc (red), Skeleton (white), Gargoyle (purple), and Gnoll (brown). Send your Warden to the Camp on your player board to use your minion dice to resolve battle plans and place Victory tokens on your Campaign board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="75" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="75" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2082" value="Worker Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="41251" value="Setting: Valeria" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="285036" value="Shadow Kingdoms of Valeria" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecompilation" id="337461" value="Shadow Kingdoms of Valeria: Rise of Titans" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="98387" value="Stan Kordonskiy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="70533" value="Mihajlo Dimitrievski" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="28790" value="Daily Magic Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="27" />
			<average value="7.71852" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.11423" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="113" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="4" />
			<wishing value="9" />
			<numcomments value="9" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>