<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="346250">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="PMC 2670" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>PMC 2670 is hard sci-fi platoon-sized ruleset intended for 15mm and it's second edition of PMC 2640 released in 2013.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Introduction&amp;#10;In 2013, we have boldly released PMC 2640, which successfully found its place on crowded 15mm sci-fi wargames market. Now, it's high time to leap forward! In the last 3 years, we have worked hard on PMC 2670, which is much more than just a new edition of the game! As you can probably guess, the action takes place 30 years later in the same dirty, gloomy PMC-verse &amp;ndash; but it's also indirectly connected to Shadows in the Void, which takes place much later in the same timeline. The story was moved forward: humanity developed new technologies and improved older ones, encountered an alien threat (or rather the aliens encountered a human threat...) and made the galaxy an even more turbulent place.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;So, what are the gameplay changes?&amp;#10;There is no revolution in the core mechanics, as better is often the enemy of good... Still, the basic rules were polished and perfected, making the game even faster, more flexible and more uncompromising &amp;ndash; but it's still the old, fine PMC! Special rules were revisited and all known question-causing or unclear elements were re-edited. But the main advantage of the 2670 edition are the added extras! Now you can lead not only merc forces, but also space bugs and rebels, which became fully playable factions. What is more, there is a fourth faction &amp;ndash; the aforementioned aliens! Forces of your PMCs were bolstered with lots of additional unit entries, offering many new tactics and army compositions. We listened to the players and added a lot of elements they asked for (e.g. power armours, medics, drop pods, and many exotic sci-fi troops). Existing units were carefully examined and rebalanced to adjust them to the new lists. But don't worry, if you already have a collection of minis for PMC 2640, it will be fully playable in PMC 2670 &amp;ndash; you'll simply get even more possibilities! We see no point in making existing armies useless or weaker &amp;ndash; we're players ourselves and know how irritating this can be! In addition to new armies and PMC units, we have updated the scenarios based on the experience from previous years &amp;ndash; but no major changes in this chapter.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Anything else?&amp;#10;Of course! All factions received their own campaign rules, allowing for even more interesting club gaming! Campaign is as important, as it was aspect of the ruleset. Whether you wish to create your own PMC, start a revolt, make bugs the dominant species on the planet or conquer new territories for your Xenotripod tribe, you will have the means to do it. Campaigns became even more challenging thanks to improvements such as quicker progress at the beginning and reduced snowball effect.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;...and?&amp;#10;The whole solitaire/coop section was redone. Thanks to universal scenarios you can use any force against any other force on any tier. Additionally, the Special Commando composition allows you to start playing with just a few finished minis &amp;ndash; perfect for people who like to collect different armies without expanding them too much.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="300" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="300" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2822" value="Scenario / Mission / Campaign Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="25158" value="Components: Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8164" value="Players: Wargames with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="143761" value="PMC 2640" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="12479" value="Marcin Gerkowicz" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="18524" value="Assault Publishing" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>