<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="347301">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_MO5FSiOEC7C2-kWlvadpQ__thumb/img/4SljwAP3Py7et2WldNhqkLr6tP4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6400000.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_MO5FSiOEC7C2-kWlvadpQ__original/img/FHNPHvPZ2v_-bCOb0yGGq_IB0Cs=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6400000.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="City Break" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In British English, a city break is a short holiday spent in a city. City breaks are perfect for anyone looking to relax and get away from it all for a few days, as well as seeking out authentic experiences. City Break is about your memories that you are proud of and like to tell people about, and the roles you adopt when you talk about your past travels!&amp;#10;You come back from your city breaks very enthusiastic and ready to share them with others. Your memories turn into posts on social media or face-to-face narrations about what you have observed, encountered, or undergone. You have to announce your adventures to the world! And you don't usually tell trivial stories!&amp;#10;Who are you when you boast about where you went and what you did or saw? When you talk passionately about the arts, you turn into a Culture Creature. You are also the Royalty Buff who devours biographies of kings and queens and enjoys visiting their castles and palaces. There is an inner Happy Foodie inside you who loves mentioning unique and memorable food and drink experiences. Your social media profiles reveal a Nature Lover who marvels at the mysteries of nature and appreciates natural beauty. Only a Sights Seeker would plan ahead for trips to the world's busiest sights and landmarks. Your followers can't wait to watch live the Motion Addict who loves public transport, the best way to connect to the city.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;City Break is a one-of-a-kind puzzle-solving board game specifically designed for a pair of gamers. What makes City Break truly awesome is that it manages to achieve an incredible strategic depth in a two-player setting. City Break is about adapting to new information, making the right choices at the right time, and solving the puzzle of the combinations of available digit-tiles, cards, and action tokens. The game gets more and more intense with each played card, while you have to keep an eye on your opponent's playing space so as not to be surprised by suddenly ending the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players use cards to fill six columns with memories, creating narratives about their past travels. They need to make sure that their narratives are credible, so they must bring them into a state of equilibrium or harmony. The credibility of a narrative is determined by its 3 sub-columns of values. Equilibrium is when a part of your narrative is in balance with the other two parts taken together (for example, B = A + C). Harmony is when two parts of your narrative balance each other out (for example, B = C).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You pursue a diversity of interests when you travel, and you develop new personas when you talk about where you went and what you did or saw. Each of the 6 outlined columns of cards of your tableau corresponds to a + or = represented at the bottom of the 90 personas. Each persona has a combination of 2 + and/or = indicating the 2 narratives you need to be credible. + symbols indicate which narratives you need to bring into equilibrium. = symbols indicate which narratives you need to bring into harmony.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of your turn, if all 6 of your outlined columns of cards either have complete narratives placed on them or are disabled, your opponent gets one final turn. The game then ends and players calculate their final scores.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your goal is to score the most Victory Points by assembling long credible narratives, developing personas, achieving target values, matching images, and earning titles. Are you quick-witted enough to deal with changing conditions, elements of randomness, and unpredictable opponents? Find out in City Break!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="36" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="37" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="38" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="39" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="40" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1104" value="Math" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1028" value="Puzzle" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1097" value="Travel" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3001" value="Layering" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3007" value="Matching" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="140521" value="George Alexandru Dragoi" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="140521" value="George Alexandru Dragoi" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="49901" value="George Alexandru Dragoi" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="1" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>