<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="347437">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/u4NtOgnFhqJrDhKVG7yziQ__thumb/img/DxjucGntk8Lk3lziGYvUOh5gWIE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6403764.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/u4NtOgnFhqJrDhKVG7yziQ__original/img/-QQNYVvZhZcnyVDQ-3rwBJzdkdQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6403764.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Evil In The North" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Evil In The North is a solitaire adventure game that is set in a dark wintry realm. The player oversees several game characters as they fulfill missions in this challenging environment. These characters represent a declining pagan population that is caught between the New Religion and the spiteful counter religion known as the Growing Evil. This latter division includes ruffians, malicious necromancers, the infamous NecroFiend occultists, and demons from foul depths.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Player guided characters will travel on a map that consists of card tiles. These tiles require various checks as the characters move from turn to turn. At the same time, game controlled characters known as NecroFiends will be spawned; eventually traveling the tile map through an automated movement system. When player characters run into a NecroFiend, conflict is likely to occur. Opposition can also emerge through the Occurrence deck (from entering a tile) or through the Demon deck (upon exiting a tile). These encounters gnaw away at a character's vital resource --their followers. A lack of followers makes a character extremely vulnerable and will often lead to elimination from the game if more followers cannot be acquired soon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combat in the world of Evil in the North is resolved through two means, Brute Conflict and DarkArts Conflict. The former combat type is associated with physical conflict and uses a Combat Results Table involving up to three 4-sided dice. The latter combat type is associated with sorcery and uses a simpler system involving the combatants' INSIGHT ratings and a single 4-sided die.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is divided into 3 stages to represent the different missions to be undertaken. To win Evil in the North, a player must fulfill every mission started. The game is lost if all player characters perish during the performance of a mission, regardless of how many missions have been completed. Without losing, you may end a game after any mission (but before another has begun).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ABOUT THE REIMPLEMENTATION:&amp;#10;This game builds on Black Metal by offering a whole new map treatment. Rather than building the tile map as you play, Evil in the North uses a preset tile map that is arranged prior to play. The preset tile map constrains player movement to a 7 x 7 grid (removing the chances of a run-away tile map). Furthermore, additional map tiles have been added to create the vast Ice Sea; a central area of the tile map consisting of 9 map tiles. Additional rules have been created to serve this new aspect of the tile map.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unlike Black Metal, a regular game of Evil In The North is played with full map disclosure (all map tiles are displayed face-up from the onset).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Other changes/additions include:&amp;#10;--Updated text on many cards (mainly to accommodate the new tile map)&amp;#10;--An updated and consolidated rulebook (integrating the Mission booklet)&amp;#10;--New and updated rulebook diagrams&amp;#10;--New rules and sections within the rulebook (including a new Q&amp;amp;A and Card Clarifications section)&amp;#10;--An official variant sheet for an advanced game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="16" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="73039" value="Category: Print-on-Demand" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="213964" value="Black Metal" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="67939" value="Eric Vannoy" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51139" value="Eric Vannoy Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>