<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="347421">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/EjbZ3V_N_FR9Gaugm0PLRA__thumb/img/ACOm1uEYfyN3D843Wv5nPpk2arc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6569829.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/EjbZ3V_N_FR9Gaugm0PLRA__original/img/WbOse5Z7UIyBYfs8yhbBKkCKFlU=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic6569829.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="Las Abejas: Flores Color Miel" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The bees will show us their unprecedented wisdom and a cooperative social organization designed around the production of honey and above all, as a daily task that is incumbent on all the beings of this planet, to maintain the ecological balance through this activity so important as is pollination.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Build your games by gathering prayers and honey. Ask your opponents if they have that card you are looking for or fly to the garden to find it. The bee that forms the most groups of ores and honey wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It includes 2 game modes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;iexcl;Vol&amp;aacute;!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Distribute to each player 7 cards for a 2 player game, or 5 cards for a 3 or 4 player game. The remaining cards are spread face down on the table, forming a garden shared by all players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to build sets of 3 cards of the same type (ores or honey) and number to play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first player takes a card from the garden and adds it to his hand. Then they must ask any player for a number and type of card, seeking to build a set of 4 with the ones he already owns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now, the player who was asked has two options:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     If he possesses one or more of that number and type, he must give it to him.&amp;#10;     If he does not have any cards of the type sought, he must answer: Fly!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The requesting player will then remove a card from the garden.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     If the card obtained from the garden matches the one you requested earlier, you must show it to the rest of the players and you can continue asking the others.&amp;#10;     If it does not match, it will be the turn of the player to his right.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When a player gathers 3 cards of the same type and number, he will place them face up to one side. The game ends with the first player who manages to play all their cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player who has managed to form the most groups wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Color Miel&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Immerse yourself in the universe of bees, where order and work are the fundamental tools to achieve the best and richest honey. Among flowers and beehives, you must be attentive to the numbers and colors to build your game. Use the speed and agility of the bees to lower all your cards and thus win the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Deal 14 cards to each player. The first player  takes a card from the deck and adds it to the ones he has.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;They can now:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     If they have the Queen, you must lower her immediately and place her in the middle. Take another card from the pot.&amp;#10;     If the Queen is not lowered, you cannot go down beehive games or honey ladder, but you can go down a bouquet or flower ladder.&amp;#10;    If you can't do any of the above, you must pass.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The next player on the right follows, always taking a card from the pot and placing it next to their cards. On their turn, the player is entitled to perform any of the actions above or:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Add a letter or more to a ladder, or complete a bouquet or beehive on the table.&amp;#10;     Draw a card from a game for another player that does not make it lose its status as a bouquet, hive or ladder, and use the drawn card to open a new game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when one of the players closes by lowering all his cards. The other players must add up the value of the cards they have in their hand. Four games make up the game. The player with the fewest points will be the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="7564" value="Animals: Bees" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="140575" value="Sofía Novaira" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="140577" value="Juana Rondina" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="49912" value="Descartes" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="7" />
			<average value="4" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.69031" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>