<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="350784">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/oQe4c7N8oCBPorQkZOPtlA__thumb/img/SR3gKc6latUCX0BJnqxDPoWrIAo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6520074.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/oQe4c7N8oCBPorQkZOPtlA__original/img/j4MwaVfRGUifwhP2cL2QbBC4fyI=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6520074.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ski Jumping" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In this game emotions, tension, but also joy and well-being await you, just as you like it during real races. In the game you will start training the physical and mental qualities of your jumper. You will manage its energy, which will be important in racing. Of course, you will jump from a ski jumping hill with a realistic-looking jumper figure. &amp;#10;As in real jumps, you will solve not only the length of the jump, but also the style and point evaluation of the judges. Your jumps will also be affected by the wind and also the equipment in which you will jump. &amp;#10;The aim of the game is to place as best as possible in the individual races of the cup tour and become its overall winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning, each player slides the jumper's figure from the hill, and based on the distance determined by the rollers, we determine the order in which the player's cards are selected. Each of them have certain predispositions such as psyche, speed, technique, etc. Once we have chosen the player's card, we go to choose the flag of which nationality you want to represent. There is also a card draw on which hill we will jump. They are shuffled, then turn. So let's say it's going to be Japan, for example. This card is placed on the 3D hill and indicates to us what nation we jump in. Based on that, the home jumpers will benefit from a better meters rating simulating crowd support. And then the size of the hill is randomly selected by turning over the top card of the bridge and finding out that we are racing on the K90 hill, for example. Then we can go into the training of our ski jumper (players cards). Based on the different predispositions of individual jumpers, we can improve individual training skills, which happens in specialized rooms in gyms on the board and therefore we can choose which ability we want to improve. They are on special cards. This gains points on the player's card, but we lose time and energy while we train. And as we lose time, we gradually get closer to the day of the race, and as soon as we get to the seventh day, we can go jump from the hill. Before the race starts and we go jumping, we calculate the points we have gathered in training and then we will find it on the spinner table. According to the hill on which the race is held. And if we had the same nationality as the flag on the hill, we would get more bonus meters. Which is like fans support us. So, after entering the values, you can jump. Jumping is made by putting your plastic figure down from the hill. At the edge of the hill there are two rollers which are triggered by the plastic figure and there have plus and minus symbol and numbers. These rollers simulate so-called random weather factor such as the Wind, or the current mental state of the jumper, etc. If we jumped +1 point. We will write down all those things in a notebook and in the final evaluation of the jump, in addition to the points gained in training, the place where the jumper finished will also be recorded. We have different point areas. The possibility of falling is incorporated into the game. If the jumper does not reach the point area or fall, he will not get any points. But he also has another way to get points for style as in real, and these are the cards that represent the points we know from ski jumping. The points work by dealing 5 cards to the player, he does not look at them. Another five cards are dealt in front of him, and after turning the hourglass, which has a limit of 30 seconds, the player tries to find the best possible numbers in order to get the best points for style. After matching the cards, the highest and the lowest value is deleted, as it works in real races. The remaining three values &amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;&amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;on the cards are summed up and written down in a notebook. All entered values &amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;&amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;are then summed up on a special designed notebook so you don't have to remember all you data and the winner gets one of the trophies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3007" value="Matching" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2876" value="Race" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2831" value="Real-Time" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5732" value="Sports: Winter Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="53231" value="MMBoardgames" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>