<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="353025">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Conquest: The Last Argument of Kings – The Spires Abomination Expansion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Abominations loom several man heights over the head of even the tallest mortal. Their gore slicked limbs spider out from its bulbous, distended abdomen and thorax. They are instruments of pure mayhem on the battlefield, scuttling forwards and reaping a bloody toll with their scythe like appendages, leaving only bloody ruin behind them. Survivors speak of a keening whine, just on the verge of hearing that pervades their memories, a sound that registers deeper than the cries of their fallen comrades. This is the only sound an Abomination can make, the only sound it is allowed to make: a keening howl to convey the depth of their misery and torment.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Abominations were not originally intended to serve as organic war engines. They were an advanced and cruel form of punishment, devised on a whim by the Sovereign. Ensconced deep within an Abomination lies the body of an Exile who has betrayed his trust or breached the most sacrosanct of Spire laws. Despite significant effort, even the Sovereign's most ardent opponents have not been able to come up with a more cruel punishment and have adopted this cruel torture for their worst enemies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Invasive cerebral procedures impairs the cognitive function of the condemned, as chemical and hormonal treatments are applied to make them lose control of their Life-Binding gifts and forcibly bond them to a lower organism. Multiple organisms were proposed and tried but the humble ant was ultimately preferred. While more gruesome examples could be made, it was found that those Abominations bonded to other species were too intractable or self-destructive. The ant's instinctive hierarchical physiology somehow makes it more susceptible to Pheromonic command, forcing the body to respond to orders while allowing compromised psyche trapped within the hellish amalgam only enough control to wail its anguish even while enacting the will of its tormentors.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="284261" value="Conquest: The Last Argument of Kings" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42870" value="Para Bellum Wargames Ltd." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>