<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="354051">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/d5FnVX1Iz7npcpffe00Qhw__thumb/img/JLwvoGRRcDWDP0ZaTLFE-P74DVw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6604953.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/d5FnVX1Iz7npcpffe00Qhw__original/img/ph3jBN3DZDknKvcBU1tadwCJaIc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6604953.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="SPYBAM" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In SPYBAM, the different players (CEOs) compete with each other to gain control of the world. You can buy properties or campaigns on each continent and negotiate mergers between players, but ... beware of spies!! Their goals are dark, and they will try to screw you up.&amp;#10;The setup begins by randomly delivering a business card and a different famous character card to each player with their own missions in order to win in SPYBAM. Even so, there are players who will have to go on a different side: the spies. They go together and win together. There will be a spy leader who knows the rest of the spies and the latter do not know the rest of their guild, so the spy leader must try to organize them without being discovered.&amp;#10;At the beginning of each round, an extraordinary event card will be raised that benefits or affects depending on how you have your properties located on the different continents. Be prepared as these events can change your plans.&amp;#10;Then each player's turn begins. Each one has 3 steps to perform:&amp;#10;1) Steal an Advantage or Disadvantage card depending on the die.&amp;#10;2) Draw a Property, Campaign or Fusion / Absorption card, choosing whether to activate it (paying its price) or save it in your deck of cards.&amp;#10;3) Negotiate one of the following 5 options: activate a card from your deck, auction a card from your deck, forcibly buy an active property (from another player) paying double its price, move your headquarters or buy an advantage card to the bank.&amp;#10;At the end of the turn of all the players, each one must invest in security the amount he considers, putting the money he considers in the security envelope. After this, all the players close their eyes and it is the spies' turn: one by one they will attack whoever they consider, leaving a token in front of the player. At the end of this dynamic, each player will look at the number of spy tokens received. If the number of millions invested is less than or equal to the spy tokens received, he will lose an active property. After this, each player receives the income from his properties and other cards before starting the next event or round.&amp;#10;The objective of each player is to complete the missions assigned to their character as soon as possible. But if you are a spy, your goal is to fulfil the common spy missions, leaving aside those of your character. Spies win as a group.&amp;#10;At any time during the game, a player can accuse another of being a spy, if he succeeds, he eliminates the spy from the game, but if he fails, he must compensate that player with a payment of money. Although if the accusation is carried out with an &amp;quot;absorption&amp;quot; card in its possession, if the accusation is correct, it takes all the spy's (Active) cards to its inventory (Not activated) in addition to eliminating it, and if it fails there is no penalty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;En SPYBAM, los distintos jugadores (CEOs) compiten entre ellos por alzarse con el control del mundo. Podr&amp;aacute;s comprar propiedades o campa&amp;ntilde;as en cada continente y negociar fusiones entre jugadores, pero&amp;hellip; &amp;iexcl;&amp;iexcl;cuidado con los esp&amp;iacute;as!! Sus objetivos son oscuros y trataran de fastidiarte.&amp;#10;El setup comienza entregando aleatoriamente una carta negocio y una carta personaje famoso distinto a cada jugador con unas misiones propias para poder ganar en SPYBAM. Aun as&amp;iacute;, hay jugadores que les tocar&amp;aacute; ir en un bando diferente: los esp&amp;iacute;as. Ellos van juntos y ganan juntos. Habr&amp;aacute; un esp&amp;iacute;a l&amp;iacute;der que conoce al resto de esp&amp;iacute;as y estos &amp;uacute;ltimos no conocen al resto de su gremio, por lo que el esp&amp;iacute;a l&amp;iacute;der debe tratar de organizarlos sin que le descubran. &amp;#10;Al comienzo de cada ronda se levantar&amp;aacute; una carta de evento extraordinario que beneficia o afecta seg&amp;uacute;n tengas situadas tus propiedades por los diferentes continentes. Prep&amp;aacute;rate puesto que estos eventos pueden modificar tus planes. &amp;#10;Despu&amp;eacute;s comienza el turno de cada jugador. Cada uno tiene 3 pasos a realizar:&amp;#10;1) Robar una tarjeta Ventaja o Desventaja seg&amp;uacute;n el dado. &amp;#10;2) Robar una carta de Propiedad, Campa&amp;ntilde;a o Fusi&amp;oacute;n/Absorci&amp;oacute;n, eligiendo si activarla (pagando su precio) o guardarla en tu mazo de cartas.&amp;#10;3) Negociar una de las siguientes 5 opciones: activar una carta de tu mazo, subastar una carta de tu mazo, comprar forzosamente una propiedad activa (de otro jugador) pagando el doble de su precio, mover tu sede o comprar una ventaja a la banca.&amp;#10;Al finalizar el turno de todos los jugadores, cada uno deber&amp;aacute; invertir en seguridad la cantidad que estime, metiendo el dinero que considere en el sobre de seguridad. Tras esto todos los jugadores cierran los ojos y es el turno de los esp&amp;iacute;as: uno a uno ir&amp;aacute;n atacando a quien consideren dejando una ficha delante del jugador. Al final de esta din&amp;aacute;mica cada jugador mirara el n&amp;uacute;mero de fichas esp&amp;iacute;as recibidas. Si el n&amp;uacute;mero de millones invertidos es menor o igual a las fichas esp&amp;iacute;as recibidas, perder&amp;aacute; una propiedad activa. Tras esto, cada jugador recibe los ingresos de sus propiedades y otras cartas antes de comenzar el siguiente evento o ronda.&amp;#10;El objetivo de cada jugador es cumplir las misiones que tiene asignado su personaje lo antes posible. Pero si te ha tocado ser esp&amp;iacute;a, tu objetivo es cumplir las misiones de esp&amp;iacute;as en com&amp;uacute;n, dejando de lado las de tu personaje. Los esp&amp;iacute;as ganan en grupo.&amp;#10;En cualquier momento de la partida un jugador puede acusar a otro de ser esp&amp;iacute;a, si acierta elimina al esp&amp;iacute;a de la partida, pero si falla deber&amp;aacute; indemnizar a ese jugador con un pago de dinero. Aunque si la acusaci&amp;oacute;n la realiza teniendo en su poder una carta de &amp;ldquo;absorci&amp;oacute;n&amp;rdquo; si acierta la acusaci&amp;oacute;n, se lleva todas las cartas (Activas) del esp&amp;iacute;a a su inventario (Sin activar) adem&amp;aacute;s de eliminarle, y si falla no hay penalizaci&amp;oacute;n.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer (Spanish)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="9" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="91" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="92" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="93" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="94" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="95" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1084" value="Environmental" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1081" value="Spies/Secret Agents" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2916" value="Alliances" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2918" value="Auction: English" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2928" value="Closed Economy Auction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3002" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2856" value="Die Icon Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2850" value="Events" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2967" value="Hidden Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2891" value="Hidden Roles" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2902" value="Income" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2910" value="Investment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2915" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2948" value="Resource to Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2892" value="Roles with Asymmetric Information" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2822" value="Scenario / Mission / Campaign Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2814" value="Traitor Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>