<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="357965">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XgmEOqm7IhIJaacmZffRMQ__thumb/img/3NhxVGrVwi0vdXfttNR8nM7wdFA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6725501.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XgmEOqm7IhIJaacmZffRMQ__original/img/0VbMjsHQMDb3v5RO7qBPfo_fDSI=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic6725501.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="New World Order Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>New World Order - the game of future - is an fast paced game  with easy set-up and game-play mechanics, but has plenty of strategy and players need to make good choices to win. You take the role of a globalist billionaire and your purpose is to collect different corporations and institutions (society has already collapsed) and by collecting them gain Achievements that are high-tech inventions or some other global development. &amp;#10;When you collect 3 Achievements with the same color you will reach Big Goal which will change our future considerably here on Earth or Space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this boardgame/cardgame hybrid players are collecting Corporation cards from the table and adding them together to maximize their points. For those points they can buy Achievement tiles which are placed on the table like a pyramid. Achievements give Victory points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you collect a three Achievements that match (they have same color on them) then a Great Goal is achieved and player gains extra 500 points Victory Points for it, which is pretty good.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Every player has 3 actions from which they have to choose 1 on their turn. Game moves clock-wise of course. The first action is to choose same corporation card or cards from the table, second - buy an Achievement for the Corp cards points and third - player can throw away a card or a set to make room for other Corp cards. That is sometimes necessary since the slots for Corp cards are limited (7 slots for 2-3 player game and 5 slots for 4-5 player game).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These actions go quickly most of the time, but there are moments where player needs to take a look at his cards and tiles he/she has and think what direction he wants go. He could go for high Corp card points (by collecting more cards) to get the expensive Achievement or forgetting about the full set and take a cheaper Achievement tile from the pyramid with a suitable color to get the Bonus points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Making things more interesting is that player can&amp;acute;t take any tile you want. He can only take a tile that is free which means it don&amp;acute;t have any other tile on top of it ( not even a on a corner). So there needs to be some tactics how to get to that tile that is unavailable at the moment. It helps if a player got &amp;quot;another action&amp;quot; card, then he can use it to take the two tiles in a row!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The good thing about the game is players can influence each other games by simple ruining other's plans and taking the cards (or tiles) he/she really needs.&amp;#10;Looking at other players despaired face is always fun! Don&amp;acute;t forget you are a ruthless globalist billionaire :)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when all corporation cards are played out and Achievement VP-s ja Great Goals are counted.Who has most VP-s will be the most powerful elite!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game is great for people who don&amp;acute;t play games much and are afraid of extensive rules. Gameplay is easily learned in the first 15 minutes. &amp;#10;For experts it could feel a bit of a filler game, but in my opinion it has too many tactical options to be that and the game goes on a bit longer for a filler (60-75 minutes for 3 players).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Also the game has deep theme and makes you think a bit where are we heading as a society. It is a great conversation starter and very fun to enjoy with a couple of beers! :)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For more information check out the game site www.newworldordergame.com&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2847" value="Advantage Token" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2875" value="End Game Bonuses" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2846" value="Once-Per-Game Abilities" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2897" value="Variable Set-up" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="37399" value="Tanel Kapp" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="9.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>