<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="358336">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mUuv7DodkXb72V70l2JM6g__thumb/img/LQ-kyv1ohDMRED13bFJDp86s6nc=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6733395.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mUuv7DodkXb72V70l2JM6g__original/img/dmSwhy9-1NnpCHWUA0k0J970ZYE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6733395.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Да оцелееш като родител" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>CONGRATULATIONS! YOU ARE NOW A PARENT!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is where the fun begins. If you've been there before, you are in for an (un)pleasant return. If you're there now - you will be back to the daily terror instead of playing to relax. If you're about to do it - you may decide not to! Like we just said - congratulations!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play:&amp;#10;You step into the uncomfortable shoes of a parent whose sweet offspring brings him joy at the same time and seems to be trying to destroy him. All parents are different: there are businessmen and punks, politicians, managers, athletes, but they are all united by one thing - they try to survive without going crazy. Well, of course, and win. Each role has pros and cons, starts with different levels of health, sanity and money and has an individual special skill. There are two ways to win - you are either the last to be still alive or the first to get to 30 health and sanity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MECHANICS&amp;#10;Before starting the game, do the following:&amp;#10;Give a random parent card to each player. Return the unused ones to the box.&amp;#10;Put cubes to indicate the current levels of sanity and health (initial values &amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;&amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#139;are marked on the parent cards).&amp;#10;Shuffle all the playing cards and create a deck. Place it in the middle of the table.&amp;#10;Give 4 cards to each player, as well as the starting money marked on their parent card. Three cards are then removed from the pile of cards and the top one is turned over so that it is visible to everyone.&amp;#10;You are now ready to begin. Each action in the game is determined by the cards you play or are already in front of you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FIRST ROUND: The last person to have become a parent takes the three cards without bidding anything, the other players take one card from the deck. If there is no parent between you, skip the first round and start directly from the second.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EVERY NEXT ROUND: You bid for the three cards visible on the market. With shouting, cunning, insults and everything. The one who bets the most wins. There are no restrictions on bidding - you can always intervene. The one who wins the bidding takes the three cards he has bid for. The others take one card from the top of the pile. The winner of the bidding starts first and can play as many cards as he wants - without restrictions. After him is the next player in clockwise direction. When everyone is done, it's time for the next round, which repeats the second round. And so on until a winner is announced in one of two ways:&amp;#10;Either the last survivor or the first who reaches 30 health and sanity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="46" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="47" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="48" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="49" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="50" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2012" value="Auction/Bidding" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51029" value="Оз books" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>