<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="360974">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/s_nvlHRnNqz1Bm5g9FnuRQ__thumb/img/Y-UtrGu9CzKpPIrLxsdAxg3aPWk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6812928.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/s_nvlHRnNqz1Bm5g9FnuRQ__original/img/vJCM-rOwtYK91ZbdMpn8QZX81kg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6812928.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Netsvis" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The game is inspired by the Etruscan divination art and is an interpretation of how dice could have been used more than 2500 years ago. &amp;#10;The Netsvis board reproduces the sacred Etruscan space and can be used both alone, to draw the wishes of the day, and in competition with other players, having as its objective the challenge to Fate with the simple throw of the dice.&amp;#10;How to play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Netsvis is a solitaire where you face pure destiny, destiny and what governs all the daily events behind it. It can be used as a divination tool (do I win or does Fate win?) But it is also a competitive pastime towards oneself. In fact, it is possible to numerically evaluate the outcome of the single game and gradually try to obtain better and better results. In this way it is also possible to compete with the participation of more players in succession of time.&amp;#10;     The two dice act alternately as dice and checkers. The white die W is favorable, the one that could win. The black die B is the unfavorable one, the one that could make you lose.&amp;#10;     At the start of the game, B is placed in the gray box in the lower center. It doesn't matter what value is shown on the top face of him.&amp;#10;     You roll W with your right hand and, starting from the square occupied by B, advance it to the right to the first square that shows the same image of the face that came out in the roll of the dice. Here the die W stops while B remains in his place.&amp;#10;     Now take B and throw it with your left hand. The result of the shot causes B to move to the first square corresponding to the exit face, starting from the position of W but in the opposite direction, ie to the left. Now two clarifications are necessary. The first, completely connected to superstition, is linked to the traditional beneficial influence of the right hand (which must be used to roll the white dice) while the left has always been considered a bearer of misfortune. The second clarification is fundamental for the purposes of the game. When the rule says: &amp;quot;Bring B into the first square on the left starting from the one occupied by W&amp;quot; it means that a possible release of the colors magenta, yellow or blue in this first throw of B will make it move to the right with respect to its initial position but &amp;quot; however &amp;quot;to the left of the white die.&amp;#10;     After placing B in the corresponding square, W is taken from the square in which it is and raised (with the right hand) and then moved to the right up to the first square equal to the exit face. Also in this case the reference to the starting point of the displacement of W is the square in which B stands.&amp;#10;     And so on, toss after toss in a continuous back and forth that leads W to the right arm of the board and brings B back to the left. The game continues until one of the two dice cannot move because it is in such a position that there is no square in front of it with the symbol that came out in that roll. If it is W, it is placed on the top white square and the player has won.&amp;#10;     If it is B, it is moved to the top black box and the player has lost. So it's fate that won the game!&amp;#10;     You can only win with an odd number of rolls and lose with an even number. This distinction also has its own symbolic meaning ... And you can win with a few moves or after a tiring sequence of rolling the two dice. Likewise, if Fate is adverse, a few moves may be enough to reach the nefarious black box. If you manage to stall, you must never lose hope: the arrangement of the numbers on the board can often turn the tables in our favor.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2001" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3115" value="Fratelli Fabbri Editori  (Fabbri Editore)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>