<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="361488">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/paKLSF-jhGV1Pxob3e1fDQ__thumb/img/I5AWP99cs0vrJKckJp1eDSPavNY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6826901.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/paKLSF-jhGV1Pxob3e1fDQ__original/img/VlIHTpjNOwu7v9qlgFDEIh99LEA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6826901.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ju 87 Stuka Ace" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ju 87 Stuka Ace allows you to simulate Junker 87 (Stuka) operations throughout the course of World War II, from the beginning of the Blitzkrieg in Poland to the anti-tank operations in the Russian campaign.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;What makes Stuka Pilot special is the brand-new game engine, built around what made the Stuka unique, the dive-bombing. This method of attack is very different from the standard bombing operated by other aircraft, and Ju 87 Stuka Pilot fully reflects this uniqueness. This is the attack sequence in JU 87 Stuka Ace: select the bomb release height, proceed with the dive, consider the current formation height and visibility, release the bombs at the set height and then execute the delicate pull phase. Each of these phases will be managed by making optimal use of the action cards in the player's hand, but you must carefully plan your play since you don&amp;rsquo;t immediately draw a new card after playing it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ju 87 Stuka Ace will allow you to fly your Ju 87 in almost all the theatres where the Stuka were used: Poland, France, England, Norway, the Mediterranean, North Africa, Italy, and Russia. The missions in the different theatres will have very different objectives: infantry units, artillery positions, tanks, transport ships, battleships are just some of the examples. Terrain and weather conditions will also play an important role in the missions; poor visibility, the scorching heat and the sand of the desert, and the frost and snow in the Russian winters: are elements the player will have to consider to succeed.  Ju 87 Stuka Ace includes even night operations: special rules will allow simulating Ju 87 D-5N attacks in Italy as members of &amp;quot;Night Battle Group&amp;quot; NSG9.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Nine Stuka models will be available to the player depending on the mission or on the progression of the campaign, including Ju 87 A, Ju 87B-1, Ju 87 R-1, Ju 87 D-3, Ju 87 D-5, and Ju 87 G-1. Depending on the capabilities of the aircraft, it will be necessary to select the most appropriate bomb load for the mission objective, evaluating both the number and the type of bombs to be used. And when flying the Ju 87 G-1, your pilot will use the Bordkanone 37 against the Soviet tanks: to better represent the Ju 87G-1 tank-buster role, a specific attack procedure has been introduced, always leveraging the player Action Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you have just a limited amount of time you can play single missions, choosing your preferred theatre of operations. If you are instead looking for a campaign game, Stuka Pilot has been designed to represent the entire career of the pilot, starting from his role as &amp;quot;rookie&amp;quot;, then moving on to the roles of Kette Leader, Staffel Leader, and finally Gruppe Leader. As squadron or group commander, the player will have to coordinate the operations of his formation, defining the best approach to the attack, while still remaining in command of his aircraft; the outcome of the mission is always based on the result of your individual attack, do not expect to remain an observer while your formation is executing its dive attacks. As the campaign progresses, you will not only be able to climb the ranks of the Luftwaffe, but also improve your skills (customize your deck of Action cards) and get the coveted medals. The Golden Leaves are waiting for you aboard your Ju 87.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="31" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="32" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="33" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="34" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="35" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="73596" value="Digital Implementations: TableTop Simulator Mod (TTS)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="76609" value="History: World War II (Battle of Britain)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3893" value="Gottardo Zancani" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="85732" value="Blackwell Hird" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="6025" value="Lock 'n Load Publishing, LLC." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="7.2" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.18748" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="8" />
			<wishing value="59" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="2.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>