<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="363156">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Disputed Land: War in Azerbaijan – 2020" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Disputed Land covers the flashpoint war between Armenia and Azerbaijan over the Armenian controlled territory of Nagorno-Karabakh, which was won in 1994.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This territory was Azerbaijan's prior to 1994. The loss was never agreed to and remained a bone of contention between the two countries. As time went on, Azerbaijan became sovereign country and quickly built up its former Soviet army. Russia remains allied to both countries now but has a defense pact with Armenia. It also sells both countries its military weapons.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;While Azerbaijan built up its military forces that are superior to Arme-nia, Armenia did could not match them due to the fact Azerbaijan used revenue from oil. By 2020, it was time for Azerbaijan to reclaim the disputed loss area.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In late September of 2020, Azer forces made a surprise attack across the Nagorno front positions and slowly made in roads. The opposing forces were fewer but it was the terrain that would determine success. But the war did bring into view future warfare using deadly armed drones that Azer forces bought from Turkey and Israel. Unable to shoot them down, Armenian tanks and radar were decimated within a week losing 173 T-72 tanks, 257 APC, 67 rocket launched artillery, 23 SAM, and 14 radar. It was a staggering blow and great military feat of future warfare tactics.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Eventually, Armenia agreed to a ceasefire in mid-October. Azer forces took the time to redirect their offensive and unleash its 1st Corps along the Iranian border on the 18th. This was a brilliant move catching the Armenian forces off guard in the Fuzuli\Fizuli area. the Azer armor and mechanized formations raced deep into Nagorno territory coming with-in 20 km of the key town of Lachin in the mountains. If taken, Azer would cutoff the only supply road into Nagorno. As Azer forces cau-tiously approached, Armenian military units in Goris began to counter-attack halting further advance. Being that the two lane road was sur-rounded my 4000 ft. mountains, Azer forces pulled back on Oct. 24.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now, Azer forces switched to another attack from Fizuli towards Shusha and the Nagorno capital. This main attack was a slugfest due to the mountainous terrain. Armenian troops fought tooth and nail but by Nov.4, Azer forces were within 10 km of Stepanakert and nearly sur-rounded Shusha. If either fell, again, the main supply road would be cut. Bitter fighting and artillery fire continued until Nov. 9, when Shusha fell to Azer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It was now Armenia agreed to Russia's peace plan. Estimated losses were up to 8000 men, well over 300 tanks lost total and hundreds of artillery guns or rocket launchers.&amp;#10;LESS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="3">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="3" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="63066" value="Country: Armenia" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="63071" value="Country: Azerbaijan" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="63069" value="Region: Caucasus" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1257" value="Perry Moore" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4366" value="Firefight Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>