<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="363440">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/QMrc-XtaUl9wN7lFro6lfA__thumb/img/HD5JmqibIWzHcqJZISYakUxcO8E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6875082.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/QMrc-XtaUl9wN7lFro6lfA__original/img/VH_jkNaM2BOtMYNP21jXiHUwvWg=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic6875082.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Middara: Lupercalia 2021 Pack" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Lupercalia beckons.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Through decadence and debauchery these lustful figures can be called from the depths of Earth&amp;rsquo;s history. Espers made manifest only through esoteric quiet whispers shared amongst the elite.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Such coveted creatures are called upon for far more than combat. Yet, their true names and seals are clutched closely to the hearts of those who covet them most. Jealousy worms its way into the heart, and rots at the very soul of those who know these secret combinations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Those lucky few able to overhear their betters slip such forbidden knowledge during inebriated tales of past forays find themselves more than excited to let their soul wear away at the chance to even behold such monstrosities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Just like our Cross Promotion Pack, our Resin Lupercalia Kits from last year are now available in plastic. The Lupercalia 2021 Pack includes a plastic set of all seven of the miniatures we made in Resin from our last Kickstarter. This also includes their Item Cards, Combatant Cards, and Adventurer Cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Profane Occultists Made Immortal&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;Toxie scrubbed the blood from her hands, noting idly that she had nailed the color when choosing her crimson fingernail polish. In the far corner of the abandoned warehouse, a half dozen corpses, all still bound hand and foot, lay in a heap as testament to her night&amp;rsquo;s labors. Her final victim lay sprawled on the concrete floor behind her, still breathing shallowly through his broken, twisted mouth. She hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually been planning to pull out his teeth when she started questioning him, but then Luperci and Tixie had radioed in that they cleared the enemy&amp;rsquo;s hideout, and that Mena was one of the captives they had freed. Threatening the Faun was one thing; dragging an innocent child into it was something else altogether.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Toxie dried her hands gingerly, then turned around to consider her captive. He was definitely dying; even if someone found him now, there weren&amp;rsquo;t enough surgeons or drugs on Earth to save him. But Toxie had to meet up with her pack to run down the last of the heathens who had escaped with the Faun, and she didn&amp;rsquo;t like leaving jobs unfinished.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;She hunkered down next to him and saw with satisfaction that his eyes were still open, though only just through the swollen wreckage of his face. She blew him a kiss.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;You get a little mercy now,&amp;rdquo; she crooned as she gently stroked a blood-free patch of skin on his forehead. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m late for an orgy, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really wait around for you to die. You know how it is. . .&amp;rdquo; &amp;#10;She turned to her gear bag and considered her options. She wanted to use her favorite, but, of course, it had to be the messiest of the lot and she had just finished cleaning up. Eh, what the hell, she thought. Grinning, Toxie grabbed the pink handle and turned back to finish the job.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Outside the warehouse, an early morning train rumbled past, just loud enough to mask the roar of a chainsaw.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This product contains 7 miniatures, Adventurers, Espers, and new Items.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These new Espers spice your game with unknown variety by adding new Espers that can be summoned by both Adventurers&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="51" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="52" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="53" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="54" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="55" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="169427" value="Middara: Unintentional Malum – Act 1" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="283313" value="Middara: Unintentional Malum – Act 2" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="284939" value="Middara: Unintentional Malum – Act 3" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="336798" value="Middara: Faunus, God of the Nymphs Resin Kit" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="336797" value="Middara: Lupercalia Pack Resin Kit" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="336796" value="Middara: Psyche, Aphorism of Love Resin Kit" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="336795" value="Middara: The Judge's Daughter Resin Kit" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="26450" value="Succubus Publishing" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="23" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="8" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>