<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="367382">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TqGmTX8RjdxxmR12k5jSCQ__thumb/img/Fmtrw_wG5cEuvB63ZFRgcIJG8Xs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic6981636.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TqGmTX8RjdxxmR12k5jSCQ__original/img/1CKwRERkitcbYAV26yolK9TAwvg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic6981636.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="China, LLC.: Qing Dynasty and Guomindang 1644-1949" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>China, LLC. is a game of China from the establishment of the Qing Dynasty in 1644 CE to the end of the Chinese Civil War of 1949 CE. Philip Jelley uses the same system as the popular Rome, Inc. in which you run China like a business, expanding its corporate power across China, Manchuria, Mongolia, Xinjiang, Tibet and the Southern and Eastern Seas until it becomes the largest, richest, most populous entity in the world. From the height of power, the Qing CEOs became increasingly detached from reality, confined to their palaces, and dominated by managerial eunuchs while their vast empire is beset by internal rebellions and new barbarians from across the far seas. Can you succeed where they failed? Even if Qing fall, you have a second chance as the Guomindang (Chinese Nationalist Party) struggle to bring order out of the chaos of a crumbling empire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Statesmen may become emperors, governors, rebels, and enemy leaders and are rated for their Military, Administration, Popularity, and Intrigue abilities. Each has a special ability, allowing them to defeat their historic foes, assassinate rivals, and influence foreign affairs. For example, the Emperor Qianlong has two Military, five Administration, two Popularity, and four Intrigue abilities, and the Conquest special ability, making him an indifferent general, but excellent bureaucrat even if he was reluctant to embrace popular reform, who expanded the Qing Empire to its greatest extent. Less useful is the Empress Cixi with one Military, two Administration, two Popularity, and four Intrigue abilities, and the Assassin special ability, whose habit of killing emperors destabilized the Qing Dynasty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The map has provinces grouped into ten commands, each with their own governor to collect taxes, crush insurgents, fight wars, or perhaps assassinate the emperor, or launch a rebellion. Victory is determined by annexing provinces, defeating wars, financing massive prestige projects, and establishing the Mandate of Heaven. Cavalry, infantry, and fleets are used to fight wars and garrison provinces, expanding direct control, or creating vassals in outlying provinces. Enemy leaders and wars move from province to province until defeated, encouraging revolts, causing unrest, reducing income, but fighting them could lead to disaster. Unequal Treaties imposed on China by foreign powers robbing her of provinces, prestige, and cash and changing the rules as they expand their own empires.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn represents 5-10 years, with 10 turns in each scenario. The four scenarios start in 1644 CE, 1735 CE, 1820 CE, and 1889 CE which may be combined into campaign games. You need to blend military acumen with careful administration, as well as intrigue, making the most of what you have each turn, just like any modern-day business. China, LLC will give you a new perception of how war is a cost, business is a benefit, and empire is somewhere in between. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you to find a balance, or heads will roll. China, LLC comes with one full color 22&amp;quot; x 34&amp;quot; mapsheet, 280 full color 1/2&amp;quot; die-cut pieces and around 12 pages of rules. Players should average from 3 to 4 hours per scenario.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="180" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2850" value="Events" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="11518" value="Country: China" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="63651" value="History: Opium Wars and Taiping Rebellion" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="64357" value="History: Second Sino-Japanese War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="134" value="Magazine: Against The Odds" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61978" value="Players: Solitaire Only Wargames" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8164" value="Players: Wargames with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="196676" value="Rome, Inc.: From Augustus to Diocletian" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="33440" value="Philip Jelley" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1244" value="Against the Odds" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="3" />
			<wishing value="9" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>