<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="369939">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Interstellar Nomad" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Interstellar Nomad is a set collection game where players earn points for completing the planet panoramas. In your quest for interstellar inhabitance, you&amp;rsquo;ll compete with an opponent to earn the highest Nomad Score. to win each round and the overall game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;DESCRIPTION Construct panorama&amp;rsquo;s of planets across the galaxy through twists and turns, outwit your opponent in this compact easy-to-learn, two-player card game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HOW TO PLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Greetings, Interstellar Nomad. Interstellar Nomad is a set collection game where players earn points for completing the planet panoramas. In your quest for interstellar inhabitance, you&amp;rsquo;ll compete with an opponent to earn the highest Nomad Score. to win each round and the overall game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A game of Interstellar Nomad is played over 2 or more rounds. Each round consists of 4 steps:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup&amp;#10;Shuffle all cards into a deck. Deal 2 cards to you and your opponent. Place the remaining cards in a face-down draw pile on the table. Draw 5 cards and place them face-down in a Universal Row next to the deck with each card alternating orientation. Once the Universal Row is in place, reveal all face-down cards. Randomly determine the starting player for the first round. The losing player starts subsequent rounds.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play Cards&amp;#10;Players take turns placing a single card onto their own play area. Cards can be played in one of two ways:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Place a card from your hand into your play area face up and in any orientation. This card will either start or continue a set. [next Resolve Card Actions]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Select a face-up card (active card) from the Universal Row and place it in your play area to start or continue a set. The card may be placed in the correct order of the set but must maintain it's previous orientation &amp;mdash; landscape or portrait. [next Resolve Card Actions]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Resolve Card Actions&amp;#10;After playing a card, the player must execute the played card&amp;rsquo;s action(s), selecting and affecting a different active card &amp;mdash; the active card must be within their play area or the Universal Row. [see Card Actions] The player then draws a card and adds it to the end of the Universal Row following alternating orientation. Play continues until all possible cards are played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Determine the Winner&amp;#10;Points are awarded as follows at the end of each round: +1 for each active card within a set -1 for each missing card in a set -1 for each inactive card -1 for possessing the Wasteland (-2 if inactive) Bonus points are awarded for each complete set: +1 for a complete set in the correct order +1 for a complete set in the correct orientation The player with the highest Nomad Score after all cards are played wins the round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first player to win 2 rounds is the winner of the game and continues their interstellar journey.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="71" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="72" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="73" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="74" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="75" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>