<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="371054">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pZL-JPooH5sEIbaXPsIh9w__thumb/img/HyjddzoksFFh1oaTOn_VfkdojwU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7315201.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pZL-JPooH5sEIbaXPsIh9w__original/img/UULU3m9zODfwVRA__DPVYh2wrcY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7315201.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Kashido" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Japan, the old capital Kamakura. Here, in this age, you are an apprentice patissier, making traditional japanese pastries.&amp;#10;One day, the master gathered all his apprentices and proclaimed:&amp;#10;&amp;quot;I will employ the one who most beautifully can decorate these pastries&amp;quot;&amp;#10;Will that person be you? Can you line up the pastries prettier than everyone else?&amp;#10;This is an abstract open information strategy game, where you exchange places of pastries of four different colours, in order to line them up orthogonally and diagonally, and score the corresponding points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup&amp;#10;Place the board in the play area.&amp;#10;Give each player a summary.&amp;#10;Place a cake tile on each of the 16 squares on the board, according to colour.&amp;#10;Put the 40 point tiles on the board edge, according to colour, with the point side face up. See to that the 10 chits in each colour are shuffled.&amp;#10;Choose the starting player in any suitable fashion.&amp;#10;Turn goes clockwise around the table; everyone takes their corresponding order chit and places before them. Everyone but the start player flips their order chit so that the special effect is face up (this effect is usable from each player's first turn)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Flow of the game&amp;#10;Turn goes clockwise around the table. Each turn consists of the two steps below, in order.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1: Optional: Exchange places of 2 adjacent cake tiles&amp;#10;Choose two orthogonally adjacent cake tiles, and swap their places.&amp;#10;Cake tiles are not adjacent diagonally.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2: Gain point chit&amp;#10;If the number of icons on a point chit matches the number of cake tiles of the chit's colour, in that row, then you gain that point chit.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You can only gain 1 point chit per turn (unless a special effect allows you otherwise).&amp;#10;The point chit you gain doesn't have to be related to the tiles you moved (if any)&amp;#10;However, if you cannot gain a point chit (or cannot see how you would be able to), regardless of whether you move cake tiles or not, you must pass your turn, without moving any cake tiles and may not take another turn until the game ends.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you gain a point chit, put it face down to show the special effect. You cannot use a power the very turn you gained it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Special effects of turn chits and point chits&amp;#10;You may use the effects of turn chits and point chits at any time during your own turn. You may use several on the same turn, but each chit is a one-time use. Once used, flip the chit to face up, so that it shows the number instead.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Explanation of the special effects&amp;#10;You may use the effect up to many times as the number indicates.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Turn order thics, red point chits:&amp;#10;You may do extra move actions&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Yellow point chits:&amp;#10;You may gain extra point chits. However, all point chits you gain must be from the same row, and all of them have to fulfill their conditions. You may use several yellow point chits on the same turn, but all chits you gain must come from the same row.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Green point chits:&amp;#10;When you want to gain a point chit, you may lower the number of necessary cake tiles.&amp;#10;Each green point chit can only be valid for gaining one point chit. If you use several green point chits on the same turn, they have to be used for different point chits (i.e. in combination with yellow point chits)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Blue point chits have no special effect. Instead, they are worth double the points of normal point chits. Their full total points are noted on their back sides.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     For all point chits, the power of the special effect is higher, the rarer the chit is.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game and and victor&amp;#10;The game ends when either all point chits have been gained, or when all players have passed their turn due to not being able to gain a point chit.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the highest total points wins the game. Blue point chits have the value printed on their back side (the front side doesn't count).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In case of a tie, the last player to go breaks the tie.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Tricks and tips&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you round the total points to be gained as 100, and try to aim for exceeding your player's share of those points (33 points on 3 players, 25 points on 4 players), you'll have an easier time to judge whether you're doing well or not.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1028" value="Puzzle" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5841" value="Theme: Food / Cooking" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="82544" value="佐藤 雄介 (Yusuke Sato)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="39728" value="Librage Co., LTD." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>