<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="371545">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7qVPbfstI1fvRNDQw79ejw__thumb/img/JDzlnXkD0vbmvAj4dCUg7sMPEug=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7095872.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/7qVPbfstI1fvRNDQw79ejw__original/img/3LdtzQFuDI0cMtpmW94zXKCnT88=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7095872.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ratten Reich: The Board Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ratten Reich: The Board Game is a physical tabletop companion to the upcoming RTS wargame, Ratten Reich. It is a grim and unforgiving world, where war has continued for many years. The war is fought between rats, mice, roaches and lizards alike in their never-ending struggle for power.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your task is to lead your faction to victory. Whatever country you play as, you have to muster supplies and equip your armies, lead them into battle, face losses and recoup them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the Ratten Reich board game, your task is to lead your faction to victory. Whatever country you play as, you have to muster and equip your armies, lead them into battle, lose them and collect new ones. Under your command, three infantry armies are given, each of which can fit five infantry tokens. Military tokens are tied to military cards, so you can equip your armies with both elite units and simple cannon fodder. And so, the era of great conquest begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Naval battles are a common feature of imperialist wars and will therefore play a significant part in Ratten Reich: The Board Game. Large empires are typically surrounded by seas and ocean, allowing the transfer and logistics of military forces to travel from one continent to another. This opportunity pushes the development of military shipbuilding.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this tabletop experience, each player is given one fleet figure to start. Choose to reinforce your fleet with heavy battleships and/or ironclads, intercept the enemy at sea, blockade ports or assist with naval bombardment. You can even execute an amphibious assault on your enemies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your army gains an attack bonus if it lands with naval support so ensure you utilize the whole of your forces! A fleet is also needed to transfer your armies to another continent.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game pads are divided into two main types: the Main Player pads and the Autocrat Trade Military pad. The regular Player tablet allows you to design armies as you wish. The Autocrat tablet allows the player to create specialized armies and provides an opportunity to regulate the resource market by setting prices for mercenary armies.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tokens are the same for all players except the Autocrat. Players can assemble armies themselves as they please. Meanwhile, the Autocrat collects and sells mercenaries whilst regulating the game market.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There is an additional battle pad that creates positive or negative conditions for the combatants. When the offensive player rolls the dice at the start of battle, the number rolled correlates to one of the six possible conditions that affect combat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You may be lucky with fair weather conditions or you may be afflicted with corruption in your army, which will give certain disadvantages in the battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tokens are an important part of the game. All resources, buildings, troops, and finances are considered tokens. Tokens in Ratten Reich: The Board Game are divided into two groups: military and economic.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Military tokens allow you to build armies on your side of the board and dually display the territories you have conquered. Economic tokens allow you to place buildings on the map, establish trade routes, conduct diplomacy, and arrange &amp;ldquo;meanness.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards are &amp;lsquo;paper helpers&amp;rsquo; in building your empire. Ratten Reich: The Board Game gives you the opportunity to build an economy, create your own armies, and create &amp;lsquo;meanness&amp;rsquo; at your enemy&amp;rsquo;s doorstep.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your faction&amp;rsquo;s main power source is the army. At your discretion, assemble your army by selecting from several types of infantry and vehicles - all of which will be under your control. If you are lacking in resources, gather a cheap army on a whim to capture colonies or to defend your cities. Perhaps you might prefer to invest in high-quality troops with impressive armor and equipment to best represent your faction.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To dominate the sea, build and tend to your fleet. Whether you play aggressively or systematically, develop and evolve your troops to master the board. You will only be dealt a few moves of peace and tranquility during the game; when these moves end, no one will have the right to stop you.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The economy is a vital part of the game. Without a reliable economy, you simply won&amp;rsquo;t be able to afford an army to face off against your enemies. Ratten Reich: The Board Game will offer you a standard set of building cards that includes: a bunker, factory, munitions factory, secret society, and market. Each building has a unique purpose.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Be wise with the limited resources you have! Construction will help create a defensive basis for negotiations, a stable economy, and eventual peace talks. You can play aggressively by contributing all of your resources to the army, but such tactics can end up being a lost cause. By spending some of your resources on the secret society and market, you can aim for a swift defeat of the enemy with both prosperity and gunfire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A strong economy is the key to maintaining the army and vice versa.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Looking to harm your enemies? For this sole purpose, we have provided an opportunity for the player to build a secret society.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will have the opportunity to inflict greater harm upon their enemies through the construction of a secret society. A secret society grants access to cards of &amp;lsquo;meanness.&amp;rsquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each faction has two unique villainy cards that the player can activate once per game. Each card gives a special ability to the player. For example, the player can build an underground city on the territory of the enemy and gain half of his resources or a player can burn their enemy&amp;rsquo;s lands. There are eleven unique cards in total, each with their own abilities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To make Ratten Reich: The Board Game more interesting, the game will interfere with your plans. Be it famine, plague, or a brutal winter, these events are meant to annoy everyone at the table as you recalculate your next move and adapt in battle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But the game does not merely take. It gives. You may come across useful event cards that offer small advantages or stability. If the Autocrat takes part in the game, then they are free to choose the event cards themselves. In the absence of an Autocrat, the cards are drawn randomly.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Six unique factions await you! Each faction will have an original design, playstyle, a variety of abilities, and different military and economic potential. Revive the old empires in the eastern part of the central continent. Build a formidable fleet. Control the colonies. Determine which of you will become the world&amp;rsquo;s new hegemony and whose country will turn to ashes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="16" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="17" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="18" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="19" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="20" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1101" value="Video Game Theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2846" value="Once-Per-Game Abilities" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="19252" value="Animals: Cockroaches" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="21462" value="Animals: Lizards" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="7520" value="Animals: Rats" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="65774" value="Theme: Anthropomorphic Animals" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="52517" value="Bankai BG" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>