<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="373560">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/nV56d1j4yC4bma3kKMQatg__thumb/img/rJZtyEMI0vFescprkhIe-jqzGkE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7149497.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/nV56d1j4yC4bma3kKMQatg__original/img/AIjc_qkADuAHLGolNPSMzyPcdkM=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7149497.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Adventures in Devil&#039;s Creek: A Solitaire Dungeon Crawler RPG in the Wild West" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>ADVENTURES IN DEVIL&amp;acute;S CREEK&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Adventures in Devil&amp;rsquo;s Creek is set in the wild west of a fictional America in the small town of Fortune&amp;rsquo;s Creek.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fortune&amp;rsquo;s Creek was once a thriving small town that was a sought-after destination for treasure hunters and traders. The mines held vast amounts of gold and precious stones. The river that flows through the town kept bringing smaller crystals and sometimes even diamonds with it. This earned the city the name Fortune&amp;rsquo;s Creek. Anyone could get rich here, you just have to reach out and grab your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But with wealth, corruption also found its way into the city and criminals soon regulated all trade routes. The legislature found itself powerless, but after three sheriffs disappeared in a very short time, the government sent a small army from Washington to ensure law and order in the city. However, the current rulers of Fortune&amp;rsquo;s Creek were unwilling to give up their gold mine without resistance and so it came to a wild, brutal battle that lasted for several days. Not only did criminals and crooks fall, many innocent people also died in the hail of bullets. After two days the last bullet was fired and the then corrupt mayor McKanzy was executed by the American army shortly afterwards. The city was now back in the hands of the state.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The events seemed to have affected not only the city but also the countryside, because the gold veins in the mines dried up and the river no longer brought any glittering stones with it. The once rich trading city became poorer and poorer. Where there was one joy and confidence, there was now more and more despair. This is how the city got its nickname Devil&amp;rsquo;s Creek. Only those who ventured deep into the mines could find gold - if they came out again. Those who made it reported strange creatures that have since found their home there. Soon hardly any people dared to venture into the widely ramified mine systems and the city was forgotten by history. You and your small group will end up in Devil&amp;rsquo;s Creek. Maybe you can get to the bottom of this and bring the city back to its former size.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The setting is enriched with &amp;quot;low fantasy&amp;quot; elements. You take on the role of three adventurers, take jobs in the local saloon and roam the countless mines of Fortune&amp;rsquo;s Creek, which were once rich in gold veins and are now inhabited by all sorts of creatures and other rabble.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;WHAT DO I NEED TO PLAY?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To play, you need a piece of squared paper, a pencil, at least three 6-sided dice and one 4-sided dice. You should also have the attached cards printed out and arranged in a stack ready to hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HOW TO PLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Adventures in Devil&amp;rsquo;s Creek can best be classified under the category of &amp;quot;Dungeon Diver&amp;quot;. You put together a group of three different characters (Brawler, Valkyrie, Voodoo Priest, White Witch, Gunslinger or Bounty Hunter) and set off to explore the local mines. Before or between the explorations, supplies can be replenished in the city, quests can be accepted or you can just relax and heal your wounds. It can be played by 1 to 3 players. The opponents are rolled and their behavior is determined by the drawing of cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAMEPLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After creating the characters, you take a piece of squared paper, on which you draw the spaces that have been thrown out of the mine. The use of a DIN A5 sheet is recommended. Dice out the first room and draw it in the middle on one edge. Then you roll the dice on the space and resolve the encounters. If you defeat a boss, you have cleared the mine. The mine systems are reset and rerolled with each visit.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="3" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1020" value="Exploration" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3096" value="Drawing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="59218" value="Category: Dungeon Crawler" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="148987" value="Tobias Gossler" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="148987" value="Tobias Gossler" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="52688" value="Bossbecher &amp; Ladymug Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>