<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="376293">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RxBKNLpdJ6Tx-MoyPaMhug__thumb/img/oW8N9iKdbg2qYrDFojRVg5JsNvQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7241651.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RxBKNLpdJ6Tx-MoyPaMhug__original/img/byz15RjOdXVl-gxS-3O-bUtN7hg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7241651.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="TKG ARENA: The Tome Weavers" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A Tome Weaver interlaces the different magical spell fragments obtained by the Arcane Scribes into a transcendent manuscript, arming the Battle mages with such ruthless combos that easily turn the tide in any war of magic. The intricacies and harmonies involved in such an enchantment are often insanely complex and requires not only a deep knowledge of the elements but also a strategic cognizance of how well all this fits together in an impossible manifest and more often than not in the midst of a chaotic and unexpected confrontation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TKG ARENA: Tome Weaver is a game set up for 2 - 5 players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning Condition&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to compile a valuable collection of spells into a volume designed to unleash a volley of spells in a battle. The value of the collection is determined by number of HARMONY points scored as it is an indication of its stability. The player with the most HARMONY points wins the game when it ends.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ending Condition&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when all cards are played from the hands of all players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setup&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A player starts the game by designating the following areas: A draw deck area O, a discard area X and five adjoining spaces that is marked A, B, C, D and E.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;X    A    B    C    D    E     O&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Determine the starting player by drawing cards from the deck of spell cards. The player who draws the highest face value starts first and turn order is clockwise. In case of a tie, the tied players keep drawing till the tie is broken with a player drawing a higher face value. The drawn cards are put back into the deck.&amp;#10;     Shuffle all 36 spell cards and deal 9 / 8 / 7 / 6 cards to 2 / 3 / 4 / 5 players respectively. E.g. For 3 players, each player receives 8 cards at the start.&amp;#10;     Place 1 face up spell card at each of the spaces A, B, C, D and E.&amp;#10;     The rest of the cards are placed faced down as a stack in O.&amp;#10;     Each player should also designate a small area in front of himself / herself to group cards of the same colour together for easy scoring later.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On each player&amp;rsquo;s turn &amp;#10;&amp;#10;     The player may exchange a card by first discarding a card from their hand to X and drawing the top face down card from O before putting it into his / her hand. If the stack at O runs out of cards, shuffle any discarded cards at X to form a new stack at O to draw from.&amp;#10;     Next, the player must either claim one of the cards placed in A, B, C, D or E or to play one of his / her cards face down in front of himself / herself. These cards are part of the player&amp;rsquo;s collection and will be scored at the end of the game.&amp;#10;     To claim a card placed in A, B, C, D or E, the player need to play either a card from his hand of the SAME COLOUR as the placed card or a card with a LOWER face value than the placed card. The played card replaces the placed card in A, B, C, D or E and the placed card is then claimed by the player as part of his / her personal collection displayed in front of himself / herself.&amp;#10;     If all players have only 1 remaining card left in their hands, the game ends and scoring begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scoring&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are three types of scoring.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     First Scoring: Check the colour of the remaining card and ignore its face value. Locate all other cards of the same colour in the collection and find the lowest face value among all these other cards. For each other card of this colour, score HARMONY points according to this lowest face value. The remaining card is not included as a card in the total number of cards considered for this purpose. E.g. The remaining card in a player&amp;rsquo;s hand is ASHW with face value 1. There are other 3 ASHW cards in the collection, with face values 3, 5, 9. The power points scored will be 3 x 3 = 9 points. If there are only 2 ASHW cards with face values, 5 and 9, the power points scored will be 2 x 5 = 10 points. &amp;#10;     Second Scoring: For each card in the collection that bears the same colour as the card that remains in spaces A, B, D and E, score 1 POWER point. For each card in the collection that bears the same number as the face value of the card that remains in space C, score 3 POWER points. The last remaining card used in the first scoring is part of the collection and its colour and face value is considered for this second scoring.&amp;#10;     Third Scoring: Each faced down cards is scored as 2 HARMONY points.&amp;#10;     The final score of each player is the sum of these 3 scorings.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="111" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="112" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="113" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="114" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="115" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2987" value="Hidden Victory Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="25573" value="Game: TKG ARENA" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="68622" value="Chub Tan" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="68622" value="Chub Tan" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="25221" value="The TKG Comic Circle" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>