<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="377361">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Quest for the Lost Pixel: Deities of Time" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>New Expansions&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Deities of Time is the FIANL expansion for Quest for the Lost Pixel. This expansion (just like Hack Slash Loot) comes with a bonus expansion called GAME OVER.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Deities of Time&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Deities of Time comes with a new time deck and deity cards. These can help heal you through your exploration, but come with restrictions that your hero must follow in order to stay faithful to your deity.&amp;#10;Village Game Mode&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This expansion also comes with a new Village Game Mode for solo players. This allows the player to build a Village in between floors. Each new build comes with special abilities that will help aid the hero throughout their journey. Building these buildings will also give you Crown Points. These Crown Points will give you a score at the end of the game. Try to beat your last score or a friends high score.&amp;#10;Nightmare Mode&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There is now a new harder mode for veterans of the game or those of you that enjoy a challenge. Tweaks to the Artifacts, Spells, and even how you attack with different elemental damage will give the player more decisions to make.&amp;#10;GAME OVER&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Want more stuff? Well here it is, more stuff. This includes more cards for your decks, replaces (and adds to) your potion deck, and provides 2 new Heroes - The Chanter and Construct&amp;#10;Rainbow Rift&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One of the most requested add-ons to the game has been dungeon variety. Although this isn't a huge variety of dungeons, here is the new Rainbow Rift. A fun yet challenging new area with goofy monsters and high rewards and XP.&amp;#10;A HUGE THANK YOU&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Again, this is the final expansion for Quest for the Lost Pixel and I just wanted to say a HUGE thank you to everyone who has supported this game and me throughout the years. The game came out in 2015 and just like the &amp;lsquo;Little Train that Could&amp;rsquo;, this game kept chugging. It truly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as well known if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for Geek Gamers and Dungeon Dive. Also, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t give enough thanks to some of this game&amp;rsquo;s biggest fans such as David Waller, bark, Prinz Eugen, Scrap Baby, Hlorridi, Nico Farhat, funkboyg, Dani Miller, Jack the Flowerchild, Away111, LordAmaury, coned, Carol (the love of my life), and so many others. Again, thank you all so much and I truly hope you enjoy the new content. There is truly an infinite amount of replayability in this game now. But can YOU get to the Lost Pixel?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="307161" value="Quest for the Lost Pixel" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="49781" value="Gummy Bear Factory Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="6" />
			<average value="8.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.25831" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="70" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="4" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>