<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="377572">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XaDMJwTpnpVMd8sasPlnQA__thumb/img/Evgk2lguMlMt890BY8k9PyM-zPk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7299621.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/XaDMJwTpnpVMd8sasPlnQA__original/img/QVyZ6gP8ANcZ5QzejJjal5IHzVY=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7299621.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Project Transylvania" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The game is set in a medium fantasy, dark themed, medieval world. The aim of the game is to encapsulate local folk stories and take you through an unique journey where you can rediscover old legends as you might know them. The game takes inspiration from some TTRPG games but at its core, it comes with its own set of unique combat rules and creatures that keeps the combat realistic and dynamic. The game can be played around a table with as many people wishing to participate but, I personally advise you to keep it up to a maximum of 5 players for a better immersion. I hope I piqued your interest and that you&amp;rsquo;ll stick around!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;bull; How is it played?&amp;#10;- Like most TTRPG games, you will need your character sheet that you will compile with the help of the source book where you will find all necessary information about the game mechanics and it will basically teach you how to play the game. Reading through, you will find out the various combat mechanics that are divided in chapters:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;STATISTICS:&amp;#10;- There is a list of statistics that you may invest points in and they all boost your character's strength, agility, dexterity, spirit and other. There are 9 statistics in total and some of them have various functions in order to keep the list small and compact.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;COMBAT:&amp;#10;- First thing first, you have to know that there are 4 types of damage and each benefits from a said &amp;quot;Main&amp;quot; statistic out of the 4 main ones. For example, there is Slicing Damage on a weapon, it means that your agility will serve as a damage multiplier for that kind of weapon. This will prevent that dexterous rogue to pickup a great sword out of the blue and use it as effectively as a fighter. There is no rule for what you can equip so you can let your imagination run wild with the actual 23 available subclasses, over 120 magical abilities and many many more to come, you can make your own unique character and set it free into the dark ages of mythical Transylvania. You will find a lot more in the source book about bleeding effects, wounds and how they can turn the tide of the combat, a progression chart where each level, your character is allowed x points that you can spend in increasing your statistic's value thus making your character stronger... There is a lot but, let's move on...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;PROFESSIONS&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your character can learn professions that will allow them to gain access to certain consumables and more. Professions are meant to bring to the table unique interactions between players that can alter the course of the story drastically, from the Thaumaturgist rogue that can either create poisons or cure them, to the alchemist vedmak who can transmute certain weapon materials, these are all things that as you progress and level up, you will be able to unlock.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MAIN STORY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game starts you off slowly, with your character not knowing about the existence of the supernatural and then slowly discovering of it's existence, you will find yourself in a situation where you've seen things and experienced but can't share them with other people freely as freedom of speech was not so common back then and being accused of witchcraft was quite common for even the most ridiculous things, a situation where you have to measure your words carefully and having to find a way to survive and make moral choices that will shape the world around you, in other words, you are the story, you make the world shift with your actions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ENEMIES:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are all sorts of monsters and beasts, some of them, are inspired off of mythical creatures from local folk stories that I grew up with as a child, like iele or moroi, pricolici and more, but, there are also simple creatures that you can find in the wilds, simple, but very dangerous sience the game tries to achieve a realistical combat feel, so, one can only imagine, if a simple wild animal is that strong, how strong can a werewolf be... or a vampire... Guess you'll find out soon. I just hope that whatever it is you decide to do while playing the game you're having fun!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2020" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="18" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2027" value="Storytelling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="4" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>