<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="379928">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/fqXTvOepdCvmKDyFKObTKA__thumb/img/nBwXX2p2jDZvlATcDyGm2LP1S1Q=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7329970.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/fqXTvOepdCvmKDyFKObTKA__original/img/xRE60kTcQT3iXONSEBmUNX_-VJM=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7329970.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fall of Lumen" />
			
						                           
						               													<description> Listen pals. We did not fight the Void to make Lumen even brighter. The flying city has proven worthless, making a profit from scrolls and abandoning us to our empty fate. Can't you figure out the Eternals on their terrace eating grapes and enjoying our show against the Seraphs? &amp;#10;Guess what? The mortals survived and pushed back the Void. We have shown the exit to the Seraphs. What about the Eternals now?&amp;#10;- Common talks in Gon'Mar Taverns -&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fall of Lumen is a stand-alone tabletop game based on deck-building and tableau building. It is a follow-up of Legends of Void. &amp;#10;Fall of Lumen takes place after the Void battles. The Outer Lands are devastated after years of fights against the Seraphs. The people of the Outer Lands are willing to return to a peaceful time and rebuild their houses and society. &amp;#10;But a small group of rebels is sick of Lumen and works in the shadow to infiltrate saboteurs in the flying city and make it fall. They are known as the Keepers, members of the ruling faction before the arrival of the Eternals. The Keepers were banned from their home long ago, but thanks to the dimensional fracture caused by the Void, they are back in the Outer Lands.&amp;#10;Their plan is as easy as it is lethal. Recall as many Keepers from the Inner Worlds to the Outer Lands and sneak them on Lumen as saboteurs. When they are enough, they will hack the anti-gravity system, and the flying city will become the falling one.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Fall of Lumen, you will compete to be the most influential Hero, who will be determined as the one who has infiltrated most saboteurs on Lumen. Each of you plays a Hero and is supported by a Faction of the Outer Lands.&amp;#10;You will move your Hero across the Outer Lands and spend their skills to gather resources such as Gold, Mana, Mithril, Dark Matter, and Genasi. Through these resources, you will acquire traits, learn spells, buy trinkets, retrieve artifacts, and hire followers to help your cause and improve your skills.&amp;#10;Finally, with enough skills, you can restore the dimensional connection to an Inner World and bring back a Keeper stuck there. To unlock a portal and reach an Inner World, you need a different combination of skills: Deception, Wit, Fighting, Wizardry, and Void (the most precious and versatile skill).&amp;#10;Meanwhile, Lumen will try to ruin your plan with the help of the Hammer patrols and other traitors, such as the Church of Teara, Justicar Esperia, and the Keyi Varh.&amp;#10;As the game gets closer to the end, your interest will switch from rescuing Keepers from the Inner Worlds to sneaking them on Lumen, which is the goal of the game and the most source of victory points. You can infiltrate a saboteur in any of the five districts of Lumen: Informers, Engineers, Fighters, Wizards, and Voyagers. Each saboteur will grant you a recurring or immediate income and victory points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The main mechanics are:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Deck-building: the deck is your main resource; improving it by buying better cards will make you perform better.&amp;nbsp;&amp;#10;     Open drafting: market elements are face-up, so you can plan what to buy and collect the resources you need to get it, but you have to get there before the other players.&amp;#10;     Tableau Building: in addition to your deck, you will hire Followers and buy Trinkets for your Hero. They are valuable because you can always count on them and not depend on the draws like cards in your deck. You can use them once per turn, and then they get exhausted.&amp;nbsp;&amp;#10;     Area Movement: the game board is divided into eight regions, irregularly shaped. Regions grant access to gather actions, markets, and Challenge locations. During the game, you will move your Hero many times from one region to another to access what you need most at that moment of the game. &amp;nbsp;&amp;#10;     Once-per-game abilities: some cards have very powerful abilities, but you can use them only once per game, then they are exiled from the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game will feature a Solo mode and a 2-player cooperative variant.&amp;#10;Fall of Lumen has No Take That elements. The interaction between players is indirect. It mainly comes from solving challenges, market acquisitions, and timing on infiltrating saboteurs on Lumen. The more saboteurs are on Lumen, the higher the cost to send a new one. &amp;#10;Our estimated complexity is 3.2 on the BGG scale (max 5.0).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="150" />
						               				<minplaytime value="80" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="150" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1097" value="Travel" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2912" value="Contracts" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2846" value="Once-Per-Game Abilities" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="27646" value="Mechanism: Tableau Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5666" value="Players: Games with Solitaire Rules" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="47199" value="Twoid Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="23" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="3.25" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>