<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="380302">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/aOjiC3H5zvyWkW2DcaWBEw__thumb/img/dfeeeQIkg6RC_Amu8fC2WoqyBtQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7513788.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/aOjiC3H5zvyWkW2DcaWBEw__original/img/FSHL3J5-id_hJw4BCDfxPCckves=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7513788.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Pick Up Artists" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Have you ever wanted to fall in love at a very legitimate and not-at-all-sketchy art university? In the year 19XX, Johnathan Dromathan invented Art. It went well. He then used the funds to open up the first art academy, which you - the player - are attending...just to ignore your education in the pursuit of &amp;quot;love.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GOAL&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Romance the group's love interest of choice by gaining the most affection via end of game cards, maximizing stats, and successfully beating the romantic interest's current affection threshold.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAMPEPLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning of the game, 2-4 players each agree upon a game mode and love interest, placing their pawns in the center of the map on the Quad space. Each player gets a player mat and 8 stat trackers to place on the corresponding stat track. Players then take turns rolling the movement dice and moving that many spaces landing on one of several different type of spaces, skipping over spaces that have players already occupying them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- Trait increase space: this will increase one of the 7 different types of traits&amp;#10;- Action card space: this allows a player to draw the top card of the action deck and add it to their hand.&amp;#10;- Event space: this space allows a player to reveal the top card of the event deck and resolve one of three possible effects based off the required stat(s).&amp;#10;- Trait Buildings: These buildings allow multiple players to land on them, and players can choose to stop early if they can reach it with less moves than the die allows. When a player ends their turn in one, the corresponding trait is increased by 1.&amp;#10;- Romance Buildings: Similar to trait buildings, except there is no stat increase, but these are the only buildings a love interest will be in.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Before ending their move on a non-building space, a player puts their colored tile over that space, taking the reward and stopping any future uses of that space.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once per day if a trait is at rank 2 or higher, a player can use its special perk ability if the trigger is activated. The traits and their perks are:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;- Charm: If you roll a 1 on your movement roll, you may use this perk and treat the result as a 3 instead.&amp;#10;- Kindness: If you land on a space that has already been claimed, you may use this perk and reveal the space and claim the reward, leaving the player tile as it was afterwards.&amp;#10;- Brawn: If you would land on a space occupied by another player, instead of jumping over them, you may use this perk and send them back to the Quad instead.&amp;#10;- Smarts: When you reveal an Event card, you may use this perk to discard it and draw again taking the new result.&amp;#10;- Tenacity: If another player rolls a 6, you may use this perk and immediately move one space, taking any rewards as normal.&amp;#10;- Humor: If you would draw one or more action cards, you may use this perk to draw another action card.&amp;#10;- Mojo (1): After you roll the affection die, you may use this perk to re-roll it taking the new result.&amp;#10;- Mojo (2): After rolling the movement die during an affection roll, you may use this perk to re-roll it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(Note: Mojo has two perks which can each be used once per day)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Furthermore during the course of the day, once per day players that enter the same building as their love interest may attempt an affection roll. First the player takes the affection die and rolls it. Each side has a 1, 2, 3, or combination of those numbers, indicating which of the love interests favored stats will be added to the roll. Then they take the movement die and roll it, adding the stat(s) used with the movement die and getting their total affection roll. If this number beats the love interest's affection threshold for the day, they succeed and move the affection track up one space gaining two affection points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each love interest has 3 different favored traits, one of which is their most favorite, a schedule that changes what building they are in each day, an increasing affection threshold to beat, and a unique quirk. Quirks affect any players that are romantically pursuing the love interest - some in positive ways and some in negative ways.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play continues clockwise until all players have taken their 5th turn. The players are moved back to the Quad and the love interest changes building based of their unique schedule. The new round then starts and play continues as normal for 4 more rounds. After the 5th turn of the 5th round, play ends and 1 bonus card per player is revealed, each with a sub goal awarding 2 affection points to the player who best completes the criteria. In case of a tie, all players tied are awarded full points. Players then add 2 affection for each successful affection roll they made during the course of the game, and 1 more affection for each of stat that is at rank 4 except for Mojo.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player with the most affection is the winner of the game and the love interest's heart!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1101" value="Video Game Theme" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2850" value="Events" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2837" value="Interrupts" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2853" value="Stat Check Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2849" value="Tech Trees / Tech Tracks" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="70948" value="Digital Implementations: Tabletopia" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="151426" value="CJ Eli" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="151427" value="Brandon Lopez (I)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="151425" value="Michael Russoniello" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="151424" value="Ross Eliot" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="3" />
			<average value="9.33333" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.942809" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="4" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>