<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="382102">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mystic Elements" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Milleniums ago, the seven emperors has agreed to divide the world according to the spheres of they control and magic they use to run their empires.   &amp;#10;  &amp;#10;They were extracting the mystical energy from the universe and used it to keep their worlds separated that there was almost impossible to travel among them. It was artificial state of balance and natural magic flow usage was restricted. Their folks lived in peace and the magic was inherited through the dynasties of each of these 7 founders.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But they have missed one thing. Balance was kept for thousands of years, but it was not perfect. There were one aspect of magic, which could not be used for keeping the balance, the most dark, unpredictable and chaotic energy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This magic energy aspect accumulated over the years, becoming stronger, requesting more effort from the seven powers. The heirs of kings noticed to problem but suspecting each other from breaching the balance to increase their own potential profit. Finally the inhabitants started to feel the problems themselves. The magic used originally for comfort of the citizens were needed more to keep the borders. Reality breaches started to appear frequently.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The heirs of original seven emperors did not manage to keep people content. Heretic voices raised about connecting the worlds back together.  However nobody knew what's exactly going on.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One day the massive amount of chaotic energy accumulated for millenias bursted out like gigantic flood from a dam and caused reality breaches that crushed all artificial boundaries. The energy started to flow uncontrollably and magic abilities started to appear randomly through the population.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There is nobody in control and world is balancing on the edge of chaos. Who can combine the aspects of mystic energy to estabilish a peace and gather the mightiest army to conquer the new world?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game contains 120 cards, 15 cards from each of eight colors representing the elements. At the beggining of the game the player choose combination of three colors which determines their 45 card deck to play with.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning of player's turn, they draw up to 7 cards and then get an increasing amount of energy of certain color to play the cards, summon spells, warriors and creatures.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Units in battle can fight each other or damage the player which causes removing the cards from the top of their deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first player which runs out of the cards in the deck loses the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2024" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="76" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="77" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="78" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="79" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="80" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="153908" value="Jaroslav Kameň" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51166" value="JerryLabs Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>