<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="382613">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Sliders" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Whilst some Winter Sports enthusiasts might disagree the Slider event down a narrow,twisting and banked ice track isn't really a spectator sport. With only one sled on the run at any one time each might seem very similar to all the others give or take the odd 'drama' of a brush with an ice wall, or a trip too high up a banked curve, etc. But one aspect makes every run different and exciting - the intermediate Time Checks that are flashed onto large electronic scoreboards for all to see, so that everyone is aware just how close the sled currently on the run is to the run-leader, how much time needs to be made up in the remaining Sectors. Take those time checks away and, dare I suggest, you have a boring spectacle for live and television spectators?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But all this is lucky for us when presenting a replay simulation of the sport.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In sliding events start speed is vital. After 50 metres we get the first time check and that reflects how quickly the sled has been launched down the runway - in the team events that involves strength and running speed and a quick and tidy entry into the sled and settlement into the seats, in individual events 'pushing off' with feet or gloved hands.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But also the start is all about getting the sled moving as quickly as possible on its journey down the course, for what speed is achieved in that first 50 metres is the momentum that will build up over the run as the weight of sled and crew and the laws of gravity get to work. In 'Sliders' we provide a Start Rating, based on actual start times, which not only sets the first segment of elapsed time for the run but also determines what we call Raw Speed (momentum) which is carried forward to the next Sector. So a good start will bring two advantages, a low Elapsed Time and a good Raw Speed carry forward. Start Ratings range from 0 to 10.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Driver Skill (the range is 0 to 4) can be used in two ways. From Sector 2 onwards one DS can be used to increase the RS by 3 before the time for that Sector is determined, or used to improve the sled's Stability (ST) by 2. This represents the driver's ability to keep to the best racing line, and to ensure that the sled is 'in shape' and stable. The increase of 3 RS converts to a time saving of 0.03 secs., but again, as RS is carried forward, that is 0.03 secs. for this and each of the remaining Sectors, so gaining that advantage high up on the track is reflected all the way down. Stability is both a driver and team function, with the driver dictating the sled's line and the crew using their weight to keep the sled at the best angle and maintaining the narrow runners in best contact with the track. High up the course stability isn't really a problem, but as speeds build steadily down the run it becomes a vital factor and there is less time to get everything right. Once a sled starts to get 'out of shape', like RS, it is carried forward to the next Sector and as each Sector has a Stability Check it becomes progressively more of a problem, maybe needing the expenditure of a valuable DS to help correct the situation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Initially the Stability Rating can be as high as 8, and until that is reduced there is unlikely to be a problem, but with lower Ratings failure of the Stability Check is likely and this will eat further into the ST figure and also reduce RS. 'Braking' (most sleds have some form of crude brakes) is a last resort for RS is automatically reduced by 20 in regaining some (1D6) STABILITY points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="66" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="67" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="68" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="69" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="70" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5732" value="Sports: Winter Sports" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="278" value="Terry Goodchild" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1259" value="Lambourne Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>