<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="382961">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Z-0E8C9Zc0Pdj969Aavfmg__thumb/img/8X7N-k3g9y0H_i-TWGliXXl05kM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7429021.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Z-0E8C9Zc0Pdj969Aavfmg__original/img/quzk05t1zWnzLC4RxBFchZaxnxc=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7429021.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="D100 Dungeon: The Rune Forge" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Rune Forge adventure book introduces a different way of playing D100 Dungeon, and will give you choices much like a choose your own adventure game. It uses all of the D100 Dungeon rules from the main rulebook with a few modifications. Also included are new rules called &amp;quot;Random Dungeons&amp;quot;, that can be implemented into any of your games; whether you're playing a quest, campaign, or using the World Builder expansion.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You will need the D100 Dungeonrule book to use this book&amp;#10;&amp;#10;THE RUNE FORGE ADVENTURE&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Deep in the mountains to the northeast of the Arcane Tower is the Ruin Forge. It was built by the dwarves exactly 100 years after they completed the Arcane Tower. Work began in the year -2489 and took just nine years to complete. The Council of Seven, who commissioned its construction, chose its location beneath the Irontorn mountains, in an effort to hide it away from preying eyes, but alas it fell foul to a powerful demon named Vakanar. Vakanar is one of a handful of demon lords that first emerged from the Demon Gate after its construction in -2790. He craved a huge arcane power and set off on a mission to capture the White Tower. Along the way he summoned a horde of minions, but when he reach the Arcane Tower he learnt of a more powerful structure being built, The Rune Forge. He changed course and waited for its completion. Whilst the dwarves dug, he planned the attack and on the day the Rune Forge was finished, Vakanar and his minions devoured its caverns, spreading torture and fire to its darkest corners. Many dwarves escaped with their lives, but an unlucky few were left behind and were tortured to death to reveal the secret of the nine rune crystals the arcane council placed within its depths. One crystal for each scripture of magic and two more for balancing the arcane power of the forge.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Numerous battles took place to regain its control, but alas the Arcane Council and their battle mages failed to breach its depths. Then, after the Great Icing of -2300 and The Melting of -1400, the location of the Ruin Forge became lost. The Lair of Vakanar (another name for the lost forge) is now where the demon lord and his minions use the power of the nine arcane crystals to sustain and power their existence, preventing them from diminishing back to the demon realm.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You have heard this tale a thousand times, as it's told in every tavern across Terra. Warming your back to the camp fire, you keep watch and recount the story you overheard a few days ago in The Broken Claw, a scruffy little inn at the heart of Blitsworth&amp;hellip;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;By chance, you have found the entrance to the Rune Forge and must now delve its depths, find the forge and use its power to enchant an item. If you can present the enchanted item to the Council of Seven at the White Tower, it will prove you have found the location of their Lost Forge and secure a handsome reward.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1117" value="Book" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2055" value="Paper-and-Pencil" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="76455" value="Game: D100 Dungeon" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="237031" value="D100 Dungeon" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="70079" value="Martin Knight" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>