<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="384212">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Atmosfear: 30th Anniversary Edition" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Atmosfear, the iconic horror-themed board game, has returned in its 30th Anniversary Edition, and it's as thrilling and immersive as ever! This modernized version of the classic game comes with updated components (through the Kickstarter campaign) and a nostalgic nod to the original, making it a must-have for both longtime fans and newcomers alike.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components:&amp;#10;The 30th Anniversary Edition of Atmosfear comes with high-quality components that are visually stunning and tactilely pleasing. The game includes a beautifully illustrated game board, six character pawns to collect keys for, multiple types of cards (Time, Fatez and Chance), and 2x 6D with the Gatekeeper's head in them! The game now comes with a QR code to find the video of the game on Vimeo instead of a VHS or DVD featuring the iconic Gatekeeper, who sets the tone for the game with his sinister presence. The components are durable and well-designed, adding to the overall immersion and enjoyment of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay:&amp;#10;The gameplay of Atmosfear remains true to the original, with some modern updates that add to the excitement. Players take on the roles of six different characters, each with their own strengths and weaknesses, as they navigate through the various regions of the board, trying to collect keys and make their way to the center to face the Gatekeeper. The video is used as a timer, adding a sense of urgency to the game, and the Gatekeeper's appearances on the screen are both thrilling and chilling (and loud!).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One of the standout features of the 30th Anniversary Edition is the addition of new event cards, which bring a fresh level of unpredictability to the game. These cards can affect players in various ways, such as forcing them to swap places, lose turns, or face challenges that can alter the course of the game. The combination of the video, cards, and unique character abilities creates a dynamic and engaging gameplay experience that keeps players on their toes and eager for more.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Theme and Atmosphere:&amp;#10;Atmosfear is all about creating a spooky and immersive atmosphere, and the 30th Anniversary Edition does not disappoint. The game's theme of horror and suspense is brought to life through the video, which features the iconic Gatekeeper, who taunts and challenges players throughout the game. The game board is richly illustrated with dark and eerie artwork that adds to the overall ambiance. The combination of the components, gameplay, and theme work together seamlessly to create an immersive and thrilling experience that will keep players on the edge of their seats.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fun Factor:&amp;#10;Atmosfear 30th Anniversary Edition is an absolute blast to play. The combination of the video, event cards, and unique character abilities create a highly interactive and unpredictable gameplay experience that keeps players engaged and entertained from start to finish. The sense of urgency created by the timer adds to the excitement, and the overall atmosphere of the game is thrilling and immersive. The game also encourages player interaction, with opportunities for strategic decision-making, alliances, and betrayals, making for a highly enjoyable and memorable gaming experience.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Overall:&amp;#10;Atmosfear 30th Anniversary Edition is a fantastic board game that successfully revitalizes the classic horror-themed game for a modern audience. The components, gameplay, and immersive atmosphere make for an engaging and thrilling experience that will keep players coming back for more. Whether you're a longtime fan of the original or new to the world of Atmosfear, this anniversary edition is a must-have addition to your board game collection. Get ready to face your fears and embrace the darkness with Atmosfear 30th Anniversary Edition!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2840" value="Action/Event" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2882" value="Elapsed Real Time Ending" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2820" value="Semi-Cooperative Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="57943" value="Game: Atmosfear" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="5641" value="Nightmare" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="10900" value="Nightmare II" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1408" value="Phillip Tanner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1315" value="A Couple 'A Cowboys" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="19" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>