<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="385581">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Antares" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In the 14th solar month of the year 2235, the merchant ship Antares encountered an unknown alien entity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During their return trip home, the crew diverted from their heading to investigate an archaeological find on a distant moon, orbiting a small binary system, outside the Alpha Centauri cluster. The site was found to contain artifacts from an ancient race that had long vanished from that system. Among the ruins the crew uncovered an alien chrysalis. Believing it to be one of the artifacts it was unknowingly taken on board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Six days after their departure from the moon the alien was released from the chrysalis, and it was free and roaming the ship. The crew made preparations to abandon ship, believing that the alien was hostile. They were correct in their assumption.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Using the collected audio and video surveillance data from on board the ship the events that followed have been pieced together.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This is the record of the events that occurred on the Antares while the crew tried desperately to abandon ship.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play out the crew's final hour as they attempt to abandon ship. Antares is geared for easy solitaire play, but can be expanded to up to 7 players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Antares is a thematic, space horror game. The actions of the crew are up to you, and the choices you make may well determine who survives, and escapes the doomed vessel Antares, and who falls victim to the alien lifeform.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Antares is the first game in the Antares series. Telling the first chapter of the story of the doomed ship Antares, and its alien cargo.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Antares is playable solo or co-op.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game play&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Build the Antares using the Cabin and Corridor tiles. The ship must have all corridor ends connected to Cabins. Different builds of the Antares offer different levels of difficulty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Choose your crew selecting one side from each of the seven crewmember cards. Each crewmember has their own unique ability and choice of two starting locations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Complete the Navigation, Reactor, &amp;amp; Mainframe Access objectives. Spending an action in the Bridge, Reactor Room, or Mainframe Access cabins will advance the matching counter 1 spot forward. Use of the Air Ducts can expedite movement through the ship, but the alien lifeform has found them to be useful as well.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Collect enough O2 Canisters and Spacesuits for any surviving crewmembers before they head to the Escape Craft. Flame throwers may be found in the Cargo Hold, and can be used to ward off an alien attack. Each encounter with the alien lifeform can cause the crew to experience Fear, Terror, or Paranoia.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Avoid the alien lifeform. As the crew complete objectives and collect precious items they are constantly at risk of attack from the alien. After each action performed a Scan card must be drawn which will indicate if the alien attacks, or if the crew is safe for one more round.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Escape if the crew manages to complete all objects they may regroup in the Escape Pod, and execute the Delta Launch Code to escape the doomed Antares merchant vessel.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="73039" value="Category: Print-on-Demand" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51843" value="Ringstrue Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>