<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="385607">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Paria" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You are an outcast. The society you were part of turned its back on you and disowned you. They say you committed a heinous crime or, perhaps, were accused of a mistake too serious to be overlooked. You were cast out of your life, denied help and ostracised.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now, you walk through a hostile world trying to regain the shreds of your lost dignity. You are willing to risk your life in an almost impossible mission to vindicate yourself in the eyes of those who were once your own. But life alone is very difficult and the challenges you face threaten to overtake you with every step you take.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Paria, by Cezar Capacle, we will live the intense experience of a solitaire role-playing game that proposes us to enter a setting that we can create completely at random. Dare to explore a world that you will have to create as you build your character and guide his or her steps through an emotional story that is aimed at deciding if you will achieve redemption or if you will be lost forever in solitude.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Create your own game world by rolling on the setting tables and with the help of the oracle tables.&amp;#10;Develop each scene by delving into your character, the causes that led to him or her becoming an outcast, and the elements that appear in the narrative.&amp;#10;You can replay Pariah as many times as you like, as your own imagination, the world creation system and the oracles will ensure that your story never repeats itself.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51845" value="Cursed Ink" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>