<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="385758">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Jeu du Skating-Rink" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Jeu du Skating-Rink represents another form of Goose variant: the introduction of two tracks, each of 63 spaces. The players divide themselves into two opposing teams, each playing on a different track. Additional interest is provided by crossing the tracks: at these points, if the two teams come together, they &amp;rdquo;come to grief and fall&amp;rdquo; and both must start the game afresh. Other hazards are marked by red or blue numerals on the respective tracks, both tracks having the same set of hazards, though not in corresponding order. The hazards are illustrated by scenes near the space&amp;rsquo;s number. For example, &amp;quot;skater taking a rest - wait twice his turn to throw the dice&amp;quot; occurs at space 43 blue, and space 10 red; &amp;rdquo;a player who asks for a match and passes one turn&amp;rdquo; occurs at blue 35 and red 47; while &amp;quot;lost his purse - each player pays him 2 to help him out of his difficulty&amp;quot; occurs at blue 27 and red 28. The game is won by reaching or surpassing space 63, so reverse overthrows are not played. There are no spaces in which the goose-doubling rule applies; in fact, the track length is the only connection with the classic Goose game. The firm of Saussine was one of the major French manufacturers of games between its founding in 1860 and closure in the 1960s. Their games are often original (the founder, Leon Saussine, held several patents) and are always attractive, making good use of chromolithography, as in the present exhibit. As well as catering for the French market, they aimed at an international clientele, here indicated by the fact that the separate rule sheet is printed in both French and English.&amp;#10;(Adrian Seville)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1900" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="9" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7863" value="Saussine Editeur" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>