<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="385715">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/79SFZ340jDWFC5n3mAKXAw__thumb/img/s7lo4esl8023yTU5ahtnujt1p1s=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7546549.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/79SFZ340jDWFC5n3mAKXAw__original/img/ghqNzR5j_9GDekYgrbqH3mh4Kjk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7546549.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Metal Melee" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Metal Melee is a multiplayer card game for 2-4 players that uses AI-generated artwork and strategic card abilities. Players use cards depicting Robots and Mechanical Titans to assemble an army and fight each other on the battlefield of Mechs. The objective is to defeat all other players' Bots and collect the most Power Shards from the Bots and Titans you destroy, emerging as the Metal Monarch and the champion of all things metal.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Featuring 176 playable cards, where no two Bot, Titan, Utility, and Pilot cards are the same, all with beautiful artwork and abilities geared for maximum mechanical mayhem. Metal Melee is for avid players of competitive card games and new players alike. Our mission is to develop a game with enough depth and variety to keep you coming back for more, all with a short and comprehensive rulebook so that you can break it out even at your more casual game night and introduce new players to a match of robot fisticuffs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The first to collect 12 Power Shards from destroyed bots is the winner unless a player is the first to raise an army of 6 Bots and 1 Titan. Players start the game by selecting between three game modes and building their decks in either a random build, grid draft, or one collectively shared deck. Players then choose a Power Plant, which has unique abilities to be used throughout the game and generates Energy for you to use each round. Improve your Energy Production by drawing Energy Crystal cards from a stack of cards adjacent to your deck called your Power Mine and then attaching them to your Power Plant. Alternatively, you may discard them from your hand to your Junkyard for a faster boost of Energy to be used that same turn. Play Bots and Titans from your hand onto your field to assemble your army. (Your field is made up of a front row that can hold 3 Melee Bots, and a back row of 3 Ranged Bots, with Support Bots that can go in either row. Titans are placed adjacent to these rows in their own designated space.) Utility cards can be played to help you maintain an edge over your opponents and protect your own field, and Pilot cards can be attacked by your Bots or Titans to grant them extra strengths or new abilities. Combat damage is determined one card at a time, with each card on your field selecting to do a basic attack or use any activated abilities. The player who reduces an opponent's Bot or Titan to 0 Health Points earns Power Shards equal to the value indicated on the destroyed card. Metal Melee is easy to pick up and learn, but challenging to master with its wide range of card interactions where no two Bot, Titan, Utility, and Pilot cards are the same.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;While we celebrate the advancements and achievements of modern artificial intelligence and have made it a feature of the AI Edition of our game, rest assured, this could not have been developed without the countless hours of testing, iteration, prototyping, and the most essential ingredient; flesh-and-blood (with some sweat and tears too). We are also releasing Metal Melee: Pixeled Edition at the same time, with handmade art in the style of 80's arcade-style gaming featuring pixel-art-themed cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2857" value="Card Play Conflict Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2841" value="Command Cards" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2978" value="Grid Coverage" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2853" value="Stat Check Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2874" value="Victory Points as a Resource" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>