<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="385948">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Z3kOJvphiKFG44L7TSN-vQ__thumb/img/labDwUT-PU1azsgx_sYB6WeeMY0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7465255.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Z3kOJvphiKFG44L7TSN-vQ__original/img/M3Ehbw_2Zhs5F6ijv33cO3HI0gY=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7465255.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Master Udo Vs. the Four Martial Arts Masters" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>You are Master Udo, a martial arts master. To prove that you are the best martial arts master around, you must sequentially challenge and defeat four other martial arts masters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Master Udo is a puzzly game about making combos. You start with 10 basic cards in your hand. Each card is separated into 2 halves: a condition and an effect. By placing cards covering the previous effect, Udo increases the length of their combo. This makes the combo stronger. However, as the combo gets larger, it gets harder to build due to the conditions. Some conditions include &amp;quot;Odd&amp;quot; (can only be played in an odd position in the combo), &amp;quot;MAX 3&amp;quot; (can only be played in a combo of length 3 or less), and &amp;quot;No right&amp;quot; (cannot be played in a combo with &amp;quot;right arm&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;right leg&amp;quot;).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There is no partial damage in this game, which means that it is often important to store up &amp;quot;charge&amp;quot; that can be spent to increase the length of a combo at critical moments. Charge can be gained by blocking attacks and by playing certain combos.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is important to be efficient with card play because the top card of each combo gets discarded once that combo resolves. Additionally, failing to block an attack results in a specific card being discarded. If the player discards all their cards, they lose. Additionally, if they can't discard or exile (remove from discard) the correct card when getting hit, they lose. Once Udo defeats 4 masters, they win. Udo can choose to challenge weaker or stronger masters in any order, but choosing to challenge weaker masters may reduce the overall glory earned at the end of the game. Defeating a master allows Udo to learn their signature move, improving Udo's strength in future battles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="1" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61977" value="Players: Solitaire Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5786" value="Sports: Combat Sports / Martial Arts" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="112177" value="Jorge Zhang" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="52831" value="Jayzee Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>