<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="386028">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/avUi8_r-lum6NoyNOoaWhQ__thumb/img/GQIuUwAu9UNV_oW3I6X1lHzxAGo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7466892.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/avUi8_r-lum6NoyNOoaWhQ__original/img/Srs1NkHWAp-u3MPMjzX4lWke268=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7466892.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The North West Frontier Event Deck" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The heart of the Deck is content of each Card. The challenges to the players on both sides of the Crags are sharper than ever, but are still &amp;quot;even&amp;quot; for both sides. As with all TVAG Event Decks, these are not your Monopoly &amp;quot;Chance Cards,&amp;quot; nor are the effects of each the same from game to game--severities and benefits vary across a wide spectrum.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;And the whimsy is still there... and the fun and a hint of Hollywood, too, but never so much as to spoil the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If playing in Afghanistan, Native Reinforcements can include Regular Foot, Horse, or Guns--but not so if elsewhere on The Grim. If the battle is in Winter, Blizzards and Frostbite can affect both sides, but the Imperials worst of all. British troops can even be introduced to the charms of the Camel Spider, the Pathan Rock Fall, and Jezail armed Snipers, while Afghan/Pathan Tribesmen can find their Black Powder is soot and ash sold them by an Infidel Dog, or that their Mullah's have one battle plan and their Hill Chieftain another, or that the Gurkha's facing them are going to blood their Kukri's today, no matter the cost!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;And besides these and so many more jolly moments that could never appear in a standard war games scenario, there is a new feature in the NWF Event Deck added as a tribute to the late author of The Sword And The Flame&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These six Cards, randomly distributed throughout the Deck among the others, bear the likenesses of some characters all Colonial War Gamers will know from beloved films, characters whom Sgt. Brom has encountered on the edges of the battlefield who carry special Intelligence for the British C-in-C concerning Reinforcements for the Imperial or Native Forces. Their numbers, type, the time of their Arrival and Entry Points will be reported some number of Turns in advance. For the first time with these Event Cards, the British Players can attempt to coordinate the time and place of new Units with their current forces to defeat the Hill Tribes, or, if it's the Afghans/Pathans who are about to be reinforced, move to prevent their arrival causing a disaster!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description rom the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2015" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="20307" value="Game: The Sword and the Flame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="4292" value="The Sword and the Flame" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="30558" value="The Sword and the Flame: Eight Hundred Fighting Englishmen" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3808" value="Patrick Wilson" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8289" value="The (Virtual) Armchair General" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>