<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="386276">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/L2uDPKAMmvXG2WhJ_Yt3OQ__thumb/img/EVnXUpPiFxDkgoxC5y_J4WVzRok=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7477782.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/L2uDPKAMmvXG2WhJ_Yt3OQ__original/img/Vhae03ZDwrRZKqxfJIjNBJxc7QM=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7477782.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Wall Streak" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Wall Streak is a board game where players take on the roles of investors, competing against one another to become the king/queen of Wall Street. Players accomplish this by having earned the most victory points at game's end. Victory can be earned one of three ways, buying company's (worth 5vp's for each owned at game's end), accumulating money (worth 1vp per every 5M at game's end), and completing investor goals (worth 3vp to 15vp). Players must find the right balance between the 3 in order to be crowned king/queen of Wall Street!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On player's turns they roll a single six sided die and move the corresponding number of spaces and then perform the action on the space. Players may pay to move forward one or two additional spaces for costs of 3M or 5M respectively. While navigating the board of Wall Streak players move following the direction/path that they are on until they reach an intersection. Once at an intersection players may change their path or continue following the path they were. The only restrictions being players are not allowed to double back and reverse course, and players must always travel clockwise in the company and money loops.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are several different types of spaces which players can land on throughout the game. When a player lands on a M, T or gold bar space they draw a card from the respective deck and perform its action, or keep it if it is stock or movement adjusting card (found in the T (Transaction) deck) or an additional investor goal (found in the M (Merger) deck). Spaces with a money amount provide players with that amount of money when they land on them. On dice spaces players will roll either a single or double D6 dice and receive or lose money according to the color dice space that they landed on. Finally  there are 50 company spaces which players can land on. When landed on players may buy the company for it's current price, initiate an auction for the company, or pay rent to it's current owner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players must must find the right balance and timing between accumulating money and buying companies. The game end is triggered once a certain number of companies are owned by all players. This number varies based on the number of players in the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="150" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="150" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2840" value="Action/Event" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2923" value="Auction: Once Around" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2856" value="Die Icon Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2987" value="Hidden Victory Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2911" value="Ownership" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2005" value="Stock Holding" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="152761" value="Dalton Versak" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="152762" value="Ana Tobin" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="53892" value="Zord Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>