<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="386401">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Kingdom of Thieves" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Welcome to the world of Kingdom of Thieves, where aspiring thieves from across the city gather to compete in the annual Tournament of Thieves. This quick paced card game blends cunning strategy, chance encounters, and a visually enchanting world. Players must outwit and outmanoeuvre their opponents to collect the most impressive treasures and earn the privilege of joining the prestigious Guild of Thieves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Kingdom of Thieves combines strategy, chance and deception as players draw cards from the deck or even snatch them from their opponents' hands, seeking the perfect balance of treasures and action cards to propel them to victory. With a diverse array of fantasy themes, including pirates, goblins, elves and dwarves, players will experience an enchanting world where diverse characters and fantastical creatures take centre stage.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players take turns drawing cards and playing treasures or actions, with the goal of accumulating five treasures and the highest score in victory points. Treasure cards are played face down, with some containing hidden traps to challenge opponents. Action cards allow players to execute strategic moves that can impact the game's outcome, adding unexpected twists and turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game ends when a player starts their turn with five treasures in play. At that point, victory points are tallied, and the player with the most points is declared the winner. With bonus points awarded for collecting multiple treasures of the same suit or even five trap cards, Kingdom of Thieves offers endless strategic possibilities for players seeking to claim the top spot among the city's elite thieves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="13" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2836" value="Lose a Turn" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2686" value="Take That" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="152797" value="Lew Husbands" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="152798" value="Lancelot Richardson" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="53909" value="Plunder Fish Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>