<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="386547">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TGP6H1gMiOg6MxKGmWjoMA__thumb/img/RuHwiAVIG5v3LDngli6gY8OPJ84=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7547565.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/TGP6H1gMiOg6MxKGmWjoMA__original/img/nDp-DSMDsoQem-KgiAdm_sdjqeE=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7547565.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Divicity" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Get ready for a fun and fierce card game in Divicity.&amp;#10;With hidden scorecards and the ability to tease other players, Divicity is an exciting and unpredictable game, perfect for getting the crowd together and having a good laugh at any time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to have more points by end of the match. Before playing the first card, the starting player can look at two of the chips of the play and return them face down in the center of the table. The starting player plays the card they want from their hand, face up. on the table. The other players, clockwise, play one card each. Players are required to play cards of the suit played by the starting player. If you do not have letters from the suit played by the starting player, can play any card. When all players have played a card, the player who played the lowest card of the same suit played by the starting player reveals the chips of score and take one of them. Then the player who played the highest card of the suit played by the leading player wins the trick and takes a second chip. In games for 5 or 6 players, the third chip is donated by the winner of the leaks to any player except himself and the player who took the first chip of the turn. When players have no more cards in their hands, the game ends. Players add up their chip scores. Whoever has the highest score wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2009" value="Trick-taking" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61999" value="Theme: Boardgaming" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="24232" value="Fel Barros" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="42325" value="Grok Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="8.2" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.748331" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="27" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>