<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="386987">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Krimi Total Fall 17: Des Alters fette Beute" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Story&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Edith, Bernd and Paul had been close friends since their student days. Together they had expanded the Stettenwerke, which Paul had taken over from his parents 49 years ago, into a successful mechanical engineering company. Their common path through life has fatefully welded the three friends together.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Six months ago Paul had sold his company. In order to spend his old age in style and with all amenities, he has rented a luxurious retirement home for himself, Edith and Bernd and their spouses. Since then, the five companions have lived in their own wing on the first floor of a historical building ensemble. Two personal carers lovingly take care of their well-being.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But this afternoon Paul lay lifeless in his bed. Deaths are the order of the day in a retirement home, but a possibly unnatural death would mean great damage to the image of the facility. The residence management is therefore determined to resolve the matter internally without making a fuss.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Die Geschichte&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Edith, Bernd und Paul verband seit Studientagen eine enge Freundschaft. Gemeinsam hatten sie die Stettenwerke, die Paul vor 49 Jahren von seinen Eltern &amp;uuml;bernommen hatte, zu einem erfolgreichen Maschinenbauunternehmen ausgebaut. Ihr gemeinsamer Lebensweg hat die drei Freunde schicksalhaft zusammengeschwei&amp;szlig;t.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Vor einem halben Jahr hatte Paul seine Firma verkauft. Um seinen Lebensabend stilvoll und mit allen Annehmlichkeiten zu verbringen, hat er sich, Edith und Bernd sowie deren Ehepartner in einer luxuri&amp;ouml;sen Seniorenresidenz eingemietet. Die f&amp;uuml;nf Weggef&amp;auml;hrten bewohnen seither einen eigenen Trakt im ersten Obergeschoss eines historischen Geb&amp;auml;udeensembles. Zwei pers&amp;ouml;nliche Pflegekr&amp;auml;fte k&amp;uuml;mmern sich liebevoll um ihr Wohlergehen.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Doch heute Nachmittag lag Paul leblos in seinem Bett. Sterbef&amp;auml;lle sind in einer Seniorenresidenz zwar an der Tagesordnung, aber ein m&amp;ouml;glicherweise unnat&amp;uuml;rliches Ableben w&amp;uuml;rde einen gro&amp;szlig;en Imageschaden f&amp;uuml;r die Einrichtung bedeuten. Deshalb ist die Residenzleitung fest entschlossen, die Angelegenheit ohne gro&amp;szlig;es Aufsehen intern zu kl&amp;auml;ren.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2019" />
						               				<minplayers value="6" />
						               				<maxplayers value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="7+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="180" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="16" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1023" value="Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1040" value="Murder/Mystery" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2073" value="Acting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2891" value="Hidden Roles" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2892" value="Roles with Asymmetric Information" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="11537" value="Series: KRIMI total (JMCreative)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="6052" value="Jörg Meißner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="52881" value="Krimi Total GmbH" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>