<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="386906">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/rxnxEjI4UrwypH9JX9AQhA__thumb/img/TC_23fzUtNMGGSMSEfVz2OP8p44=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7480057.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/rxnxEjI4UrwypH9JX9AQhA__original/img/8IJIJlmYENIkeXwmBzQZXlSOQMk=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7480057.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bohnanza: Dahlias" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Bohnanza: Dahlias is a special edition of Bohnanza for 3-5 players that features the same gameplay as the original design.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the game, you plant, then harvest flower cards in order to earn coins. Each player starts with a hand of random flower cards, and each card has a number on it corresponding to the number of that type of flower in the deck. Unlike in most other card games, you can't rearrange the order of cards in hand, so you must use them in the order that you've picked them up from the deck &amp;mdash; unless you can trade them to other players, which is the heart of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On a turn, you must plant the first one or two cards in your hand into the &amp;quot;fields&amp;quot; in front of you. Each field can hold only one type of flower, so if you must plant a type of flower that's not in one of your fields, then you must harvest a field to make room for the new arrival. This usually isn't good! Next, you reveal two cards from the deck, and you can then trade these cards as well as any card in your hand for cards from other players. You can even make future promises for cards received right now! After all the trading is complete &amp;mdash; and all trades on a turn must involve the active player &amp;mdash; then you end your turn by drawing cards from the deck and placing them at the back of your hand.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you harvest flowers, you receive coins based on the number of cards in that field and the &amp;quot;meter&amp;quot; for that particular type of flower. Flip over 1-4 cards from that field to transform them into coins, then place the remainder of the cards in the discard pile. When the deck runs out, shuffle the discards, playing through the deck two more times. At the end of the game, everyone can harvest their fields, then whoever has earned the most coins wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1013" value="Farming" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1026" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2915" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2008" value="Trading" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5" value="Game: Bohnanza" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameimplementation" id="11" value="Bohnanza" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="10" value="Uwe Rosenberg" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="71164" value="Beth Sobel" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8" value="AMIGO" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="16" />
			<wishing value="72" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>