<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="386918">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/aHpEjH_PKFt9F2YV7jIxAQ__thumb/img/_ocBSkwqbiCTR7CNEDKVzfHjbF8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7492412.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/aHpEjH_PKFt9F2YV7jIxAQ__original/img/VUfEbYfiBwGDyT0aql6Qjskrd0I=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7492412.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Sirens: The Deep Sea" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A beautiful and colorful world in the deep sea. Build your own world with 1-4 players (cooperative) and fight against monsters over different 3D areas from the lower deep sea to the higher regions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Story (NOT a story game - just enjoy your gameplay)&amp;#10;Sirens are the warriors in the deep sea. They have two fins and are fighting on their mounts. Mermaids are the peaceful beings as well as traders and workers. Mankind is always looking for new resources. And in recent years they have made a discovery. There are unique and valuable resources in the deep sea. Moreover, there is life there. But with modern technology, they can't get into the deep themselves. There is dark and unknown territory. So they have doung a way to ally with the hostile Sirens and Monsters. Through them, the humans want to get their hands on the resources. The task is to use these resources by yourself, to build your own world and to secure the deep sea.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Free mode: Build your own world and fight your own way over all 3D areas (normal, hard or with an own mix of rules). A high replay value.&amp;#10;     Scenarios: Play individual scenarios.&amp;#10;     Three 3D areas/levels: Your worldmap (25x20 fields and around 75x60cm) is based on 3D areas (three 3D levels). These 3D areas can be placed individually to increase the replay value.&amp;#10;     Powerful underwater streams: Every area has its own streams which will move all beings in specific directions.&amp;#10;     Collect resources: Corals, mussles, metals, pearls, plants and many more. Build and upgrade your Sirens.&amp;#10;     Absorb energy ot boost your Sirens and resource growth: Each defeated creature gives you energy points. Choose wisely and strategically.&amp;#10;     Mount Combo &amp;amp; Sirens Power Spell (Sirens Singing): Individual Siren abilities. Mount Combo and Sirens Power Spell (Sirens Singing).&amp;#10;     Custom dice system: Custom dice, initiate, dodge and critical damage&amp;#10;     Monsters, Bosses and The Oldest: All have an ability boost to their attack and defence skills. &amp;#10;     Conquer new Coral Castles: To get more resource fields and healing spots you have to conquer new castles.&amp;#10;     The Oldest: They are huge monsters from the old time and the darkest areas in the deep sea.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2024" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2850" value="Events" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2822" value="Scenario / Mission / Campaign Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="66292" value="Crowdfunding: Gamefound" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="140308" value="Florian Molzahn" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="53928" value="Forgotten Tales" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="14" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>