<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="387236">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6q2X6J2DD73VFd30JnAaZQ__thumb/img/0SB0sRMWd6U8m7jX1fOSUDAh_1Q=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7497024.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6q2X6J2DD73VFd30JnAaZQ__original/img/0nF0BCD9NVji_3WRAwSXS0WZ-xs=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7497024.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Chaves: Confusões na Vila" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Chaves: Confus&amp;otilde;es na Vila, it's a fun card game that features 3 different ways to play, with the same components, all of them inspired by the characteristics of the characters from the most beloved village in the world.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the first game mode, each player will receive 3 cards each turn from the deck and draft, passing 2 cards to the player on his left. After that, all players will place a card on the left and another card on the right, confronting them with those of the other players. Each card has an icon that shows which card it wins. In each space, it will be checked who won, and the winner receives the card as points. The first to score 25 points wins the round and scores points. At the end of 3 rounds, the player with the most accumulated points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the second game mode, each player receives 7 cards from the deck and wins the round by getting rid of all the cards in the hand. A card from the deck is opened in the center of the play area and, clockwise, players will try to play a card from their hand that has an icon related to the card in the play area. If not, he must draw 1 card from the deck. At the end of 3 rounds, whoever has won the most rounds is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In the third game mode, each player receives 2 cards from the deck. In each turn, the current player must perform one of the following actions: 1. play and apply the effect of his card; 2. Discard up to 2 cards and draw new cards from the deck. The round continues until one player reaches 25 points, thus winning the round. At the end of 3 rounds, whoever has the most accumulated points is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="40" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="40" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3007" value="Matching" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3099" value="Multi-Use Cards" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="12892" value="Rafael M. Verri" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="15605" value="Galápagos Jogos" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="50478" value="Ludofun" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="10" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>