<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="387281">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/3t2ZP4pQxJ4GZrIt_a6pHQ__thumb/img/ngrFwYCAvUBIA_Hz8wKsSDNPebw=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7502143.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/3t2ZP4pQxJ4GZrIt_a6pHQ__original/img/M81ef9CdGvG7GSabhlby3LOaZ_U=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7502143.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="MindMeld: The Party Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Welcome to Mindmeld, the party game where great minds think alike.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mindmeld: The Party Game is a competitive, high-energy party game where you and your partner draw cards with key words to choose from and try to come up with a word that connects these two key words.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The twist?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You have to come up with the same word as your partner to score the most points!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Can you get on the same wavelength as your friends to lock in a victory?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Everyone at the table is playing, both with their partner and with all the other players; so if you don't match with your partner, you can still score points by matching words with another player (but not quite as many points as you would when you match with your partner).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Now for a little more detail: &amp;#10;1) Everyone has a partner (there is a special rule in case your game group has an odd number of players)&amp;#10;2) taking turns, two partners each draw a Mindmeld card (each card has a set of 5 words to choose from). &amp;#10;3) They will choose a word from the card and say, &amp;quot;3-2-1!&amp;quot; and shout out the word they chose from the card.&amp;#10;4) All players (including the partners that choose the cards) then write the word that comes to mind that will connect the two shouted words.&amp;#10;5) The partners that drew the cards, as soon as they finish writing their word on their erasable boards say, &amp;quot;3-2-1!&amp;quot; and every player shows their word and shouts it out.&amp;#10;6) Then you score the round- If you and your partner matched words, you each score three points. If you match with anyone else, you and that player score one point.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;That's it?&amp;quot;, you ask. You bet! Like we said before, this game is as fun as it is easy to play. Young and old alike, this game scales to every age and type of player you can imagine!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fast and fun, Mindmeld is a great filler or end-of-the-night game that players can join and leave at anytime.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mindmeld: The Party Game. Get in sync. Be of one mind. And join the fun!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="12+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1025" value="Word Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="152980" value="Zack Boatman" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="95910" value="Aaron Frias" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="95910" value="Aaron Frias" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="53987" value="TMI Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>