<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="387297">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Hunt A Killer: Murder On Ice" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Murder On Ice is a Membership Exclusive that is only available to Hunt A Killer subscribers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Figure skater Sofia de la Torre is, you could say, on thin ice. After her coach of over a decade is found murdered, Sofia is the police&amp;rsquo;s prime suspect.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When Nathan LaPalma is found dead on the ice rink one day, everyone has the same question: why would someone kill a figure skating legend. Nathan, an Olympic-medalist-turned-coach, is famous both in and out of the skating community for his style, talent, and unbeatable coaching. And yet, someone had it out for the skating superstar. Could one of his own proteges be the killer?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You&amp;rsquo;ve been called in by Nathan&amp;rsquo;s student Sofia de la Torre to unspin the mystery of her coach&amp;rsquo;s death. And for good reason. The police are close to pinning Nathan&amp;rsquo;s murder on Sofia herself, and she&amp;rsquo;s desperate to find the real killer. Can you break into the competitive, and often secretive, world of figure skating enough to vindicate Sofia and track down the icy murderer?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To catch the killer and bring justice to Nathan and Sofia, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Prove to the police that Sofia is innocent. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to prove that she&amp;rsquo;s innocent before you can move on to finding the real killer!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unravel whispered secrets that the evasive skaters don&amp;rsquo;t want you to know.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Track clues and evidence across multiple episode boxes to build a complete picture of the crime.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Puzzle out secret messages, ciphers, and codes to unlock additional clues to the killer&amp;rsquo;s identity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Difficulty: 4/5 - Hard&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="900" />
						               				<minplaytime value="600" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="900" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1040" value="Murder/Mystery" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3002" value="Deduction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="72156" value="Series: Hunt A Killer" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="46279" value="Hunt A Killer" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>