<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="387405">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vBC2OdwPvXZBJqbuoh7aKQ__thumb/img/B4OWdSSJI_99-Fpoiv4d-KX51uM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7501541.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vBC2OdwPvXZBJqbuoh7aKQ__original/img/81DXlj8UEAZtiX6wwd5Fxw_LdPM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7501541.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="THEIA: The Millennial Wars" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>THEIA is a dynamic and engaging board game that brings the excitement of the tactical wargame to life. The game features an assortment of fantasy races, including Humans, Earthbound, Dark Walkers, and Marlock, each with its own unique army and lords. In THEIA, the ultimate goal is to lead your army to victory by vanquishing your opponents' forces on different battlefields.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To achieve victory, you'll need to master a vast array of tactical options. You'll have access to powerful spells from 4 different magical schools, each with its own strengths and specialties. You can also customize your heroes with a wide range of items, from weapons and armor to magical artifacts, to create an unbeatable combination of skills and abilities.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;THEIA offers different experiences in one game, making it accessible to players of all levels of experience. At its simplest, THEIA is a basic, card-driven chess-like strategy game that is easy to pick up and play. The game mechanics are straightforward, and the focus is on using your forces to outmaneuver your opponents and gain the upper hand on the battlefield.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For those who crave a greater challenge, THEIA also offers an advanced tactical tabletop experience. This version of the game is more complex and strategic, requiring careful planning and execution to emerge victorious. With the double-sided map tiles, you can craft a unique strategy each time you play. This advanced version of THEIA is sure to test your skills and strategic thinking.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="154570" value="Tugra Sahiner" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="53996" value="Diving Eagle Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>