<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="388039">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rainbow Dragons" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>How are Rainbows made?? Magical dragons race across sky chasing storms and leaving rainbows in their trail.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Rainbow Dragons is a fun set collection game with 6 color dice that is great for kids but has the strategic depth for adults too.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game plays 3-6 players, setup is fast, games are quick, easy to learn and makes a great filler game at 25-45 minutes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On your turn you roll a single rainbow die. It will show one of 6 colors that you can collect and create sets. If you like the die you put it down on your score card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Otherwise you can offer the die to another player. If they say yes then you give them the die and they add it to their score card. After they accept your die you then roll 2 dice. You can now add those dice to your card or trade them for even more dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players have to use strategy to know when to offer a die, when to say yes and when to say no. If a player says no the die goes back to the dice pool and it is lost to the player who rolled it. A player can continue to roll dice as long as the other players are willing to trade.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once on your turn you can turn in a set of dice for points. You will get more points for higher sets of dice with the largest reward going to a complete rainbow (1 die of each of the colors). Your score is impacted by your neighbors dice so you are always watching what the other dragons are doing.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you turn in a set you advance your marker down the scoring track towards the win. First player to the end wins the game immediately. The game also ends with the 3 rainbow or when there are no more dice when a player needs to roll. At this point the player with the most points wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2024" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="25" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2856" value="Die Icon Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2950" value="Different Dice Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2915" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="9107" value="Peter Hansell" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5364" value="TableStar Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>