<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="388406">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fravan" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Fravan (from Gothic: Fraujinassus, meaning &amp;quot;dominion&amp;quot;) is an abstract board game for two players who play on an initially empty hexagonal board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Objective:&amp;#10;The objective of the game is to conquer as much territory as possible with as many stones of your color when both players pass.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Components:&amp;#10;&amp;ndash; A hexagonal board with 7 intersections per side (but can be played on smaller or larger boards for shorter or longer games respectively).&amp;#10;&amp;ndash; A set of equal stones, black on the obverse and white on the reverse.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Definitions:&amp;#10;&amp;ndash; A flank is a configuration in which two friendly stones in a straight line (along one of the six cardinal directions) are the same distance from one stone, with the same number of empty intersections (can be zero) and no other stones in the middle.&amp;#10;&amp;ndash; A flip is the color change of a stone to the opposite color when flanked by enemy stones.&amp;#10;&amp;ndash; A territory is a set of one or more empty intersections connected in a straight line and flanked by friendly stones. You own a territory if the stones that flank it are your color.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Turns:&amp;#10;Black plays first, then alternates. On your turn, perform these actions in the following order:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Place a stone of your color on an empty intersection.&amp;#10;2. Flip all enemy stones flanked by friendly stones.&amp;#10;3. Flip all friendly stones flanked by enemy stones.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If when performing the previous actions there are more flanked stones, perform actions 2 and 3 in that order until at the end of your turn there are no flanked stones.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Infinite flanks:&amp;#10;When a stone is flanked by both friendly and enemy stones simultaneously, for obvious reasons the stone will be flipped, but doing so will make it flanked by enemy stones which will force it to flip once more, causing a series of infinite flanks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This problem is solved by adding the following rule:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A stone flanked by enemy stones that is in turn flanked by friendly stones can never be flipped, since the mentioned friendly stones are a &amp;quot;shield&amp;quot;, so they will protect it, unless they no longer flank it. However, an enemy stone that is on a shield can be flipped only if it is flanked by a stone placement.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;End of the game:&amp;#10;The game ends when the board is full or both players pass their turns consecutively. At the end of the game, the one with the most stones of their color and conquered territory on the board wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To make the game fair, before the game starts, the first player places a starting black stone at an empty intersection, and then the second player chooses sides. This balancing method is called the pie rule.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2043" value="Enclosure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="26432" value="Category: Combinatorial" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="153220" value="Saïd Gadwen" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>