<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="388623">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/31SI07aLUXrR9mCnYNGRVw__thumb/img/-TyAx90kR1f_E2ICj-xNBAL8lT8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7590049.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/31SI07aLUXrR9mCnYNGRVw__original/img/XYWlAwrmZXJUzRSYS_-svJmsCeQ=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7590049.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Cruxy" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Meet Cruxy the Penguin and his polar friends! Their favorite game is to carve words on the ice floes. Come and join them!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this game you will be filling the crossword grid with made-up words of the indicated length and required letters in them. The more set conditions you fulfill, the sooner you win! To make the game even more fun and exciting, use the powers of Cruxy and other animals &amp;#226;&amp;#128;&amp;#149; their special effects may influence other players and bring you closer to success at the same time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Four different game modes, fifty double-sided boards of increasing complexity and a unique combination of literacy and strategy make Cruxy a new word in the world of board games!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played by turns so players have some time to think over their options and come up with the word of the needed length, with the required letters, or a symbol occupied by the word. All the objections are marked on the playing board. Remember that you can only add a word to the grid using one or more letters already placed in the grid. Also the words to fill in should meet the criteria: a) a word cannot be used twice, b) proper nouns are prohibited, etc. Check the full list in the rules!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once a player wrote down a word and crossed the things they used out from their box, it's the player's from their left turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To make the game even more fun, reach Cruxy's friends, different animals of the South Pole for the special effects they create! These effects may boost your own success or influence other players. &amp;#10;For example, there is a Seagul that allows a player to use shorter or longer words for a moment, or a Kraken that pulls out an extra letter for your opponents, and many other creatures with their own power.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The player who fulfilled all the tasks but any 2 of any kind becomes the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;     Add new words to the grid and fulfil different conditions.&amp;#10;     Apply animals&amp;rsquo; effects at the right moment to influence the game play.&amp;#10;     Be the first to cross out the most conditions in your player area and win the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1025" value="Word Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="147663" value="Sonja Müller" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51867" value="Red Cat Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>