<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="388811">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Villa&#039;s Vengeance: The Raid on Columbus, New Mexico March 9, 1916" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The Mexican Revolution that began in 1910 with the overthrow of dictator Porfirio Diaz degenerated into civil war following the assassination of President Francisco Madero. By end of 1915 the forces of President Carranza were arrayed against a variety of leaders supporting either themselves or General Victoriano Huerta. Pancho Villa, commander of the Mexican Army del Norte, at first supported Carranza, but then went rogue after the US Government recognized Carranza&amp;rsquo;s government. Historians still debate Villa&amp;rsquo;s reasons, but in early March 1916 he decided to enter the US and raid the town of Columbus, New Mexico. Although the town was where the 13th Regiment US Cavalry was garrisoned, he knew most of the troopers were scattered along the border. Believing the town was only weakly guarded, his force of just under 500 men were to steal arms, provisions and horses while also wreaking as much havoc as possible. Such a raid he believed could galvanize the US government into a retaliatory strike that would drag Carranza&amp;rsquo;s government into a war with the US it could not win, or a humiliating capitulation that would outrage the Mexican people. Either way, Villa reasoned, it would mean the downfall of Carranza.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Villa&amp;rsquo;s Vengeance is an introductory level wargame simulation portraying the March 9, 1916 raid on Columbus, New Mexico. Players are cast in the roles of Villa&amp;rsquo;s raiding force and the defending US regular and militia forces.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each copy of Villa&amp;rsquo;s Vengeance is composed of the following:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    One 11 by 17 inch area map with game record keeping tracks.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    One sheet of 63 double sided, un-mounted units.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;    6 pages of rules.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players will also need an opaque container (mug, envelope or anything similar), a six-sided die (D6) and standard deck of playing cards to play the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players draw cards to determine which player can activate, and with how many units as well as determine game events (Random events occurrence and end of turn). A six-sided die is used to resolve combats and various other game events (random event determination, rally and morale checks).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1065" value="World War I" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2857" value="Card Play Conflict Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="812" value="Paul Rohrbaugh" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="106504" value="Dariusz Buraczewski" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="17180" value="High Flying Dice Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>