<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="388908">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/sKMj55wDmug81SPYJQSwWQ__thumb/img/ZdVDzPPslCGJ6Y3s38b0Id0J338=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7526483.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/sKMj55wDmug81SPYJQSwWQ__original/img/CHYeg7wQDNrJvkttz8y2uuhUlKU=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7526483.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Spiritual Dominion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Who is the master of this land, the psychic who calls himself an angel? Selfish citizens? Or a schemer wearing a monstrous mask? Everyone said that God promised to become the master of this world after seven days. God never appeared, but from the first day, everyone's inner thoughts will be presented to everyone in the next morning.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Victory conditions for the three factions&amp;#10;Leviathan 1: Draw a card from the deck every round and distribute it to anyone other than yourself. Each player can have multiple cards. There were three declarations of artifacts on the field at the same time, and Leviathan won. Leviathan was not allowed to reveal or hint to others what the card he gave to others was.&amp;#10;Angel 1-2: The task of an angel is to preach. Each round marks a player in the spiritual field. When the mark reaches 3 (Leviathan needs seven marks), this character is regarded as a believer. The believer on the spot plus the angel Wins when the number is greater than half the number.&amp;#10;Humans 2-5: Conditions for victory. After seven days, neither Leviathan nor Angel wins.&amp;#10;Cooperation and deceit will of course be required to win, but remember that you are all God's children so in some cases your alignment will change.&amp;#10;At the beginning of the game, each player draws an identity card (Leviathan, human, angel), Leviathan shows his identity, and then draws a card from the pile to represent the beginning of a new day, everyone takes turns to speak, and finally Leviathan decides Who is this card for (the three rounds of getting the card can be activated), and then enter the night, people other than the angels close their eyes, the angels start to preach, and they can put a mark on the spirit collar. At dawn after 10 seconds, Leviathan draws the next card and repeats this cycle seven times.&amp;#10;There are three artifacts in the deck that can be used all the time, three events that happen once and a blank Bible book, a total of seven cards and seven rounds, representing what happened within seven days.&amp;#10;Artifact &amp;quot;Lantern&amp;quot;&amp;#10;You can check the identity of others. You can change the imprint arrangement in the spiritual realm&amp;#10;Artifact &amp;quot;laurel crown&amp;quot;&amp;#10;You can remove a marker from a player&amp;#10;Artifact &amp;quot;Sword&amp;quot;&amp;#10;You can kill a player, and whoever kills the Leviathan becomes the new Leviathan.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Event &amp;quot;The Dragon on the Spire&amp;quot;&amp;#10;Leviathan and Instigator get an extra chance to question&amp;#10;Event &amp;quot;Sermon not from the gods&amp;quot;&amp;#10;Directly discard the cards for the next round (the number of rounds minus one)&amp;#10;Event: &amp;quot;Dark March&amp;quot;&amp;#10;People who have been preached join the angel camp and no longer follow the civilians to victory.&amp;#10;Event 'Blank Bible'&amp;#10;Nothing happened.&amp;#10;Claim: Leviathan can't say what he is dealt, and the person who gets the card can claim that he is any one of the seven claims, and the effect can be activated as long as no one questions it. The person who doubts can open the station when the skill is activated. If it is true, he will be silenced for one round. If it is false, he will get this card from the opponent. No one doubts and can change his claim in the next round. Each person can only question once.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="7" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="7+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1023" value="Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2014" value="Betting and Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2891" value="Hidden Roles" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2915" value="Negotiation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2858" value="Prisoner's Dilemma" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2820" value="Semi-Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>