<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="389158">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Soft Underbelly, 1943-1945" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>At the end of 1942, with the operation TORCH large American forces poured into the Western Mediterranean. In a short time, thanks to their efforts, Italy was ousted from the conflict and the Allies returned to European continent, definitely arresting the expansion of the Axis.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game allows to recreate events which took place between 1943 and 1945, when this area became the epicenter of some of the most bloody battles of the WW2.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game uses wooden cubes, square counters and circular&amp;#10;markers together. It is for two players and lasts about an hour on average. The map is zoned.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game lasts 8 rounds divided into impulses; with each impulse the players take turns moving and fighting with their specialized forces, blocks and counters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Whoever controls the majority of areas marked with a star (Rome, Tunis, Naples, Munich and so on) wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The blocks can be converted with specialized units, like tanks and aircraft; each with its own conversion cost.&amp;#10;The combat mechanic is very simple: at the end of the movement I place one of the three attack arrows and start rolling the dice, one for each attacking cube; if a 6 is rolled then he inflicts a loss on the enemy. If tanks also participate in the attack, the result for hitting drops to 5; if there are also planes involved it drops to 4.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players can play some events: Arrival of reinforcements, Additional impulse (which allows you to extend the turn), Arrest battle (allows you to immediately end a battle), partisans, etc. But the event markers are generic, it is the player who must decide where to place them on a special track to trigger that type of event. And he can do it at any time...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="79503" value="Decades: The 1940's" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="108647" value="Sergio Schiavi" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="108647" value="Sergio Schiavi" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="39147" value="Dissimula Edizioni" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>