<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="389341">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/gvtDhcUxtxuxz6BKgQJyjQ__thumb/img/Oi2WuJ4iacdzRFKBBV69gvIkwwQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7569292.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/gvtDhcUxtxuxz6BKgQJyjQ__original/img/zG2F8uCnmM2HDaE7rOGPVPkmAIg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7569292.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="鬼来 (Onikuru)" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A hidden role game in which players are children trapped in a house around which an Oni is lurking. But some of the players are puppets sent by the Oni who will try to lure the players into a false sense of security. A player will move to one of three types of locations: Rooms to search and obtain item cards, Hidding place to be safe from Oni and the Entrance, where a player can &amp;quot;peak through the window&amp;quot; (aka look at the top card of the Oni deck) to know which card will be moved in front of the entrance or place an item card under the current Oni card in front of the entrance.&amp;#10;At the end of the round, the card in front of the entrance is revealed. If the card is an Oni, every players outside a hiding place will be devoured. The card is then removed and the next card on the Oni deck is placed face down in front of the entrance.&amp;#10;The children win by placing a talisman at the entrance the turn an Oni will be revealed.&amp;#10;The Oni's Envoy win if there are less children alive remaining than them.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Translated game introduction;&amp;#10;Today, the same room, the same friends, the same people.&amp;#10;&amp;quot;What do you want to do?&amp;quot; &amp;quot;I want to play.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;Such an ordinary day is suddenly disrupted.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Suddenly, It is pitch black outside the room that was brightly lit just a moment ago.&amp;#10;You hear a noise coming from the living room, which is supposed to be empty. Gently, You take a peek.&amp;#10;What is that? Is that...? Not a person, with horns? An Oni?&amp;#10;Your companions peek outside the room, livid and trembling.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If we continue to hide, we will be eaten eventually. It's obviously dangerous outside, but we must somehow find a way to get rid of the demon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Working together with your friends, you are going to bring back that ordinary but happy life!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;But...? There seems to be impostors among your friends... Something doesn&amp;rsquo;t add up...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1024" value="Horror" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2891" value="Hidden Roles" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2685" value="Player Elimination" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="112889" value="Momoko (ももこ)" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="153682" value="Aoko (あをこ)" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="54131" value="Red Seed" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>