<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="390014">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/MwotbEz8LlqDDtb1cKPY5w__thumb/img/aVTUhjRLQK9pt_MN4k4YcHYdntY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7571906.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/MwotbEz8LlqDDtb1cKPY5w__original/img/usF9vPNYBK-vM9HdtHYYzb8kZBY=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7571906.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Ultimediation" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Ultimediation is a cooperative strategy game.  Your mission is to restore peace on an Earth plunged into a world war. You are a mixed team of the best human mediators supported by extraterrestrials who are part of a very advanced civilization. You come to Earth in avatars to save humanity and life on Earth. You work together to choose the best strategies to evacuate people, remove attacks and successfully mediate between sides. Will you save the World before Earth is destroyed, human beings are lost forever, or the time for mediation runs out? Up to you to play out!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;GAME PLAY&amp;#10;&amp;#10;CHARACTERS &amp;#10;Agapi - protector, Keplerian&amp;#10;Andromeda - mediator, human&amp;#10;Diamandis- mediator, human&amp;#10;Elli, teleoprtator, Keplerian&amp;#10;Ilias - protector - keplerian&amp;#10;Nikitas - mediator, human&amp;#10;Vera - mediator, human&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game takes place on a board which represents the Earth and it is divided by 45 squares identified by the alpha-numeric coordinates.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Arrival on Earth&amp;#10;The mission begins with the arrival on Earth. The teleportator, Elli, arrives at square E3 in Africa where she establishes the base.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two teams made up of a protector and two mediators arrive on two squares defined by the drawing of cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At each turn each character can do up to 3 actions selected from the following (move, use power cards, teleport humans, remove attacks and mediate).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MEDIATIONS&amp;#10;To succeed in the mission, peace must be restored through mediation. For this purpose, the mediators move to the bases of the warring governments which are in their submarines. Mediation consists of drawing mediation cards. Mediation cards contain answers to the following question: &amp;quot;Which of your needs you want to fulfill by waging war?&amp;quot;. If answers are justifications (judgments, accusations, insults, criticism) then mediators are losing energy up to be removed from the mediation zone. If answers are needs ( equity, freedom, food, peace, make the world better, respect, security) then the team is getting closer to the victory. Depending on the level of the game there is a need to get 2-3-4 good answers from both governments.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EVACUATION OF HUMANITY&amp;#10;Part of your mission is to save as many people as possible.&amp;#10;Humanity is represented by the 43 tokens. At the beginning of the game, humans are evenly distributed throughout the Earth.&amp;#10;When an attack card lands on a square with humans, they escape or they are lost.&amp;#10;To escape, you can move tokens to the adjacent squares, provided there is space (maximum two tokens on a square) and provided that these squares are not already destroyed by the attack tiles.&amp;#10;When there are no free places on the adjacent squares, or if they are destroyed, the humans are lost and the tokens concerned are removed from the board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To save people it is necessary:&amp;#10;- to teleport them to the base in Africa. All characters can do this by using their &amp;quot;Teleportation of humans&amp;quot; action.&amp;#10;- to teleport them to the spaceship. This can be done only by Elli, the teleporter.&amp;#10;- If the base and the spaceship are already occupied, people are teleported to other spaces on Earth where they will be safer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;REMOVING ATTACKS &amp;#10;During each game turn, there are attack tiles that land on different places on Earth. Number of attacks is defined by the result of the dice roll.&amp;#10;Part of your mission is to undo the destruction that results from the attacks of war. You are endowed with a power that allows you to move in time in the near past, and to modify the present. In the game this is called &amp;quot;removing an attack&amp;quot;. This consists of removing an attack tiles from the board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;END OF GAME CONDITIONS&amp;#10;The game ends when one of the following occurs:&amp;#10;- Mediations have been completed with both governments.&amp;#10;In this case, the players have won the game.&amp;#10;- A horizontal line on the board is completely covered by attack tiles.&amp;#10;In this case, the players have lost the game.&amp;#10;- The &amp;quot;game turns&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;lost humanity&amp;quot; cubes come together. That represents losing too many humans and having mediation time run out. &amp;#10;In this case, the players have lost the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2024" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1015" value="Civilization" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2838" value="Action Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2857" value="Card Play Conflict Resolution" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2875" value="End Game Bonuses" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2836" value="Lose a Turn" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2958" value="Moving Multiple Units" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3099" value="Multi-Use Cards" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3102" value="Questions and Answers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2822" value="Scenario / Mission / Campaign Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2829" value="Turn Order: Claim Action" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="66292" value="Crowdfunding: Gamefound" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="10" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>