<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="39064">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Triumph of Fascism" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>(from the designer:)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Triumph of Fascism: The Spanish Civil War 1936&amp;ndash;1939 is a two-player a Card Driven Wargame: a board game integrating the political and military spheres of a historical conflict, with cards driving the action. Players assume the side of RED (Republican forces &amp;ndash; the elected government) and BLUE (anti-Republican forces/ &amp;rdquo;Nationalists&amp;rdquo;/ Fascists / Francoists &amp;ndash; those seeking to overthrow the elected government) in the Spanish Civil War (SCW). This epic conflict involved the toppling of a democratically elected government, its replacement by a totalitarian regime, significant foreign intervention, a major component in the march towards WWII and a struggle for control of Spain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each side begins enlisting its political &amp;ldquo;camps&amp;rdquo; (BLUE: Nationalist Army, Carlist, Falange and Army of Africa, RED: PCE, Republican Army, UGT, Anarchist, POUM, Cataluonia and the Northern Autonomous Governments ) to build their national armies and by gaining support from foreign powers (BLUE: Germany, Italy and Portugal, RED: Britain, France and Russia) to improve their resources to wage the conflict. Players will also decide their resource investment in force preparation: there is an &amp;ldquo;untried columns&amp;rdquo; mechanic very similar to one first utilized by Panzergruppe Guderian.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are three phases to a game turn: Strategic, Action, and Logistics.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Strategic Phase requires players to &amp;ldquo;spend&amp;rdquo; their Action Cards (think of ACs as currency) planning their turn, influencing political dynamics (enlisting support of &amp;ldquo;camps&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;foreign powers&amp;rdquo;), impacting the battle for hearts &amp;amp; minds, pursuing alternative historical foreign policy paths and shaping the air and naval war. Additionally, players construct a Hearts &amp;amp; Minds (H&amp;amp;M) pool. The H&amp;amp;M pool is supplemented during the turn by wide variety of actions and events (reflecting the vagaries of support for both sides); the more friendly H&amp;amp;M blocks placed into the pool, the greater the chance of gaining dominant control of Spanish provinces.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During the Action Phase, players utilize their respective decks of Action Cards (ACs) to activate units for movement and combat, implement events (receive reinforcements, etc.), conduct a range of political operations, generate replacements or strategically redeploy units. And, in a twist from other games in the Paths of Glory genre, players must plan out their play of ACs in advance: players secretly specify the order of play of their ACs (&amp;quot;the AC stack&amp;quot;) and allocate one AC to &amp;quot;the AC reserve&amp;quot;. Limited air operations occur during the Action Phase.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During the Logistics Phase, players addresses attrition, rebuilding units, determining province control and other odds and ends. Province control is a function of controlling Provincial Presence Locations and the Provincial Capital and making a successful Province Allegiance Attempt (H&amp;amp;M blocks have an important effect). One key H&amp;amp;M dynamic is a random draw from the H&amp;amp;M pool, placing those H&amp;amp;M blocks on provinces and a variable ending to the phase; players are not quite sure &amp;ldquo;when the music will end&amp;rdquo;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The campaign game is playable in about six to eight hours, while a shorter introductory scenario takes between two and four hours. The game is won by controlling key geographical locations (ex: dominant control of provinces and control of urban areas), which generates victory points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Triumph of Fascism is somewhat of a sequel to Triumph of Chaos (ToC). Changes versus ToC include inclusion of: &amp;#10;&amp;bull; A less-abstracted air and naval components&amp;#10;&amp;bull; A significant hearts &amp;amp; minds mechanic &amp;#10;&amp;bull; More of an emphasis on the buildup to the conflict&amp;#10;&amp;bull; A foreign policy track; allowing for a wider range of outcomes the conflict could take&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Both games utilize the Paths of Glory game engine, supplemented by a significant political &amp;ldquo;game&amp;rdquo; component, which has its roots in Days of Decision and Persian Gulf: Battle for the Middle East.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Originally planned release date was Spring 2015.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="56" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="57" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="58" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="59" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="60" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22185" value="Admin: Cancelled Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="32906" value="History: Spanish Civil War" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="4801" value="David Dockter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="94" value="Clash of Arms Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="5" />
			<average value="8.6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.95959" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="13" />
			<wishing value="70" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>