<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="391063">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/i4MsyV4_Okzy_gUZiyI9gQ__thumb/img/v1MH-8QPuVa584hqRcLXUlUDdBg=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7555331.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/i4MsyV4_Okzy_gUZiyI9gQ__original/img/VlGbbMLqjcmfrBsU-NZk3oLW4v8=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7555331.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Rad Zone Totality: Exhibition Centre Expansion" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This is the second expansion of Rad Zone Totality and is designed to be used in conjunction with the core rules. It includes the search matrix for the Exhibition Centre and the building map. All the search matrix references for the map are found below, so this is a totally new location and map for your survivors.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Exhibition Centre (EXC) search matrices are listed first. Search modifiers do not apply to all tables in the matrix: guidance is provided in the title of the table. Some of the tables are designed to increase the random nature of searching so may point you to another table. At the back of the book are the maps. Because this is a digital product these pages can be printed individually.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;UkGamesExpo&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This Rad Zone Totality expansion was released to coincide with our first appearance at the 2023 UKGamesExpo in Birmingham, England. It has been designed in homage to this awesome event, although the map provided here is nowhere near the size and scale of the NEC.&amp;#10;Situation&amp;#10;&amp;#10;On the outskirts of the industrial sector of the city, you have discovered a large building with a sign at the front reading &amp;ldquo;Exhibition Centre&amp;rdquo;. There is a rumour that this place was once used as a base for a small bandit group, but they joined the Quarantine Denizen and haven&amp;rsquo;t been seen since. You suspect there could be useful loot inside, including Equipment and Raw Materials. There is a huge sun symbol, with a V in the centre, painted on the outside (the symbol of the Quarantine Denizen) and you wonder if this has put off potential looters. You might be in luck today!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You may now select the Exhibition Centre when out on a mission! Refer to the tables in this expansion when exploring the building.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="90" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="90" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2819" value="Solo / Solitaire Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="359231" value="Rad Zone Totality" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="108963" value="Toby Lancaster" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="45947" value="DR Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>