<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="391049">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/5s9exJ3inoT7UDjyb1hcDQ__thumb/img/c0l8kEOduig2JOIcDWfwMg3ozEY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7577969.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/5s9exJ3inoT7UDjyb1hcDQ__original/img/8mENRY9dKpMUo3UbZGS5oe8geiQ=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7577969.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Revelando Emoções" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>It all begins when...&amp;#10;While organizing our move, we found a lost box, forgotten a long time ago. Upon opening it, we discovered many photographs. We quickly called everyone to come and see the photos and remember each moment that was captured.&amp;#10;Do we have the same memories of those moments? What feelings do we perceive when we look at them?&amp;#10;We sat in a circle and pulled out the first photo...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players: 2+&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is played in a series of levels, and players win by reaching level 5. The game begins with two revealed pictures, and one player must choose a feeling card and secret selects a picture that he/she thinks best relates to the feeling, then the other players have to vote on which of the open pictures corresponds to the chosen feeling.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Then they must choose a single voting token that indicates how many spaces the pawn will move on the track, depending on whether the guess is correct or incorrect. Then a new picture is opened, and the next player to the left must remove the chosen picture and reveal a new one, and they must open a new feeling card so that there are always 4 cards available.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the voted picture is the one chosen by the player, the level marker moves to the right the number of spaces indicated on the voting token. If the guess is incorrect, the marker moves to the left.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the level marker reaches 0, everyone loses immediately, regardless of the level (it doesn't go back to the previous level). When the picture is chosen correctly, the marker moves to the right the number of spaces indicated on the voting token. If the marker reaches the star, the next level is reached. The marker goes back to space 5, and an additional picture is revealed. There are 3 pictures at level 3, 4 pictures at level 4, and 5 pictures at level 5. To win, you need to reach the star at level 5.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2017" value="Voting" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="60651" value="Mechanism: Image Interpretation" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="104317" value="Éderson Ayres" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="154162" value="Thiago Koche" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="154163" value="Ariana Picolotto" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="7938" value="Ludens Spirit" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>