<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="391562">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Nbk-8tPDP118mH_DYCa3ZQ__thumb/img/BdF37k457Wl_-5KXpAoNqKfM0K4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7564643.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Nbk-8tPDP118mH_DYCa3ZQ__original/img/y4ZD6Gks0ISg11ROz1xNQgibBhc=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic7564643.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Crane Game" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="ようこそクレーンへ" />
			
						               													<description>The card game has a theme centered around a crane machine and collecting prizes. The players take on different roles: Chief Officer, Crane Player, Cheerleaders, and Referees. Players aim to accumulate the most prizes and coins to achieve different titles at the end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To set up the game, the cards are folded and placed on the game board along with a prize. Each player starts with three coin cards. The Chief Officer, Crane Player, and remaining players are assigned their roles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;During gameplay, the Chief Officer gives one of their coin cards to the Crane Player, who acts as the crane operator. The Crane Player uses their hand, mimicking a crane arm, to try and grab prizes from the game board. The Chief Officer verbally guides the Crane Player on the movement of the crane arm.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Crane Player closes their eyes and moves the crane arm based on the Chief Officer's instructions. The Chief Officer can give instructions to move right, go forward, and drop a prize. The Crane Player tries to grab the prize using their thumb and index finger. If successful, they must rely on intuition to return the prize to the game box without opening their eyes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the Crane Player successfully returns the prize to the game box, the Chief Officer receives the prize. However, if the Crane Player fails to grab the prize or drops it midway, their team's turn is over. The game continues with each player taking turns as the Chief Officer and the Crane Player moving to the left.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After everyone has completed a round as the Chief Officer, the second round begins with new assignments. After each player has had three turns as the Chief Officer, the game ends. The player with the highest number of special prizes becomes the &amp;quot;Best Player,&amp;quot; while the player with the most coins becomes the &amp;quot;Best Crane Player.&amp;quot; The player with the most prizes and coins earns the title of &amp;quot;Crane Master.&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2021" />
						               				<minplayers value="3" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1032" value="Action / Dexterity" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="106103" value="高井 九 (Kyu Takai)" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="6844" value="Daiso (ダイソー)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>