<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="391549">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Pillars of Heracles" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Join us in an epic journey through the world of Archaic Period Greece, where heroes are born, civilizations rise and fall, and the gods themselves shape the destiny of mortals. Prepare to immerse yourself in a strategic and immersive board game experience.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this game, you will embark on a quest to build and shape your own city-state, compete against formidable adversaries, and navigate the intricacies of ancient Greek society. As a player, you will have the opportunity to forge alliances, engage in epic battles, delve into mythical lore, and witness the rise and fall of empires.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Against its rich historical and mythological backdrop, the game offers a unique blend of area control, rondel mechanics, and deckbuilding, tableau building, set collection and resource management. As you expand your city-state and manage your resources, you'll need to strategize your moves on the rondel, carefully planning your actions. Building and managing your deck allows you to customize your strategy and prepare for exciting challenges.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Will you channel the wisdom of the mighty Olympian gods to lead your city-state to greatness? Or will you rely on cunning tactics and military might to conquer your rivals?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As you explore the game's intricately designed world, you will encounter iconic figures from Greek history and mythology, engage in trade and diplomacy, and face the challenges and rewards of city-building. Every decision you make will shape the fate of your city-state and determine your path to victory.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Are you ready to step into the world of legends and forge your own destiny? Join us and become part of the legacy of the ancient Greeks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;mdash;description from the publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2024" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="90" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="14" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1029" value="City Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1015" value="Civilization" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2664" value="Deck, Bag, and Pool Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2081" value="Network and Route Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2813" value="Rondel" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2015" value="Variable Player Powers" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2933" value="Worker Placement, Different Worker Types" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="131489" value="Ol치h Tam치s" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="132337" value="Szab칩 D치vid" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="46993" value="Apeiron Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>