<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="39155">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Hardball Wars" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>HardBall Wars is the &amp;ldquo;brother&amp;rdquo; to our football game, GridIron Wars. While I was designing GridIron Wars, an idea popped into my head&amp;#10;regarding a similar method to resolve a baseball game. After putting the idea to paper and mailing it to a couple of trusted friends,&amp;#10;HardBall Wars was born. HardBall Wars is simple enough for a child to learn, but robust enough to satisfy even the most veteran of baseball gamer.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Many may wonder, why a baseball game? Aren&amp;rsquo;t there plenty of good ones already on the market? In short, the answer is yes. There are many&amp;#10;fantastic baseball games on the market. With HardBall Wars, I&amp;rsquo;m really not re-inventing the wheel. You&amp;rsquo;ll never hear me tout the game as&amp;#10;better or more realistic than any other game currently on the market.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;However, having said that, I do feel like this game stands up well against any other baseball game in terms of what is truly most important,&amp;#10;the &amp;ldquo;fun factor&amp;rdquo;. My testers and I have had an absolute blast playing the game. The unique batter-pitcher interface, combined with the X-&amp;#10;Factor deck, makes the game unique and in my humble opinion very fun to play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;My philosophy with Downey Games has always been to price games as low as possible, making the games accessible to all. Most current baseball&amp;#10;board games sell in the $50-$60 range. While that is reasonable to most, it does make it an expensive proposition to purchase multiple&amp;#10;seasons or teams. With HardBall Wars, I&amp;rsquo;ve purposely designed the game with a cost factor in mind. For that same $50 or $60 you&amp;rsquo;ll be able&amp;#10;to purchase multiple seasons of HardBall Wars. Also unlike other games, we strive to rate nearly every player who stepped foot on the field&amp;#10;of play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HardBall Wars is based upon a modified log5 method. That may not mean much to some, but using this method allows the pitcher and batter to&amp;#10;&amp;quot;Interact&amp;quot; on every at-bat. Rather than a 50/50 model or a generic pitcher grade, with HardBall Wars you'll see the difference between&amp;#10;pitchers and batters and their impact on the at-bat in a very visual way. You'll also immediately see the difference in righty/lefty&amp;#10;matchups at the plate.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fielding is not neglected in HardBall Wars. You'll see the difference between the gold glove shortstop and the lead gloved fielder not only&amp;#10;in terms of errors committed but also the ability to turn hits into outs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The most unique aspect of HardBall Wars is our introduction of the X-Factor Deck. And often times it can generate a lot of excitement.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Within the X-Factor deck just about anything you&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen in a baseball game can take place. From run downs, appeals, dropped third&amp;#10;strikes, rain delays, rain outs, ejections, brawls to even the extremely bizarre like the now famous Pine Tar incident&amp;mdash;all are possible&amp;#10;within the X-Factor Deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The deck is far more than just a Rare Play mechanism. There are many conditional events within the deck and even some very mundane plays.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The X-Factor deck simulates the events that happen in real life that as a tabletop gamer you don&amp;rsquo;t often see in your own gaming. One can see&amp;#10;something out of the ordinary in almost every baseball game in real life. And we have brought that to the tabletop through the use of the X&amp;#10;-Factor Deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With HardBall Wars, the decisions as a manager are all yours. You decide when to steal bases. You decide when to Hit and Run or Sacrifice&amp;#10;the runner to the next base. You'll make the call when to intentionally walk the opposition&amp;rsquo;s slugger, or when to bring the infield in to&amp;#10;cut down a runner at the plate. You'll make the call as when to attempt a squeeze bunt or play for the big inning. You'll make the call to&amp;#10;bring in the lefty specialist to face the opposing left hand slugger, or stick with your right hand throwing starter. With HardBall Wars, you&amp;#10;may even be ejected from the game! Nearly every situation that faces a major league skipper is replicated in the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The printed game features game charts printed in full-color, the season of your choice, 3 dice, a die-cut X-Factor deck also printed in full color, score sheets all packaged in a sturdy game box.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2008" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5586" value="Sports: Baseball" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="4793" value="Jeff Downey" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3566" value="Downey Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="13" />
			<average value="6.23077" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.24985" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="23" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>