<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="391666">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Down the Chimney Dice &amp; Card Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Players roll dice to collect Gift Cards worth different values; at the end of five rounds the player with the highest total value Gift Cards is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game includes its own dice tower and specialty dice. The dice each have one of six holiday symbols on them: gift, holly, candy cane, snowflake, star, and coal. Players are each dealt three Gift cards, which have different quantities of the symbols on them -- the more symbols, the higher the value. The active player drops the six dice down the tower, then tries to match the rolled symbols to the cards in their hand. If there is a match with a card, those dice are set aside and the remainder re-rolled. Also, the card that matched is set aside for later scoring. Each player may roll the dice up to three times on their turn. If a coal symbol is rolled, that die remains on the table, and if the player accumulates three coal symbols, their turn is over and they may not score any cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;After the third roll, all other player may attempt to match the symbols on the set-aside dice to those on their Gift cards, and those Gift cards are kept by that player, so everyone is potentially accumulating points. If three coal symbols are rolled, no player scores any points that turn. If the active player rolls three of a kind of any symbol (except coal) they may decide to take an Action card, which must be played immediately. The Actions are 'Nice' (take an extra roll of all six dice), 'Naughty' (next player loses their next turn), and 'Gift Exchange' (the active player may swap one of their Gift cards with a higher-value Gift card of another player, or from the Gift card deck).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When the active player's turn ends, play passes clockwise to the next player. Once all players have had five turns (five rounds), the game ends and each player's collected Gift cards are totaled. The player with the highest total wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game is a tie-in to the publisher's &amp;quot;Elf on a Shelf&amp;quot; system.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2022" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6364" value="Holidays: Christmas" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="50586" value="The Lumistella Company" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>