<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="392074">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/sOG3HWpsaXnRKFw-IIxoEw__thumb/img/eyvZbAUCvu6qpEo8RQgTh53N_AU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic7584747.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/sOG3HWpsaXnRKFw-IIxoEw__original/img/LZw67JxOnYV4wM4aA3Lo7d-4PSo=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic7584747.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Dabula" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Dabula is a two-player board game that takes about 3 to 10 minutes to play and offers a great deal of fun and challenge.&amp;#10;- - -&amp;#10;Goal&amp;#10;Your goal is to reach the other side of the board. That seems fairly easy but since your opponent has the same task there are some things that will most likely make it a bit more intricate to forfill.&amp;#10;- - -&amp;#10;How to play&amp;#10;Choose a color and arrange all your tiles facing down before you. That's your stock.&amp;#10;Take 2 random tiles from your stock and place them in the nearest left and right corner of the playing field.&amp;#10;Draw 2 new tiles. You can place the tiles behind, next to or in front of one of your own tiles (you can not place them diagonally).&amp;#10;The symbol on the tile must have at least share one attribute with all tiles that are adjacent to it horizontally and vertically (same symbol and/or same number of dots). These rules also apply to the tiles of your opponent that you encounter and therefor becomes a bit more difficult to place your tiles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each turn you can place one tile from your hands onto the game board according to the rules of placement. After that you take a new tile from your supply to replenish your hand to 2, your turn is over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you do not have a matching tile in your hand you put the tile beside the bord creating a discard pile and you take a new tile from your supply to replenish your hand to 2, your turn is over (you do not place a tile on the board in this turn).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you have a tile in your hands that matches exactly (symbol and amount of dots) to one of the tiles of your opponent that is adjacent to one of yours you have the opportunity to take over that position.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You can place your tile on top of the already present tile and make a dabul!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From that moment on only the tile on top of the pile decides who can place tiles adjacent to the pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your opponent can do the same thing again if he also has (or draws) that exact match too. This can end up in a pile as big as 8 tiles! This option is literally a game changer! Within seconds you can interfere in the strategic plans of your opponent and force him to change his offensive playing to defensive, take a detour or even force him to concentrate on another segment of the game board.&amp;#10;- - -&amp;#10;When do you win?&amp;#10;The rule is very simple: if you reach the opposite side, you win. &amp;#10; The tiles do not have to form a continuous path, you just have to reach the opposite side of the playing board first to win. But do not let this simplicity fool you, be careful!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Defending your territory is just as important as crossing over to the other side.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Create barricades to avoid that your opponent has an easy crossing. Take over positions to thwart your opponent and force him to change his plans.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Act quick, keep track of all sides and try to combine your strategy with the (bad) luck you might encounter!&amp;#10;- - -&amp;#10;Expert mode&amp;#10;Whoever reaches the other side first and has a continuous path of tiles in his/her color wins.&amp;#10;It is therefore possible that you are already on the other side, but you still have to reclaim fields in your path that your opponent has taken over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tip: there are 4 tiles of each symbol in the game for each player. Sharpen your tactics so that you will have enough pieces left at the end to repair your path.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="10" />
						               				<minplaytime value="3" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="10" />
						               				<minage value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="116" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="2" />
					<result level="117" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="118" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="119" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="120" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61206" value="Category: Two players fighting games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>