<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="392371">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Chatuchak" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Bangkok's Chatuchak market, with its colorful tent booths, is one of the world's biggest markets.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players have the task to group the market booths better by market segments like decoration, cloths, furniture, plants or food.&amp;#10;Each player manages a section of the market area.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To group the booths in their section better, players want to rearrange booths. But you can relocate booths only as long as they stay along the same alley!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Your own market section has booths along 4 horizontal and 5 vertical alleys, so it has 5 rows and 6 columns of booth spots.&amp;#10;One of the spots in your 5x6 grid is empty, the other 29 spots have a booth and each booth belongs to 1 out of 5 market segments.&amp;#10;In each turn you move 1 booth horizontally or vertically to the empty spot, so to the spot where your last-moved booth came from.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For victory points players try to reach goals better than their opponents. There are 12 goals to compete for, like having 1 of the 5 market segments grouped the best, or having 2 specific market segments connected the best, or having the longest straight path with 1 market segment or the biggest rectangular area with 1 market segment.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;These goals bring you a victory point when you reach it first, if you take over from another player, and if you have the lead at end of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The number of turns players have, depends on the progress at the time track. So that you can assess, but can't know, the remaining number of turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="9" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2940" value="Square Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22184" value="Admin: Upcoming Releases" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8374" value="Crowdfunding: Kickstarter" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="124" value="Corné van Moorsel" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="41528" value="Ron van Dalen" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="77" value="Cwali" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>