<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="392368">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Easter Egg Hunt" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Hunt for Easter Eggs in a grass field! A family game inspired by the advent of Easter on 2023, the guy who came up with the original idea, a good friend of mine, wanted to make a simple game that parents can play with the children on Easter, to pass the time and possibly learn something about the important significance of that day.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game itself is very simple, but even as luck-based as it is, it is still very fun with an addictive gameplay loop. That said, there are two &amp;quot;Modes&amp;quot; to the game, a &amp;quot;Lucky Hunt Mode&amp;quot;, the original way the game was meant to be played, and a &amp;quot;Strategic Hunt Mode&amp;quot;, decided to be implemented given the issue with how luck-based it is, which is forgivable since it is a family game, but for a more strategic or &amp;quot;fair&amp;quot; experience, we came up with Strategic Hunt Mode.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each Player chooses an Easter Bunny with Powers, from Friendly, Mean, Playful and Peeky Bunny. These Powers can be used every other Turn, so knowing when to use them is important. The game itself is about flipping Cards on a Board called the Grass Field, reminiscent of &amp;quot;Snap&amp;quot;, but not quite. You flip a Card, and if it is a Dud, your Turn immediately stops. If you do draw an Elemental Egg, for which there are five Elemental types, Fire, Air, Earth, Lightning and Water, you get to draw again, and you if you draw an Element of the same type, you gain +1 additional Points, and get to draw again, and so on. This is to offset the low chance of getting multiple Eggs of the same Element at one time, as well as the lack of gaining Powers from Fusion reactions, because if another Elemental type was revealed and drawn, a Fusion Element happens, with 10 different combinations that are consulted from a Chart. There are also Composite Elements, which is when new Eggs are pushed into something called an Egg Nest, and when 3 unique Elements are arranged in the Egg Nest, an reaction happens and an effect occurs, which you will need to consult the Chart again. There is 4 Elements as well, and 5, called Compound and Etheric, and both work the same way, Discarding the Elemental Eggs to gain a Power, hence for the cost of doing so, they are very powerful.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For Strategic Hunt Mode, a push your luck mechanic is implemented, where you can keep drawing Cards until you draw a Dud, upon doing so, losing all Points accumulated for that Turn. For Fusion reactions however, you use an Elemental Egg already in your possession to react with a Card revealed on the Board, and again, you can do this multiple times, until you draw a Dud. Besides these two changes, some of the Powers for the Element Charts work differently.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-description from designer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2023" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="10" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1115" value="Religious" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2841" value="Command Cards" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2875" value="End Game Bonuses" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2661" value="Push Your Luck" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="3103" value="Resource Queue" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="85717" value="Calixtus Ashley Wee" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>