<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="39539">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/kyxJYw6Tql9cQSQq53__bA__thumb/img/dSBsvB9MeAk724eZ0aaP5T9OxvA=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic405167.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/kyxJYw6Tql9cQSQq53__bA__original/img/_OffnqoQ9d1Gkr-jpqpcxKLfzCc=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic405167.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Oblivion Pack" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This 12-scenario pack was released by Fanatic Enterprises to utilize the new armies made available by the ASL module Armies of Oblivion.  The scenarios all include armor and the armies of Bulgaria, Croatia, Romania, Hungary or Slovakia.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 116 Bad Neighbor Policy: A small scenario set on boards 3 and 49. The scenario features a March 1939 border action featuring a small Slovakian combined arms force attacking a small Hungarian force. This is nice tourney sized scenario.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 117 Sanok Action: This scenario is set on boards 48 and 2. This is a medium sized scenario set in the opening days of Barbarossa. The scenario features a dug in Russian force holding off a German-Slovakian force that needs to capture some pillboxes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 118 Zaporhze Island: This is another tourney scenario set on boards 47 and 8. Some dug in Russian defenders defend a stream crossing and try to hold some buildings against a infantry armor Hungarian force.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 119 The Face of War: During the Crimea Campaign, this scenario features the Rumanians attacking some dug in Russians supported by late arriving armor. This scenario is set on boards 19 and 16. This is your typical attack counterattack situation.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 120 Nasty Business: Much of the time Axis Minor troops were performing security services. This scenario set on boards 19 and 49 features a small partisan screening force attempting to delay rear echelon Slovakian troops from attacking the buildings on board 49 from a force of partisans set up on 49. This is a medium sized scenario.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 121 Allies in a Few Days: This one is set on boards 40 and 42. This is a meaty scenario featuring a river crossing with a twist. A dug in Russian force tries to keep a Rumanian force from crossing the river but the twist is that the Rumanians have troops popping out of the ether behind their lines. This action represents a situation where the Russians had broken through the Rumanian lines and reached a river. The Rumanian 1st Armored Division was tasked with counterattacking but the Russians were still dealing with bypassed units.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 122 Slovakian Slugfest: This one is set on boards 40 and 50. The Germans are attempting to squash the Slovakian Uprising. The Germans are attacking down these boards against Slovakian armor and infantry supported by partisans. Some unique set up conditions give this good replay value.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 123 Enemies All Around: The Bulgarians show up in this scenario. A small rear echelon German unit is surrounded. The Bulgarians have to destroy their vehicles. This scenario is set on boards 24 and 50.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 124 Paulis Detachment: This is a very meaty scenario featuring the Hungarians fighting the Rumanians on boards 49 and 22. A dug in Rumanian force tries to hold off an strong Hungarian attack.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 125 Lessons Learned the Hard Way: Here is a quick playing tourney scenario set on board 48. A small German force sets up HIP and tries to ambush a Bulgarian Reconnaissance unit. This should be a good one for lots of play with a great deal of replay potential.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 126 Path to Retribution: The Yugoslavian armored brigade shows up in this one as they try to catch and destroy a German/Croatian combined arms force. This meaty scenario is set on boards 41 and 49.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 127 Junkyard Wars: This scenario features the Bulgarian Armored Regiment attacking a force of Germans. Both sides get substantial armor and this is a meaty scenario. This scenario is set on boards 16 and 48&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2006" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="180" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="41" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="42" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="43" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="44" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="45" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="243" value="Advanced Squad Leader" inbound="true"/>
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="11040" value="Armies of Oblivion: ASL Module 12" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="11448" value="Paul Kenny" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8970" value="Fanatic Enterprises" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="18" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>