<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="42699">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4eZxlLj7tglNG5z6p64ovQ__thumb/img/eThsYaq9eEPo33OWCnwiUL7thUk=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic481974.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/4eZxlLj7tglNG5z6p64ovQ__original/img/gCe4QuDkVyVwpAErbuRcjj21Gkk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic481974.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fighting the Taliban" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>FIGHTING THE TALIBAN: Pakistan's Operation Sherdil, Aug. 2008&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The threat was and remains real.The Taliban and al-Qaeada are slowing taking over this country with nuclear weapons. Not a good thing. Operation Sherdil (Lion Heart) began in August 2008 and was initially aimed at preventing the imminent fall of Khar, headquarters of Bajaur District, to the Taliban. The military operation was intended to reclaim all of Bajaur from the Taliban and al Qaeda, which amounted to around 3000 terrorists. On August 3rd, a 200-strong force from the paramilitary Frontier Corps were surrounded by 300-400 Taliban fighters, heavy fighting erupted as they tried to break out. After a three-day battle, the Pakistani troops routed back to Khar, and the Taliban seemed victorious. They quickly followed the Pakistani force and began to threaten Khar. Operation Sherdil was later expanded to recapturing all of Bajaur district from the Taliban. This proved to be a tall order and led to a protracted series of battles over two months. Pakistan's resolve came into question (as it still does). By late October, many of the objectives had been reached but not all. Loysam was not retaken until Oct. 25th. Over 2700 terrorists had been killed, yet, Bajaur Agency remained unsettled when the army left. It remains so to this day.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Game&amp;#10;Each turn is six days, with half mile hexes. Units are battalion and company for Pakistani forces, and platoon size for al-&amp;#10;Qaeda and Taliban. The game is a true conventional military force taking on the terrorist groups in Bajaur Agency from August through October, 2008. The terrorists were well armed and had fortified many of the small towns outside of the city of Khar. They had been slowly taking over the area. Sherdil was prompted when a small force of paramilitary found themselves surrounded and under siege at Loysam from 300 Taliban. This Pakistani force managed to breakout and fled to Khar, which was under Taliban pressure. It was at this time the Pakistani military unleashed its forces in what many claim ended in a draw. Some 8000 soldiers, 20 Cobra gunships and F16 jets pounded the enemy, which numbered 3000. Pakistan's resolve came into question with this early offensive.&amp;#10;In the game, the Pakistani army does not have unlimited resources to conduct a long offensive as each attack will cost. How well the Pakistani player orchestrates his attack will dictate who the winner is. The Taliban can literally appear and disappear in certain types of terrain making any attack questionable. Their unique movement and evasion will cause any Pakistani player frustration.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2009" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1069" value="Modern Warfare" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="10624" value="Country: Pakistan" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58531" value="History: War in Afghanistan" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1257" value="Perry Moore" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4366" value="Firefight Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="13" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="7" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>