<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="4785">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_MSYhVn0jkIPm9KrCZ0glg__thumb/img/xFQ6fvtsBMXGwpySd36BYCHV7uo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic15784.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_MSYhVn0jkIPm9KrCZ0glg__original/img/chzzzSYMw3yKsineySBjIbhIVP4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic15784.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mysteries by Vincent: Case of the Wirst Case Scenario" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>How to Host a Murder styled party game.  No audio comes with these games, just clue booklets and party planner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Case of the Wirst Case Scenario&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A murder mystery party game for 10&amp;#10;That magnate of the publishing world, Mr. William Rudolph Wirst, President &amp;amp; CEO of Wirst Publishing, has invited you to attend a very special celebratory dinner to be held at the Hi-8 Hotel, Midtown Manhattan, New York. After dinner, Mr. Wirst will unveil the latest title soon-to-be published by his company: It was the Wirst of Times, It was the Best of Times. The manuscript, of course, is Mr. Wirst's own memoirs, and he promises to regale everyone with excerpts - information that some might even consider, well . . . shall we say . . . scandalous? Incriminating? Surely it will be a night to live on in the memories of all who live through it . . .&amp;#10;Your Dinner Companions Include:&amp;#10;P. Leigh Jerreyes is an RN by trade, and new to the world of writing. She is a budding author who has written her first book of poems entitled, &amp;quot;Bedpans and Betadine.&amp;quot; She's brought her manuscript with her, hoping to convince Mr. Wirst to publish it. After all, her creative writing teacher told her she was raw with talent and wide-eyed with wonder. Leigh herself modestly dismisses such praise, saying &amp;quot;I only want to pursue one of my greatest dreams in life.&amp;quot; She wears her nurse's uniform wherever she goes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lilla &amp;quot;Li&amp;quot; Belle S. Lander is a media darling whose articles have been published in every major newspaper across the country. Flashy and charismatic, Li is an award-winning journalist whose written words spark controversy and terror in even the most sedate circles. She is also hoping to sell her first book-length Washington expose': The Hussies in the House. Li often wears business suits or professional clothing.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Allyssa T. Fairre is easily the most successful tabloid writer in the country. Her work of tracking down Elvis-impersonating extra-terrestrials has brought her a great deal of notoriety. Suave, elegant and chic, she is known to turn up anywhere around the globe in pursuit of a story. Never married, she claims to be in search of the &amp;quot;right rich man for a husband.&amp;quot; Yet she rarely lacks handsome male escorts, and often wears rather revealing attire.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Starr Cross is the epitome of the &amp;quot;femme fatale&amp;quot; romance writer and her books have long topped the romance charts. Her latest titles, The Letches of Lidgefield County and Lust Knows No Bounds, have sold well over twelve million copies worldwide. Yet hers is a rags to riches story: Starr worked as a cocktail waitress before selling her first book. Her rise to the top was the equivalent of a bungi jump in reverse. In the publishing industry she is considered to be a hot property, frequently sought after by other houses and literary agencies. Starr prefers clothes with ribbons and ruffles.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lowe Z. Ajante is a used car salesman turned literary agent who is sure his hard work will pay off soon. He believes in good old American free enterprise, waving his stars and stripes in the faces of pouting pessimists. He knows his attempts to constantly upgrade his stable of authors will eventually bring him fame and fortune. Lowe is a flamboyant dresser who believes polyester double-knit has taken a bad rap, and is sure it will make a comeback any day now.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Murray &amp;quot;Mur&amp;quot; DerMisteree is an internationally famous writer of mystery novels, second only to Agatha Christie. Though some say he has far surpassed the Queen of Crime, as he is critically acclaimed for the realism of his work. &amp;quot;Makes you feel like you're right there committing the crime,&amp;quot; says the L.A. Whines. Personally, Mr. DerMisteree has been described as a brooding intellectual, a genius in his genre. He frequently wears his hunting clothes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Pickford &amp;quot;Pick&amp;quot; E. Publichere is a new publisher who has recently released a number of trendy titles, including - The Mother-in-Law Excuse Book: A Guide to Avoiding Holiday Hassles and Other Traumas. He has been described by Kiss Up Now magazine as a calculating, competitive entrepreneur, sure to make it big. His closest colleagues call him &amp;quot;Pick,&amp;quot; while the thousands of writers who receive his rejection letters each year refer to him by different names. Pick always wears business suits.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ray Gene Bull is an award-winning sportswriter who enjoys traveling to remote parts of the world in search of little-known sporting events. Thus he is known in professional circles as the &amp;quot;Mr. National Geographic&amp;quot; of the sports world. Physically fit and ruggedly handsome, Ray is a former quarterback for Poedunck University. He is as popular with members of the opposite sex as he is with his readers. Ray prefers clothes that display sports logos.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Portia &amp;quot;Por&amp;quot; Rytere is a literary novelist whose mixed metaphors are often only understood by MENSA members, and whose analogies are so deep that one must reread her books many times to grasp the hidden meaning. Her latest seven-hundred page novel, And Then They Died, is a fictitious rendition of the mating rituals of tsetse flies, and like her other books, is published by Wirst Publishing. Por is the past president of Superior Novelists of Balderdash, or SNOB, and the ex-wife of Richard Rytere. Elegant eveningwear usually comprises her wardrobe.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Richard &amp;quot;Rich&amp;quot; Rytere is sometimes called the King of Commercialism, having capitalized on the &amp;quot;quick read.&amp;quot; One of Wirst Publishing's hottest authors, Rich's books have yet to miss the bestsellers lists. His latest novel, Life, Love, and Rain Falling Silently on the Mountaintop, is bound to be his greatest work yet. But fame and fortune have not changed Rich - he's still the same fun-loving guy from Philly, who prefers hot dogs to filet mignon. He owns a wide collection of flashy ties.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ever wonder what it would be like to be a famous author? Here's your chance to play one for the evening! Why don't you try on fame and fortune and see what it feels like?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This mystery is probably the easiest ten-person mystery game to put on. Since the setting is modern day, the costumes are usually something a person finds in their closet.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;So have fun, and while you're at it, sign a few autographs for your adoring fans!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1996" />
						               				<minplayers value="10" />
						               				<maxplayers value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="180" />
						               				<minplaytime value="180" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="180" />
						               				<minage value="18" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="111" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="112" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="113" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="114" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="115" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1039" value="Deduction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1040" value="Murder/Mystery" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="4982" value="Series: Mysteries by Vincent" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1867" value="Cindy Vincent" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1119" value="Mysteries by Vincent" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>