<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="55888">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/P3ownRHUAkKjb-yr39GcfA__thumb/img/t5sG7Jxg4grRQcBzR6Tg7Orf6t8=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic553903.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/P3ownRHUAkKjb-yr39GcfA__original/img/6GDC4QWwpNV4WKvNTOx95rxYGUw=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic553903.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Monopoly of Three Kingdoms" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="大富翁三國群英會" />
			
						               													<description>This is a monopoly-like game with three kingdom's theme.Roll your dice,buy locations,employ generals to conquer other lords and unite ancient China.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Some rules differences between this and Monopoly:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;         Each player starts with a property and their starting space is that starting property rather than the Go space (called the palace in this game). For example, Cao Cao starts the game at Chen Liu and owning that deed.&amp;#10;             In addition, the colored set corresponding to the starting property of that pawn is also free to purchase for that pawn when landing on it. For example, Cao Cao can buy any blue property (including Chen Liu if he ever lost it, Shou Chun, or Xia Pi) for free when landing on it and no one owns it.&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;         No bonus for completing a colored set.&amp;#10;             Unlike monopoly, you can start building &amp;quot;houses&amp;quot; (camps in this game) even w/o collecting a complete colored set.  However, you can only build them when you land on a property and only on that property.&amp;#10;             Only 3 houses before a &amp;quot;hotel&amp;quot; (city [walls] in this game).&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;         Free parking space replaced by a Shrine space where if you land on it, any accumulated money in that space is split between the player that landed on it and the bank at around 50/50.&amp;#10;         Jail/Just visiting space replaced by maintenance space&amp;#10;             Each player pays 200 taels [aka gold] per property owned (doesn't matter about houses).  &amp;#10;             Player who pays the LEAST money from this gets a free camp built on a property of their choice.  Money paid for maintenance goes to the shrine space.&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;         Go to Jail space replaced by a Disaster Aid space. &amp;#10;             Each player pays 10% rounded down to the nearest 100 taels of their current cash on hand to the shrine space.  &amp;#10;             The player that pays the MOST money from this gets a free camp built on a property of their choice.&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;         Community Chest cards are called Secret Pouches (ala Zhuge Liang) and are generally somewhat more powerful than in Monopoly, though some are still weak as well.&amp;#10;         Chance spaces replaced by a Tavern space where you can recruit officers to join you.  &amp;#10;             Only 3 officers are displayed at a time and these 3 are replaced whether or not you recruit one after landing on a Tavern Space.&amp;#10;             Each player can recruit a total of 3 officers, which each officer having a special passive ability specific to that officer.  For example, Diao Chan forces an opponent paying rent to you to pay an additional 1500.  Lu Bu allows you to not pay any rent for landing on a space, but after using him, you must put him back at the bottom of the officer draw deck.  &amp;#10;             There are a total of 30 officers to choose from.&amp;#10;        &amp;#10;         After a player goes bankrupt, that player actually submits to the player that caused the bankruptcy.  &amp;#10;             The bankrupt player is now considered a Subordinate while his master is considered the &amp;quot;New Ruler&amp;quot;.  &amp;#10;             They share resources, officers, and properties. The New Ruler essentially gets to move two pawns per turn instead of one, with the Subordinate rolling his own moves but the results of the space the Subordinate's pawn landing on being resolved by the New Ruler.  &amp;#10;             This keeps the subordinate tied to the game instead of being completely eliminated.  When the ruler wins, the subordinate gets second place.  &amp;#10;             There can be multiple levels of subordinates as a result of cascading bankruptcies etc. &amp;#10;        &amp;#10;         The game is won when only one ruler is left and the rest are his subordinates.&amp;#10;    &amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Overall, a more complex game than monopoly, especially cause of the officer cards and the somewhat more powerful community chest.  Also, the free camps from the maintenance and disaster aid spaces promote hoarding of cash while developing only a few properties normally.  Easily expandable to 6, 7, or 8 players, really. Though that'll increase the game length dramatically, of course.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2009" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="50" />
						               				<minplaytime value="50" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="50" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="2">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="11518" value="Country: China" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="100" value="Series: Monopoly-Like" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22883" value="Theme: Romance of the Three Kingdoms" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="25824" value="Jia-Yu Lin" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="41948" value="Chia-Yu Lin" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="9215" value="TWOPLUS Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="8" />
			<average value="6.75" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.829156" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="12" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="1.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>