<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="63148">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RYbEJGC7rs-C2ftFZAMa1g__thumb/img/mrOHhItdcvBUZiR8-RbZ0A0VIqU=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic620348.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/RYbEJGC7rs-C2ftFZAMa1g__original/img/8svfVG2kC4Jl2SX_Wu4eX_W8Eao=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic620348.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Crusade and Conquer" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>A modern twist on the classic game of chess        &amp;#10;Welcome to the realm of Crusade &amp;amp; Conquer! Be wary of flying dragons, defending flag bearers, and the castle&amp;rsquo;s move-restricting levels. A fantastical world where a modern twist on the classic game of chess feeds the eternal feud between King Ulric and King Montfort, the realm of C&amp;amp;C is a place that knows no grandmasters and players enjoy the luxury of an entirely new endgame&amp;hellip; what's your endgame?&amp;#10; Game Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing Crusade &amp;amp; Conquer is similar to chess... well kind of.  While many of the characters and their movements mirror classic chess,  the new board, castles, and game pieces have introduced twists and turns that will make even the most strategic and advanced players think twice.   But this game is not just for the masters.  Anyone can learn... and once you do you'll never turn back.&amp;#10;The Castle&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Castle has two levels or floors. The upper level is where the King and Queen begin the game; with the King always starting on the X. Remember, the game is lost if the opposing Flag Bearer reaches your King&amp;rsquo;s starting X.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game pieces cannot jump up or down more than one level in a single movement and must stop their movement as soon as a level is traversed. There are two exceptions to this rule:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;bull;Castle Exception #1: the Knight is allowed to complete the L-shape movement as long as it only moves one level per turn. If the Knight must move up two levels to complete its L-shape movement, the move is not allowed.&amp;#10;&amp;bull;Castle Exception #2: because it can &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo;, the Dragon&amp;rsquo;s movements in and around the Castle are not restricted. However, the Dragon can only move more than one space in a single turn if it is flying over teammates.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Dragons&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A Dragon may move one space per turn in any direction. A Dragon may jump its teammates in any direction for as many spaces as they are in a straight line. A Dragon cannot jump opposing game pieces, even if they are between teammates. With the exception of the Flag Bearer, a Dragon may kill any opposing game piece by moving in any direction. A Dragon may also kill any opposing game pieces (except the Flag Bearer) by jumping teammates to complete the move. A Dragon must end its move as soon as it kills an opposing game piece. A Dragon may traverse more than one level of The Castle in a single move only if it is jumping over teammates.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Flag Bearers&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A Flag Bearer may only move one diagonal space per turn. A Flag Bearer cannot jump teammates or opposing game pieces to complete a move. A Flag Bearer cannot kill any opposing game pieces but can only be killed by the opposing King. A Flag Bearer must end its move as soon as it traverses a level of The Castle. A Flag Bearer can win the game by reaching an opposing King&amp;rsquo;s starting position.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning Crusade &amp;amp; Conquer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are two potential endgames (ways to win the game) in Crusade &amp;amp; Conquer. The first endgame is to kill the opposing King. The second endgame is to get your Flag Bearer into the opposing King&amp;rsquo;s starting position (the opposing X).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2009" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="96" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="97" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="98" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="99" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="100" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1035" value="Medieval" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2676" value="Grid Movement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="4024" value="Traditional Games: Chess" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="36449" value="Martin Maheux" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="11" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.22474" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="25" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="8" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="4" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>