<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="65747">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/AxIelVjJ9qr2j9GZerBOvg__thumb/img/iQ83o8nPfzJwaa2s3o95Lv82qJE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic656877.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/AxIelVjJ9qr2j9GZerBOvg__original/img/FcicxS4Ol2Z5Gl_YUrpgCN99T9k=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic656877.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="House Hunt" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Object of the Game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The overall object of the game is to be the player with the best deal on a home. The best deal is determined by the total cost of purchasing the home less the total value of the home.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each mini-game contributes to the total cost and/or total value of the home which is recorded on the home buyer's contract. At the conclusion of the games, the cost and value of each home is calculated, producing a winner(s).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each mini-game has a contributory goal to the overall goal.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Mortgage Mambo, the mini-game goal is to get as many loan offers as possible and then to select from those offers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Realtor Roundup, the mini-game goal is to get to the best realtor and therefore get the largest number of buyer incentives.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Inspection Perfection, the mini-game goal is to increase the cost or decrease the value of your opponents Home Buyer's Contract.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;House Hunt General Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For both single player games and games of two or more.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Each player should take a blank Home Buyer's contract. Each player will need a pen or pencil to record results on their home buyer's contract.&amp;#10;   2. Select one Home Profile from the set of Home Profile cards. Each player will use the same home profile as a starting part for their home contract.&amp;#10;   3. Each player then uses a pencil to fill out their home-buyer's contract with the information from the home profile card.&amp;#10;   4. For a complete game, play in the following order:&amp;#10;          * Mortgage Mambo&amp;#10;          * Realtor Roundup&amp;#10;          * Inspection Perfection&amp;#10;   5. You may also play each game by itself or skip one or two of the games. If Inspection Perfection is played, it should always be played last.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Realtor Roundup and Mortgage Mambo Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For two or more players:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Select one side of the draw box for the game you are playing to pull cards from.&amp;#10;   2. Place the END GAME marker in the middle of the draw box For a longer game, place it closer to the side opposite where you will draw from.&amp;#10;   3. All player tokens begin at START.&amp;#10;   4. Select one player to be first. This is the current player.&amp;#10;   5. The player on the right of the current player draws a task card from the draw box and asks the current player the question on the outside of the card.&amp;#10;   6. If the current player requests a hint, the player on the right opens the card and reads the hint (usually a set of multiple choice answers).&amp;#10;   7. The number of spaces a player may move is stated on each task card and depends on whether the current player got the answer right and whether a hint was used. Follow the directions on the task cards.&amp;#10;   8. When a player lands on a space with directions, the player should follow those directions prior to the next player taking a turn.&amp;#10;   9. When a current player's turn is over, play proceeds clockwise to the next player, who becomes the current player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For single players:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Set up play as for two or more players.&amp;#10;   2. Draw task cards and answer the questions.&amp;#10;   3. If you need a hint, open the task card enough to see the hint while still obscuring the answer.&amp;#10;   4. When you've answered the question, open the card completely to confirm if your answer is correct.&amp;#10;   5. Move your token as directed and record any changes to your home buyer's contract.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Inspection Perfection Rules&amp;#10;&amp;#10;For two or more players only.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Shuffle Inspection Deck. Each player should take four (4) cards from the deck, making certain not to show the cards to other players.&amp;#10;   2. There are two objectives to this game. The first is to discard all of your cards. The second is to ask other players questions that you think they don't know, forcing them to pick up another card from the pile and to receive a penalty which will affect their home buyer's contract.&amp;#10;   3. Play proceeds as follows:&amp;#10;          * A player chooses a card from his/her hand and asks any other player the question on the card.&amp;#10;          * If the questioned player gets the answer correct, s/he receives the reward specified on the card.&amp;#10;          * If the questioned player gets the answer wrong, s/he receives the penalty specified on the card and must draw a card from the inspection pile.&amp;#10;          * In either case, the questioning player discards the card in the common discard pile.&amp;#10;   4. Play then proceeds to the player on the left of the player who just asked the question.&amp;#10;   5. When one player has no more cards, the game is over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Ending The Games&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the end of the games, complete the calculations on your home buyer's contract. The person with the best deal wins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2007" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2005" value="Stock Holding" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="34611" value="Erikheath Thomas" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>