<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="67272">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/O3szDg42qix3wEtmablTfw__thumb/img/2OpQmxoD4usgLBaruswPiwZ_1cQ=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic3135500.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/O3szDg42qix3wEtmablTfw__original/img/oWwnwORhtrjjiy9bnHXgrVZV04w=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic3135500.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Bloody Steppes of Crimea: Alma – Balaclava – Inkerman 1854" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Krwawe stepy Krymu: Alma-Bałakława-Inkerman 1854" />
			
						               													<description>Tactical game about three famous battles of Crimean War.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game scale:&amp;#10;1 hex = 200 m (Alma 250 m)&amp;#10;1 game turn = 30 minutes&amp;#10;1 counter = infantry battalion-riffle company/cavalry regiment/artillery battery.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game description&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game uses the standard hex-and-counter system, and ten-sided dice. Each hex represents 200 metres or 218 yards of terrain (Alma 250 metres or 273 yards), each game turn corresponds to 20-30 minutes of real time.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Infantry is represented by battalions and light infantry companies, cavalry by regiments (sometimes divided into two counters), artillery by batteries (classified by weight).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each game turn is divided into phases:&amp;#10;1)Command phase &amp;ndash; players use their Commanders-in-Chief and dispatch riders to give orders to subordinate commanders.&amp;#10;2)Activation phase &amp;ndash; after determining the initiative, players, using the Activation Markers, choose the division to activate. Activated units, move, fire, commence melee combat and reorganise disorganised units. The opponent can react by firing or counterattacking&amp;#10;3)Reorganisation phase &amp;ndash; players reorganise broken units&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The principle of the game is based on an order system, which is associated with target hexes. The player must carry out the assigned order (of course, he gives them to himself), until the order is changed by the Commander-in-Chief, or the division commander manages to change it by himself. The order must be associated with a target hex (i.e attack hex, defend hex). The possible orders are: ATTACK, DEFEND, FORCED MARCH.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game tries to present the diversity of combatants tactics mainly through unit formations. And so &amp;ndash; Russian infantry can fight in company or closed columns, French infantry in closed columns or lines and the British infantry only in lines. Each side can form squares, and can use skirmishers. The French Eastern Army excels in light infantry tactics due to it&amp;rsquo;s many formations of such units (chasseurs, zouaves, algerian tiraillieurs).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game treats the concept of  zone of control differently from other games &amp;ndash; it gives up the obligation to stop moving the unit in the enemy ZOC. The ZOC is a phenomenon that allows to fire or initiate close combat, and it is dependent on the units formation and the range of its firearms.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unit movement doesn&amp;rsquo;t differ from other hex-and-counter systems.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game discerns fire combat and melee combat. The fire combat takes into consideration the following aspects:&amp;#10;1)firing unit strength&amp;#10;2)firing unit formation (skirmishers)&amp;#10;3)target formation&amp;#10;4)distance to target&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fire combat is initiated at the cost of movement points in the unit&amp;rsquo;s activation phase, and once as a reaction for the enemy&amp;rsquo;s doings. Fire combat is based on the unit&amp;rsquo;s morale modifier, which is a combination of unit&amp;rsquo;s morale, training and other &amp;ldquo;psychological&amp;rdquo; factors. Fire combat effects in loss of  endurance, disorganisation and in critical cases, breaking of the attacked unit. Losing movement point is also the effect of fire combat.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Artillery fire combat is constructed similarly to infantry fire combat &amp;ndash; it only takes into account the differences in range and firepower of guns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As a rule, to initiate melee combat, the unit must fight in a compact formation (column, line) or be a cavalry unit. Starting combat requires for a attacking unit to posses sufficient movement points after moving (a marker is placed, on the unit that meets that condition). Melee combat is also based on the unit&amp;rsquo;s morale, strength, formation, also the terrain and attacks from the flank or the unit&amp;rsquo;s rear. Effects of melee combat are disorganisation (also of the attacking unit) or breakdown and taking flight. Cavalry combat also includes the unit&amp;rsquo;s momentum &amp;ndash; which is taken from the type of the unit (heavy, lancers, light cavalry). Cavalry may react by counter-charging.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The loss of unit&amp;rsquo;s endurance during the game is marked on special tables. The use of tables intents to show precisely the diverse levels of combat losses.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2014" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="600" />
						               				<minplaytime value="600" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="600" />
						               				<minage value="15" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="2">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="2710" value="Post-Napoleonic" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="67176" value="Cities: Sevastopol" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="58051" value="History: Crimean War" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="10606" value="Sławomir Łukasik" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="11687" value="Strategemata" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="15" />
			<average value="7.26667" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.48174" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="76" />
			<trading value="4" />
			<wanting value="8" />
			<wishing value="22" />
			<numcomments value="8" />
			<numweights value="4" />
			<averageweight value="3.25" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>