<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="67411">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Level II" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Level II is a fast paced skirmish miniatures game, set in the future.&amp;#10;In the year 2222 mankind manages to devastate their home planet.&amp;#10;Nuclear fusion as well as manipulation of genes have become daily buisiness in this harsh world ruled by corporate groups.&amp;#10;Journeys to Mars have become possible and science is about to find a way to travel to the stars.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;One of Level II's biggest strengths is, that it consists of a ruleset only. No miniatures come with this game!&amp;#10;This way a player may pick any of his miniatures and calculate their point costs referring to the extremely well elaborated and very fine tuned equipment list.&amp;#10;There are rules for about everything that has ever set it's metal or plastic foot on a futuristic war-torn gametable:&amp;#10;Humans, aliens, different kinds of humanoids, tough races, weak races, robots, androids, crafts, cannons, artillery, sabotage, special ammunition, cybernetics - everything you could wish for.&amp;#10;Even the equipment table basically covers everything &amp;quot;out there&amp;quot; - maybe you'll have to substitute sometimes some weapons (like a boltpistol with a common pistol), but you will be able to work with everything that you might find in the hands or at the belt of your miniature.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The rulebook covers the basic rules as well as experts' rules and campaign rules.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Even though Level II is designed for small scale skirmishes with only a couple of individual fighters per side, the rules don't prevent you from playing large scale combats as well. &amp;#10;In that case however players should have only a few different troop types, to keep combat simple.&amp;#10;For example on the one hand you could get about 50 - 100 light weighted fighters for 1000 points, but if you really spice them up, you may field less than 10 tough guys for the same value, too.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Level II uses an unique command system:&amp;#10;The army of a player is divided into several groups (one at least!) consisting of a number of fighters depending on the faction they are fighting for.&amp;#10;Each group gets one command (e.g. &amp;quot;advance&amp;quot;), represented by a chit placed at that group's position. Depending on that command, each fighter of that group may take up to two different actions (mostly moving + something different, like e.g. taking aim).&amp;#10;In order to change that command, certain conditions have to be met (roll versus a certain value with modifiers according to circumstances like e.g. groupleader killed or minimum distance not met) - if the roll fails the command is either changed later or even not at all.&amp;#10;Specialits may act according to their specialities whenever the player sees fit.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Level II plays very realistically: Most weapons kill an unarmoured human with one hit - just as in real life. This way you will have to be very careful with about everything: &amp;#10;How are you going to spend your points?&amp;#10;Where and (even mor important:) how are you going to move your fighters?&amp;#10;This way, Level II is a very tactical skirmish game where the skill and the experience of a player garantee a victory instead of lucky dierolls.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="61" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="62" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="63" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="64" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="65" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2057" value="Chit-Pull System" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="26399" value="Markus D. Still" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="26399" value="Markus D. Still" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="11651" value="Flying Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="8" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.707107" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>