<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="68391">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pzu08wEpW2bVD_abFtd5mQ__thumb/img/ZqYFzZ1kU3HVLUljKXNrCH5foJ0=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic696253.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/pzu08wEpW2bVD_abFtd5mQ__original/img/-dWRQIe350sWRyKa48j7isnwlO4=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic696253.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Mentirosa" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Mentirosa&amp;copy; is a version of liar's dice that is played with Spanish Poker dice and the exclusive Mentirosa Player Tubes available only in this timeless game set.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The object of the game is to guess what your opponents have rolled without going over.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unlike traditional poker games that require a poker face and mostly silence, Mentirosa encourages you to trash talk, taunt and tease your opponents. It's the main strategy, hence the name of the game: Mentirosa (Spanish: liar).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;EACH SET INCLUDES:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;* 6 Mentirosa Player's Tubes&amp;#10;    * 6 sets of casino-grade poker dice&amp;#10;    * Loser Chips : These chips will help you keep track of the winners and losers.&amp;#10;    * Mentirosa Professional or Travel storage case&amp;#10;    * Instructions in English and Spanish.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2 to 20 Players (with extra sets) Ages 10 and up.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to play Mentirosa&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this version of liar's dice, the object of the game is to guess the number rolled, of any suit, among all the dice.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To begin the game, each player rolls a single die in open view of other players. The player&amp;#10;with the highest suit starts the play. If a tie occurs, only those players in the tie roll again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players throw five poker dice into their tube. They look in their tube to see what they rolled.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A turn begins when the starting a player makes a call, for example three Jacks. This&amp;#10;means they believe that there are at least three Jacks among all the dice in play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The next player has two options:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Raise the call. This is done by, raising the suit called, raising the number of dice&amp;#10;      called, or both. In this example, the next player could call three Queens, three&amp;#10;      Kings, three Aces, or four of anything else. Any of these would be higher than the&amp;#10;      three Jacks called. Or...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. Challenge the call. When a player challenges a call, he or she does not believe&amp;#10;      that the hand called, in this case three Jacks, exists among all the dice in play.&amp;#10;      To challenge, a player raises their tube, revealing their hand and signaling to the&amp;#10;      other players to do the same. At this point, the suit in play is counted.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In this example, if there are at least three Jacks among all the dice in play, the&amp;#10;challenger receives a loser chip and a new turn begins. If there are less than three Jacks among the dice in play, the calling player receives a loser chip and a new turn begins.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The loser begins the next turn. There is no passing. Once a call is raised, it is the next player&amp;rsquo;s turn and he or she has the same two options.The game continues in this manner, player after player, until a call is challenged.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Once a player receives 5 loser chips, they are out of the game. Last man standing wins!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;History of Mentirosa&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game of Mentirosa&amp;reg; is known in many countries, by many different names. Its ancestry comes from a close relative, Cubilete, a game known to have been played as early as the Roman Era, especially in Spain.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Traveling to the Americas during the Spanish Empire, it became widely popular in Cuba and other parts of Latin America during the 19th and 20th centuries.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It is rumored that Mentirosa came about when the American GI's in Cuba combined the popular American game, Liar's Poker, with the cups and Spanish Poker dice used to play Cubilete.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Arriving in South Florida with exiled Cubans in the 1950s, Mentirosa&amp;rsquo;s 21st century rebirth will give a new generation of players the opportunity to enjoy this classic game the way it was meant to be played.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Source: www.mentirosa.org&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2004" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="81" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="82" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="83" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="84" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="85" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1023" value="Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1030" value="Party Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2014" value="Betting and Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="22160" value="Mechanism: Bluffing – Dice Cup" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="36187" value="Robert Barrueco" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="11773" value="Yuca Productions" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="6" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>