<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="69481">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mSsxzHNs3yUTMNlkFsk1TA__thumb/img/p_4SPp9lDekeultFdTxNeEoSljs=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic731162.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mSsxzHNs3yUTMNlkFsk1TA__original/img/J-jn4yhD502Fu36q0GUizCS_QSE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic731162.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="MelodieXpress Composing Music" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The MelodieXpress Composing Music Pack takes up where the MelodieXpress Note Reading Pack leaves off. Composing Music adds more and cards and more games to extend the fun and increase the learning.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Overview&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At its heart MelodieXpress is a collection of games about music. The packs include playing cards based around music notation - notes, clefs, key signatures and more. MelodieXpress uses a series of card games to teach the elements of music theory, and to teach the players the skills of sight-reading and composing music.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Composing Music Pack brings further cards, along with its own guide book. New notes include semi breves, minims and quavers, and more accidental notes (sharps, flats and naturals). It also introduces time signatures - 2:4, 3:4, 4:4 and 6:8 time - plus bar lines and the key signatures for the Alto clef - (C major, G major, D major, A major, F major, B flat major and E flat major).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The focus is still on fun, but the additional cards in the Composing Music pack provide the basis for new games as well. The cards are combined with those from the Note Reading Pack to provide the expanded deck used in the new games.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Gameplay&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Guide Book provides some additional definitions and an introduction to the required music theory. It also presents 13 new games. Depending upon the game playing time can run from 5 to 30 minutes. The majority of the games cater for 2-6 players, though some can extend to include more if needed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The early games build upon the skills developed in the Note Reading Pack, with games based around the key signatures, scales and chords. The later games make use of the new cards to introduce rhythm and melody.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;lsquo;Rhythm&amp;rsquo; is a game for 2-6 players and introduces the use of key signatures and time signatures. Players progressively play cards from their hands to build up sequences of music. The grouping of notes must be consistent with the time signatures which start each sequence. As the game progresses players may add cards to their own or others sequences, aiming to build tunes of at least 18 notes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;lsquo;Sure Time&amp;rsquo; starts with a time signature and a sequence of 10 notes. Each player in turn chooses bar line and rest cards to introduce into the sequence and marks out each of the bars within the sequence of notes. Points are scored for correctly sequencing the cards. Each player faces a different combination of cards and time signatures as play progresses around the table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;lsquo;Beat the Bar Line&amp;rsquo; allows players to compose their own music. Each player progressively weaves together a communal collection of note cards with bar lines, rests and time signatures from their individual hands to build a growing composition. The game also introduces repeat bar lines and double bar lines with special rules for their play.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;lsquo;Composing Music&amp;rsquo; adds additional challenges for those players who are learning an instrument or are taking choral lessons. Play starts with a player building a 3 bar segment of music built from the game cards. Points are scored based upon the composition. The following player in the sequence may then gain bonus points by correctly playing the piece. They then add a bar to the piece of music. Play continues with players alternately attempting to play the developing composition and then adding bars until all of the cards set out for that session have been used. Variations to the game allow for the substitution of different key signatures as the game progresses, as well as the use of accidental notes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Taking it Further&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Together the Note Reading and Composing Music Packs are intended to provide a fun series of games and activities which introduce the basics of sight reading and music notation. Additional packs and resources extend the system still further.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game system is designed to be flexible and open ended. The variety of cards allows players and teachers to develop their own games and activities beyond those provided in the pack. &amp;#10;Additional games will also be published on the MelodieXpress website, sharing new games and activities as they are developed.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The MelodieXpress System&amp;#10; MelodieXpress is a fun, educational and easy way to learn to read music. Using the approach that we learn best through play, MelodieXpress uses games and activities to introduce the key concepts of musical notation and music theory. This step-by-step approach allows you to learn at your own pace, while the games provide an enjoyable way to learn and consolidate your knowledge of music.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;MelodieXpress Composing Music is not a complete game. Ownership of MelodieXpress Note Reading is required.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;ISBN 978-0-9807592-1-1&amp;#10;Patent Pending&amp;#10;&amp;#10;[Publisher's Information]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="5" />
						               				<minplaytime value="5" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="5" />
						               				<minage value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="241" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="242" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="243" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="244" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="245" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1094" value="Educational" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1054" value="Music" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2023" value="Cooperative Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2048" value="Pattern Building" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2060" value="Pattern Recognition" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2009" value="Trick-taking" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="28718" value="Theme: Music Making &amp; Makers" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="69480" value="MelodieXpress Note Reading" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="36790" value="Paul Edgar" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="36788" value="Amanda Just" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="36789" value="Beth Lang" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="12021" value="Amagination" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>