<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="69633">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/p_eG26CaGTYD9ZifqH-uag__thumb/img/V1tbXaH76SHKPl4rWiMlUg0L8LI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic988023.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/p_eG26CaGTYD9ZifqH-uag__original/img/tHFXdfWC8EtGeskcgd82UHQCZ5w=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic988023.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="Una serata a Saint Vincent: con Tony Binarelli" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>(Text extracted from the introduction of the game, written by Tony Binarelli)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;quot;The noise of the ball that bounces on the roulette wheel. The rustle of cards that slip on the green table. The sound of dice shaken in the dice-box. The murmur of the players. The silence of expectation. The blue smoke of cigarettes. Anxiety, joy, frustration depicted by the gambling on the faces of the crowd around the tables. This is the atmosphere in the halls of a casino. A thrilling atmosphere that attracts and disrupts all your senses. An extraordinary and unrepeatable sensation that Fortune gives you when filling your pockets with money or taking away everything you have. Because, in fact, winning does not matter.  What is important is risking and defying the Fate at that beloved and, at the same time, hated green table.&amp;#10;The purpose of this game is just to give everyone a chance to try these feelings, tempting fate seamless. Come with me and your friends to spend an evening at this very special casino every time you want. You will not regret. Challenge your luck with roulette, poker, telesina, Macao, s1ot machines and many other exciting and funny games. If you are cautious, intelligent and, above all, lucky, you will have the chance not only to clean your playmates out, but also to break the bank of the casino and become the King of Players&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is composed by: &amp;#10;1 - A game board with all the squares indicating the different gambling rooms: roulette, poker, Telesina, Macao, dice, Tic Tac, Black Jack, +6 / -6. Moreover there are also: the Ballroom, the Night Club, the Grill Hall and the Entrance Hall.&amp;#10;2 - A dice-box &amp;#10;3 - Two 6-side dice&amp;#10;4 - Five poker dice for the Tic Tac game. &amp;#10;5 - A deck of French cards used for following games: Poker - Telesina - Macao - +6 / -6. &amp;#10;6 - A deck of 35 surprise cards (the &amp;quot;Black Jack&amp;quot; deck). &amp;#10;7 - A slot machine. &amp;#10;8 - Nr. 16 tokens with the shape of mini-bottles, different by colour, to be used to indicate the position of each player on the game board and the different bets on the roulette panel.&amp;#10;9 - A roulette wheel. &amp;#10;10 - A lot of paper chips for the players&amp;rsquo; stakes and to compose the bank (denominations: 5, 10, 20, 50, 100)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;(Testo tratto dall'introduzione del gioco, scritta da Tony Binarelli)&amp;#10;&amp;quot;ll rumore della pallina che saltella sulla ruota della roulette.&amp;#10;ll fruscio delle carte da gioco che scivolano sul tavolo verde. Il suono dei dadi agitati nel bicchiere. Il mormorio dei giocatori. Il silenzio dell&amp;rsquo;attesa. Il fumo azzurro delle sigarette. L&amp;rsquo;ansia, la gioia, la frustrazione che il gioco dipinge sui volti della folla attorno ai tavoli. L&amp;rsquo;atmosfera che si respira nelle sale di un casin&amp;ograve; &amp;egrave; questa. Un&amp;rsquo;atmosfera da brivido che seduce e sconvolge tutti i tuoi sensi. Sensazione straordinaria e irrepetibile che ti d&amp;agrave; la&amp;#10;fortuna quando riempie le tue tasche di soldi, oppure ti toglie&amp;#10;tutto ci&amp;ograve; che possiedi. Perch&amp;eacute;, in realt&amp;agrave;, vincere non importa.&amp;#10;Ci&amp;ograve; che conta &amp;egrave; rischiare, sfidando la sorte a quell&amp;rsquo;amato e&amp;#10;allo stesso tempo odiato tavolo verde. Lo scopo di questo gioco &amp;egrave; proprio quello di dare a tutti la possibilit&amp;agrave; di provare queste sensazioni, di sfidare la sorte senza soluzione di continuit&amp;agrave;. Vieni insieme a me ed ai tuoi amici a trascorrere una serata in questo casin&amp;ograve; molto speciale ogni volta che vuoi. Non te ne pentirai. Sfida la fortuna alla roulette, a poker, a telesina, a macao, alla s1ot machine e a tanti altri giochi esaltanti e divertenti. Se sarai accorto, intelligente e soprattutto fortunato non solo avrai la possibilit&amp;agrave; di sbancare i tuoi compagni di gioco, ma anche di far &amp;laquo;saltare il banco&amp;raquo; dello stesso casin&amp;ograve; e di trasformarti quindi nel Re dei Giocatori&amp;quot;.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Il gioco si compone di:&amp;#10;1 - Un tabellone contenente tutte le caselle indicanti le varie&amp;#10;sale da gioco: Roulette, Poker, Telesina, Macao, dadi, Tic Tac, Black Jack, +6/-6, inoltre vi sono il Salone delle Feste - Il Night Club - il Grill e la casella Ingresso.&amp;#10;2 - Un bussolotto per giocare con i dadi&amp;#10;3 - Due dadi numerati.&amp;#10;4 - 5 dadi con i simboli delle carte per il Tic Tac.&amp;#10;5 - Un mazzo di carte francesi che viene utilizzato per i&amp;#10;seguenti giochi: Poker - Telesina - Macao - +6/-6.&amp;#10;6 - Un mazzo di 35 carte sorpresa (mazzo&amp;quot; Black Jack&amp;quot;).&amp;#10;7 - Una slot machine.&amp;#10;8 - 16 segnalini a forma di mini-bottiglie, ognuno di diverso&amp;#10;colore, per segnalarci movimenti di ciascun giocatore sulla&amp;#10;tavola da gioco. Le bottiglie sono di diversa forma, ma abbinate dallo stesso colore.&amp;#10;9 - Una roulette.&amp;#10;10 - La riproduzione di fiches per la composizione delle poste&amp;#10;dei singoli giocatori e per la dotazione del banco. Nei seguenti tagli: 5, 10, 20, 50, 100.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="126" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="127" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="128" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="129" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="130" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1023" value="Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2014" value="Betting and Bluffing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3115" value="Fratelli Fabbri Editori  (Fabbri Editore)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="7" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>