<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="70533">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/LZHGyviRO6sBANENsqtI8A__thumb/img/tLQzPreg2jwEhFhf7ytbwFM0ZjE=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic717275.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/LZHGyviRO6sBANENsqtI8A__original/img/5Ceae_Wg4cxoVI_UvfzMstVHb0k=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic717275.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Evolution Earth" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Evolution Earth is a board game for 2-4 players aged 10 or up. Playing time is from 45 minutes up to 2 hours depending on the number of players and playing experience.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Evolution Earth is a dynamic board game of strategy, tactics and probability. It is a game of area control, card and resource management.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is very dynamic and always full of surprises and no two games are alike. You will need your tactical skills and learn what to play and when to play and where to play. You will also mastermind deeper strategic plans in order to dominate a superiority in many aspects of Animal Kingdom or just simply trying to conquer continents for your species.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You, as the player of your precious species, will try to profit from forces of nature for the benefit for your species and try to protect your species from natural disasters. Create the best possible life strategy for your species as they compete against other players&amp;acute; species. Use your species&amp;acute; cooperative skills and choose the best competitive strategy against your opponents species that try to survive as well. Conquer the land and conquer the seas. Control your natural resources and rule the elements. Harness the primeval forces of nature for your victory. The prosperity of your species rests on your hands.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Evolution Earth&amp;acute;s rules: The laws of nature are an uncompromising and absolute and merciless as Mother Nature is. Only the most adaptive, cooperative, competitive and most fit can survive in a world of a persistent struggle for reproduction, nutrition and living space. For those species that can not adapt and survive must die out and become extinct and give way to a new species that are more adapted to new conditions in an ever changing Earth and try to survive and thrive and speciate and expand to conquer new territories in a land and sea.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;At the beginning of the game, a 1 000 000 000 years ago, the Earth is more or less still an ocean planet. Ice Age has ended long time ago and snowball Earth has melted into a great planet of temperate ocean. Only a few protocontinents or cratons have become to exist over the endless surface of the vast ocean as a predicting sign for the upcoming continents, that will one day thrive with a different kind of life forms. Primordial plant life has already radiated, expanded from oceans into protocontinents and animal kingdom will soon expand their living space into a protocontinents niche too.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The animal kingdom still consists only a single-celled organisms that will soon burst into a multitude of populations of many kinds of multicellular first animals expanding their living space from the depths of ocean floor into all over the vast seas and harboring protocontinents: The Cambrian critters. These numerous types of animals will also victoriously, as a reward and prize for surviving and succeeding, evolve in time into the very first fishes, insects, reptiles, dinosaurs, mammals and birds.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The face of the Earth will change numerous times during millions of years. Protocontinents rise into a great full continents from the depths of the ocean. These large masses of land move and drift apart and reunite again. Volcanic eruptions, pandemic diseases spreading from populations to populations, climate changes, ice ages and asteroid impacts will afflict all life from time to time. Will your species survive and dominate the Earth or will they will they die out and become extinct fossils?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The great contest of survival is beginning. Are you ready to conquer the Earth?&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This description is an edit from the rulebook.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="121" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="122" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="123" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="124" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="125" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1089" value="Animals" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1036" value="Prehistoric" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2080" value="Area Majority / Influence" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2041" value="Open Drafting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2002" value="Tile Placement" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="33094" value="Tomi Rantala" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="33094" value="Tomi Rantala" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>