<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="71402">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vx2swMNUXMPn6kdQFM32bg__thumb/img/uI0zIjB_TtkN5-cVB0SIGf18A0k=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5900950.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/vx2swMNUXMPn6kdQFM32bg__original/img/K9137hnYQlVwgyB3TfGTW8MjW4o=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5900950.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="CUPONK" />
			
						                               				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="Cuponk Deluxe: Le Flush Royale" />
			    				
				<name type="alternate" sortindex="1" value="커퐁크" />
			
						               													<description>This game is for one to as many people want to play.  As described in the rules there are 2 CUPONK (Ping Pong with graphics) balls and a 30 Card &amp;quot;Trick Deck&amp;quot; that the player draws from, it illustrates a specific trick to attempt and the number of tries to complete it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If the player completes the trick in the amount of tries given they collect the card and the next player draws a new trick.  If the player fails to complete the trick in the number of tries, then the next player attempts the same trick.  Follow the same rules for completing the trick.  If all players fail, then discard the trick and move on to the next trick card, it would now be the original first player's turn again.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You can play until any preset goal you want, first to three tricks, five tricks, or until the deck is gone and count up the totals.  The game even recommends combining 2 or more trick cards into &amp;quot;Expert&amp;quot; tricks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each of the three versions has their own trick deck, so if you purchased all three you can combine them into one 90 card deck.  Also included are blank cards for making up your own.&amp;#10;It's actually way more fun than you would think, and the cup lights up and makes sound effects unique to the version you purchased.  The cards are really just stepping stones to making your own even more elaborate tricks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;-----From the Box-----&amp;#10;&amp;#10;What exactly is CUPONK? The object: sink your ball into the cup and light it up. Get it in and you&amp;rsquo;ll hear the sweet sounds of victory, YEAH! You rock. Miss the shot and your friends get the chance to one-up you. When playing CUPONK your entire home can become a legitimate playing field. Tables, walls, chairs &amp;ndash; IT&amp;rsquo;S ON! Test out sick trick shots like Door Jam, Stairing Contest and Wall Banger. What you don&amp;rsquo;t like the names? Okay tough guy, make up your own! &amp;#10;Show your skill and sink sick shots. Features lights and crazy (gorilla / wild wrestling / killer zombie) sounds! Includes 1 CUPONK cup, 2 CUPONK balls, 30 trick cards, a ramp accessory and instruction guide. &amp;#10;Requires 3 AAA batteries (not included). For 1 or more player(s). Ages 9 and up. &amp;#10;[Taken from HASBRO Site]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are three versions in the first wave: Gorillanator, El Campeon, Let it R.I.P.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The second wave includes three versions: Boomshakalaka, Monsterosity, King of L.A.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A deluxe edition, Le Flush Royale,was released alongside the second wave. It includes a cup with a plastic lid/backboard, Cuponk head band, five stickers, six balls, a set of thirty cards and instructions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are also two different sets of extra balls. They each include seven new balls and five stickers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="4">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="2" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="2" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="15" />
						               				<minplaytime value="15" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="15" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="106" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="107" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="108" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="109" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="110" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1032" value="Action / Dexterity" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="4730" value="Dan Sanfilippo" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="51" value="Hasbro" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8291" value="Korea Boardgames Co., Ltd." />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="105" />
			<average value="5.12845" />
			<bayesaverage value="5.48085" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="22784" bayesaverage="5.48085" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.35533" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="251" />
			<trading value="10" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="5" />
			<numcomments value="43" />
			<numweights value="9" />
			<averageweight value="1.1111" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>