<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="71720">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6pqAXxlwAkGJCYpeP9iP2g__thumb/img/ty1j4KQb26lSGOIfCHNEevjjEFY=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic797156.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/6pqAXxlwAkGJCYpeP9iP2g__original/img/s1BgTtGKYL06rzPZ5FRDpn4Opmk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic797156.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="While The City Sleeps: A game of heroic action in Granton City" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>The heroes and villains who populate the world of Granton City Press will soon be population a new table top miniatures game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;An agreement has been reached with Rattrap Productions LLC to bring the Granton City world to the games table with the fall release of &amp;lsquo;While the City Sleeps: A Game of Heroic Action in Granton City&amp;rsquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;While the City Sleeps is a fast-paced tabletop miniatures game of heroic combat set in the world of Granton City. Players control the actions of heroic crimefighters or nefarious villains and their henchmen. Each player will have anywhere from 1 to a dozen models whose actions they determine.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Combat is fast and deadly. Using the results of two six-sided dice, players try and fight through the defenses of their opponents. Heroes and Major villains can withstand punishment but their henchman will be falling left and right to slugs, knives and fists.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;All characters are pre-generated so players will be ready to go straight from the book. Special abilities will give the major characters an edge over those around them, but even the greatest hero can fall to the villain's henchmen if he is unsupported.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two experienced players will be able to play out their favorite action from the world of Granton City in about 2 hours on a game space no bigger than a dining room table.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;When approached about incorporating the diverse characters from Granton City Press into a table top miniatures game, I thought it was a great idea,&amp;rdquo; said Richard A. Johnson the man behind Rattrap Productions LLC. &amp;ldquo;Initially we tossed around the idea of incorporating the characters into one of our existing games but came to realize there was enough unique and interesting new character in Granton City to support a new game themselves.&amp;rdquo;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Johnson said he had been working on a new game, and it turned out to be a perfect vehicle for characters such as The Black Wolf, The Starling, Ghost Wind and Churchill: Alien Bounty Hunter.    &amp;#10;    &amp;#10;The new game will be an ideal place for the soon to be released Black Wolf miniature from Zombiesmith Miniatures. Watch for more news on the miniature front in the weeks ahead.    Granton City Press expects to have The Black Wolf #1: Metal Monsters of Doom out in April. Black Wolf #2, and spin-off titles Unit 13, Ghost Win and Churchill: Alien Bounty Hunter follow in the fall, with a release expected to coincide closely with Rattrap&amp;rsquo;s release of While the City Sleeps.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="121" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="122" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="123" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="124" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="125" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1047" value="Miniatures" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1093" value="Novel-based" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2028" value="Role Playing" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="2119" value="Richard Anderson" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="6373" value="Rattrap Productions LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>