<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="71921">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jp6tP-KF6DfP7RiyramRJA__thumb/img/cI1b_svFn-c4sp9XsAWWPfk2RYM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic729472.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/jp6tP-KF6DfP7RiyramRJA__original/img/D-VYTOssTNmlnjQS3nv5ts7FagA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic729472.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Spicks and Specks: The Board Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Based on the hit ABCtv music quiz show&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Come together with family and friends to test your music knowledge. Sing, dance, scribble and shout your way through a non-stop hit parade of musical trivia and hilarious tasks. Spicks and Specks - out of the box and into your loungeroom - the music quiz that hits you with it's best shot!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Aim of the Game:&amp;#10;Spicks and Specks is your chance to come together with family and friends to sing, dance, scribble and shout. Take on a hilarious hit parade of musical trivia and tasks and reach the Final Countdown before the other team beats you to it!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Setting Up:&amp;#10;First, players must split up into two teams. Teams may consist of as many players as you like but must have at least two players in each. Position the game board where all players can reach it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;How to Play:&amp;#10;Each space on the board corresponds to a question category (see: Categories) and states whether the opposing team asks the playing team a question or ifthe playing team chooses one of it's own members to ask their remaining team mates. Used cards are returned to the bottom of the deck.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Play moves in a clockwise around the board, one space at a time. For each correct answer, a team may move forward one space and answer the next question, up to a total of three spaces in one turn. A team's turn is over if they correctly answer three questions in a row, or if they answer a question incorrectly.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a team fails to correctly answer a question asked by one of their own teammates, the opposing team answers correctly, they move the playing team back one space on the board. Play continues as normal.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a team is stalled on a certain category and answers incorrectly three turns in a row, they automatically proceed to the next space on the board at the start of their next turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cards:&amp;#10;There are five types of cards that correspond to the coloured spaces on the game board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winning the Game:&amp;#10;The first team to make to the finish space wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Categories:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Know Your Product:&amp;#10;The opposing team reads out the four different choices of genre. The playing team selects the genre of the trivia question they would like to answer and the opposing team reads the question aloud.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Sir Mix'n'Matchalot:&amp;#10;The opposing team reads out three artists and clues to three interesting facts. The playing team must match the artists to the facts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Medley:&amp;#10;When you land on a Medley space, you get to choose a question to answer from any category on the board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cover Versions:&amp;#10;A player from the team draws a picture (in silence) representing the song title on the question card. The other team mates must guess the correct answer from the picture.&amp;#10;Note: You can't include letters or numbers in your drawing!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Mondegreens:&amp;#10;A player from your team reads out the misinterpreted song lyrics on the question card. The other team mates must guess the song title.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Word Up:&amp;#10;A player from your team reads out the random words on the question card. The other team mates must guess the song title.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Musician or Serial Killer:&amp;#10;The opposing team reads out the name from the question card. The playing team must then guess if the person is a musician or a serial killer&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Cover or Original:&amp;#10;The opposing team reads out a song title and artist. The playing team must decide whether that song was an original or a cover version of another artist's song.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Common People:&amp;#10;The opposing team reads out the names of three musicians. The playing team must identify what the three musicians have in common.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two Little Words:&amp;#10;A player from your team looks at the name of a musician on the question card and then says two single-word clues to their team mates (the words in the musicians name are not permitted). The other team mates must guess the musician.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Substitue:&amp;#10;A player fromyour team sings a song from the question card, substituting the lyrics of the song with words from a book, magazine or from the games rules. The other team mates must guess the song title.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Final Countdown:&amp;#10;A player from your team asks the other team mates a music trivia question. If the playing team answers the question correctly the move to the Finish space and win the game!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;taken from the rule book of the game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2008" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="1">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1054" value="Music" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1027" value="Trivia" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2073" value="Acting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2038" value="Singing" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2019" value="Team-Based Game" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="3" value="(Uncredited)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="926" value="Imagination Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="26" />
			<average value="5.93796" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.17505" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="83" />
			<trading value="2" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="7" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="1" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>