<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="74034">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Epic Engagements" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From Manual Prologue:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Story So Far...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Shortly after the discovery of faster&amp;minus;than&amp;minus;light travel, humanity reached for the stars and expanded beyond its home solar system to colonize planets throughout the Milky Way galaxy. Hundreds of planets have been inhabited, with the species seeing unprecedented growth and prosperity, all ruled autonomously and under the protection of the Free Alliance of Stars. Man had believed, after almost limitless exploration and colonization, that mankind was unique, and that no other intelligent life of any kind existed outside of human&amp;minus;controlled planets. Then, the Continuum attacked the Sirius system. Human defense forces did not believe there to be a threat in the universe, and were woefully unprepared for the invasion, with nearly every man, woman, and child murdered by the alien menace.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Three weeks after the last message was received on Earth, the human fleet dispatched from Jupiter Base reached the Sirius system only to find that every colonized planet had been bombarded from orbit, utterly devastating the colonial surfaces. No sign was left of life, human or otherwise, until a small lifeboat was recovered in space with a dying scientist, Dr. Mark Wallace, who chronicled the assault on the colonies shortly before his death. Humans were not alone in the universe, and they were being systematically eradicated.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;30 years later, the war was being waged in every corner of the galaxy, and Humanity had taken advantage of its genetic predisposition of reason and their inherent ability to quickly learn and adapt. They first learned the name of the enemy via decoding communications taken during battles, and later reverse&amp;minus;engineered power sources, propulsion systems, and most importantly, the highly advanced weapons systems that the enemy had used against them. Humanity now had a hope of repelling the invaders, and would stop at nothing until the Continuum was stopped.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Continuum is a collective of enslaved worlds, made up of several hundred species native to planets outside of our galaxy, all burning with the sole desire to subjugate all habitable planets and species, or destroy them if they were deemed a threat. The only chance that humanity has to stop them is to travel to the Continuum Homeworld, located somewhere in the Crab Nebula, and to destroy their leadership and command and control structure, defeating the threat forever.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Epic Engagements is a stand-alone tactical starship combat game that can use included components as well as models from Star Wars Miniatures: Starship Battles or any other models. Players begin on opposite ends of a 24x36&amp;quot; Star Map and using a turn-based &amp;quot;simultaneous action&amp;quot; mechanic wage war on one another using capital ships such as carriers, frigates and fighters to defeat the enemy force.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="240" />
						               				<minplaytime value="240" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="240" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1016" value="Science Fiction" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2020" value="Simultaneous Action Selection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="38557" value="Pete Ruth" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="38557" value="Pete Ruth" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="10" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>