<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="76359">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mDfGd0SOa6VWkfDSCFQ-HQ__thumb/img/q3JgJOFew7U65Drm1-3M8xG0b6E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic770561.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/mDfGd0SOa6VWkfDSCFQ-HQ__original/img/PAYTGob-7FGnTJNXSw7y4n88zSU=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic770561.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Tivolispelet" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the game rules:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;TIVOLI GAME &amp;#10;Game idea&amp;#10;Welcome to Tivoli! Here you can enjoy yourself at all the famous attractions. Take the train on wheels, show your skills on the range, try your luck at the wheel of fortune, drive bumper cars and take a trip to the carousel or roller coaster. But you do not forget haunted house! Here, although unpleasant things happen, but because you have to visit all attractions, you have no choice.&amp;#10;It must also be fast and have luck with dice and cards carnival. Winner is the player who, after visiting all the attractions, first go through the whole Tivoli.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game contains: &amp;#10;1 game board&amp;#10;6 tokens &amp;#10;1 dice&amp;#10;48 carnival cards (8 of each color) &amp;#10;96 Event cards&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Preparation&amp;#10;Each player must equip itself with a checker and 8 carnival cards of the same color. The cards are mixed and put into a pile, face down, in front of each player.&amp;#10;For each attraction (other than the shooting range and wheel of fortune) each event includes 16 cards. These are, face down, in the box at each attraction. Game pieces are placed at TIVOLI input. Then turn each of the top amusement park in his card and place it, face up, in front of him. The card talks about the attraction which he / she must first go.Till finally determined who to start (eg, the youngest player).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game&amp;#10;The player who is next in line to hit the dice and move their game piece as many steps as the die shows. When the player comes to the entrance (marked with red arrow) to move the right attraction is finished, even if the dice show more. The next time it is his turn, he / she go into. The wagons, radio, cars, ghosts, etc. serves as a playground. In each attraction (other than the shooting range and wheel of fortune) are two or three games box whose color is different from the others in attracting. Ports of one player in such a field, he / she take an event card and follow the instructions. The card is then back bottom of the pile (not freebies).&amp;#10;(When two or more players are on the same attraction as follows: It is not allowed to be lost or end up on the same playing field as a front current players. It means that behind the present author can not always use all their dice dots the movement.&amp;#10;This rule does not apply if a player receives an event card which gives an extra roll or extra step forward, which means that he / she can catch up or overtake.&amp;#10;A player who is emerging from an attraction to turn the next card in his amusement park high in order to know where he / she was then attending. (You do not stop. On the blue arrow that marks the end). They use carnival cards must always be available, with the front up, front of the player.&amp;#10;A player who visited all the attractions to be as fast as possible to get to the end.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Freebies&amp;#10;Part of the event cards are free tickets. One player who receives such a card will keep it indefinitely. Anyone who has a freebie do not follow an instruction in an event card if he / she does not want. It might include whether to stand over a roll of the dice or move back to their game play. A free ticket can be used in all sites, regardless of where it was. However it only once, and when it is used on the bottom back in its rightful high.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Shooting range and wheel of fortune&amp;#10;At these sites there are no games or field events. One player who will be visiting the shooting range or wheel of fortune must normally stay on the red arrow, even if the dice show more. The next time it is his turn, he must be better than a five or six (the highest score on the range) and first or second (lucky for wheel of fortune) to move their gamespiece to the blue arrow and turn over a new carnival cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Extras casting&amp;#10;On the 'three game fields are images even dice. A gamer that end up on any of these fields will have an additional roll.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winner&amp;#10;The player who, after having visited all attractions, first go through Tivoli will win the game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1991" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="60" />
						               				<minplaytime value="60" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="60" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="36" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="37" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="38" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="39" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="40" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="405" value="Kärnan" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>