<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="76873">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="One Lap of the Track" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This is a non-replay game based loosely on the 400 Metres track event. Eight players each control a single runner on a staggered lane track - special rules apply for 4 to 7 players.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each runner has fifteen Bid Tokens, totalling 100 points of Stamina, and for each of the eight Turns a Movement Card is exposed to show the Movement permitted for the top bidder, the second highest bidder, and so on. One or more of the tokens are placed face down in front of the player and the bids examined when all players have made up their minds.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The highest bid claims the first Movement shown on the card, the second highest the second, etc, etc. A Tie-Break Card quickly settles the matter between equal bids. The used Bid Tokens are discarded, except for the Zero token which is taken back into the hand (useful to bluff with!) and the next Turn takes place using a new Movement Card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Some Movement Cards give a significant Movement advantage to the top bidder, others may have the top three positions gaining equal Movement, but the lower bidders are at a definite disadvantage. All 27 Movement Cards are different (eight are dealt randomly for each race), so bidding tactics and bluffing vary with each race.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Four Movement Cards are on display when the race starts, the one used for the first Turn plus the next three Turns, and at each Turn another Movement Card is revealed, so some forward planning is possible - and necessary! And the staggered lanes means that the true position of the runners is not known until they enter the home straight which deliberately adds to the uncertainty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If heats and/or semi-finals are run half of the unused Stamina can be carried forward to the next round or Final, and in any event unused Stamina can help a runner 'win' a photo finish if runners are level after eight Turns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Although designed as a multi-player game for eight players the game can be played by as few as four players with the special rules provided. It has excellent possibilities for Play-by-(e)Mail.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5712" value="Sports: Athletics / Track and Field" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1259" value="Lambourne Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>