<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="81856">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/brBmCe_An2Nnxew38vcjfg__thumb/img/_WZyGmgFDH_V2yYndHkaaf2w7E4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic807597.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/brBmCe_An2Nnxew38vcjfg__original/img/0aadN47A3VpIZAMfgKNHY2BkCMk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic807597.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Lost &#039;The End&#039; Board Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>In this epic &amp;lsquo;Print and Play&amp;rsquo; board game you will play as either Jack, Kate, Sawyer or Hurley, as you travel around the island encountering not only fellow 815 survivors but also the island&amp;rsquo;s natives known as the &amp;lsquo;Others&amp;rsquo;. You may even come across polar bears, boars or the mysterious and deadly Smoke Monster.&amp;#10;As well as being uniquely structured to encompass the events of 6 seasons of LOST, this game is very heavy on theme and detail.&amp;#10;The sheer depth of the game, and the large number of Encounter cards, ensures that even after several plays there will still be more surprises left for you.&amp;#10;So step aboard Flight 815 and be prepared to begin the ultimate LOST experience...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A summary of play&amp;#10;You will start the game rolling a die and moving around the outer track of the Island Game Board, visiting locations such as the Barracks, the Cockpit section, the Black Rock and the Hatch. When rolling the &amp;lsquo;Eye&amp;rsquo; symbol you do not move and should instead draw one of your Flash-backwards card (later in the game Flash-forwards and Flash-sideways cards are used). Your &amp;lsquo;Flash&amp;rsquo; cards usually instruct you to increase or decrease your Skill points or gain Fate points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;When you visit certain locations, and have encounters, the marker on the story track will be steadily advanced. When the story track reaches certain points, changes will be made to the game; for example the Encounter Deck being used may change to another one, or certain Friends counters may become de-activated.&amp;#10;The story track will also instruct you and the other players to move to one of the separate game boards or a different game track on the main board.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;As you progress through the various stages of the game, the Encounter decks will continually change so that you meet people and find items from the different seasons of the LOST saga. Also your chosen character&amp;rsquo;s skill points will gradually improve making future challenges easier, and you will gain all important Fate points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;You will receive Mystery Counters as rewards. Each of the various mysteries depicted (for example Jacob, the Numbers) is made up of a set of 5 cards. If you can collect a complete set, they can be traded in for additional Fate points.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Eventually the action will move to the centre track on the game board where one of the players will be chosen to succeed Jacob. The end game will then commence. Along with the other players you must defeat the Man in Black and play the Desmond card at the Light Source space in order to save the island and win the game. Whichever player has the most Fate points at this point is declared the winner, but should your fail and allow the Man in Black to survive, all players lose the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;LOST &amp;lsquo;The End&amp;rsquo; is a Print and Play board game from MM Games, for 2 to 4 players, due for release in November 2010.&amp;#10;It takes on average between 2 to 3 hours to complete a game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game is non-profit making and is a fan-made project intended for the entertainment of fans of the the TV series LOST. No copyright infringement is intended.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="150" />
						               				<minplaytime value="150" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="150" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2004" value="Set Collection" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="7218" value="Matthew Meadows" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="7218" value="Matthew Meadows" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="5546" value="MM Board Games" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="3.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="6" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>