<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="82154">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/YvT9xExvej9btEECor3y3A__thumb/img/GgGTW_tU-UTl46p4hQEj7VyOH4U=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1117874.png</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/YvT9xExvej9btEECor3y3A__original/img/UWijoLoTJOLGLUGkk5TEn7RPi8c=/0x0/filters:format(png)/pic1117874.png</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Killer Bunnies Odyssey Promo Cards" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Promo Cards are distributed at conventions, bunny promotions and special bunny events. Some cards are distributed when you buy your game through Playroom Entertainment or from select retailers.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;There are seven copies of each promo card: one for each color deck with a cost requirement relating to their corresponding color, and one with colorless cost requirements.  For the colored cards, the &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; is replaced by the letter corresponding to the deck that they belong to.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Triple Bunny (Available with some purchases of A-Decks)&amp;#10;AX61/AW01: Triple Bunny allows a player to add (+3) Civ Points to his d20 die at the start of each turn if the player has three Triple Bunny cards in The Bunny Circle.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Time Circuits (AX62 available with 3-Pack Starter Decks; AW02 available with Killer Bunnies and the Conquest of the Magic Carrot)&amp;#10;AX62/AW02: Time Circuits may be used once by a player to add Civ Points to his d20 die equal to the number that the player rolls on the d12 die if it matches the number value of the current minute, hour (AM or PM), day, month or year (last two digits).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Onyx Lotus (Available with some purchases of C-Decks)&amp;#10;AX63/AW03: Onyx Lotus may be used for one turn by a player as any three saved Resource cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Female Mating Bunny (Available with some purchases of B-Decks)&amp;#10;BX31/BW01: Identical to BX01/BX02, but with different art.  (Note that both versions are misprinted.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Point Of Hue&amp;#10;BX32/BW02: Point Of Hue may be used once by a player to force any one opponent to trade any one of his bunnies in The Bunny Circle for any saved Resource cards from the player equal to the bunny&amp;rsquo;s point value. The player chooses the bunny and the saved Resource cards.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Wonka Chocolate - Bunny Modifier (Available with some purchases of Killer Bunnies and the Quest for the Magic Carrot: Chocolate Booster)&amp;#10;BX33/BW03: Wonka Chocolate may be placed under any bunny in play and coats the bunny in chocolate. Any player may consume the bunny to satisfy any Feed The Bunny card. No Civ Points are awarded to any player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Psych-Out Bunny (Available with some purchases of C-Decks)&amp;#10;CX31/CW01: Identical to CX02, but with different art.  (Both versions are misprinted.)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Night at the Roxbunny&amp;#10;CX32/CW02: Night At The Roxbunny may be used once by a player only after sunset and before sunrise to take any two cards from his Discard Pile and to shuffle them back into his Draw Pile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Peter Venkbunny&amp;#10;CX33/CW03: Peter Venkbunny may be used once by a player to force all opponents to take any card with a Symbol out of their five-card hand and to place it face down. For each card, the player attempts to guess the Symbol. If correct, the opponent subtracts (-1) Civ Point and the player adds (+1) Civ Point to his d20 die. The player rolls the d6 &amp;#3;die once to determine how many times (per card) that he may guess.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Sighter Bunny&amp;#10;DX31/DW01: Identical to DX03 and DX04, but with different art.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Tear Me a New One&amp;#10;DX32/DW02: Tear Me A New One may be used once by a player to either add (+1) Civ Point to his d20 die or tear this card in half and add (+5) Civ Points to his d20 die.  The player must actually own this card if he wishes to tear it in half.  This card may not be repaired and used again after it has been torn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Flame On&amp;#10;DX33/DW03: The player with Flame On saved may sacrifice this card to eliminate the burn cost for any Double Ground Weapon, Triple Ground Weapon, Double City Weapon or Triple City Weapon card.  The Card Cost of the weapon (without the burn cost) must still be paid.  Flame On must be a saved Special to be used immediately.  The Card Cost is paid when this card is saved.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1079" value="Humor" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6507" value="Animals: Rabbits" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="3975" value="Game: Killer Bunnies" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="66603" value="Killer Bunnies and the Ultimate Odyssey" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="1501" value="Jeffrey Neil Bellinger" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="28222" value="Jonathan Young" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="244" value="Playroom Entertainment" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="11" />
			<average value="4.90909" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="2.64419" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="66" />
			<trading value="24" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="13" />
			<numcomments value="8" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>