<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="83055">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cEZXFkjBhjodaEhjPa7seg__thumb/img/AqukqvAmspLx6MiAB3m882pDUP4=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic810593.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cEZXFkjBhjodaEhjPa7seg__original/img/vtZ2AxafVw6BEmSOIlFtw3PuxOg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic810593.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Illegal Game" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the Publisher&amp;#10;&amp;#10;[ Do you dare to dream? ]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The American Dream (The Illegal Game), is a family game, a tribute to immigrants from all over the world, live their adventures, laugh with them, earn money, work two jobs, go to school, learn English and Spanish while you play, get marry travel through Queens, Brooklyn, Manhattan, the Bronx, Staten Island, be an immigrant for two hours, a hilarious experience that will take you a long time to forget. Buy for your friends, for your boss, for your grandparents so they'll remember the good old days. Family entertainment for ages 10 to adult.   BE AN IMMIGRANT FOR A DAY AND SEE WHAT IT TAKES TO MAKE THE AMERICAN DREAM YOUR OWN.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is presented in a way that is easy to understand and execute, meaning that by playing it you may only spend your time going through these situations whereas in real life you may lose your dignity.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Illegal Game is a bilingual board game (English and Spanish for now) that allows you to experience what we have just discussed, that&amp;rsquo;s right, as soon as you arrive at JFK you are thrown into a series of circumstances that are part of the daily lives of illegal aliens just as we described above, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand what it feels to be cheated, scared, insecure, happy, struggle, etc., the game itself takes a couple of hours to play but will allow you to experience first hand, albeit on a small scale, what real people go through to survive in New York.  Play it to the end until you are able to retire and enjoy the American dream.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To start the game you need a minimum of two (2) players and a maximum of twelve (12), the more players in the game, the better the game runs, between seven and ten players would be ideal, although the game&amp;rsquo;s dynamics allows other players to join in at any time, even after the game has already started, as long as they start up from the square marked as &amp;lsquo;Start&amp;rsquo;. Any of the players can also double up as a the Bank and all players get a &amp;lsquo;Profession&amp;rsquo; card and 5.000 (five thousand) game dollars to start.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Put the two sets of cards on their appropriate location on the board, that is, the cards that say 'Professions' on the space marked 'Professions' and the 'Main Board' cards on the spot next to them, you pick up a &amp;lsquo;Main Board&amp;rsquo; card every time the board instructs you to pick up a card and follow its instructions.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game is uni-directional.   Use one die, this will tell you the number of squares that you have to move your token.  Follow the instructions of the square where you land. If you have to go back any space(s) then follow the instructions for that square also.  Except for the Professions cards, all other cards go back to the bottom of the pile.  If you get deported you must start again from the beginning (JFK).   Lose a day is the same as miss a turn.   You can be married in your country and still get married in this game. (This is just a game)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Profession:   The Professions card, stays with you while you are playing, since it indicates the salary your are to collect every week.    If you get another profession card,  you can keep it if you wish hold two or three jobs at the same time. You can hold up to three jobs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Money:   Follow the instructions on the game board only when you land on them, not as you pass. (Except when it comes to 'Pay day', every time you pass Pay Day you get pay, even if you don't land exactly on it).  That is collect your salary as you pass.  This is the only exception, you are entitle to your salary as you pass, you don't need to have an exact landing, but if you land right on the Pay day square, collect twice your salary.  All bills have the value of an imaginary game dollar, whether Euro, Liras, Sucres, Pesos, Franks, etc., so 1000 liras is the same as 1000 dollars or 1000 Pesos, for the purposes of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;End of game: All players that retire win.   To retire, only a perfect landing on the final square is allowed.   At the end of the game, if you have 6 or less spaces to go, you need that exact number to come out on the die in order to beat the game, if you get more on the die than what you need,  wait for your next turn before trying again.   Your game ends on the square that reads: Retire happy, where the retired players can walk into the Sunshine scenery area, to wait for the rest of the players (Imagine that!) Retire back to your country, move to Florida or Hawaii, whatever your dream might be.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2007" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="7">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="8">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="9">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="10">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="11">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="12">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="12+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="160" />
						               				<minplaytime value="160" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="160" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1021" value="Economic" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="40867" value="Jorge E. Freire" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="14633" value="The J. E. F. Aliens Game Corporation" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="0" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>