<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgameexpansion" id="83680">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cpx8nNg-w0TQMixw0lxhZw__thumb/img/oOmbgDs8VvJXGUzlU7Hrj99Q8Xo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1188897.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/cpx8nNg-w0TQMixw0lxhZw__original/img/wzFOcF-ytkM3sIag4DY5SM0sFgg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1188897.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Leningrad Pack" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>16 Scenarios compatible with the ASL system.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 62 Uncle Joe's Fury, July 1941: An old fashioned combined arms assault on boards 48 and 44 with a good sized Russian infantry and tank force attempting to capture buildings and kill Germans who are equipped with infantry, tanks and guns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 63 Out Land, August 1941: The Finns and the Russians go at it in this scenario. Finnish infantry assaults the board 10 and 42 villages attempting to capture buildings against infantry, guns and tanks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 64 The Iron Ring is Closed, August 1941: This is a very meaty scenario. 44 German squads, OBA, halftracks and assault guns attack on boards 40, 49, 42, 24, 22 and 23. The Russians defend with 42 squads and several guns. The victory conditions are interesting with each side attempting to control the riverbank.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 65 Straight to the Front, September 1941: This scenario offers some good replay value. The Germans attack across boards 19 and 11 attempting to capture some buildings. The Germans get SS infantry and some AFV. The Russians start with some infantry and receive random tank support. A medium sized scenario should be popular.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 66 Tedium, October 1941: This is a classic slogging match across boards 19 and 44. Dug-In Russian troops try to stop a combined arms German force. The Germans have infantry, tanks and halftracks against the Russians with infantry, fortifications and Guns.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 67 A Cold Day in Hell, December 1941: The Finns and the Russians go at it in this small infantry only action. The action takes place in winter conditions on boards 8 and 42. This should make for good tourney action.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 68 Beast of Prey, March 1942: A real and true slugfest in the woods. Once again dug-in Russian defenders on boards 32 and 36 try to hold Germans from exiting the board. The Russians get infantry, fortifications and Guns while the Germans get SS infantry and some Stugs.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 69 Tiger Woods, August 1942: Yes! Another scenario with Tiger in its title!!! If that is not enough to get you excited then this scenario's OB should do it. The Germans get 4 Tigers up against a couple of Russian T-43's and a AA Truck. Each side gets a good number of infantry. This action takes place on boards 36 and 42.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 70 Worker's Settlement No. 8, September 1942: This cool infantry only scenario (well the Germans get one INF gun) takes place on board 33 and 4. This scenario has a cool twist for entry conditions with the Russians entering anywhere on 3 board edges. A cool twist in the VC makes for some uncertainty on where to attack. Sure to be a favorite for the tourney crowd.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 71 Cold Steel Rain, January 1943: This is another meaty scenario that should offer some good replay value given the variable VC. The Germans get infantry and some AT Guns and defend on boards 33 and 48 against attacking Russian infantry, OBA and some T-60 tanks. .&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 72 Manos a la Manos, February 1943: The Spanish Blue Division makes its debut in this action on boards 13 and 18. The Spanish infantry with an AT Gun and some variable additional forces must defend some terrain against a lot of Russian infantry, tanks and Flamethrower tanks. The Russians got the numbers but do they have the time to capture the victory terrain?!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 73 Polar Star, February 1943: Another meaty old-fashioned scenario, this time on boards 17, 19 and 18. The Germans get 24 squads, fortifications, Stugs and some AT Guns and must hold off a swarm of 32 Russian squads, Assault guns and tanks from exiting and capturing some buildings. Lots of options in this one fore each side.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 74 Fruitless Fighting, March 1943: The classic capture the village type scenario on boards 12 and 17. This scenario features 20 Russian squads supported by tanks and assault guns attacking the village against an outpost of SS infantry and some fortifications. The Germans receive reinforcements in the form of infantry and 4 Tiger tanks.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 75 Porech'e Push, August 1943: My favorite of the scenarios in this pack. The Russians fight out of a bridgehead against a strong German force to capture the hills overlooking their bridgehead. Really get the flavor of the historic action in this one. The Russians get a bunch of infantry and an assortment of AFV against German infantry, guns and additional forces that they select from an available force pool. This scenario is set on boards 3, 8 and 49.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 76 The Battle of Krasnogvadeisk, January 1944: This is another one of those big scenarios that capture the flavor of east front action. Set on boards 18, 49 and 22 this is a meaty scenario with 26 Russian squads and 5 AFV attacking to capture some buildings against 21 squads, 4 tanks and some fortifications.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;FE 77 Stalin's Revenge, June 1944: Another Finnish versus Russian scenario setup on boards 5 and 32. This is a smallish scenario featuring 9 Finnish squads and a couple of AT Guns against 15 Russian squads and 3 AFV. This is a brutal one for the Finnish as they attempt to stop the Russians from capturing some buildings.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2004" />
						               				<minplayers value="0" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1042" value="Expansion for Base-game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1046" value="Fighting" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2016" value="Secret Unit Deployment" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="18637" value="Cities: Saint Petersburg (Russia)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="10316" value="Country: Finland" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="10643" value="Country: Germany" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="18581" value="Country: Soviet Union" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="62" value="Game: Advanced Squad Leader" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameexpansion" id="243" value="Advanced Squad Leader" inbound="true"/>
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="11448" value="Paul Kenny" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="8970" value="Fanatic Enterprises" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="18" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>