<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="84880">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Sxb3Fkqe0SIE3LtQs_N0yA__thumb/img/M4TpdmaosIXGVEARUXOdboAZ72E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic1624075.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/Sxb3Fkqe0SIE3LtQs_N0yA__original/img/6OAUV1asGSoLX4PmFOBAslmx_Ds=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic1624075.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Home Rulette" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Almost all of the events portrayed in this game actually took place in Washington DC during the 1980s. The exact circumstances and names have been changed to protect the guilty.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game portrays the fauna of the District of Chaos and the institutions of its home rule government in realistic situations. Some parts of this game may be unsuitable for the politically naive.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Home Rulette is a political parody game themed on political corruption. In the game, players move their pieces along the path based on dice rolls.  Other players can impede movement through card-play.  Cards are gained by landing on spaces.  The first player to reach the end space is the winner.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;ldquo;Home Rulette takes place in the District of Chaos, a make believe capitol city of a world super power.  The game is totally fictional.  Obviously nothing so ridiculous as the characters, events or institutions contained in this game could exist in the real world.This make-believe capital city had been created by the country&amp;rsquo;s Founding Fathers as a neutral place, free from local political funny-business, where people could safely go and conduct the nation&amp;rsquo;s business. &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;However, this concept had one fatal flaw:  it worked, and as we all know, its standard government policy to try and fix things that aren&amp;rsquo;t broken. As with any congressional action, many interest groups had to be satisfied.  One of these groups was the Humor Lobby.  If improvements had to be made, they should be funny.  Congress thought long and hard on what could be done to generate the most amount of laughter over the longest period of time.  Then the idea came to them.  Why not take the capital city which belongs to all of the country&amp;rsquo;s citizens, and hand it over to a few local people who tried to burn it down in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;.  At this suggestion smiles broke out on the Congressmen&amp;rsquo;s faces as the potential for a  massive comic effect rolled through their minds. Then like drunk Olympian gods who decided to reach down from the heavens and play some tricks on some unfortunate mortals, they passed a&amp;hellip;..bill. The results were as anticipated.  The &amp;lsquo;wheeling, dealing and stealing&amp;rsquo; which occurred as a result of this act kept the city and the country laughing for years.  The District of Chaos lurched from misadventure, to atrocity, to debacle, and then back again, as the inmates played government.  To quote his excellency Mayor-For-Life Marion Larry at his third coronation, &amp;ldquo;The government can give people the change, &amp;hellip;but it&amp;rsquo;s up to the individuals to take advantage.&amp;rdquo; This game gives you, the ordinary citizen, the chance to &amp;ldquo;take advantage.&amp;rdquo;  What happens when a coalition of welfare entrepreneurs, black supremacists, radical homosexuals &amp;amp; common criminals take over the local government of the national capital city of a modern superpower? &amp;#10;Wheel, Deal &amp;amp; Steal&amp;#10;Bash Chinks&amp;#10;Blackmail Opponents&amp;#10;Spread a fatal social disease&amp;#10;Flim-flam the Feds&amp;#10;Harass Honkeys&amp;#10;Come Alive, Dis Ain&amp;rsquo;t no jive Screw a Honky, Vote De Donkey&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1988" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="0+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="1" />
						               				<minplaytime value="1" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="1" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1009" value="Abstract Strategy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1001" value="Political" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="2" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>