<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="86085">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZFzOJ_-OnahS1-xAig7PGQ__thumb/img/griOMxNqO1vReJP9zaSgbfpOxRM=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic849853.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/ZFzOJ_-OnahS1-xAig7PGQ__original/img/DN14IV-19Qk8VzEwlTNBzUEVIOE=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic849853.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Tembisa" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the back of the box: Tembisa is a unique combination between card and dice game that allows you to play three different games which are all based on Africa and its adventures.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The three different games are:&amp;#10;1. Tembisa, the treasure hunt&amp;#10;2. Tembisa, the African farms&amp;#10;3. Tembisa Memory&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The game materials consist of 1 die, 4 wooden pawns and 56 playing cards. Besides a startcard and finishcard (showing the treasure in a cave), the cards show different situations you come across (e.g. a hungry lion, a wild river, a giant snake, friendly villagepeople). Each card also shows a negative number, STOP, or 1 or 2 dice to roll.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Tembisa, the treasure hunt&amp;#10;A line is laid out of the playing cards. All cards, except for the start and endcard are placed facedown. A player rolls the die and moves his or her pawn accordingly. If the card where the pawn ends is not face upwards yet, do it now. In either case: this card shows a picture of what you met, together with a it's effect on your pawn: move it accordingly. (The number of places shown backwards, STOP or roll 1 or 2 extra dice.) The card where pawn ends up has no further effect for that players turn.&amp;#10;When six uncovered cards are in a uninterrupted row, this region is deemed fully explored. Only the positive cards keep their effect.&amp;#10;The player to reach the endcard showing the treasure first, wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. Tembisa, the African farms&amp;#10;For this variant, the start and end card are not used.&amp;#10;Players try to build the biggest farms. A farm is build by placing a -1 card on the table. This farm can be enlarged by placing a -2, -3, ... on top in order.&amp;#10;A player is allowed more than one farm, all starting with a -1.&amp;#10;The STOP and 1 and 2 dice cards are used for protecting and stealing cards from the other players: to attack play a stop card on anothers farm, depending on further STOP or dice cards, a dice duel commits between attacker and defender. If the attacker wins he or she robs a die roll of cards from the top of the attacked farm. These must be used immediatly to enlarge his or her owns farm(s) or be discarded.&amp;#10;A STOP card can also be used to protect one farm. When placed on top a farm of your own, that farm is protected against robbings. However, you cannot enlarge it anymore either.&amp;#10;Players hold six cards in their hands, drawing 1 extra at the start of ones turn. This can be a card from the drawpile, or the top one of the (open) discard pile.&amp;#10;At the end of ones turn cards are discarded or taken to fill up to 6 cards.&amp;#10;STOP and dice cards are removed from play once used. &amp;#10;Gameplay continues till there are no more cards in the discard and drawpiles. (The discardpile is reshuffled and becomes the new drawpile each time.) Then the values of the farms are added for each player, the player with the largest farm is the winner! (Just count as if each card had a positive number, instead of a negative.) Cards held in hands don't count.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3. Tembisa Memory&amp;#10;A variant on ye old Memory. The goal is to make pairs of cards. The STOP cards count as jokers, it can form a set with any other card. However, two STOP cards are not a set!&amp;#10;The 1 die and 2 dice cards are also jokers, but also give a number of bonus points at the end of the game: roll one or two dice accordingly for the number of bonus points.&amp;#10;Scoring: The values of the couples are counted, dice bonusses are added. Player with the most points wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2002" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1022" value="Adventure" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2047" value="Memory" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="42528" value="Steve Marnach" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="6" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="5" />
			<trading value="1" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>