<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="87545">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Runaway Sleigh" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Krampus,the dark twin to that jolly elf Santa Claus, is tired of his diminished and secondary role in the Christmas holiday, and has booby-trapped Santa's sleigh.  The sleigh has flown off on it's own and now it is a race: Krampus is out to ruin everyone's night by stealing gifts and Santa is trying to retreive the sleigh and deliver the presents.&amp;#10;The board consists of eighteen areas, the north and south poles which are the base points for the Santa and Krumpus players.  The sleigh is placed in the center of the board.  The game includes three dice, hand painted with both numbers and the following symbols:&amp;#10;1,2 :footprints&amp;#10;3,4  :sleigh&amp;#10;5    :a spring&amp;#10;6    :a hand&amp;#10;and on one die, a three is an asterisk, representing a wild face.  The game may be played with normal dice, but one 3 face must be marked to represent the wild symbol.&amp;#10;Setup continues by rolling the dice six times (3d6) and laying cubes that represent the gift targets on the resulting spaces, which are numbered from 3-18 (1 and 2 are the poles, and will never have gift targets placed on them.)&amp;#10;The dice and the player's tokens are manipulated using the dice.  Each turn the player may roll 3 times, keeping a die or two each time.  If a die is kept, it must be used at the end of rolling, there is no deciding to reroll later.  Whatever is rolled on the third roll is kept and used.  &amp;#10;Keep on footprint to move one space, two to move three spaces, and keep three footprints to move four spaces.  Movement is orthogonal only, never diagonal.&amp;#10;Keep one sleigh to move the sleign one space orthogonally, two to move three, three to move hour.  In addition, if the player's token is in the same space as the sleigh, you must roll two sleighs to board the sleigh.  Once on the sleigh, the sleigh is moved with either footprints or sleighs (not a combination of both, though you may wait until the end of the third roll to decide which you will use to move the sleigh.)  Move the sleigh to bring it closer to you, or to keep the other player from intercepting it.  The sleigh may not be moved remotely if the other player is riding it.&amp;#10;Roll and keep three springs to eject a player riding the sleigh back to his or her base.  (In variant play, any gifts on the sleigh at this point remain aboard)  While unlikely, it is possible to eject yourself from the sleigh if you roll all three dice three times and it pops up.  If so, too bad, back to base with yourself!&amp;#10;If on the sleigh and in the same space as a package, roll and keep two hands to deliver the package as Santa or steal the package as the Krampus. In either case, place the package in your base as a point.  &amp;#10;The wild symbol may substitute for any other in the above combinations.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Winner is player to pick up the most gift tokens when the last one is picked up, ties going to Santa, because it's Christmas, after all.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Variant Challenge 1: To 'win' a gift and get the point, you must return to your base with it (no roll required to drop it)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Variant Challenge 2: Use Variant Challenge 1, but the other player may also steal gifts from your base, and the winner is the first to get ALL the gifts.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2007" value="Pick-up and Deliver" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="6364" value="Holidays: Christmas" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="37975" value="Tim Park" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="37975" value="Tim Park" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="772" value="(Looking for a publisher)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="1" />
			<average value="4.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>