<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="88671">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8T3XJ8lr85td0R_q02KcGw__thumb/img/tzHn5hB5OgmgNIZySy1tvh_Vq2E=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic890349.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/8T3XJ8lr85td0R_q02KcGw__original/img/sBve_TYnYWtpSRvkgo63zl4n6Mk=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic890349.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Necromancer: Rise of the Undead" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Necromantic acolytes are dueling in a deserted graveyard to become the most powerful Necromancer! This is achieved by collecting arcane tomes of power &amp;amp; the chest of ultimate secrets, or by destroying your enemies minions with devastating spells and hordes of undead monsters.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This game has been taken to several war gaming conventions in the uK where it achieved Best Participation game at Warfare (Reading 2010)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The games consists of 4 players each representing a Necromancer in charge of an undead horde. To begin with eaxh player has 3 ghouls, these are; fast, good at searching but weak in combat. During each turn the players will raise a skeleton and a zombie to supplement their force. So more figures will enter play as the game progresses. The turn order is determined randomly by pulling stones from a bag. There are six stones, one for each player and the other two represent the resurrection of skeleton &amp;amp; zombie. When a players stone is drawn, they are allowed to move all their figures. No diagonal movement is allowed, nor are you allowed to enter a space occupied by other players pieces, and finally there's a stcking limit of 4 figures per area. After moving any figures against to an enemy must fight (this is compulsory), otherwise they may search for artifacts. Specially prepared dice are used for both searching &amp;amp; combat. These dice have the following faces; 2 x swords, 1 x shield, 2 x eye and 1 x swirl. During searching a number of dice are rolled, if any show the 'eye' the item has been found and will need to be carried back to the Necromancer in order to be used or scored. In combat, both players roll their respective dice, lokking for swords or shields. Basically a shield will negate a sword, any any excess swords on either side will kill a minion each. Spells can be played to influence the outcome of a battle ie 'Battle rage' - All swirls count as swords, thereby increasing your chance of killing your opponents figures.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;zombies are slow, not good in searching but the best fighters, skeletons are average across the board. The Necromancer himself, is very good at searching, but otherwise similar to a skeleton.Points are awarded for kills and for collecting items. The first player to acquire 25 points wins. Sets of gems are worth more than singles, scrolls give you another spell but are not worth any points, relics are worth 2 points, the chest is 4 (this is placed in the centre of the board) and potions are worth 1 but can be used in combat to roll an extra die. Kills are worth 2 points each, however the Necromancer is immortal so each wound he takes is worth 2.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="45" />
						               				<minplaytime value="45" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="45" />
						               				<minage value="10" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="86" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="87" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="88" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="89" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="90" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1010" value="Fantasy" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2046" value="Area Movement" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3320" value="(Unknown)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>