<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="89549">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/J17zQO0kLd8ogymSzSNKtA__thumb/img/ZjY6QcGj2Fdd8HfMbO-u8BD_Rpo=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic883670.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/J17zQO0kLd8ogymSzSNKtA__original/img/1LG6BknTB2PAbnO5TViJXwNEmCA=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic883670.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="The Lone Ranger: Frontier Town" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>&amp;quot;Return with us now to those thrilling days of yesteryear...&amp;quot;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In 1948 the Lone Ranger radio program made the following announcement, &amp;quot;In celebration of the 15th year of this program you can get your very own model of the Lone Ranger Frontier Town. With this offer you can follow the adventures of The Lone Ranger and Tonto.&amp;quot;  That day, faithful fans of the masked man and his sidekick rushed grocery stores all across America buying up boxes of Cheerios.  On each the 9 boxes of cereal were printed paper card models depicting an exact likeness of the wide-open, wild and woolly western town made famous by the Lone Ranger and Tonto.  Four play maps featuring locations such as the Sawtooth Mountains, the Powderhorn River, the Overland Trail and yes even the Lone Ranger&amp;rsquo;s Secret hideout were also made available via mail-order.  Once all 71 pieces were assembled children could follow along with their favorite radio adventures or play 1 of these 8 exciting scenarios.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 1 - The Race for Life!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Rimrock Bridge&amp;#10;Game End: Old Spanish Fort&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: While camping near Rimrock Bridge, the Lone Rnager overhears a band of bad-men plotting to ride to the Old Spanish Fort to give the commanding officer false information about an attack by Comanche Indians.&amp;#10;One player is the Lone Ranger, the other is the band of bad-men. First to reach the fort wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 2 - The Sheriff and the Rustlers&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Town Meetin&amp;rsquo; House&amp;#10;Game End: Abandoned Silver Mine&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: Cattle Rustlers, after gathering near the Meetin&amp;rsquo; House, plan to go into action against Ranchers near Lone Ranger Frontier Town. Sheriff &amp;ldquo;Two-Gun&amp;rdquo; Taylor discovers their plan and heads toward Abandoned Silver Mine, so that he can climb shaft and warn the Ranchers from this high tower. Rustlers try to reach the mine first to head off the Sheriff and stop the warning. One player is Sheriff Taylor. Other is gang of Rustlers. Winner is one who reaches mine first!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 3 - Save the Bridge!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Red Valley Desert; Sam, the Guide&amp;rsquo;s House, and Range Rider&amp;rsquo;s Inn (For three players. If only two play, start from any two of above locations.)&amp;#10;Game End: Lone Pine Railroad Bridge.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: Tonto sends up smoke signal from Red Valley Desert that a scheme is afoot to blow up the Lone Pine Bridge and wreak the Union Pacific Frontier Train. Signal is seen by Sam, the Guide, and a cowboy at Range Rider&amp;rsquo;s Inn. One player is Tonto, one is Sam the Guide and one is cowboy. All start riding toward the bridge. First there saves the bridge!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 4 - Find a Fortune!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Hidden Valley.&amp;#10;Game End: Powderhorn Land Office.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: Two or three desert rat prospectors (depending on whether 2 or 3 players are in the game) have discovered a rich vein of silver ore! Each has been working alone but by a strange coincidence all have stumbled on the vein at the same time&amp;hellip; So all start heading for the Powderhorn Land Office at full speed in order to register their claim to the land.&amp;#10;The silver mine belongs to the one who reaches the Land Office first.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 5 - Stop the Hold-up!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Sawtooth Mountains and Echo Canyon (One player from each location.)&amp;#10;Game End: Union Pacific Railroad Station.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: The Lone Ranger is on a scouting expedition up in the Sawtooth Mountains. Tonto gallops up with news that a gang of hold-up men are riding down from Echo Canyon and mean to move in on the Railroad Station and hold up all the passengers on the in bound train as it stops in Lone Ranger Frontier Town!&amp;#10;One player is the Lone Ranger and the other is the gang of &amp;ldquo;toughs.&amp;rdquo; Does the Lone Ranger reach the station in time to prevent the robbery? Play the game and see!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 6 - The Big Rodeo&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Old Cattle Trail Bridge and Outpost General Store. (One player from each location.)&amp;#10;Game End: Lazy &amp;ldquo;Y&amp;rdquo; Ranch Corral.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: The Lazy &amp;ldquo;Y&amp;rdquo; is holding a big wild-west rodeo for the entertainment of the citizens of Lone Ranger Frontier Town. One of the big events is a match race for two riders &amp;ndash; one to start at the bridge and the other from the General Store.&amp;#10;First rider to reach the corral is to win one of the finest cow-ponies in the Lazy &amp;ldquo;Y&amp;rdquo; string!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 7 - Hidden Gold!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Adobe Village and Southwest Bugle. (One player from each location).&amp;#10;Game End: Rainbow&amp;rsquo;s End Island.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: A notorious outlaw steals a precious old Treasure Map from a young Indian brave who lives in the Adobe Village. This map shows location of priceless old Indian relics buried for safekeeping on Rainbow&amp;rsquo;s End Island. A reporter for the Southwest Bugle hears about the theft and determines to beat the outlaw to the island and surprise him there!&amp;#10;One player is reporter who starts from the &amp;ldquo;Bugle&amp;rdquo; while the other, the outlaw, starts from the Adobe Village. First player at the Island wins the game and the Treasure!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game No. 8 - Kidnapper&amp;rsquo;s Hide-out&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Start: Alkali Ike&amp;rsquo;s Log Cabin, Mother Williard&amp;rsquo;s Rooming House and Rancher&amp;rsquo;s National Bank. (For three players, each to start from one of these three locations&amp;hellip;If only two play, start from any two of the three  locations.)&amp;#10;Game End: Rustler&amp;rsquo;s Cave.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Summary: Lone Ranger Frontier Town is startled one sunny morning when Wash Perkins, who owns the Grist Mill, discovers that Sheriff Taylor&amp;rsquo;s Indians are holding Kate captive in Rustler&amp;rsquo;s Cave for Ten thousand dollars ransom.&amp;#10;Wash sounds the alarm, and the first to rush to the rescue are old Alkali Ike, a cowboy staying at the rooming house, and a cashier from the bank.&amp;#10;One player is Alkali Ike, one is the cowboy, and one is the bank cashier. The glory for rescuing Kate Taylor goes to the one who arrives at Rustler&amp;rsquo;s Cave first!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;HOW TO PLAY (General instructions printed on back of each map section)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Punch out game markers and circular playing discs. Place playing discs in container (such as a cup), shake well and allow each player to select one disc in turn. Each player then moves his game marker according to the directions on the disc he draws. Of course, no player may look at disc before selecting it.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;2. Start each game on spot of Ground Plan colored GREEN, which is nearest the starting location indicated for that particular game...And move toward goal on circular stepping stones printed on Ground plan.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;3. End each game on spot of Ground plan colored RED, which is nearest to ending location for that particular game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;4. Playing discs marked &amp;ldquo;Overtake player ahead&amp;rdquo; does not apply in all games, since some players in some games will take entirely different routes to the goal. If you are playing a game in which this disc does not apply, either remove it from play or give person who draws it another turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;5. It is up to each player to figure out shortest route to his destination.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;6. If you need more game markers for extra players simply cut them out of plain cardboard and color with pencil or crayon.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1948" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="6+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="20" />
						               				<minplaytime value="20" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="20" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1055" value="American West" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1044" value="Collectible Components" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1064" value="Movies / TV / Radio theme" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1120" value="Print &amp; Play" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2011" value="Modular Board" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2035" value="Roll / Spin and Move" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="20240" value="Characters: The Lone Ranger" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="3320" value="(Unknown)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="17749" value="Cheerios" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="1" />
			<wishing value="3" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>