<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="90595">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/PZUNnoEE8gunluBkHp7Hww__thumb/img/ZpnS-R9Qp9n7KcOqUvGasFuit2w=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic5723289.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/PZUNnoEE8gunluBkHp7Hww__original/img/E_65b5GQTjJji4p3Y4EKitIcl74=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic5723289.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Lórum" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Hungarian card game played with a traditional Hungarian deck of cards (standard deck without the cards 2-6, which uses German suits). At first players bid for being the starting player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;From wikipedia (edited) :&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Lorum consists of 8 or 6 different individual games or contracts each with its own aim and rules. Each game is played four times making a total of 32/24 games in a session. The winner of a trick leads to the next. Suit must be followed; if that is not possible, any card may be discarded. The trick is taken by the highest card of the led suit and there are no trumps.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The composition of the eight/six contracts varies, but always comprises the following four deals:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;No Hearts. In No Hearts, also called Reds, the aim is to avoid winning Hearts or &amp;quot;reds&amp;quot;. A red may not be led to the first trick unless forehand only has reds. Players may not discard a red to the first trick unless they only have reds. In the succeeding tricks, reds may be discarded if a player has no card of the led suit. Each red card taken in tricks scores 1 point.&amp;#10;Obers. The aim is in Obers to avoid capturing Obers. Each Ober is worth 2 points. An Ober may not be led to the first trick, nor may an Ober be laid to it unless the player only has an Ober in the led suit (i.e. the Ober is a singleton). In the remaining tricks, Obers may be discarded at any stage if a player cannot follow suit.&amp;#10;No Tricks. In No Tricks, also just Tricks, the aim is to avoid taking any tricks. Each trick is worth a point.&amp;#10;Lorum. This contract is, like the last deal in most compendium games, a Domino-type contract. Forehand leads any card to the table. The next player in turn must play either a card of the same rank in another suit or lay off the next highest card of the same suit next to the first card. An Ace follows a Seven. If a player is unable to play a card, he misses a turn. Players may not miss a turn if they are able to play. Every turn missed costs one point. As soon as the first player goes out by laying off his last card, the remaining players score a point for each card still held in the hand. Alternatively the deal can continue until each player in succession goes out. In this variation, the second player to go out scores 1 point per card, the third player, 2 points per card and the last player, 3 points per card.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In addition, one or more (typically two or four) of the following contracts are usually inserted between the third deal above (No Tricks) and the final deal (Lorum).[6]&amp;#10;&amp;#10;First and Last Trick. In First and Last (Erster und letzter Stich) the aim is to avoid taking the first and last tricks; each of which counts as 4 (variation: 5) points. Short variant: Only two cards are dealt to each player, the stock being given to the next dealer. The first player to lead plays one of his two cards. The winner of the trick then leads to the 'last' trick. Suit must be followed if possible. Each trick scores 4 (or 5) points.&amp;#10;Fifth Trick. In Fifth Trick (F&amp;uuml;nfter Stich) players must avoid taking the fifth trick, after which the deal is ended. It scores 8 points.&amp;#10;Seventh Trick. As Fifth Trick except players avoid taking the seventh trick.&amp;#10;Red King. The aim in Red King, also called Red King-less, is to avoid capturing the 'red king' (the King of Hearts). It scores: 16 points when captured in the first trick, 8 points in the second to seventh tricks, 32 points in the last trick and 64 points if announced before playing the last trick.&amp;#10;Hairy Ape. As Red King, but players hold their cards facing their opponents; then play cards at random. If two or more are of the same suit, the highest wins otherwise each card 'takes' itself. The player who take the red King scores 8 points.&amp;#10;Train (Vonat). Using the Ace-Ten scoring system, card points are added cumulatively as they are played. The first to exceed 25 wins 1 point, 50 wins 2 points, 75 wins 3 points and 100 wins 4 points.&amp;#10;Quart(el) or Kvart. In Quartel, to the first card played, the 3 next higher cards of the same suit must be added in sequence by whoever has them until and unless no-one has the next higher card. Players do not need to play in clockwise order. The trick is won by the player who placed the last card in the sequence and he then leads to the next trick. If an eligible player has a highest card of its suit at that stage of the game in his hand (usually an Ace, but also a Seven if the Eight of the same suit has already been played), he can put it away as &amp;quot;high&amp;quot;. The game ends when the first player goes out by discarding his last card. This may not necessarily be the current player. The cards remaining in the other players' hands score 1 point each.&amp;#10;All Bad (Mindenrossz). A combination of several contracts e.g. No Tricks, No Hearts, No Obers and No Red King.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="1" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="1" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1002" value="Card Game" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2040" value="Hand Management" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="8120" value="Card Games: Shedding / Stops" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="98" value="Components: Traditional Playing Cards" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="171" value="(Public Domain)" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="10" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1.36015" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="10" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="6" />
			<numweights value="2" />
			<averageweight value="2.5" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>