<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="91456">
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Raiding Stonehenge" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Object of the game: The object of the game is to score the most points. Players score 10 points for each complete set of disks they collect at end of game. A set normally contains one disk of each color: White, red, green, blue, yellow. Players LOSE one point for each disk not in a set.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Equipment: Deck of 60 cards, excluding the Trilithon cards.&amp;#10;50 disks, 10 per color. Each disk type represents a different item type from Camelot.&amp;#10;1 gray figure (to mark start player).&amp;#10;1 colored figure per player.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Playing the Game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Starting player picks a card, from the bottom of one of the vertically arranged line of cards, adding it to his hand to make a hand size of 6.&amp;#10;2. Going clockwise, each player picks the last card at bottom of a vertically arranged line. More than one card can be taken from the same line during a turn.&amp;#10;3. Players simultaneously play one card and place face down.&amp;#10;4. Players then flip their cards face up.&amp;#10;5. Non-black card playing players go first, highest to lowest, players put their figure next to the pile of disks matching their color. In event of tie, the player closest to start player places first, then the second place player goes.&amp;#10;6. All black card playing players then place their figures, starting with highest number and going to lowest, next to any color on the board. In event of tie, break same way as non-black card players.&amp;#10;7. If every player is next to a unique color, each player takes a piece.&amp;#10;8. If more than one player is next to the same pile of same colored disks, In order of highest the lowest number played next to each pile (colored card played first, then black card played after), player take and set aside disks. Players may not set aside disks from the disks they are taking.&amp;#10;9. Player add the disks they just took (if any) and puts it into their pile of disks they took prior, or new pile in front of them, if they don't have any. It is recommended players sort their disks by color to make tracking easier. Which disks were taken prior is public knowledge. In addition, any disks they set aside to be put back, go back into the pile(s) the color(s) of the disks they are to put back. Also, if there are not enough piece to take or set aside, players take or set aside whatever they can. This means that players may take and/or set aside no disks.&amp;#10;10. Cards are replenished, left to right (one card at a time per line), replenishing each line of cards to the number of cards equal to the number of players in the game. Cards remaining in lines that were taken slide down, and new cards back filled in so each line equals the number of players in the game. The last card dealt onto each line, is the last card in that line, and would be the last card players would take from that line in future turns.&amp;#10;11. Each player takes back their figure.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game ends when all players are unable to replenish their hands to five cards. At that point, game is over, and players total up their points. The player with the most points wins. In event of a tie, all the players who are tied look at their remaining cards in their hands. The player with the highest card wins. If two players tie, they each look for the next highest card. Continue until one player has a card that is greater than their opponent. That player wins the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2007" />
						               				<minplayers value="4" />
						               				<maxplayers value="5" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="5+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      			

			      			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="14759" value="Country: England" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="63" value="Game: Stonehenge" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="8933" value="Richard Hutnik" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1001" value="(Web published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4238" value="Paizo Publishing" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="3" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>