<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="94369">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/GmJNLTZOUjNYthYSoXYP-Q__thumb/img/oPe3usGa816Ry6crJnZJJuHG03Q=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic936629.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/GmJNLTZOUjNYthYSoXYP-Q__original/img/Q_h6jW3gvOzxHXvugOI1-AXW0eg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic936629.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Guam: Island War Series, Volume II" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>(from the company website)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Guam is a large island for a Pacific island battle. However, it has the fewest exclusive rules of the three games currently in the series (Saipan &amp;amp; Tinian and Attu &amp;amp; Kiska). This means that it should be the easiest and quickest to learn. The large size of the island allows both players to employ a wide variety of strategy options. As with most of the other games in the series, the victory conditions do not focus on geographic locations. The situation is simply a fight between both sides.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Planning is the first step, and quite possibly the most important one too. The US player has to examine the Japanese dispositions, by looking over the map and using the limited intelligence rules to try to figure out where the Japanese main defenses are. Next in the planning cycle is to pick landing locations and then select the composition and order of your beachheads and landing forces. Once the US player lands on the island he has to eliminate the Japanese units. That is a pretty simple goal, but it may not be as easy as it sounds! You have to do it within the game&amp;rsquo;s time limit. He will have to find that perfect balance between time, maneuver, and combat. Too slow, cautious, or methodical and you run out of time. Too impatient and aggressive and you will suffer too many casualty points to win.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;In Guam the Japanese player has many options; the most of all the games in the series. You still have many of the same conditions as the other games, such as fortifications, being outnumbered, defending against an overwhelming invasion, and your opponent has air and naval superiority. However, you have a large enough force on a large enough island to allow far more opportunity for maneuvering. The Japanese player also has a variety of terrain types to incorporate into his defense. The clever use of dummy positions can fool the US player, making him attack unmanned positions or chasing scattered dummy units all over the map. But as in all the games, the Japanese player must have a well thought out plan with several courses of action in mind. Fortifications and dummies must be well placed in anticipation of US player moves.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Series&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game scale:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Unit size: Platoon, Company, and Battalion.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Scale: Hex scale: 1/2 mile.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game Turn: Each turn represents 12 hours.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The Pacific Island Series game system is a simulation of ground combat in the Pacific during World War II. Each game in the system represents a battle between Allied and Imperial Japanese forces on one of the many Pacific Islands. The series includes Saipan/Tinian -Vol. I,  Guam - Vol. II and Attu &amp;amp; Kiska - Vol. III.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Two sets of rules are provided with each game. The first contains the Standard Rules that are common to all the games in the Pacific Island Series. The second set contains the Exclusive Rules for each game in the system, which includes Special rules, the Initial Deployment and the Reinforcement Schedule. Generally the unit scale is battalion, but there are company and platoon formations represented. The time scale, unless noted in the Exclusive rules, is 1/2 day per turn.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;The focus of the series is on the land battles of the Pacific, therefore all naval and air forces are abstract. The games are designed for two players, but can accommodate multiple players. For example, one player can play the US Marines, one can play the US Army, and the third plays the Japanese.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;This series of games is loosely based on or inspired by several different game systems, including SPI's Island War series and GRD/GDW's Europa series, but many concepts are quite original. The tactical situation for the defender can be described as &amp;quot;against the odds&amp;quot;, which means it will be very difficult for the player playing the defender to win the game tactically. The victory conditions are designed in such a way that the defender can win by performing better than his historical counterpart. This also puts a lot of pressure on the attacker because he cannot afford to make many mistakes.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game features include:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;1. Limited intelligence.&amp;#10;2. Amphibious Landings&amp;#10;3. Weather and Night rules&amp;#10;4. Banzai attacks&amp;#10;5. Coastal Defense units&amp;#10;6. Beachheads and Replacements&amp;#10;7. Fortifications&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="0" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="3" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="0" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1017" value="Dice" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1049" value="World War II" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2026" value="Hexagon Grid" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="70778" value="Islands: Marianas (USA)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="71225" value="Series: Island War Series (Legion Wargames)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="6231" value="Michael Taylor (I)" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="9512" value="Legion Wargames LLC" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="9" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
																				<rank type="family" id="4664" name="wargames" friendlyname="War Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="1" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="3" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="2" />
			<wishing value="15" />
			<numcomments value="5" />
			<numweights value="1" />
			<averageweight value="2" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>