<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="95824">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_8E9mbohZKb0WrCFdl4zjQ__thumb/img/jBiclfUN4FgClq8QhTygTghRlLI=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic956125.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/_8E9mbohZKb0WrCFdl4zjQ__original/img/xqKviWiHvCIW8UOFi73EYVMblHM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic956125.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="5" value="Der Tempel des Schlangengottes" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>Central idea and goal of the game&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Players are adventurers trying to find the temple of the God of Snakes in the jungle. Unfortunately, this is a rather dangerous endeavour as the jungle is full of poisonous snakes. The expedition that is first to reach the temple wins the game. Be careful not to run out of snake antivenom though...&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game-play (short summary)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player moves their token on a board. Normal movement is one space, but moving 2, 3 or 4 spaces is possible via a push-your-luck element (pulling an item out of a bag, which, depending on what you draw, allows you to move more spaces or costs you some of your antivenom). A player who has no antivenom left is eliminated from the game. Event cards add another luck element.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Game-play (detailed description)&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each player gets a player token (wooden jeep) and 6 bottles of antivenom (cardboard chits). The jeeps are placed on the starting area of the board. Players try to get their jeep to the temple by moving it on the board. The board has four types of spaces: normal spaces, swamp spaces, river spaces and event spaces.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Normally, players move their jeep one space per turn. On each space, there can only be one jeep, and players must move their jeep. Instead of moving one space, players can choose to call upon the God of Snakes - either because they want to get on more quickly or because moving one space would take them on a space they can't stop on (because it is already occupied by another player's jeep or because it is a swamp space on which players are not allowed to stop).&amp;#10;&amp;#10;To call upon the God of Snakes, a player has to reach into the &amp;quot;magic bag&amp;quot;. The bag contains 4 wooden snakes, two green ones, a blue one and a red one.&amp;#10;If a player draws the dangerous red mamba, they are not allowed to move on and immediately use up one of their antivenom bottles. The red snake is then put back into the bag. &amp;#10;If a player draws a blue or green snake, it means that the God of Snakes has answered their prayers. The snake is put on the next free altar space in the center of the board. The number on the altar space tells the player how many spaces they move (2, 3 or 4 spaces). When the last blue or green snake has been drawn, all snakes are returned to the bag.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Drawing the blue snake announces dangerous water snakes. If any player is on a river space when the blue snake is drawn (or if they would land on a river space after moving), they lose a bottle of antivenom.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a player lands on an event space, they have to draw an event card. Event cards are either positive or negative: losing/gaining a bottle of antivenom, choosing a player to lose a turn, having to draw a snake from the bag, getting another turn, losing a turn, moving forwards/backwards one or more spaces.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If a player has lost all their antivenom, it becomes too dangerous to continue the expedition and they are eliminated from the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1995" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="4" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="3">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="4+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="30" />
						               				<minplaytime value="30" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="30" />
						               				<minage value="6" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1041" value="Children's Game" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1031" value="Racing" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2078" value="Point to Point Movement" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="7509" value="Animals: Snakes" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="500" value="Manfred Ludwig" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgameartist" id="48589" value="Peter Walkerstorfer" />
		
									
			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="16590" value="Polehnia Spiele" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="0" />
			<average value="0" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="1" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="2" />
			<numcomments value="0" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>