<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="96927">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/O1w5kQVmo5KiUd45xsqylg__thumb/img/-b2add-3tgHSPRK962bJ8XNG07I=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic970257.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/O1w5kQVmo5KiUd45xsqylg__original/img/o_iFitVPcurMGnUcLIb5n-bLmmg=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic970257.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Geus en Spanjool" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>This game is situated in the low countries during the revolt against Spain, resulting in the independency of the Dutch Republic.&amp;#10;One player takes the Spanish side and the other the Dutch. Control of the land is achieved by controlling the various cities. To signify the control each city is covered with a chit which has a Spanish side and a Dutch side. &amp;#10;At the beginning of the game the players decide on the number of rounds they will play (about 10 rounds per hour can be played, 20 to 30 round are recommended) and a die is rolled for each city. On a roll of 1, 2 or 3 the Spanish side is up, on 4, 5 or 6 the Dutch side. Each player gets three leaders to control their armies and 15 units of infantry. The Spanish get an extra two units of cavalry and the Dutch two units of naval troops (watergeuzen)&amp;#10;Each round both players roll a die. Their separate scores are the number of action points they have for that round. The combined number of both dies is used to decide on a random effect to be carried out before the round is started. &amp;#10;Victory points can only be scored as the result of a specific random effect. For each province (there are 16 provinces with 1 to 8 cities) where one players controls all cities that player scores a victory point for each city in the province. &amp;#10;The player with the highest roll starts the round, in case of a tie the Spanish player. Units are moved over the board by leaders, they cannot move alone. The naval units can move independently but only from one coastal city to another. Movement costs actions. A player can conquer cities by spending action points storming, starving or tricking them. A random event can cause the city to change its alliance at the start of a new round as well.&amp;#10;Battles between armies are  a special affair: both sides take only one turn rolling dies, one die for a unit of infantry, three for cavalry and three for each point their best leaders ability is higher than the other players best leaders. First the defending player rolls the dies, scoring a hit for each 6 rolled. Then, after taking her losses, the attacker does the same, the defender taking her losses. The winner of the battle is the player who rolled the most sixes or, when both rolled the same number, the defender. The defeated player loses the entire army, both units and leaders!&amp;#10;After the last round there is a final victory point calculation. In this calculation a point is awarded for each city the player controls, regardless of province control.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="1994" />
						               				<minplayers value="2" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="120" />
						               				<minplaytime value="120" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="120" />
						               				<minage value="12" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="1">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="1" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1070" value="Renaissance" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1019" value="Wargame" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2001" value="Action Points" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="61979" value="Players: Two Player Only Games" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamedesigner" id="48058" value="Karim van Overmeire" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="4" value="(Self-Published)" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="16728" value="vzw Excalibur Historische Spelen" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="2" />
			<average value="6.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="4" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="1" />
			<numcomments value="2" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>