<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><items termsofuse="https://boardgamegeek.com/xmlapi/termsofuse"><item type="boardgame" id="97111">
         <thumbnail>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/o1ewdsZMRGHmUwUAK77skQ__thumb/img/Wx5uklDXsWFe22BFvKqVB-7Ae6Q=/fit-in/200x150/filters:strip_icc()/pic974900.jpg</thumbnail>
      <image>https://cf.geekdo-images.com/o1ewdsZMRGHmUwUAK77skQ__original/img/5lNWohPHbVhSDnMxscQLPhwEfbM=/0x0/filters:format(jpeg)/pic974900.jpg</image>
                                     				
				<name type="primary" sortindex="1" value="Fastscore Football" />
			
						                           
						               													<description>From the publisher's website:&amp;#10;&amp;#10;A perfect complement to Second Season Football for solo replay projects.  FastScore Football allows the Replayer to quickly play out a whole day's schedule of games, including realistic scores, in just minutes!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;It's a quick play game that generates the score of a football game with a few rolls of the dice. It incorporates ease of play, a simple ratings system and simple charts. Hundreds of simulated seasons are run, ensuring the accuracy of each Fastscore season while factoring in each team&amp;rsquo;s strength of schedule.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Although the ratings seem simple, there is a great deal of background information packed into each rating. This game uniquely takes into account the offensive and defensive styles of each team by separating scoring frequency and scoring ability. For example, some teams may score frequently, but fail to execute in the red zone- thus adding points to the board with field goals more frequently than touchdowns. Others may rarely score but efficiently march into the endzone- thus scoring more touchdowns than field goals.   Additionally, offensive and defensive strengths in the running and passing game are reflected in the ratings and will influence the score of the game.  For example, teams with strong defenses against the run will more effectively shut down teams that rely on the running game.  And in close games, give your team a fighting chance by going for a 2-pt conversion!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;With Fastscore football, teams will perform similarly to their real-life stats in points for and against, touchdowns for and against, field goals for and against, and most importantly, their win-loss record.  These stats are fine-tuned to a 250-season average typically within 10 points of actual, and within 2 TDs and FGs of actual.  Strength of schedule is factored into the ratings to ensure the utmost in accuracy.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;And the best part: we&amp;rsquo;ve included the as-played schedule for each season! And we didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there- we know that your time is valuable, so we&amp;rsquo;ve calculated the final team ratings for each game on the schedule- taking into account home field advantage and the run/pass ratings- so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do the calculations yourself.  Just sit back, roll the dice and mark down the score of the game.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fastscore Football is played using two differently colored 6-sided dice. Each team has seven ratings representing offensive and defensive abilities and a clutch rating. Better ratings are color coded in green while worse ratings are color coded in red. Higher offense ratings represent teams with punishing offenses. Lower defense ratings represent teams that effectively shut down their opponents.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;If you play Fastscore as a stand-alone game, you can finish a season replay in a few hours! You can also use Fastscore Football as a complement to detailed, play by play games like Second Season Football. If you are enjoying a single team replay, play your favorite team&amp;rsquo;s games with your favorite football game while playing out the other games on the schedule with Fastscore, and see how your team is doing in the standings! A week&amp;rsquo;s worth of games can be completed in less than 15 minutes!&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Fastscore offers great value for the gamer. Each Fastscore set includes multiple seasons for one low price! We intend to rate every season from current day to the seasons of yesteryear.&amp;#10;&amp;#10;Each season includes: &amp;#10;&amp;#10;    Rules of the game&amp;#10;    Scoring Charts&amp;#10;    Team Ratings Chart&amp;#10;    As-Played Schedule with pre-calculated game ratings for each team&amp;#10;&amp;#10;&amp;#10;</description>
										      	               				<yearpublished value="2010" />
						               				<minplayers value="1" />
						               				<maxplayers value="2" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_numplayers" title="User Suggested Number of Players" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results numplayers="1">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
			
		<results numplayers="2+">		
					<result value="Best" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Recommended" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="Not Recommended" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			               				<playingtime value="0" />
						               				<minplaytime value="0" />
						               				<maxplaytime value="0" />
						               				<minage value="8" />
						      			<poll name="suggested_playerage" title="User Suggested Player Age" totalvotes="0">
			<results>		
					<result value="2" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="3" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="4" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="5" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="6" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="8" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="10" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="12" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="14" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="16" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="18" numvotes="0" />
					<result value="21 and up" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			<poll name="language_dependence" title="Language Dependence" totalvotes="0">
			
		<results>		
					<result level="1" value="No necessary in-game text" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="2" value="Some necessary text - easily memorized or small crib sheet" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="3" value="Moderate in-game text - needs crib sheet or paste ups" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="4" value="Extensive use of text - massive conversion needed to be playable" numvotes="0" />
					<result level="5" value="Unplayable in another language" numvotes="0" />
				</results>					
	</poll> 			      			 			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamecategory" id="1038" value="Sports" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2072" value="Dice Rolling" />
		
									
				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamemechanic" id="2070" value="Simulation" />
		
									
			

			      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamefamily" id="5640" value="Sports: American Football / Gridiron" />
		
									
			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      			

			      	      	      			

			      			

			      	      				
		 			

			
		
					<link type="boardgamepublisher" id="1095" value="Replay Publishing" />
		
									
			

			
	

	

	
	
	
   		<statistics page="1">
								<ratings >
			<usersrated value="4" />
			<average value="7.5" />
			<bayesaverage value="0" />

			<ranks>
															<rank type="subtype" id="1" name="boardgame" friendlyname="Board Game Rank" value="Not Ranked" bayesaverage="Not Ranked" />
												</ranks>

			<stddev value="0.5" />
			<median value="0" />
			<owned value="7" />
			<trading value="0" />
			<wanting value="0" />
			<wishing value="0" />
			<numcomments value="1" />
			<numweights value="0" />
			<averageweight value="0" />
			</ratings>
								</statistics>
     
	
          
</item>
</items>